<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-industrial-corridors-labour-intensive-sectors-may-getboost_8250201.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Industrial corridors, labour-intensive sectors may get a boost]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance minister Arun Jaitley may propose a package of tax incentives for the labour-intensive leather, gems and jewellery sectors as part of the government's signature "Make in India"  initiative to boost manufacturing, create jobs and revive exports.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Finance minister Arun Jaitley may propose a package of tax incentives for the labour-intensive leather, gems and jewellery sectors as part of the government's signature "Make in India"&nbsp; initiative to boost manufacturing, create jobs and revive exports.<br /><br />Besides, India's plans to create its own versions of China-style mega industrial cities peppered across the country equipped with production units, public utilities, residential areas, schools and hospitals will likely get a big fiscal push in Budget 2017-18.<br /><br />There is expectation that outlay for industrial corridors will be substantially raised from Rs 1448 crore in 2016-17, signalling the government's intent to use these mega enclaves as one of the major vehicles to push the `Make in India' initiative.<br /><br />The country has notified five major industrial corridors - Delhi-Mumbai Industrial Corridor (DMIC), Amritsar Kolkata Industrial Corridor (AKIC), Chennai Bengaluru Industrial Corridor (CBIC), Visakhapatnam-Chennai Industrial Corridor (VCIC) and Bengaluru- Mumbai Economic Corridor (BMEC), spread across 15 states.<br /><br />The budget may also propose to remove minimum alternate tax (MAT) for enterprises that operate out of the 200-odd special economic zones (SEZs) in the country. Currently, units operating out of these duty-free enclaves pay MAT at the rate of 18.5 percent on their book profits.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/m/Make_in_india_356x200_4623_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-11 20:40:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>