<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-rs-24-lakh-cr-for-transport-infra-aai-land-to-be-monetised_8401501.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Rs 2.4 lakh cr for transport infra; AAI land to be monetised]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Touching a possible hot potato in his Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said the Airport Authority Act will be amended to monetise its land. The resources, so raised, will be used for airport upgradation. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol bureau</strong><br />
<p>The government will spend Rs 2,41,387 crore on expanding rail, road, water and air transport infrastructure in the next financial year. This is almost 11% higher from Rs. 2,18,000 crore set aside for the multi-modal infrastructure in the 2016-17 Union Budget.</p>
<p>Touching a possible hot potato in his Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said the Airport Authority Act will be amended to monetise its land. The resources, so raised, will be used for airport upgradation. <br /><br />He also said&nbsp;select airports in Tier 2 cities would be taken up for operation and maintenance under the public-private partnership model.</p>
<p>Of the 2017-18 allocation of Rs. 2,41,387 crores, Rs. 131,000 crores will go to railways.</p>
<p>The 2017-18 Union Budget, tabled today by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, has set aside Rs. 64,900 crores for expanding the national highways implemented under its National Highways Development Programee. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Jaitley revealed the pace of construction of roads under Pradhan Mantri Gram Sadak Yojna had accelerated to 133 km per day against 73 km during 2011-14.</p>
<p>The government has taken up the task of connecting habitations with more than 100 persons in left wing extremism affected blocks under Pradhan Mantri Gram Sadak Yojna.</p>
<p>All such affected habitations are expected to be covered by 2019 and the allocation for PMGSY, including the state's share is Rs. 27,000 crores in 2017-18.</p>
<p>Total length of roads, including those under PMGSY, built from 2014-15 till the current year is about 1,40,000 kms, which is significantly higher than previous three years, Jaitley said in his almost 2-hour-long speech.</p>
<p>Coastal connectivity roads -- connecting 2,000 kms -- have been identified for construction and development, the Finance Minister said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/r/road-project-356_4541_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 21:42:29</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>