<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/budget-2017-telcos-want-lower-withholding-taxprepaid-cards_8373081.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Telcos want lower withholding tax on prepaid cards]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Telecom companies transfer prepaid vouchers and SIM cards to independent distributors at a discount, who further sell to retailers or subscribers.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Dhirendra Tripathi</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol</strong><br /><br />Telecom companies transfer prepaid vouchers and SIM cards to independent distributors at a discount, who further sell to retailers or subscribers. The companies prefer not to withhold tax &ndash; the rate as such being 5 percent --&nbsp;on discount offered to distributors since they claim distributors are not their agents and hence, discount offered to them could be termed as commission.<br /><br />The sector is now reconciled to the stance of the authorities but given the low margins, wants the withholding tax to come down to 2 percent in the 2017-18 Union Budget, as per COAI&rsquo;s suggestions sent to the Finance Ministry.<br /><br />&ldquo;The revenue argues that this discount to the wholesalers/ distributors on the pre-paid vouchers is actually a commission and therefore liable to withholding taxes. Heaps of cases have piled up before the courts on this matter and Budget 2017 must provide some viable solution to this problem,&rdquo; Naveen Aggarwal, Partner &ndash; Tax, KPMG, said.<br /><br />Another provision -- this one brought in by Finance Act 2012 -- relates to treatment of transmission services through satellite or cable &ndash; as &lsquo;royalty&rsquo; and not as standard service. Also, use of equipment irrespective of any actual possession or control of rights, properties or information has been termed as royalty.<br /><br />Industry lobby group Cellular Operators Association of India disputes classification of such services as royalty, contending that this violated Double Taxation Avoidance Agreements signed by India with other countries. The body wants a retrospective amendment to exclude standard service arrangements for rendition of telecommunication services.<br /><br />Telecom companies are looking for some clarity and relief on service tax on spectrum allocated before April 1, 2016 but actually allotted after that. There have been cases where service tax has been levied on spectrum allotted after April 1, 2016. Companies want to be spared of this service tax since the allocation was done before that date and the allotment was only a procedural exercise. <br /><br />For obtaining permission to lay optical fibre cables within municipal limits, telecom operators are required to pay right of way access charges to local authorities/municipalities. Local bodies are liable to pay tax on such access charges though as a matter of practice, no tax is being discharged by them since they argue that this tax is related to land and buildings on which they have exclusive taxation powers and that income of state government/local bodies could be subjected to Union taxes. <br /><br />However, where service tax demands are confirmed by the authorities, local bodies are trying to make recoveries of both -- the tax amounts as well as interest and penalties from the business entities. <br /><br />COAI wants retrospective exemption be given to local bodies from payment of service tax on such charges.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/t/telecom_1_5713_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 16:45:40</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>