<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-government-restricts-cash-transactions-beyond-rs-3-lakhs_8401421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Government restricts cash transactions beyond Rs 3 lakhs]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The government has also proposed a penalty in case if there is a cash transaction beyond Rs 3 lakh.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>The government today proposed a cap on cash transactions beyond Rs 3 lakh from April 1, 2017, part of its broader strategy to clamp down on black money.</p>
<p>"It is proposed to provide that no person shall receive payment or aggregate of payments of an amount of three lakh rupees or more from a person in a day, or in respect of a single transaction, or in respect of transactions relating to one event or occasion, otherwise than by an account payee cheque or account payee bank draft or use of electronic clearing system through a bank account," Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said today while presenting Union Budget 2017-18.</p>
<p>Such restriction, however, will not be applied to government, banks or an person notified by the Centre.</p>
<p>The government has also proposed a penalty in case if there is a cash transaction beyond Rs 3 lakh.</p>
<p>"The penalty is proposed to be a sum equal to the amount of such receipt. The said penalty shall however not be levied if the person proves that there were good and sufficient reasons for such contravention," the government said.</p>
<p>The announcement is based on the Special Investigation Team's (SIT) recommendations last year.</p>
<p>SIT was formed by the government more than two years back, to curb black money as well as recover large amounts of money stashed abroad by evading taxes or generated through unlawful activities.</p>
<p>In addition, less than three months back, Prime Minister Narendra Modi, scrapped Rs 500 and Rs 1000 notes -- comprising 86 percent cash in circulation -- taking away their legal tender status from midnight of November 8.</p>
<p>It triggered the world&rsquo;s largest currency recall exercise, as part of the Modi-government&rsquo;s move to crack down on India&rsquo;s thriving black transactions and also push the country towards a &ldquo;less-cash&rdquo; economy.</p>
<p>In India has a massive amount of domestic black money, which adversely affects the revenue of the government, creating a resource crunch for its various welfare programmes.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/c/cashcleanup_356_4856_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 21:17:30</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>