<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/real-estate/budget-2017-lower-holding-period-for-capital-gainsboon-for-homeowners_8399981.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Lower holding period for capital gains a boon for homeowners]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In his Budget speech Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said the holding period for considering gain from immovable property to be long term will be reduced to 2 years from the existing 3 years.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>Homeowners seeking to sell their house after two years of getting possession will cheer Budget 2017-18 as the duration of holding to avail long term capital gains benefits is proposed to be reduced to 2 years from the earlier 3 years.</p>
<p>The move, which is aimed at boosting the real estate sector, is being widely hailed by stakeholders. &ldquo;The announcement on long term capital gains on immovable property is an extremely good news for real estate investors as they can book profits by paying a bare minimum income tax at the end of two years only on profits earned from sale of property,&rdquo; Getamber Anand, President, CREDAI National, said.</p>
<p>In his Budget speech Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said the holding period for considering gain from immovable property to be long term will be reduced to 2 years from the existing 3 years.</p>
<p>&ldquo;We also plan to extend the basket of financial instruments in which the capital gains can be invested without payment of tax,&rdquo; Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said in his budget speech.</p>
<p>Long-term gains from the sale of property is exempt if invested in purchase or construction of a house property, with certain conditions.&nbsp;However, short-term capital gains are taxed at 20 per cent, except for equities where the tax treatment is different.</p>
<p>This proposed amendment comes into effect from April 1, 2018 and will apply in relation to the assessment year 2018-19 and subsequent years.</p>
<p>Anuj Puri, Chairman &amp; Country Head, JLL India said that the move would lead to more activity in the real estate sector. &ldquo;The time limit for capital gains to be considered as a long term gain has been reduced to 2 years from the earlier 3 years. More supply will enter the housing market now,&rdquo; Puri said.</p>
Shishir Baijal, Chairman &amp; Managing Director, Knight Frank India, felt that the amendment to the long term capital gains exemption will lead to greater compliance. &ldquo;The move to reduce the tenure of the Long Term Capital Gain from 3 years to 2 years will encourage compliance amongst the real estate stakeholders,&rdquo; Baijal said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/a/affordable-energy--356_5247_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 19:45:06</Entry_Date><Category>Real Estate</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>