<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-health-recordssenior-citizensaadhaar-getsthumbs-up_8399341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Health records of senior citizens on Aadhaar gets a thumbs up]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Embedding health data of senior citizens on Aadhaar card was among the major healthcare initiatives proposed by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech on Wednesday. Healthcare industry chiefs lauded the proposal saying such digital penetration could be key to affordable and accessible healthcare to Indian masses.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Chaitanya Gudipaty</strong><br /><strong> Moneycontrol</strong></p>
<p>Embedding health data of senior citizens on Aadhaar card was among the major healthcare initiatives proposed by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech on Wednesday. Healthcare industry chiefs lauded the proposal saying that such digital penetration could be key to affordable and accessible healthcare to Indian masses.</p>
<p>&ldquo;For senior citizens, Aadhaar-based smart cards containing their health details will be introduced. A beginning will be made through a pilot in 15 districts during 2017-18,&rdquo; Jaitley said in his speech.</p>
<p>Terming the healthcare push in the Budget as &ldquo;promising&rdquo;, Apoorva Patni, Director of Patni Healthcare said: &ldquo;Aadhaar-based smart cards for senior citizens with their health details is a welcome move. By digitising and collating the data of the senior citizens, the data can further provide insights/analysis and serve as a great potential to improve the quality of lives of the citizens.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Patni, the son of Patni Computers co-founder Ashok Patni, added: &ldquo;This will only lead to better and seamless facilities being made available to the general public who face numerous hassles on a daily basis. These measures will help strengthening the existing healthcare system and making it robust database for healthcare players.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Till now, the health data in India was fragmented and government&rsquo;s move to consolidate it with the Aadhaar Card is a positive sign as it shows that preventive healthcare is a priority for this government,&rdquo; said Vishal Gondal, CEO and Founder of healthcare wearables startup, GOQii.</p>
<p>He added: &ldquo;We are hoping that this benefit will be extended to the wearable healthcare segment too which has been propagating the concept of preventive healthcare in India.&rdquo;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/aadhaar_uidai_new_2144_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 18:21:36</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>