<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-to-go-for-growthbudget-accept-bigger-deficit-poll_8379881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt to go for growth in Budget, accept bigger deficit: Poll]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Median forecasts ahead of Finance Minister Arun Jaitley's Budget are broadly in line with figures discussed over the past few days, with deficit forecasts ranging from just under 3 percent to as high as 4 percent for the coming two years. The poll was conducted Jan. 27-30.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>India's government is expected to unveil a Budget on Wednesday aimed at boosting economic growth through additional spending, with borrowing seen rising to 3.3 percent of gross domestic product in the coming fiscal year and 3 percent in the year after that, economists polled by Reuters say.</p>
<p>Median forecasts ahead of Finance Minister Arun Jaitley's Budget are broadly in line with figures discussed over the past few days, with deficit forecasts ranging from just under 3 percent to as high as 4 percent for the coming two years. The poll was conducted Jan. 27-30.</p>
<p>That will effectively delay by a year an earlier plan of bringing the fiscal gap down to 3 percent of GDP in 2017/18 from the current 3.5 percent Budgeted for this year.</p>
<p>Twenty-four of 36 economists surveyed said the government's key theme in the Budget will be to use additional borrowing to support growth.</p>
<p>Possible measures include reducing personal income and corporate tax as well as higher public investment.</p>
<p>Only four economists said the government will choose to dish out more subsidies, while the remaining eight said fiscal consolidation will be the theme.</p>
<p>The 2017/18 Budget comes less than three months after Prime Minister Narendra Modi's bold and risky gamble to outlaw high-value old currency bills, which has slammed the brakes on Asia's third-largest economy and hit the poor particularly hard.</p>
<p>With uncertainty over how quickly the economy will recover, economists say the new Budget is likely to echo what India has become accustomed to in the past -- expansion of spending programmes rather than fiscal restraint.</p>
<p>"As has been the case at times in the past, we think that the government will have to tread very carefully between the need for stimulating demand in a weak economic environment after demonetization and continuing on the path of fiscal consolidation," wrote Nupur Gupta, economist at Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>"We expect the government to Budget for a fiscal deficit target of 3.3 percent of GDP, 30 basis points higher than planned in the government's medium-term fiscal consolidation program."</p>
<p>While Standard and Poor's has warned India needs to maintain its fiscal consolidation path for any prospects of a ratings upgrade, Jaitley is under pressure to boost growth after the government's shock decision in November sparked a cash crunch.</p>
<p>A recent Reuters poll predicted that Asia's third-largest economy lost considerable momentum in the final three months of 2016 after the move dented consumption and business confidence.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/2/2017-01-31T071121Z_1_LYNXMPED0U0C2_RTROPTP_2_INDIA-BUDGET_356.JPG]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 13:06:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>