<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-positive-for-farmers-small-businesses-hp-india_8399641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017 positive for farmers, small businesses: HP India]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The tax relief given by the Government for the middle class tax payers will definitely boost the purchasing power, thereby aiding the overall growth of the economy, says Rajiv Srivastava, MD, HP India.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Rajiv Srivastava, MD, HP India:</strong><br /><br />&ldquo;The Union Budget 2017-18 is extremely positive for the common man, farmers, small and medium businesses and would drive significant growth in Indian economy. Government&rsquo;s commitment to make taxation rate reasonable, tax administration fair and expand the tax base is the step taken in the right direction. The tax relief given by the Government for the middle class tax payers will definitely boost the purchasing power, thereby aiding the overall growth of the economy. The major tax relief given to the MSMEs and SMEs with an annual turnover of Rs 50 crore, would enable them to invest in job creation, increase capital expenditure and explore their digital journey."<br /><br />"The strong emphasis laid on technology in almost all the development areas in the budget reaffirms that technology has been at the forefront of India&rsquo;s recent economic growth and digital transformation. It has been recognized as an important enabler across initiatives ranging from agriculture to skill development to manufacturing and infrastructural development. The Government&rsquo;s focus on making India a digital payment economy will definitely help companies like HP to contribute in technology adoption in rural and semi-urban areas, thereby bringing the Digital India&rsquo; vision closer to reality. We also welcome the Finance Minister&rsquo;s commitment to introduce and implement Goods and Services Tax (GST) as per schedule and start GST awareness programme from April 1, 2017 for all stakeholders.&rdquo;]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/5/500_note_Budget_2017_rupee_356x200_3015_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 18:57:13</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>