<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-a-rs-131-lakh-cr-booster-to-give-indian-railwaysfacelift_8390301.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: A Rs 1.31 lakh cr booster to give Indian Railways a facelift]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The corpus -- called Rashtriya Rail Sanraksha Kosh -- will be used to carry out various passenger safety works and will come up over 5 years.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dhirendra Tripathi<br /></strong><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>The Indian Railways will spend Rs 1.31 lakh crore on maintaining and expanding its network, improving passenger safety and amenities, buying new wagons and coaches in 2017-18.</p>
<p>This allocation is higher by 8.2 percent from Rs 1.21 lakh crore&nbsp;the government had set aside as capital outlay for the fourth largest network in the world.</p>
<p>The highlight of the section devoted to railways was the creation of a Rs. 1 trillion corpus for passenger safety.</p>
<p>The corpus -- called Rashtriya Rail Sanraksha Kosh -- will be used to carry out various passenger safety works and will come up over 5 years.</p>
<p>Besides seed capital from the government, the railways will arrange the balance resources from their own revenues and other sources.</p>
<p>&nbsp;The government would aim to eliminate all unmanned crossings by 2020, a measure to prevent train mishaps.</p>
<p>There will be no service charge on train tickets booked online via IRCTC.</p>
<p>This was the first time in independent India that the Union Budget had provisions on railways after it was decided to merge the Railway Budget with the main Budget.</p>
<p>Of the Rs 1.31 trillion capital expenditure planned by the railways, the government will provide Rs 55,000 crore from the Union Budget to help it undertake maintenance and development of its network.</p>
<p>Jaitley said the government would list the various railway entities -- Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation,&nbsp;IRCON&nbsp;International Ltd and Indian Railway Finance Ltd among them -- on stock exchanges. There isn't any railway entity that is listed yet.</p>
<p>He said the government would focus on passenger safety and cleanliness among other areas, ensuring bio toilets in every coach of the railways by 2019.</p>
<p>A new Metro Rail Act will be enacted by rationalising the existing laws. This will facilitate greater private participation and investment in construction and operation, Jaitley said in almost 2-hour long speech.</p>
<p>In line with its policy of encouraging use of renewable power, the government proposes to feed about 7,000 stations with solar power in the medium term, with the project already underway at 300 of those.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Railways_rail__356x200_1230_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 15:51:07</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>