<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/railway-budget-railways-to-have-special-safety-fundrs-1-lakh-cr_8392741.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Railway Budget: Railways to have special safety fund of Rs 1 lakh cr]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[With railways plagued by repeated derailments, government today proposed setting up of a special safety fund of Rs 1 lakh crore that will cover upgradation of tracks and signalling besides elimination of unmanned level crossings.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>With railways plagued by repeated derailments, government today proposed setting up of a special safety fund of Rs 1 lakh crore that will cover upgradation of tracks and signalling besides elimination of unmanned level crossings.</p>
<p>The Railway Budget, merged with General Budget 2017-18, also provides for commissioning of new railway lines of 3,500 km will against 2,800 kms in 2016-17.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced the Plan size for the next fiscal for the Railways at Rs 1,31,000 crore as against Rs 1.21 lakh crore last year.</p>
<p>He proposed creation of 'Rashtriya Rail Sanraksha Kosh' (National Rail Safety Fund) with a corpus of Rs 1 lakh crore.</p>
<p>Emphasising on safety, the Budget proposed elimination of all unmanned level crossings on the broad gauge network by 2020.</p>
<p>Addressing concerns of the differently-abled persons, Jaitley announced that 500 stations would be made disbaled friendly.</p>
<p>The Budget also promised to equip all coaches with bio toilets and announced "Clean my coach' App for passengers.</p>
<p>In order to encourage E-ticketing, Jaitley announced withdrawal of service charges from tickets booked through IRCTC.</p>
<p>Railway PSUs IRCTC, IRFC and Concor are to be listed on various stock exchanges.</p>
<p>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBslQpB4onkHTB8Ei9quwBxDOyqg">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE3J8DU_uiR6ilTdJKHisn5k8cv_g">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/r/railway_Budget_2017_railways_356x200_2722_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 14:14:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>