<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/24x7booking/jaitley-scotches-doubt-to-present-budget-at-11-am-today_8390141.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Jaitley scotches doubt, to present Budget at 11 am today]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The tweet came as doubt was being cast over presentation of the Budget in the wake the death of former Union minister and Indian Union Muslim League leader E Ahamed early this morning.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Brushing aside doubt in the wake of death of a sitting member, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today announced that he will present the Union Budget for 2017-18 as scheduled at 11 am.</p>
<p>"Watch me live presenting the Union Budget 2017 at 11 am, February 1, 2017," Finance Minister Arun Jaitley tweeted.</p>
<p>The tweet came as doubt was being cast over presentation of the Budget in the wake the death of former Union minister and Indian Union Muslim League leader E Ahamed early this morning.</p>
<p>Some quarters even demanded putting off the Budget presentation till tomorrow following the tradition of Lok Sabha adjourning for the day as a mark of respect whenever a sitting MP passes away.</p>
<p>The government, however, felt that performing a constitutional duty did not mean any disrespect to the departed soul and there were two precedents where death of a sitting MP and minister did not prevent the then government from presenting the Budget on the scheduled day.</p>
<p>Sources said the government cited death of minister M B Rana on the Budget day on August 31, 1974. The then Speaker G S Dhillon decided to go ahead with the Budget presentation.</p>
<p>Indira Gandhi was the prime minister then.</p>
<p>Also, on April 19, 1954, sitting member Jujhar Pal Sorein passed away on the day of presentation of the Railway Budget, but the House proceedings were held as scheduled.</p>
<p>Sources said that on both occasions, the Lok Sabha met in the morning and was adjourned for a few hours as mark of respect to the departed and the Budget was unveiled in the evening, in line with the schedule.</p>
<p>In those days, the Budget was presented in evening, usually at 5 pm.</p>
<p>The Budget presentation, the sources said, is likely after an obituary reference.</p>
<p>Also, all Budget papers are printed with today's date, postponement will cause many hassles, the government argued.</p>
<p>Sources said Jaitley met President Pranab Mukherjee in the morning to fulfil the constitutional obligation of getting a go-ahead from the head of state for the Budget presentation.</p>
<p>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBslQpB4onkHTB8Ei9quwBxDOyqg"> LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE3J8DU_uiR6ilTdJKHisn5k8cv_g"> Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/j/Jaitley_arun_FM_Finance_minister-356x2x00_2643_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-01 00:00:02</Entry_Date><Category>24X7booking</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>