<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-time-to-pay-taxpropertyjewellery-receipt-if-undervalued_8399921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Time to pay tax on property & jewellery receipt if undervalued]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The existing definition of property for the purpose of this section includes immovable property, jewellery, shares and paintings. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>If you are receiving property, jewellery, shares or paintings that could be valued over Rs 50,000 without any payment or with inadequate payment compared to its price, be prepared to pay tax. The taxman will be watching all such transactions in future.<br /><br />The Union Budget 2017-18 proposes amendment to the Income Tax Act to tax such receipts under the head &ldquo;income from other sources&rdquo;.</p>
<p>&ldquo;In order to prevent the practice of receiving the sum of money or the property without consideration or for inadequate consideration, it is proposed to insert a new clause in sub-section (2) of section 56 to provide that receipt of the sum of money or the property by any person without consideration or for inadequate consideration in excess of Rs. 50,000 shall be chargeable to tax in the hands of the recipient under the head "Income from other sources",&rdquo; the Memorandum to the Union Budget has said.</p>
<p>The existing definition of property for the purpose of this section includes immovable property, jewellery, shares and paintings.</p>
<p>The government also proposed to bring about consequential amendment in section 49 of the Income Tax Act for determination of cost of acquisition.</p>
<p>The memorandum says that presently anti-abuse provisions under the I-T laws are currently applicable only in limited cases of individuals, HUF, firms or companies. Therefore, receipt of sum of money or property without consideration or for inadequate consideration does not attract these anti-abuse provisions in cases of other assesses.</p>
The amendments will take effect from April 1, 2017 and the said receipt of sum of money or property on or after April 1, 2017 shall be chargeable to tax in accordance with the provisions of proposed new clause in the income tax.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/t/Tax_up_down_coins_356x200_4023_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 19:12:29</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>