<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/planning/budget-2017-small-steps-towardempowermenthomemakers_8335281.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Small steps toward the empowerment of homemakers]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Budget 2017 has taken small steps to help homemakers to build their future.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Taking constructive steps for betterment for women and homemakers, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced preferential treatment for MUDRA loans or the higher allocation to ICDS Anganwadi centers.<br /><br />The Finance Minister announced that Mahila Shakti Kendra will be set up at village level with an allocation of Rs 500 crore in 14 lakh ICDS Anganwadi Centres. This will provide one stop convergent support services for empowering rural women with opportunities for skill development, employment, digital literacy, health and nutrition. The budget highlighted the nationwide scheme for financial assistance to pregnant women announced by the Prime Minister on December 31. Under this scheme, Rs 6,000 each will be transferred directly to the bank accounts of pregnant women who undergo institutional delivery and vaccinate their children.<br /><br />For the welfare of women and children under various schemes across all ministries, the budget has proposed to step up the allocation from Rs1,56,528 crore in BE 2016-17 to Rs 1,84,632 crore in 2017-18.<br /><br />As the Finance Minister chose to reduce the income tax for the low income group, it will leave more money in the hands of the homemakers. The increase in investments in the education sector is also seen positively by homemakers as their children may get to access quality education.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_demonitisation_356x200_5312_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-24 19:08:37</Entry_Date><Category>Planning</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>