<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-experts/market-volatility-norm-as-earnings-coincidebudget-rel-mf_8276641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Market volatility norm as earnings coincide with Budget: Rel MF]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Sunil Singhania, CIO-Equity Investment, Reliance Mutual Funds says Indian investors have been very mature and positive towards the market. They have absorbed all the FII selling that has taken place, says Singhania.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[This would be the first time in many years when the earnings season coincides with the Budget. So, Sunil&nbsp;Singhania, CIO-Equity Investment, Reliance Mutual Funds, says volatility is going to be the order of the day.<br /><br />But even with all the events that are to happen this year, namely a Donald Trump US presidency, State elections and the implementation of GST, Singhania remains positive on the markets.&nbsp;<br /><br />For a couple of months, there may be a slowdown in foreign institutional investments (FII). But overall, this year will end in high flows back into the market.<br /><br />He says Indian investors have been very mature and positive towards the market. They have absorbed all the FII selling that has taken place, says Singhania.<br /><br />He is positive on the consumption segment, financials, and the cement sector. He prefers private sector banks over PSU banks. <br /><br />"The economy is growing and is resilient, the young population will continue to spend in shopping malls, theatres and other such places," he says.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Sunil Singhania&rsquo;s interview to Anuj Singhal &amp; Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /> <br /> <strong>Anuj: What is the most important issue that needs addressal in this Budget?</strong> <br /> <br /> A: Our top two to three from the Budget perspective is already well communicated by both the Finance Minister and as well as the Prime Minister. We do believe that this is going to be a Budget of growth, focused on growth. Obviously, a few sectors again which are well documented, well sort of communicated in terms of housing and infrastructure would be the key. From our perspective, we always look at Budget as one off continuity and we do believe that this fiscal consolidation as well as tax rationalisation should be the way forward. <br /> <br /><strong> Sonia: The other big issue everyone is worried about is the indirect transfer provision for foreign portfolio investors. The possibility of triple taxation is really scaring everybody. Would there be a clarification in the Budget and if not how big a concern would that be for foreign investors?</strong><br /> <br /> A: We are very confident that the government would not do anything which would unnecessarily disrupt investments into the country. Again, obviously, the attempt is to try and plug loopholes and to that extent we are very confident that the intention of any regulations whether direct or indirect would be towards that endeavor. So, we are very confident that honest structural long-term investments into the country will keep on getting encouragement from the government.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: What is the call on the market now, would you still be a bit cautious or do you think the worst is behind us?</strong><br /> <br /> A: Last one year in particular, we have seen lot of events causing higher volatility than normal. The trend going forward is also going to be of that. We have Trump taking over as President, we have the Union Budget, we have the state elections, we have earnings season which are coinciding with the Budget for the first time in so many years so volatility is going to be the order of the day. <br /> <br /> Having said that as equity investor and looking at the way the country continuous to be resilient irrespective of the all the news flows and all the events which are happening we remain quite positive. Our view would be that Indian equity is headed upwards. Yes, as I mentioned earlier the volatility is here to stay and that would always be the case. As we speak, we are more or less fully invested and we remain quite confident. <br /> <br /> <strong>Sonia: Since you are fully invested and you are confident you think we are looking at new highs by mid-2017 or is that a tall ask?</strong><br /> <br /> A: I don&rsquo;t know about mid 2017 but the way the economy is hitting new highs in terms of its absolute gross domestic product (GDP) there is no reason for us to believe that even if the equity markets keep on giving us 12-15 percent returns will have a new high every year. <br /> <br /> <strong>Anuj: What are the top two or three sectors that you are still bullish on in the first half of 2017?</strong><br /> <br /> A: We continue to maintain our stance, I think capital expenditure will improve going forward first led by government and government companies and then as demand picks up by the private sector. We continue to bet on companies which have good technology and where the operating leverage are lower. While we like the infrastructure space we are playing that more through our overweight stance on cement than construction companies because they are very few construction companies which have decent balance sheets. <br /> <br /> Again our view on financials continue to be positive however, we are moving to some part of the financials in to asset management companies or life insurance companies either directly or through the quasi route. We continue to prefer the private sector banks rather than public sector banks. <br /> <br /> The third sector where we continue to have our overweight stance is obviously the consumption segment and though in the recent past last couple of months it has got impacted by demonetisation. We do believe that the country is resilient, the economy is growing the young population will continue to spend and we are already seeing signs of it anecdotally when you visit malls or go to movie theaters and all so we will continue to maintain our overweight on that sector. <br /> <br /> <strong>Sonia: One final word on flows we are seeing some funds return back into global emerging markets. All be it India is still underperforming but do you think that the worst is over as far as the FII selling is concerned and should be expect a pickup in flows anytime soon?</strong><br /> <br /> A: These flows, we tend to focus a lot of the near term flows and time and again we have seen that it is possible that for a couple of months FII flows are negative, but when we take a year as a whole every year has been a record year for India as far as flows. Our view is that yes post Trump there was a strengthening in the dollar and money did move away from emerging markets into US that has already turned.<br /> <br /> Other than India almost all emerging markets have seen a big inflows. In India there was this concern about demonetisation, but I think that is also subsiding and it is a matter of days or weeks before we start to see flows returning back to India as far as foreign flows are concerned. <br /> <br /> However, interesting thing is that Indian investors have been much more matured and much more positive and almost all the FIIs selling has been more than absorbed by domestic institutions which is a welcome change from the past and it gives a lot of stability to the Indian equity markets for a time to come.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Sensex_BSE_Stockmarket_bulls_bear_356x200_3005_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-16 15:38:01</Entry_Date><Category>MF Experts</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>