<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-govt-to-turn-15-lakh-health-sub-centers-to-wellness-centers_8391061.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Govt to turn 1.5 lakh health sub-centers to wellness centers]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In the health sector, the government is committed to take structural reforms in the medical practice and education, said the Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech today. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /></strong></strong>
<p>In the Union Budget today, the government has allocated Rs 48,853 crore for health and family welfare for 2017-18 as compared to Rs 39,688 crore in 2016-17.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley reiterated the government's commitment to structural reforms in healthcare and&nbsp;medical practice in his Budget speech today.&nbsp;</p>
The government plans to amend the Drugs and Cosmetic Rules to ensure availability of drugs, including generic drugs, at reasonable price.&nbsp;<br /><br />The aim is to eliminate diseases like Tuberculosis by 2025 and measles by 2020 completely from the country. An&nbsp;action plan to eliminate Kala-Azar and Filariasis diseases by 2017-18 and leprosy by 2018will be put in place, the Finance Minister said.<br /><br />Also, an action plan has been prepared to reduce IMR from 39 in 2014 to 28 by 2019 and MMR from 167 in 2011-13 to 100 by 2018-2020.<br /><br />The government will turn 1.5 lakh health sub-centers to health wellness centers to ensure quality service to citizens of the country. <br /><br />The government will also set up two new All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS) at Jharkhand and Gujarat.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/budget-2017_union_356x200_0305_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 12:05:49</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>