<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/budget-2017-startup-indiaflop-need-5-year-tax-break-reveals-survey_8369001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Startup India a flop, need 5 year tax break, reveals survey]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Moneycontrol.com conducted a survey of Indian startups across sectors to get a sense of their suggestions for the Modi government this Union Budget. Startups were questioned on a range of issues including tax holiday, demonestisation, investment climate and Startup India policy. Here are the results:]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Chaitanya Gudipaty and Pulkit Gupta</strong></p>
<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>A five-year tax holiday tops the list of startup-friendly rules that Indian entrepreneurs seek from the Narendra Modi-led government in Budget 2017. About 59 percent of startups across sectors say that the tax exemption period should be extended to five years from the current three-year tax-free norm, according to a Moneycontrol.com survey.</p>
<p>PM Modi had a year ago announced a three-year tax break for startups while launching the Startup India programme. The tax break extension wish-list comes on the back of several startups failing to break-even after three years of operations. It's imperative to point out that the current tax sops are applicable for companies that have received an approval from Department of Industrial Policy and Promotion (<a href="http://dipp.nic.in/English/Investor/startupindia/Definition_Startup_GazetteNotification.pdf">classifying them as a 'startup'</a>).</p>
<p>Even Modi's move had faced criticism on this count last year.</p>
<p>Moneycontrol.com had earlier reported that the government may announce a string of initiatives to support the country&rsquo;s startups, including widening of the tax-free regime to five years and faster procedural clearances in Union Budget 2017-18. The government is also likely to make it easier for founders to exit their companies, responding to concerns about difficulties in shutting down a company in India, sources said. (<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/budget-2017-good-news-for-startups-fm-may-raise-tax-holiday-to-5-years_8238741.html">Read here</a>)</p>
<p>Commerce Minister Nirmala Sitharaman had recently said that her ministry had submitted startups suggestions about an extended tax holiday to Finance Minister Arun Jaitley. About 23 percent of startups that took part in the Moneycontrol survey batted for a seven-year tax free regime, while 18 percent were satisfied with the current three-year tax exemption.</p>
<p><strong>Ease of Doing Business</strong></p>
<p>India is home to the third-largest number of technology startups after the United States and Britain, and they attract billions of dollars in funding every year, despite byzantine government regulation and red tape that many investors often complain.</p>
<p>Fifty-five percent, or nearly 6 in 10 startups, feel that the government regulations have been fair and in turn improved ease of doing business in the country.</p>
<p>Startups, however, are wary about the sluggish investment climate in India. About 75 percent of the startups feel that investments climate for startups have become tighter in the past 12 months.</p>
<p>Last week, US-based Fidelity Investments had marked down the value of its holding in Sachin Bansal- and Binny Bansal-led ecommerce major Flipkart. The markdown now pegs the valuation Flipkart at USD 5.58 billion.</p>
<p><strong>Demonetisation Drubbing</strong></p>
<p>According to the survey, 54 percent of the respondents felt that demonetisation didn't have any negative impact on their operations or business.</p>
<p>Mobile wallet startups such as Paytm, Freecharge and Mobikwik were one of the biggest beneficiaries of the government's demonetisation drive launched on November. Nimble on their feet, they used the occasion to promote the use of mobile wallets and to an extent were largely successful. Smaller retailers, kirana stores and auto drivers started using mobile wallets to get payments from their customers.</p>
<p>Some startups even came forward to ease woes of the cash-dependent last-mile logistics in packaged goods sector. BeatRoute Innovations, a startup that focuses on facilitating last-mile retail between packaged goods companies, distributors and neighbourhood stores, launched a cashless transaction service for traders and distributors to ease their hardship.</p>
<p><strong>Startup Nationalism</strong></p>
<p>Interestingly, over a whopping 79 percent startups believe that the government should offer additional benefits to home-grown startups over international ones.</p>
<p>The debate over protectionism of startups picked up pace late last year when Flipkart's Sachin Bansal and founder of taxi aggregator Ola Bhavish Aggarwal had reportedly joined hands to pitch for a level-playing field for cash-muzzled crunched Indian startups. The duo had sought India-centric policies and regulations to battle foreign startups such as Amazon and Uber that have rich cash reserves.</p>
<p>In the past, many Indian ecommerce players clamoured for opening FDI in online retail earlier in their beginnings. As they grew and acquired scale, their tonality changed. Many asked for selective opening, as they feared a deluge of foreign competition.</p>
<p><strong>Modi's Startup India scheme &mdash; A flop?</strong></p>
<p>More than six out of 10 startups (65 percent) believe that the government's Startup India campaign failed to help them. While 23 percent said that the programme aided them, 12.5 percent startups were divided on the effects it had on their business.</p>
<p>Besides in 2016, nearly 200 startups shut shop. These included big names such as Peppertap, BeStylish, AskMe, Fashionara and Localbanya. Bigger players like MakeMyTrip chose to list on the US bourses against Indian exchanges.</p>
<p><em><strong>Survey methodology</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Moneycontrol.com conducted a survey to review Budget wish-list of various startups across India. Startups were questioned on a variety of issues ranging from tax holiday to startup policies. About 50 startup CEOs participated in the survey which included multiple choice questions. The survey was carried out between 25th January, 2017 and 29th January, 2017.</em><br /><br /></p>
<p>Also Read:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/budget-2017-startups-play-nationalism-card-demand-more-sops-survey-says_8369441.html">Startups play nationalism card, demand more sops, survey says</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/budget-2017-what-startups-feel-about-modi-government%E2%80%99s-initiatives_8369481.html">What startups feel about Modi government&rsquo;s initiatives?</a></p>
<p><br /><br /> <a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/startup_18" data-show-count="false">Follow @startup_18</a>
<script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" type="mce-no/type"></script>
</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/stat1_4736_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 14:23:17</Entry_Date><Category>SME</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>