<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-banks-wish-list-npa-relief-housing-sops-taxwithdrawal_8360281.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Banks' wish list: NPA relief, housing sops, tax on withdrawal]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[To deal with stressed assets, further measures could also be taken to assuage the risks associated with project loans turning bad.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>A higher dose of capital infusion into state-owned banks by the government, measures to ease the burden of bad loans, increased allocation for infrastructure, and clear steps towards &lsquo;housing-for-all&rsquo;, are some of the announcements the banking sector is hoping to hear in the NDA government&rsquo;s fourth Budget on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Investment and consumption should get equal focus,&rdquo; <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/statebankindia/SBI">SBI</a> Chairman Arundhati Bhattacharya had said at a recent press conference, adding that the government should provide incentives on home loans and some relief on direct taxes. She feels there should be measures to discourage cash payments and encourage electronic payment.</p>
<p>To deal with stressed assets, further measures could also be taken to assuage the risks associated with project loans turning bad. Goldman Sachs in its report said that the government could announce the creation of a stressed asset buyout fund or a &lsquo;Bad Bank&rsquo; in the budget.</p>
<p>Rana Kapoor, MD and CEO, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/yesbank/YB">YES Bank</a> feels the government must do more to encourage people to put their savings into financial instruments.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Financial savings must be promoted by improving tax incentives (enhancing 80C limits to Rs 3 lakh from current level of Rs 1.5 lakh), increasing their inflation adjusted post tax returns,&rdquo; he said in his Budget wish list.</p>
<p>This includes reducing lock-in period eligible for tax rebate to 1 year from 5 years and enhancing threshold for mandatory tax deduction at source on interest income to Rs 50,000 a year from Rs 10,000, currently.</p>
<p>With respect to bank recapitalisation, rating agency ICRA says the government should increase the outlay for recapitalising public sector banks, beyond the Rs 100 billion that had been indicated under Indradhanush, a scheme for revival of public sector banks. This, according to them, will help bolster their balance sheets prior to the advent of the Basel III norms and enable them to support a recovery in economic growth.</p>
<p>There is also an expectation that the government could curb excessive withdrawal of cash. Ambit in a report said that they expect the Government to announce an &lsquo;anti-rich&rsquo; Budget which focusses on installing penalties on cash transactions, tax on the withdrawal of cash from the banking system.</p>
<p>IDFC Securities, in a report, said that the thrust on &lsquo;Housing for all&rsquo; would be positive for housing finance companies as well as banks doing mortgage financing, but more for lenders who focus on affordable housing.</p>
<p><strong>What the banking industry wants:-</strong></p>
<p>--Higher capital allocation for public sector banks</p>
<p>--Tax sops for card and electronic payments</p>
<p>--Housing for all</p>
<p>--Launch of &lsquo;Bad Bank&rsquo;</p>
<p>-- Higher allocation to infrastructure, housing and urban development to ease stress level of corporate India&rsquo;s balance sheet</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/bank_Budget_2017_rupee_356x200_3046_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 15:54:52</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,SBI,YB,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>