<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/khattar-hails-budget-as-reformist-measure-pro-farmer_8397701.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Khattar hails budget as reformist measure, pro-farmer]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Reacting to the proposals in the Budget presented by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today, he praised the Centre's move to bring "much-needed" reforms in political funding by making political parties file income tax returns, and lowering the maximum cash donation received by any party from one source to only Rs 2,000 from Rs 20,000.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Hailing the Union Budget for 2017-18, Haryana Chief Minister Manohar Lal Khattar today termed it as a "big, bold and reformist measure which is pro-common man and pro-farmer" and said it will give demand, economy and digitalisation, a "decisive push".</p>
<p>Reacting to the proposals in the Budget presented by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today, he praised the Centre's move to bring "much-needed" reforms in political funding by making political parties file income tax returns, and lowering the maximum cash donation received by any party from one source to only Rs 2,000 from Rs 20,000.</p>
<p>The Budget reflects the thinking and pro-poor vision of Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Khattar here said, adding that it is a big, bold and reformist measure which is pro-common man and pro-farmer and will give decisive push to demand, economy and digitalisation.</p>
<p>Hailing the "renewed commitment" of the NDA government to double the income of farmers in five years, he said allocation of Rs 10 lakh crore for farm credit by banks, setting up of an irrigation fund by NABARD, Rs 8,000 crore Dairy Processing Infra Fund and expansion of national agriculture market will give farmers, agriculture and allied sector, the much needed boost.</p>
<p>The Budget gives salaried people big relief by halving the tax to five per cent on income between Rs 2.5 lakh and Rs 5 lakh, housing a boost by vowing to complete one crore houses by 2019 and reducing the holding period for land and building to two from three years and industry the space by reducing corporate tax from 30 per cent to 25 per cent for companies with turn-over of Rs 50 crore, the Chief Minister said.</p>
<p>Mixing fiscal prudence with sagacious use of resources at his command, Jaitley has given infrastructure the muscle it needs with the allocation of Rs 3.96 lakh crore which will help create lakhs of jobs, he said.</p>
<p>The Union Finance Minister has given digitalisation a push by disallowing transactions over Rs three lakh in cash and targeting 2,500 crore digital transactions across platforms like UPI.</p>
<p>All these measures, put together, shall place the economy in high-growth trajectory and create jobs for lakhs of people, he claimed.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/f/Farmer_farming_agriculture_356x200_3000_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 16:54:02</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>