<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/hemisphere-prop-finally-ready-to-actsurplus-vsnl-land_8415861.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Hemisphere Prop finally ready to act on surplus VSNL land]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[After countless huffs and puffs over many years, Hemisphere Properties India Ltd, the government-owned special purpose vehicle that was formed to take over the surplus land of the erstwhile Videsh Sanchar Nigam Ltd (renamed Tata Communications Ltd in 2007), may finally be ready to take off the block.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dhirendra Tripathi</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />After countless huffs and puffs over many years, Hemisphere Properties India, the government-owned special purpose vehicle that was formed to take over the surplus land of the erstwhile Videsh Sanchar Nigam (renamed <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/telecommunications-service/tatacommunications/TC17">Tata Communications Ltd</a> in 2007), may finally be ready to kick off proceedings.</p>
<p>The company has chalked out a capital expenditure of Rs 690 crore for 2017-18. This is a staggering jump of over 60 times from the 2016-17 revised estimate of Rs 11 crore. The 2016-17 estimate was itself revised upwards from a mere Rs 1 crore spend planned earlier.</p>
<p>As per the PSU&rsquo;s charter, its objective is to construct, acquire, hold, manage, develop, administer, protect, preserve and to deal in any other manner with surplus land, including sale and purchase thereof.</p>
<p>If the monumental rise in the company&rsquo;s capital expenditure is any indication, it means the public sector company might have left all the administrative and statutory hurdles behind and is ready to get on with developing its land parcels. Among the prime properties it owns are a large piece in Delhi&rsquo;s posh Greater Kailash-II area and another on the outskirts of Delhi.</p>
<p>Hemisphere was formed to take over the 'surplus land'&nbsp;of Videsh Sanchar Nigam when the government sold strategic stake in the international call services provider to Tatas in 2002.</p>
<p>As per the shareholder agreement between the government and the Tatas, the surplus land belonging to VSNL was supposed to be demerged with VSNL having no right to it.</p>
<p>Hemisphere was established in 2005-06 and the government came to have 51.12 percent stake in the company in March 2014. <br /><br />Tata Sons, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/power-generationdistribution/tatapowercompany/TPC">Tata Power</a> and other shareholders of Tata Communications own the rest of the shares. <br /><br />The company owns anywhere between 540 acre and 773.13 acre across Delhi, Chennai, Pune and Kolkata. The exact quantum of land the company owns is not certain as some parcels are under dispute.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hemisphere could so far do nothing with the land owing to completion of requisite statutory requirements.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/l/land__0552_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-03 10:35:13</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,VSN,TPC,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>