<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-government-pegs-fy18-fiscal-deficit-aim-at-32gdp_8388681.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Government pegs FY18 fiscal deficit aim at 3.2% of GDP]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Jaitley, however, spelled out the fixed deficit target for 2017-18, but introduced a new framework specifying a fiscal deficit “range” from 2018-19 onwards.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p style="margin: 0cm; margin-bottom: .0001pt; background: white;"><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /></strong><br />The government on Wednesday pegged the fiscal deficit target at 3.2 percent of GDP for the financial year 2017-18, ensuring adherence to the path of fiscal consolidation, without compromising on public investment.</p>
<p>"...I have pegged the fiscal deficit for 2017-18 at 3.2% of GDP and remain committed to achieve 3% in the following year," Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said.</p>
<p>Fiscal deficit a measure of how much the government borrows in a year to meet part of its spending needs.</p>
<p>The revenue deficit of 2.3% in budgeted estimated 2016-17 stands reduced to 2.1 percent in the revised estimates, Jaitley said.</p>
<p>"The Revenue Deficit for next year is pegged at 1.9 percent, against 2 percent mandated by the FRBM Act," he said.</p>
<p>Fiscal Responsibility and Budget Management (FRBM) review committee, headed by former Revenue Secretary NK Singh, last month, has recommended 3 percent fiscal deficit for the next three years, keeping in mind the sustainable debt target and need for public investment.</p>
<p>The committee has also provided for &lsquo;escape clauses&rsquo;, for deviations upto 0.5% of GDP, from the stipulated fiscal deficit target.</p>
<p>The government today also said that its fiscal policy continues to be guided by the principle of a gradual reduction of deficit and needs to maintain "tight fiscal plan".</p>
<p>"However, any fiscal straight jacketing to meet the FRBM target would not be advisable," the government said.</p>
<p>A push through higher public spending is has been indentified as crucial for providing an impetus to economic growth.</p>
<p>"The government has, therefore, consciously decided to shift the FRBM target of achieving fiscal deficit at 3 percent of GDP, by another year to 2018-19. The estimate of fiscal deficit at 3.2 percent of GDP in 2017-18 shows a correction of 0.3 percent over estimates of 2016-17," the government said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/g/GST_Impact_On_Fiscal-Deficit_CRISIL_230614_0125_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 21:16:12</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>