<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-here’s-how-to-setright-tone-for-telecoms-growth_8346001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Here’s how to set the right tone for telecoms growth]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Steady growth and expansion of telecom sector is fundamental for the government’s ‘Digital India’ program that is poised to redefine the lives of its 1.25 billion citizens.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Vishal Malhotra</strong><br /> <br />As excitement continues to mount for the government&rsquo;s annual budget, telecoms sector has lined up its wish list to address most critical concerns. The sector is anxiously eyeing for a growth-positive budget. <br /><br />Steady growth and expansion of telecom sector is fundamental for the government&rsquo;s &lsquo;Digital India&rsquo; program that is poised to redefine the lives of its 1.25 billion citizens. The government&rsquo;s efforts in steering the sector on an accelerated path has been encouraging. But, for India&rsquo;s surging telecoms industry; addressing the sector&rsquo;s most pressing direct and indirect tax issues will be pivotal for ensuring growth amidst concerns over burgeoning debt, rising litigations and high regulatory pay outs and levies.<br /><br />In the run up to the budget, let&rsquo;s take a look at some of the direct tax issues that would require a dramatic closure: <br /><br /><strong>Tax depreciation on spectrum acquired prior to April 1, 2016</strong><br /><br />Tax treatment of spectrum fee has been a subject matter of conflicting interpretations. The industry believes that spectrum is in the nature of an intangible asset and is thus, cost incurred for acquisition of the spectrum is eligible for tax depreciation under section 32 of the Income-tax Act, 1961 (&lsquo;Act&rsquo;). The tax authorities, however, are largely taking a position that spectrum payments are eligible for amortization under section 35ABB of the Act which provides for amortisation of license fee.<br /><br />Introduction of Section 35ABA with effect from April 1, 2016, which provides for amortization of spectrum payments, vindicates the industry&rsquo;s position that spectrum payments cannot be amortised under section 35ABB. The industry is therefore expecting a clarification that spectrum acquired and put to use prior to April 1, 2016 would be eligible for depreciation under section 32 of the Act. <br /><br /><strong>Non-applicability of withholding tax provisions on payments made for spectrum trading/sharing</strong><br /><br />Under the Act, royalty includes use/right to use of equipment, process, patent, invention, model, secret formula or process etc. Further, royalty does not include any consideration for outright transfer of right to use an intangible. Thus, payment for spectrum, being in the nature of air waves/ electromagnetic waves and not equipment, process, patent, etc.; and additionally, transfer of the right to use spectrum is in nature of sale per se, does not qualify as royalty. <br /><br />The telecom Industry is hopeful that necessary clarification would be issued to the effect that payments made in connection with the trading/sharing of spectrum are not in the nature of royalty and hence, are not liable to tax withholding.<br /><br /><strong>TDS on telecommunication charges paid to foreign operators</strong><br /><br />Explanation 5 and 6 to section 9(1)(vi) intends to bring payments for transmission by satellite; cable; optic fibre or similar technology; and use of equipment irrespective of actual possession or control by the user, within the purview of royalty. Payment made for anything which is widely available in the open market to all those willing to pay for cannot constitute &lsquo;royalty&rsquo;. Further, the use of own equipment/process by a telecom operator to provide services cannot be viewed as use of such equipment/ process by the recipient of service.<br /><br />To mitigate unwarranted litigation and hardship, particularly, in relation to telecommunication charges payable to non-resident telecom operators (which are generally tax protected), the telecom Industry is awaiting amendments/clarifications these explanations would not have any bearing on standard telecom services and further, these explanations cannot be imported into DTAAs.<br /><br /><strong>Applicability of section 194H of the Act to discount extended to pre-paid distributors </strong><br /><br />There is extensive litigation on whether the discount allowed by the telecom operators to the distributors on pre-paid telecom services is liable to tax withholding as commission under 194H of the Act. The Industry will welcome the position of applicability of TDS provisions on pre-paid discount. However, given the low margins for the distributors, the Government should prescribe a lower withholding tax rate (say 2%) since the presently applicable rate of 5% is not commensurate with such margin<br /><br /><strong>Moving on to the indirect tax aspect, certain pertinent issues would require empathetic closure which include:</strong><br /><br /><strong>Withdrawal of customs duty exemption on certain telecom goods</strong><br /><br />In line with the &rsquo;Make in India&lsquo; initiative, to encourage indigenous manufacturing, the Industry is expecting that in the current budget, concessional rate/exemption may be extended to inputs required for manufacturing of telecom and IT equipment and exemption/concessional rate may be withdrawn on import of such final goods. Further, in addition to battery, chargers and headphones, the customs duty exemption may be withdrawn for few more parts/components required for manufacturing of mobile phones.<br /><br /><strong>Allocation of spectrum being a sovereign function should not be taxed</strong><br /><br />Assignment of spectrum, a scarce natural resource, is an important sovereign function of the government, and treating such activity as &lsquo;service&rsquo; at par with normal commercial transactions is deviation from standard practices adopted across world. Consideration payable for allocation of spectrum is in nature of statutory payment and applicability of service tax thereon leads to payment of tax on a statutory levy - resulting in tax on tax. This is unintentionally punitive resulting in material distortion and discrimination to the industry. <br />Industry is therefore expecting relief from applicability of service tax on assignment of spectrum. <br /><br />Here&rsquo;s hoping that the Union Budget of 2017 will turn out to be a defining year for telecom&rsquo;s tax concerns. <br /><br /><em><strong>(Views expressed are personal)</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>The author is Tax Leader for Telecommunications practice of EY India</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_finance_ministry_356x200_5541_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-25 19:41:43</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>