<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/union-budget-2017-18-makeindia-push-seems-to-have-died-down-says-pawan-goenka_8401401.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Make in India push seems to have died down, says Pawan Goenka]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Pawan Goenka did show his dissapointment on one aspect, and that was the concept of Make in India. He says that although the topic of Make In India was very hot in India two years ago, the government's enthusiasm towards this initiative seems to have died down.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Pawan Goenka, Managing Director, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-carsjeeps/mahindramahindra/MM">M&amp;M</a> is all praises for the Budget that was tabled today in the Parliament. He says the Budget the government did not introduce new things, just for the sake of doing something different and unique.<br /><br />"The Budget was not a populist one, that was designed to win voters. I did not see anything in the Budget that would influence the upcoming elections," he says.<br /><br />But he did show his dissapointment on one aspect, and that was the concept of Make in India. He says that although the topic of Make In India was very hot in India two years ago, the government's enthusiasm towards this initiative seems to have died down. He is hoping that the govevrnment puts more focus on it. <br /><br />He also said that the government, after demonetisation, did not do anything to spur short-term demand in the Budget.<br /><br />"It was a good, solid, prudent Budget. There was very little that was wrong with the Budget," says Ajay Singh, Chairman of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/transportlogistics/spicejet/SJ01">SpiceJet</a><br /><br />He says cutting tax for firms earning less than Rs 50 crore can help boost the aviation sector.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch video for more.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/m/Make-In-India2_1744_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 21:25:56</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,MM,ML04,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>