<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/brokerage-recos-others/union-budget-2017-2018-review-aditya-birla-money_8405621.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-2018 Review: Aditya Birla Money]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Budget took a small pause on fiscal consolidation by targeting fiscal deficit @ 3.2% for FY18, 20bps higher than planned in the government’s medium term fiscal consolidation program. The lower reduction in fiscal deficit is to stimulate demand in a weak economic environment post demonetisation – a step in right direction.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">"A right cause never fails" &ndash; That is how the FM started by quoting Mahatma Gandhi in context of the demonetization drive the government undertook. The continuation of this drive was visible in Union Budget 2017-18 in the form of embargo on cash transactions beyond a threshold (3 Lakhs), capping of cash donations to political parties and various cashless and digitization drives.<br /><br /> The language and intent of the Union Budget was straight forward and centered around i) Quality of expenditure (Capital expenditure upped by 24%); ii) benefits to the society&rsquo;s lower strata (infrastructure in rural India, MNREGA allocation higher by 24%; infrastructure status to affordable housing); iii) Agriculture &amp; Farming (Micro Irrigation Fund, Higher allocation to Mudra); iv) better tax compliance (to bring in MSME into the taxfold, the corporate tax has been cut by 5% for firms with turnover up to Rs 50 crore; v) public spending in the absence of private Capex (Increase in Infra spending by ~25%); vi) Fiscal prudence (3.2% Fiscal deficit) and lower net borrowing (Rs 3.5tn). There was status quo on the Capital gains (securities)&nbsp; front.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Other key proposal / highlights were:<br /><br /></strong>1. Total allocation for rural, agricultural and allied sectors for 2017-18 is Rs 1,87,223 crore (+24%); Allocation for infrastructure stands at a record Rs Rs 3,96,135 crore (+24%); Defense expenditure excluding pension at Rs2,74,000 crore (+12%)<br /><br />2. Penalties on cash transaction above Rs 3 lakh<br /><br />3. Personal income tax&nbsp; - Tax slab of Rs 250,000 to Rs 500,000 to attract 5% instead of 10% earlier; Surcharge of 10% for those whose annual income is Rs 50Lakh to Rs 1Crore; 15% surcharge on incomes above Rs 1 crore to continue.<br /><br />4. Clarification on Indirect transfer (concerning FPIs) was a welcome move; Foreign investment promotion board (FIPB) to be abolished. This is symbolic in terms of the intent and simplification of doing business rules.<br /><br />5. Political parties will be entitled to receive donations by cheques or digital modes; Maximum cash donation any party can receive will be Rs 2000 from one source; An amendment being proposed to RBI Act to enable the issuance of electoral bonds for political funding.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Budget took a small pause on fiscal consolidation by targeting fiscal deficit @3.2% for FY18, 20bps higher than planned in the government&rsquo;s medium term fiscal consolidation program. The lower reduction in fiscal deficit is to stimulate demand in a weak economic environment post demonetisation &ndash; a step in right direction. Clearly no &ndash;ve news (especially on the capital gains and indirect tax front) is +ve from market&rsquo;s perspective. Budget is positive for most sectors, particularly Infrastructure, Agriculture and Financials. With quality spending (Capital expenditure) and not too expansionary budget, we are in the reckoning for a possible rating upgrade during the course of next year. <br /><br />Overall by containing the Fiscal deficit @ 3.2% and restricting the net borrowings @ Rs 3.5tn, the government has taken a balanced approach towards fiscal prudence and growth, and clearly sent a message that buoyancy in tax and tax compliance will be a thrust area for the Government (assumptions of 15% growth in direct taxes and 8% growth in indirect taxes, being such an example)<br /><br /><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The views and investment recommendations expressed by investment experts/broking houses/rating agencies on moneycontrol.com are their own, and not that of the website or its management. Moneycontrol.com advises users to check with certified experts before taking any investment decisions.<br /><br /></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_356x200_4046_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 12:50:55</Entry_Date><Category>Brokerage Recos - Others</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>