<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-see-no-changeindirect-taxes-corp-tax-cut-likely-say-pros_8389341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: See no change in indirect taxes; corp tax cut likely, say pros]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Nilesh Shah, MD & CEO, Envision Capital and Govindarajan Chellappa, MD & Head of India Research, Jefferies both believe the most watched for in the Budget 2017 would be the fiscal deficit number and more than just the number, it will be government’s commitment to stick to the path of fiscal consolidation]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Market experts Nilesh Shah, MD &amp; CEO, Envision Capital and Govindarajan Chellappa, MD &amp; Head of India Research, Jefferies both believe the most watched for in the Budget 2017 would be the fiscal deficit number and more than just the number, it will be government&rsquo;s commitment to stick to the path of fiscal consolidation.</p>
<p>Earlier there was a commitment to take fiscal deficit number to 3 percent, said Chellappa.</p>
<p>Shah said there is an expectation of higher allocation to social sector, especially rural. The number on indirect tax collection is also very important, said Shah.</p>
<p>There could be likely tinkering of personal tax where the minimum slab for individual&rsquo;s could be increased but unlikely that changes would be made to indirect taxes, said Chellappa, adding that corporate tax too, is likely to be cut as per expectation.</p>
<p>Talking about earnings trajectory, Chellappa said the full impact of demonetisation was not visible in the third quarter and the lagged impact would be likely seen in fourth and future quarters.</p>
<p>Sector specific, Shah said the banking space that has seen growth till now will continue to deliver because the end in terms of asset quality woes seem to be nearing. So buy big stocks on dips.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch accompanying videos for more details.<br /><br /></strong></em></p>
<p>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>
<p><em><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></em>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_budget_356x200_5221_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 10:17:49</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>