<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-lost-opportunity-for-life-sciences-sectorindia_8372001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Lost opportunity for life sciences sector in India]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[No major reforms on the tax and regulatory front was announced in the Lifesciences sector.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Hitesh Sharma</strong><br /><br />The Budget 2017 was presented by the Finance Minister amid high expectations given the impact of the demonetisation scheme announced in November and the potential deglobalisation policies in certain developed countries. While the Indian lifescience industry is facing uncertain times with the US President urging pharma companies to manufacture their drugs in the US itself, one expected some sort of stimulus for the Indian industry. <br /><br />However, with a strong focus on the rural spending, infrastructure and poverty alleviation with fiscal prudence, no major reforms on the tax and regulatory front was announced in the lifesciences sector and therefore, one wonders if this was a chance missed for the Indian Lifescience sector to really push its standing in the global economy. <br /><br />On the policy front, the action plan to reduce the IMR and MMR in the country needs to be lauded and is in line with the agenda of the Government of &lsquo;Health for all&rsquo; as announced in the first Budget of the current Government in 2014. Further, the formulation of an action plan to eliminate 3 diseases i.e. Kala-Azar and Filariasis by 2017, leprosy by 2018 and measles by 2020 while eliminating tuberculosis by 2025 is a welcome move and may have an impact on the players in the Lifescience industry. <br /><br />Moreover, there may be some cheer to the consumers on account of reduced prices proposed to be introduced through amendments in the Drugs and Cosmetic Rules and new rules for medical devices. While this is themed to make healthcare services more affordable to the mass at large, since the facilities differ in terms of safety, efficacy and other norms, the policy should ensure that it is not tethering the more compliant companies to reconsider certain products to be manufactured.<br /><br />The focus of the Government on energising the youth of the country and creating skilled labour with specialists in each field is evident from the policy measures announced in the Budget. The creation of two new All India Institutes of Medical Sciences in the States of Jharkhand and Gujarat as well as steps taken to increase the number of specialist doctors would result in a higher portion of the population of the country having access to a better quality of healthcare at an affordable price. <br /><br />The proposed repeal of the R&amp;D Cess Act, 1986 would lead to savings from R&amp;D cess on import or sharing of technology, currently taxed at 5% - a welcome move. <br /><br />Some of the key asks of the industry which still remain unanswered are fine-tuning of the Patent Box regime, postponement of the phasing out of the weighted deductions to R&amp;D, depreciation on certain medical devices such as life-saving equipment, clarity on deduction for freebies provided to doctors, service tax on clinical trial services in India and the inverted duty structure on APIs and formulated pharma products.<br /><br />On the FDI front, while the Finance Minister has announced the liberalisation of the FDI policy, one would need to wait for the amendment in the policy to gauge the impetus provided to foreign investment in the Lifescience sector. <br /><br />To conclude, while this Budget has focused on various reforms across various sectors, one wonders if certain further impetus could have been provided to the Lifescience industry and this was a chance missed to make India one of the top players in the global Lifescience economy. <br /><br /><br /><em><strong>The author is Tax Partner &amp; National Leader &ndash; Lifesciences of&nbsp; EY India</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>Rahul Kakkad and Mahesh Nayak are senior tax professionals at EY who have also contributed to this article. </strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>Views expressed are personal.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/p/pharma_Budget_2017_rupee_356x200_2650_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 11:14:03</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>