<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/budget-presentationtrackls-speaker-to-decideformat_8387781.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget presentation on track, but LS speaker to decide on format]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ahamed had served as minister of state for external affairs in the erstwhile UPA government.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />
<p style="margin: 0cm 0cm 13.5pt 0cm;">The Union Budget 2017-18 will be presented today. However, a change in format, if any, will be decided by&nbsp;Lok Sabha Speaker Sumitra Mahajan.&nbsp;<br /><br />Following the passing away of Former Central Minister and sitting Lok Sabha MP E Ahamed's early on Wednesday, uncertainty loomed over the Budget presentation.<br /><br />According to tradition, in the event of the death of a sitting MP, the House adjourns for a day, after mourning the member's death.<br /><br />Mahajan will consult the Lok Sabha Secretary General, Parliamentary Affairs Minister Ananth Kumar, opposition leader Mallikarjun Kharge and the Attorney General before deciding on the change in format.<br /><br />There are three possible likelihoods. One, the Budget will presented in the Rajya Sabha alone; it could be presented post lunch session and third, the Budget will be presented in Lok Sabha after which both houses of the Parliament will be adjourned for the day.<br /><br />Ahamed had served as minister of state for external affairs in the erstwhile UPA government.</p>
He had suffered a heart attack during President Pranab Mukherjee's address to the joint session of Parliament on Tuesday.<br /><br />Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486010854175000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEdyKoKLx2Og6E-8WMONHUL67FUZw"> LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486010854175000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFWl3cZRaK3xhZKvcIwFsgoiElU_Q"> Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_2000_356x200_3919_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 07:42:37</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>