<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/need-to-balance-fiscal-disciplinekeep-demand-intact-cea_8386601.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Need to balance fiscal discipline and keep demand intact: CEA]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Demonetisation has created high uncertainty as far as growth is concerned, said the Chief Economic Advisor Arvind Subramanian. Alongwith domestic market, global events including currency and commodity movements also add to this uncertainty. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Economic Survey 2017 has projected for Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth of 6.5-6.75 percent for FY17 and 6.75-7.5 percent. Without demonetisation, this GDP number would have been 7 percent for the current fiscal. <br /><br />Demonetisation has created high uncertainty as far as growth is concerned, said the Chief Economic Advisor Arvind Subramanian. Alongwith domestic market, global events including currency and commodity movements also add to this uncertainty. <br /><br />At present, private consumption and the government&rsquo;s investment push are driving the economy. The need of the hour is balancing fiscal discipline while keeping the demand intact, Subramanian said. Avoiding fiscal discipline does not mean consolidating aggressively. <br /><br />In the next fiscal, government will have to maintain caution on fiscal outlook. Oil bonanza from excise duties will not be available and implementation of the Goods &amp; Services Tax (GST) will add to the uncertainty. <br /><br />However, Subramanian believes that GST will boost Tax to GDP ratio in long-run. He also said that this is the time to look at idea of Universal Basic Income scheme despite the challenges. <br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Arvind Subramanian&rsquo;s interview to Shereen Bhan on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: IT would be unfair to say that this is an economic survey merely talks about the implications and the impact of demonetisation. There is plenty more that it does talk about. If I could start by asking you about your outlook as far as growth is concerned, would it be fair for me to say that your outlook at growth today is more cautious than optimistic?</strong><br /><br />A: I do not know in terms of words, but certainly what we said is that relative to the base line that both the Central Statistical Organisation (CSO) and we had forecast for this year, growth is going to be a quarter to half a percentage point less. So that means more cautious relative to the base line.<br /><br /><strong>Q: But talking about growth projections for the year ahead as well, FY18, you are projecting 6.75-7.5 percent. At this point in time, given what you see as both the local factors as well as the great uncertainty that we see in the global environment, do you believe that perhaps the lower end is more realistic a target?</strong><br /><br />A: Firstly remember that the fact that this year&rsquo;s forecast is a bit down because of factors we have outlined also as an impact on next year&rsquo;s forecast because if the starting point is weaker, obviously the next year is also going to be affected by that. Now whether it will be at the lower end or at the upper end of the range, as you said will depend on a lot of things and that is why we give a range. There is a lot of uncertainty. <br /><br />There is uncertainty about whether there is any lingering effect of the demonetisation on the domestic side, also about what the follow-up actions will be taken. And then on the international side, huge uncertainty. You saw today, the executive order against the H1B visa. But more broadly, we do not know how oil prices are going to behave. We do not know more broadly, could trade tensions escalate, because currency movements are going to be very important. <br /><br />The dollar has been rising, the Chinese currency has been declining. If that happens, east-Asian currencies decline with this, what does that do to our exports, and of course, the resurgence of medium-term protectionism. All these uncertainties and so to reflect that, we have a range and it is very difficult to say whether we will be at the upper or lower end of this range.<br /><br /><strong>Q: You have listed out several of these challenges that the economy faces both domestically as well as globally. But if I were to ask you to prioritise for us the key risks that you see today, perhaps both on the upside as well as the downside to the projection that you have made so far.</strong><br /><br />A: On the upside, if you look at export data for the most recent quarters, there has been an uptick in both goods and services. From negative growth, we are in positive territory for non-oil manufactured goods. And that reflected in turn the fact that the world economy started to recover. Now, if next year, as the International Monetary Fund (IMF) forecasts, world growth is going to be higher than this year, there is some upside potential to exports which will have spill-over effects on private investment as well.<br /><br />_PAGEBREAK_<strong><br /><br />Q: There is also the rising threat of protectionism and a very real threat of de-globalisation.</strong><br /><br />A: Exactly. Now, even on the external side, there is a short-term which could be positive because of what I just said. Your demand goes up with the US because of fiscal expansion, other countries, their currencies decline, therefore the Japanese outlook is looking better, German outlook is looking better as a result. So, you have to balance all these factors and then we will see how it goes. <br /><br />The protectionism is something that is also a much more or so medium-term challenge because this retreat from globalisation seems to be very real, seems to be kind of pervasive and broad-based across the board. So, it is something that we have to be very watchful about.<br /><br /><strong>Q: I will come to the export picture as well as globalisation in just a bit, but the need for a stimulus at this point in time. Given where we are today, private consumption has been impacted because of demonetisation, spending continues to be led by the government, credit offtake continues to be anaemic. We continue to be faced with the challenge that you pointed out in your previous survey which is the challenge of private sector balance sheets which remain broken. In that situation, is there a need for a stimulus?</strong><br /><br />A: As you rightly said, the economy has been in a sense, driven by consumption, private consumption and government consumption and investment and exports in investment have been relatively weak. But the export picture is changing. <br /><br />That is one thing. On the other hand, we were hoping the monsoon will be good and farm incomes will improve so you might get some improvement in private consumption as well. And then the whole role of the government is as always with a kind of slight slow-down because of demonetisation. <br /><br />On the one hand, you want government to compensate for that, but on the other hand, you also want the other side, all the considerations that you want to maintain, fiscal prudence, you want to maintain the credibility you have acquired by saying you are going to stick to a certain path, so you have to balance these considerations. So, that in turn is going to determine whether you should have, some people want expansion.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Do you want expansion?</strong><br /><br />A: That we have to see tomorrow. We will see what the Budget will do tomorrow.<br /><br /><strong>Q: But do you think there is need for expansion today because while you talk about how India must not embrace fiscal activism which seems to have worked for advanced economies, you also talk about sticking to the path of fiscal consolidation, but then you also say that the operational framework designed in 2003 will need to be modified for fiscal policy for the India of today and the India of tomorrow. How should we reconcile what you said in those chapters with what you are saying now?</strong><br /><br />A: It is completely consistent. The experience shows that fiscal indiscipline is bad. That is obvious. That also led to our two crises. So from that, avoiding fiscal indiscipline but that does not necessarily translate into steady consolidation or aggressive consolidation. The choice between those will be determined very much by the circumstances and we will see what happens tomorrow, what choices are made.<br /><br /><strong>Q: What do the circumstances today tell you the need of the hour is?</strong><br /><br />A: The need of the hour is to balance the need for the government to not take away demand with the need to maintain credibility and reduce the debt and continue the path of fiscal consolidation. It is that balance that needs to be struck always. <br /><br /><strong>Q: So, in this balance, what can be done as far as demand contraction is concerned which is real, specifically post demonetisation.</strong><br /><br />A: The exact answer, I cannot give you because you will get it tomorrow. But what we shared with you in the survey is the thinking that goes behind it.<br /><br /><strong>Q: I don&rsquo;t want to dwell too much on demonetisation but you have done analysis of what it means in the short term &ndash; clear pain and perhaps you are the first from within the government that has acknowledged it as openly as you have. In the long term and I quote to you what the survey says, while you call it a tax on black money you also say, &ldquo;To really quantify the decision and the magnitude of the long term changes it will take several years to understand the impact on illicit transactions.&rdquo; So, you are not really clear of what demonetisation will finally do for the Indian economy?</strong><br /><br />A: There are potential long term benefits but by definition long term means that the evidence will come in not today or tomorrow but months and years down the road. We are not ducking our responsibilities here. There is a section in the chapter which says, what are the markers of success? In this case there can be clear, you can identify clear markers of success &ndash; 1) What is going to happen to the cash to GDP ratio going forward?<br /><br />_PAGEBREAK_<br /><br /><strong>Q: At 9 percent post demonetisation I understand now.</strong><br /><br />A: Remember it is long term, we need to sustain lower levels over a sustained period of time, number one. Number of tax payers, how much income is reported to tax payer. Real estate prices what happens over time? Indirect tax registration what happens over time. So, this is a case where you can lay down markers. You can even say this is what happened before demonetisation, we will track these and the evidence will come in over time.<br /><br />The point is that because it is long term benefit you can&rsquo;t make a judgement today. That is intrinsic to saying its long term.<br /><br /><strong>Q: In the short term has it achieved some of the objectives that the government stated it should achieve?</strong><br /><br />A: We provide some data on that, we have talked about the short term cost but we show evidence that digitalisation has picked up quite substantially partly because of follow-up government action. Also there is some sign at least temporarily that real estate price has come down. However these are too early to make any definitive judgements on.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Given everything that you have spoken off, how concerned would you be on the revenue picture for next year?</strong><br /><br />A: Next year as we spell out in the survey. There are two or three important challenges next year. One is that we are not going to get the same bonanza from oil excise because this year we raised it, next year we are not going to get that bump. If anything indirect tax revenue to GDP could go down a little bit.<br /><br />Second, next year is going to be the first year of implementing the GST.<br /><br /><strong>Q: July 1 2017?</strong><br /><br />A: We will have to wait and see. However the point is that initially there will be teething problems. I am absolutely convinced that in the long run GST will increase the tax to GDP ratio. However in the first year there will be implementation challenges both for the centre and for the states and the centre has promised compensation.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Speaking of compensation, you are factoring in a 14 percent growth as far as taxes are concerned. So how concerned will you be about that?</strong><br /><br />A: That is why he fiscal outlook for next year, we have to be cautious about for these reasons and that has to feed into the Budget deficit target and what we are planning for. <br /><br /><strong>Q: I want to talk to you about some ideas that you specifically, on addressing the NPA situation and this is something that you spoke about in the previous survey as well, you clearly believe that things have not worked as per the government&rsquo;s expectations. You think there is a need for an out of the box idea? I do not know whether you mean a bad bank necessarily when you talk about a public asset reconstruction agency or rehabilitation agency. Has there been any formal discussion on that?</strong><br /><br />A: First, we clearly say that existing solutions have not been a fruitful and productive as we expected or wanted them to be. So, the problem is huge, very difficult, intractable in some ways. So we must search for new solutions and the government is very aware of that. We have had discussions on this. So, we will be looking at all options going forward.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Is it an option that is being considered at this point?</strong><br /><br />A: Governments are open to all possible solutions.<br /><br /><strong>Q: On another option, the universal basic income scheme and you have talked about the fiscal implications of that, 4-5 percent of GDP, but you also said that it will mean doing away with other schemes that cannot be an add on. Is this a serious option on the table? Can we expect any forward movement perhaps, in the short-term?</strong><br /><br />A: The time is right to discuss this idea because it is an important and radical new idea because it can eliminate all the things that go with poverty. But also, there are lots of challenges to this. Converting and idea into policy reality means overcoming these challenges for which, India is such a big country, so many things.<br /><br /><strong>Q: It is only discussion at this point?</strong><br /><br />A: We have to discuss this, yes.<br /><br /><strong>Q: This was an idea that you brought up in the previous Budget as well. The excess capital of the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) and what to do with it. Have you managed to gain any momentum on getting the government to see merit in that thought? Getting the RBI to see merit in that thought especially post demonetisation?</strong><br /><br />A: Let us see how it works out over the next few months?<br /><br /><strong>Q: Can we expect to hear something on that front?</strong><br /><br />A: Let us see how things pan out.<br /><br /><strong>Q: So today more confident about the state of the Indian economy? Would the challenges internally be more difficult to deal with or would the external challenges be more difficult?</strong><br /><br />A: All challenges are difficult, we have to meet all of them.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/g/GDP_Gross_domestic_price_economy_Growth_inflation_Growth_GST_356x200_5350_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 21:32:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>