<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/insurance/budget-2017-offer-income-tax-benefits-to-spread-insurance-products_8326641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Offer income tax benefits to spread insurance products]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The number of people who avail some quality cover under personal insurance is very low and revenue collection of government is no way going to get affected materially by extending some tax benefit as non-life penetration still stands at a low of 0.7% of GDP and personal insurance would be hardly measurable.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Saroj Satapathy</strong><br /><em>Ideal Insurance Brokers</em><br /><br />We have seen some bold moves made by Government of India throughout 2016 to extend insurance cover to the maximum number of people belonging to lower/middle segment of social strata. Post demonetisation, we see lot of activities in turning the economy towards digitalization. Incentives given by the government is only going to make more people buy insurance through this channel (digital) proactively. Exposure to insurance through different schemes including covering passengers travelling by train is going to grow the demand for availing better and larger cover in time to come.<br /><br />While it is correct that government is trying their best to bring the entire gamut of population under some insurance scheme to have better quality of life yet it is beyond doubt that to bring the last person standing under some quality cover, there is need to popularise such schemes initially by incentivising and also allowing tax benefit to make it viable too. The number of people who avail some quality cover under personal insurance is very low and revenue collection of government is no way going to get affected materially by extending some tax benefit as non-life penetration still stands at a low of 0.7% of GDP and personal insurance would be hardly measurable. On the contrary such action will make people buy better cover and provide social security and in some way increases the revenue collection. <br /><br />The wish list can go on but realistically some of these are a must consideration:<br /><br /><strong>Why service tax?</strong><br /><br />When we buy a term policy or health insurance policy there is an additional out go of service tax @15%. Sometimes the service tax component is such that you can avail another add-on cover. Term Insurance which is a pure insurance product, health insurance which is a must today and so also related product like critical illness and personal accident policy should be exempted from service tax to avail a higher cover and also make it a popular and address the need of a healthy population.<br /><br /><strong>Income tax exemption limit:</strong><br /><br />The rising cost of medical treatment mounted by a continuous medical inflation, the cost of availing such cover is going up whereas the exemption under IT still remains below expectation. The limit should be increased to at least INR 75000 to have the right cover. Further, it is time to have a formula linking exemption limit to medical inflation after deciding on a basic formula to maintain continuity. It is time to popularise insurance of home considering the recent rampant will of natural hazards causing huge damage to home and property and with no or least insurance cover thereby contributing to a colossal national loss. By exempting premium paid for home insurance from IT, we can attract more people for covering such risk protecting their personal wealth and national wealth in turn. Personal accident insurance premium paid can also be exempted to include more citizens availing the policy.<br /><br />By providing such exemption and deduction, we would create a very healthy, happy and content middle class which will percolate it down the level.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_356x200_3121_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-23 18:47:29</Entry_Date><Category>Insurance</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>