<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/re-visiting-tax-rates-needhour-cut-corporate-taxes_8341101.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Re-visiting tax rates need of hour; cut corporate taxes]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Re-visiting the tax rates is the need of the hour to soothe the common man from the perils of Demonetisation. Considering the cost of living even in a Tier III city the current tax slabs and the available deductions are just too little.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-m_2215887323565665176m_-4350971299302345787gmail-il"><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-il">Nishit</span></span><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-m_2215887323565665176m_-4350971299302345787gmail-apple-converted-space">&nbsp;</span><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-m_2215887323565665176m_-4350971299302345787gmail-il"><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-il">Dhruva</span></span>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Personal taxation perspective:&nbsp;</em></strong>Re-visiting the tax rates is the need of the hour to soothe the common man from the perils of demonetisation. Considering the cost of living even in a Tier III city the current tax slabs and the available deductions are just too little.</p>
<p>With demonetisation, bank loan rates are expected to reduce, so an increase in the allowable interest expense from its current Rs 1.5 lakh limit, as a deduction could be a welcome move.</p>
<p>Increase in exemptions with regards to salaried people would be much appreciated considering the increase in cost of living, rentals and medical expenses. Medical expenses limit was last set over a decade ago. Other such deductions that have been sitting on the sidelines need some attention, considering the inflation and current economic scenario.</p>
<p>The present deduction of 1.5 lakhs under 80C could also be looked into and increased to 2 lakh.</p>
<p><strong><em>Corporate Tax:&nbsp;</em></strong>One could also look into the reduction in corporate tax rate as promised by Modi a while ago which could land up at 25 percent gradually. By far it is still at 30 percent so even a 2.5 percent reduction would strengthen the confidence of the corporates in the promises and foresight of Modi led Government.<br /><br /> If India wants to continue attracting FDIs and foreign headquartered MNCs, the corporate tax rates in India compared to other Asian countries is too high. Whilst China is at 25 percent, Hongkong and Singapore are at 15 percent and 17.5 percent, respectively. So, overall a corporate tax rate cut is much awaited. The industry also expects a cut in the current MAT rates, which is in excess of 18 percent.</p>
<p>One also needs to bear in mind that if corporate tax rate is reduced the government is bound to do away with the corresponding deductions and exemptions which are in place. With sunset clause set at March 31, 2017, certain weighted deductions could be phased out if the corporate tax rate is reduced. <br /><br />However, if India wants to continue its focus towards &ldquo;Make in India&rdquo; R&amp;D would play a crucial role and the weighted deduction under section 35D is expected to continue.</p>
<p>Over the period, we have seen a number of cases over disallowances under Section 14A. Considering that DDT is levied on dividend distribution, it would be a positive move if the government clarifies that no disallowance towards dividend earned since there are already economic costs levied upon its distribution. This clarification could also go a long way in reducing the litigation on this issue.</p>
<p>Another expectation is a reduction in TDS rates for individuals from 10 percent to 5 percent. Deduction of TDS at 20 percent for non-residents not having PAN in India is a bottleneck for those whose income is otherwise not taxable in India. A mere tax identification number or TRC should be enought for the need for non-deduction of tax at source.</p>
<p><strong><em>Other matters/reforms:&nbsp;</em></strong>Demonetisation saw an influx of cash across the country. It's time for the government to convert this painful process into positives by extending fiscal benefits for stressed assets that have grown exponentially into the Indian financial sector.</p>
<p>Stressed assets = NPAs + Restructured loans + Written off assets.</p>
<p>India&rsquo;s REIT and InvIT platforms are rated amongst the best in the world. Fiscal benefits for this sector could boost the real estate and infrastructure in India, which has seen growing interests from overseas players.</p>
<p>With demonetization, real estate and infrastructure sectors are hard hit and needs to be seen what sort of fiscal benefits are extended for Tier 3 &amp; Tier 4 developers.</p>
<p>Place of effective management i.e. POEM and Indirect Transfer Provisions are some of the other matters, which could see some additional clarifications for its effective implementation.<br /><br /><em><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-m_2215887323565665176m_-4350971299302345787gmail-il"><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-il">(Author is Nishit</span></span><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-m_2215887323565665176m_-4350971299302345787gmail-apple-converted-space">&nbsp;</span><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-m_2215887323565665176m_-4350971299302345787gmail-il"><span class="m_4930617660980836704m_-6522236661642914444m_3698619159008038590m_-2824534077110352105m_-4640581536550177316m_7860083476652830064gmail-il">Dhruva</span></span>, Managing Partner, MDP &amp; Partners)</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/t/Tax_up_down_coins_356x200_4023_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-25 14:17:50</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>