<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/brokerage-recos-others/union-budget-2017-2018-review-crisil_8416621.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-2018 Review: CRISIL]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Reviving fortunes in the hinterland by bolstering the agricultural economy and rural infrastructure seems to be the primary motivation of the Union Budget announcements this time, as evinced in higher allocations for MNREGA and the Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana, among others.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The imprimatur of Bharat is unmissable in the budget.</p>
<p>Reviving fortunes in the hinterland by bolstering the agricultural economy and rural infrastructure seems to be the primary motivation of the Union Budget announcements this time, as evinced in higher allocations for MNREGA and the Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana, among others.</p>
<p>Increase in credit availability, the focus on micro-irrigation and dairy-related activity, making farm incomes more predictable &ndash; all will have an upshot: it will bolster rural incomes and support consumption demand, which should benefit makers of consumer goods and durables, two-wheelers and tractors.</p>
<p>Increased outlays on roads, housing, sanitation and electrification through various schemes would make a difference in rural livability. In the process, there would be significant opportunity to the construction, cement and metals sectors.<br /><br /><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The views and investment recommendations expressed by investment experts/broking houses/rating agencies on moneycontrol.com are their own, and not that of the website or its management. Moneycontrol.com advises users to check with certified experts before taking any investment decisions.</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_356x200_3121_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-03 12:22:58</Entry_Date><Category>Brokerage Recos - Others</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>