<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-post-demonetization-fm-should-strengthen-finserv-sector_8343641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Post demonetization FM should strengthen finserv sector]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The FM may also have to sweeten the Union Budget 2017 for the people of India, at large, who have faced some hardships due to demonetisation; and also to promote digital transactions and head towards a cashless economy.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>BMR Advisors</strong><br /><br />The Finance Minister (&lsquo;FM&rsquo;) is expected to present the Union Budget 2017 on February 1, 2017; the Railway Budget will not be a separate event and will be incorporated into the general Union Budget, breaking the 92-year old long-standing tradition of presenting a separate Railway Budget. <br /><br />With demonetisation, the government has demonstrated its intent of focusing on eradicating black money and making India a cashless economy. To achieve these goals, the FM will need to further strengthen and &ldquo;democratize&rdquo; the existing banking and financial services (&lsquo;FS&rsquo;) sector, in general, with a special impetus for FS in rural areas. The FM may also have to sweeten the Union Budget 2017 for the people of India, at large, who have faced some hardships due to demonetisation; and also to promote digital transactions and head towards a cashless economy. In the ensuing paragraphs, we have outlined key expectations of the FS sector.<br /><br />Key expectations<br /><br />Policy reforms<br /><br />&bull; Implement the recommendations of the Working Group on Development of the Corporate Bond Market in India to deepen the corporate bond market and reduce the reliance of Indian corporate houses on bank lending. <br />&bull; Increase the capital infusion into cash-strapped PSU banks, beyond the approximately INR 70,000 crores (~USD 10.29 billion) announced in the Union Budget 2015. So far, the Government has infused INR 25,000 crores (~USD 3.67 billion) into PSU banks.<br />&bull; Implement the recommendations of the Alternative Investment Policy Advisory Committee (&lsquo;AIPAC&rsquo;) for unlocking domestic pools of capital (held by pension funds, insurance companies etc) by channeling capital flows into Alternative Investment Funds (&lsquo;AIFs&rsquo;).<br />&bull; The draft of Financial Data Management Center Bill, 2016, submitted to the Finance Ministry should be cleared at the earliest. A Financial Data Management Centre under the aegis of the Financial Stability Development Council should be set-up, as was announced by the FM in the Union Budget 2016, to facilitate integrated data aggregation and analysis in FS sector.<br /><br />Direct tax<br /><br />&bull; Simplify the existing India-based Fund Manager (&lsquo;IBFM&rsquo;) tax regime to promote India as a viable fund manager jurisdiction. Since the introduction of the IBFM tax regime in 2015, none of the offshore investment groups has established an IBFM, till date.<br /><br />&bull; Amend the &lsquo;indirect transfer&rsquo; provisions to provide a specific carve-out for offshore investment funds. In addition, implement the recommendations of the Expert Committee for rationalizing the &lsquo;indirect transfer&rsquo; provisions. <br /><br />&bull; Withdraw the sunset clause for the concessional tax rate of 5 percent available to offshore investment funds on interest income from specified INR denominated bonds and Government Securities. Separately, extend the concessional tax rate to all types of INR denominated debt securities.<br /><br />&bull; Provide a clear taxing framework for taxation of income arising from offshore INR Denominated Bonds, i.e. Masala Bonds. Further, amend the relevant provisions to grant concessional tax rate of 5 percent on interest earned on Masala Bonds, in line with the press release dated October 29, 2015.<br /><br />&bull; Provide a clear taxing framework for taxation of unsponsored ADR / GDR programmes, as well as DRs that are issued on the back of unlisted equity shares and other Indian securities.<br /><br />&bull; Accede to the long-standing requests of the insurance sector to (i) allow the carry-forward of losses indefinitely, and (ii) exempt general insurance companies from the MAT provisions, bringing them at par with life insurance companies.<br /><br />&bull; Implement recommendations of AIPAC for revamping the AIF taxation regime; for example:<br />- Extend tax pass through status to Category-III AIFs;<br />- Net losses incurred by AIFs should be passed onto investors;<br />- Remove withholding tax obligations on distribution of exempt income by AIFs to its resident investors.<br /><br />Indirect tax<br /><br />&bull; The Government recently exempted service tax on the fees charge by an acquiring bank to a merchant on card transactions upto INR 2,000. This exemption, though welcomed in light of demonetisation, is not sufficiently comprehensive as services by the interchange and issuing bank have not been exempted from service tax. As a result, only a third of the ecosystem supporting card / electronic payment transactions have been incentivised. The Government should therefore aim to provide support to the ecosystem to further encourage adoption of card based and electronic payments. <br /><br />&bull; Clarify that income / financial gain generated by NBFCs from securitisation transaction is akin to interest income, since the element of service is embedded in the securitisation process is minimal. Since the primary income in the nature of interest is exempt from levy of service, similar treatment should be extended to income generation from securitisation of assets which is essentially differential interest as well as a transaction in actionable claim. This subject has been attracting litigation in the recent past. <br /><br />&bull; Clarify that income earned from participation in Collaterized Borrowing and Lending Operations (&lsquo;CBLO&rsquo;) market is essentially in the nature of interest income, since such income is derived through lending of funds. Accordingly, income earned from participation in CBLO markets should be treated to be covered in the negative list and thus, not liable to service tax. The service tax authorities have litigated this issue.<br />&bull; Mutual funds levy an entry / exit load charge from investors, i.e. unit holders for documentation, asset management, etc. The charge is in relation to investment instruments and should not be subjected to service tax. Clarification should be issued on applicability of service tax, since there is no service per se that is provided by mutual funds to unit holders.<br /><br />&bull; Clarity is required on non-applicability of service tax on mere apportionment of general administration and other common expenses from head office to branches (which is claimed as a deduction by branch under section 44C of the Income-tax Act, 1961), as there is neither provision of service inter se the head office and the branch, since such deduction is claimed under a special provision of direct tax statute and no services are rendered for a consideration by the head office. <br /><br />&bull; Make suitable announcement on the implementation date of GST in India and also issue the final GST laws and rules to facilitate availability of adequate preparation time and smooth transition to GST regime. <br /><br />The FS sector will, once again, need to be at the forefront for heading towards a cashless economy as well as to ably support other key sectors such as the Infrastructure, Agriculture, etc. The FM will need to formulate policies that provide thrust to the FS sector, especially, the banking sector, with emphasis on developing secure digital infrastructure for non-cash transaction. The Government should look to increase overseas investor confidence by, amongst other things, simplifying the (i) IBFM tax regime, and (ii) &lsquo;indirect transfer&rsquo; provisions and (iii) widening the service tax exemption provided to acquiring bank, to the interchange and issuing bank as well to provide coverage to entire ecosystem. Expectations remain rife from the Union Budget 2017 for the FS sector and one would need to wait and watch to see if these are met.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_2000_356x200_3919_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-25 15:54:07</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>