<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-corp-i-t-rate-may-be-cut-by-125-15-percentage-points_8229261.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Corp I-T rate may be cut by 1.25-1.5 percentage points]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[FM Arun Jaitley may announce overhaul of India’s corporate tax structure by slashing the statutory rate and removing layers of exemptions, incentives and deductions that had made the system complex and prone to misuse]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gaurav Choudhury</strong></p>
<p><strong>Moneycontrol<br /></strong></p>
<p>Finance minister Arun Jaitley may cut the corporate income tax rates by 1.25-1.5 percentage points to 28.75-28.5 percent in the Budget for 2017-18, but will likely remove a plethora of exemptions that allow companies to cut down on their effective tax payouts.</p>
<p>The move, which Jaitley had first announced in 2015, will signal the beginning of reforms of one of India&rsquo;s complex tax systems that had become mired in layers of exemption and sops over the years, making it difficult to administer.</p>
<p>In November 2015 the government had laid down a comprehensive road map for phasing out the corporate tax exemptions by 2018 as it looks to reduce the tax rate, simplify the administration and improve India&rsquo;s competitive edge globally.</p>
<p>Tax deductions and exceptions have been prone to misuse and consequential litigation</p>
<p>The exemptions could be phased out on the basis of four major principles. Profit-linked, investment-linked and area-based tax deductions.</p>
<p>Besides, the government may not allow the so-called sunset date to be advanced. This effectively implies that existing tax exemptions will run their course, but government will not extend these any further, sources indicated.<br /><br /><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2017/t/tax.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>This will also ensure that the area-based exemptions given to north-eastern and hilly states will not be cut short mid-way.</p>
<p>In case of tax incentives with no terminal date, a sunset date of March 31, 2017 or March 2018 may be provided, either for commencement of the activity or for claim of benefit, depending upon the structure of the relevant provisions of the (Income Tax) Act.</p>
<p>&ldquo;With a larger share of the economy captured in the tax net, the government has greater space to lower corporate income tax rates along with removal of all tax incentives and concessions,&rdquo; Chandrajit Banerjee, Director General, Confederation of Indian Industry (CII), said.</p>
<p>Currently, there are 32 incentives applicable on corporate profits before calculating tax. While the statutory tax rate of 33.99 percent, including cesses and surcharges, companies are paying an effective tax rate of 24.67 percent after factoring in incentives, exemptions and tax deductions.</p>
<p>The government may also lay down a roadmap phase out the weighted deduction. Weighted deduction allows the tax payer to claim a deduction that is more than the actual expenditure incurred.</p>
<p>Cold chain units, warehousing facilities for storage of agricultural produce, affordable housing projects and production of fertilizers are some of the areas where weighted deduction of 150% of capital expenditure is allowed at present.</p>
<p>At present, India gives tax holidays to various sectors including power generation, distribution and transmission, special economic zones and telecom.</p>
<p>There is a fear that the phasing out of exemption may adversely impact a range of sectors from information technology to pharmaceuticals by discouraging investment in investment in research and development (R&amp;D) and the special economic zones (SEZ) that currently enjoy these incentives.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/t/tax_356X200_0900_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-09 11:33:23</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>