<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-computer-emergency-response-team-proposed-to-check-cyber-frauds_8392941.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Computer Emergency Response Team proposed to check cyber frauds]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Amid government's push on digital transactions, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today announced setting up of a Computer Emergency Response Team to strengthen security of the financial sector amid increasing incidents of cyber frauds.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Amid government's push on digital transactions, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today announced setting up of a Computer Emergency Response Team to strengthen security of the financial sector amid increasing incidents of cyber frauds.</p>
<p>"Cyber security is critical for safeguarding the integrity and stability of our financial sector. A Computer Emergency Response Team for Financial Sector (CERT-Fin) will be established," Jaitley said in his Budget Speech in the Lok Sabha today.</p>
<p>The entity, Jaitley said, will work in close coordination with all financial sector regulators and other stakeholders.</p>
<p>Last year, more than 32 lakh debit cards of various public and private sector banks were compromised. It was one of the biggest cyber frauds related to banks in India.</p>
<p>Post demonetisation, promotion of a digital economy is an integral part of government's strategy to clean the system and weed out corruption and black money.</p>
<p>The Finance Minister also announced that a bill relating to resolution of financial firms will be introduced in the ongoing Budget Session of Parliament.</p>
<p>"This will contribute to stability and resilience of our financial system. It will protect the consumers of various financial institutions," Jaitley said.</p>
<p>Together with the Insolvency and Bankruptcy Code, a resolution mechanism for financial firms will ensure comprehensiveness of the resolution system in the country, he added.</p>
<p>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBslQpB4onkHTB8Ei9quwBxDOyqg">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE3J8DU_uiR6ilTdJKHisn5k8cv_g">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/budget-2017_union_356x200_0305_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 14:22:02</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>