<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/nifty-still-below-8600-selling-continues-budget-session-begins_8378001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Nifty still below 8600, selling continues; Budget session begins]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[ONGC, Tata Steel, Dr Reddy's Labs, NTPC and Bharti Airtel are top gainers while GAIL, Coal India, TCS, Adani Ports and Infosys are losers in the Sensex.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /><br />11:55 am&nbsp;Economic Survey expectations: </strong>Even as Finance Minister Arun Jaitley prepares to table the Economic Survey 2017 in Parliament, former Principal Advisor to Planning Commission Pronab Sen has expressed apprehensions over the applicability of the Economic Survey 2017 in the Budget. Seconding the views of commentators, political and otherwise, Sen said there seems to be a consensus that Budget 2017 will be more political than economic. It would be hard to guage how much the survey will weigh on the Union Budget, he told CNBC-TV18. The survey will also steer clear of making comments on fiscal deficit on the back of measures such as demonetisation, he added.<br /><br /><strong>11:45 am Result poll: </strong>Country's largest private sector lender ICICI Bank is expected to see earnings pressure in Q3 owing to elevated slippages and higher provisions. Profit is seen falling 27.8 percent year-on-year to Rs 2,180.2 crore in the quarter ended December 2016. Net interest income, the difference between interest earned and interest expended, may decline 1.7 percent to Rs 5,359.1 crore compared with Rs 5,453 crore in year-ago period. Analysts expect slippages to remain on the higher end between Rs 7,000-8,000 crore (against Rs 8,029 crore in Q2). Hence, slippages from restructured book and movement of stressed assets (sale to asset reconstruction companies, addition to S4A, 5/25 &amp; SDR) will be closely seen.<br /><br /><strong>11:40 am Budget expectation for FMCG: </strong>Even as the fast moving consumer goods (FMCG) sector comes to terms with a steep fall in demand due to demonetisation, major firms are turning to Budget announcements to bring back consumer confidence.</p>
<p>Companies such as Marico, Emami and Godrej expect a growth-oriented, all-inclusive, and a progressive Budget, according to reports by broking firms.</p>
<p>Analysts expect tax policy for cigarettes to be benign, with an anticipation of an increase in excise duty on cigarettes by 10 percent across slabs and also the likely introduction of 59-mm segment in the current slab structure.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Morgan Stanley&rsquo;s Indira Badrinarayan also expects no changes in the cigarette taxes in the Budget as goods and services tax (GST) does not look imminent in the current fiscal.<br /><br /><strong>11:35 am Market outlook: </strong>Sanjeev Prasad of Kotak Institutional Equities expects a pro-growth Budget tomorrow and likely cut in corporate tax and personal income tax due to demonetisation, indicating that India is moving towards a more tax-moderate regime. Prasad said it is hard to find midcap stocks with right valuations currently, giving an example he said non-banking finance companies (NBFCs) are trading at 3-4 times FY18 book value making them more expensive than the likes of HDFC Bank or HDFC.<strong><br /><br />11:30 am&nbsp;Note ban may delay banks' asset quality recovery: </strong>Demonetisation is likely to push back recovery in banks' asset quality as the cash shortage had a "disruptive impact" on India's informal economy, rating agency Fitch said today.<br /><br />The impact of demonetisation on asset quality will start showing significantly in data for the January-March quarter, te rating agency said.<br /><br />"Demonetisation is likely to push back the recovery in Indian banks' asset quality, given the disruptive impact that cash shortages have had on the country's large informal economy," Fitch Ratings said in a statement.<br /><br /><strong>11:27 am Market check:</strong>The Sensex is down 120.57 points or 0.4 percent at 27728.99 and the Nifty is down 47.15 points or 0.5 percent at 8585.60. About 798 shares have advanced, 1480 shares declined, and 249 shares are unchanged.</p>
<p>ONGC, ITC, Bharti Airtel, Tata Steel and Dr Reddy's Labs are top gainers while GAIL, TCS, Coal India, Adani Ports and ICICI Bank are losers in the Sensex.</p>
<p><strong>11:20 am President Mukherjee says:<br /></strong>37&nbsp;percent&nbsp;of Ujjwala beneficiaries&nbsp;belong to SCs&nbsp;and STs<br />Over 20 crore LED bulbs have been&nbsp; issued via Ujjwala yojana<br />1.5 crore free&nbsp;LPG connections have&nbsp;already been provided in FY17<br />Sowing area has shown 6 percent&nbsp;increase in this rabi season<br />Focus of govt has been holistic&nbsp; development of agriculture<br />Favourable monsoon aided average, yield of kharif crops<br />Soaring price of pulses was a grave concern<br />Pulse prices have been&nbsp;brought under control<br /><strong><br />11:15 am President Mukherjee says: <br /></strong>1.4 lakh villages declared&nbsp; open-defecation free<br />Over 20 crore RuPay cards have been issued so far<br />Unprivileged got access to LPG connection as the rich gave it up<br />Over Rs16,000 crore made available&nbsp; to self-help groups<br />Govt committed to affordable housing&nbsp; via 'housing for all' by 2022<br />Free gas connections are being&nbsp; provided to 5 crore households<br /><br /><strong>11:10 am President Mukherjee says:</strong><br />It's a historic session as railway budget is merged with the union budget<br />Resilience shown in fight against corruption &amp; black money is remarkable<br />Swachh Bharat scheme is turned&nbsp; into a 'jan andolan'<br />Core of all government policies is the welfare of needy<br />Financial inclusion key to poverty alleviation<br /><strong><br />Don't miss: <a class="bl_14" title="Buy, sell, hold: 5 crucial stocks to watch out post Q3 results" href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/stocks-views/buy-sell-hold-5-crucial-stocks-to-watch-out-post-q3-results_8376581.html">Buy, sell, hold: 5 crucial stocks to watch out post Q3 results</a><br /></strong></p>
<p>The market continues to struggle with the Sensex is down 108.06 points or 0.4 percent at 27741.50. The Nifty is down 41.55 points or 0.5 percent at 8591.20. <br />About 795 shares have advanced, 1385 shares declined, and 254 shares are unchanged.</p>
<p>ONGC, Tata Steel, Dr Reddy's Labs, NTPC and Bharti Airtel are top gainers while GAIL, Coal India, TCS, Adani Ports and Infosys are losers in the Sensex.</p>
<p>President Pranab Mukherjee is addressing a joint sitting of the two Houses of Parliament. The government will table the Economic Survey 2017 in the Parliament. The survey will put out economic growth forecasts. It is widely expected to recommend the rollout of universal basic income scheme. Government sources have told CNBC-TV18 that the Union Budget is likely to have a pro-poor focus. It hints at higher allocations for existing rural infra, irrigation and social welfare schemes.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/BSE_Sensex_Budget_2017_bse_stock_market_356x200_0254_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 11:00:35</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>