<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/budget-2017-stocks-focussingrural-infra-housing-to-gainsays-sbi-mf-cio_8345621.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Stocks focussing on rural infra, housing to gain,says SBI MF CIO]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Due to a push towards affordable housing, the housing sector, even with poor volumes off late due to demonetisation, may start to do well, says Prabhat Awasthi, Head-Equities, Nomura India. Cement sector will also gain due to this. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[With the government's focus on affordable housing, improving irrigation and power connectivity and the push to a digital economy, the stocks focusssed on rural areas stand to gain this Budget, says Navneet Munot, Chief Investment Officer, SBI Mutual Fund.<br /><br />With affordable housing, the housing sector, even with poor volumes it posted due to demonetisation, may start to do well, says Prabhat Awasthi, Head-Equities, Nomura India. Cement sector will also gain due to this. <br /><br />The Narendra Modi government has been promoting "housing for all". Under the Pradhan Mantri Awas Yojana, the government aims to build 7 crore houses by 2022. The NDA government has also put into place, various other schemes that are aimed at the welfare of the rural population.<br /><br />The consumer discretionary space looks very attractive, especially the auto sector, says Aditya Narain, Independent Market Expert. He also likes banks and a few NBFCs.<br /><br />He also says that the market is currently driven by money from domestic players rather than foreign institutional investors. The mix of the domestic money has shifted. <br /><br />Munot adds that market wants the tax scheme to be more simplified. He feels the effective rate of corporate tax will not go down since the exemptions will be removed. <br /><br />However, he fears that government may bring down its capital expenditure compared to last year's Budget. He says higher consumption and private capex without government capex will not help revive the investment cycle in the economy.<br /><br />Narain is of the opinion that the government may not focus on as many reforms in the coming years as it did in the last 16-18 months. He feels it is hard to take a call on the fiscal deficit number this year after government banned high-value denominations.<br /><br />This government is not for the faint-hearted, says Sudhir Kapadia, National Tax Leader of EY. This government is willing to take risks.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch videos for more.<br /></strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_farming_agriculture_356x200_3555_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-25 21:32:00</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>