<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/brokerage-recos-others/union-budget-2017-2018-review-yes-securities_8416581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-2018 Review: Yes Securities]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Government projects fiscal deficit target of 3.2%, in line with market consensus. FY18 Revenue deficit pegged at 1.9%, below FRBM mandated level of 2.0%. Focus of the Budget on Investment and Consumption revival]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Government projects fiscal deficit target of 3.2%, in line with market consensus<br />&bull; Promises to remain committed to 3.0% FRBM target in FY19<br /><br />FY18 Revenue deficit pegged at 1.9%, below FRBM mandated level of 2.0%<br /><br />Focus of the Budget on Investment and Consumption revival<br /><br />Realistic growth assumption of Gross tax revenues at 12.2%, lower than FY17 growth of 17% that was driven by additional revenue measures<br /><br />FY18 nominal GDP growth pegged at 11.8%, tad lower vs. advance estimate of 11.9%<br /><br />On direct taxes, key change of reduced personal income tax from 10% to 5% for<br />income between Rs 0.25-0.50 mn. In addition, corporate tax rate for MSMEs with<br />turnover up to Rs 500 mn reduced to 25%<br /><br />No key change on indirect tax front<br /><br />Tax receipts to be supplemented by Dividends &amp; Profits (Rs 1424 bn) &amp;<br />disinvestment proceeds incl strategic sale (Rs 725bn) in FY18<br /><br />&bull; FY18 Non tax revenues assume no fresh spectrum auction<br />On the expenditure side, total spending budgeted to rise by 6.6% lower than FY17 RE growth of 13.6%<br /><br />A faster growth in capital expenditure to improve &lsquo;Quality of spending&rsquo; marginally<br />Gross and net market borrowing budgeted at INR 6.05 tn and INR 4.23 tn respectively<br /><br /><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The views and investment recommendations expressed by investment experts/broking houses/rating agencies on moneycontrol.com are their own, and not that of the website or its management. Moneycontrol.com advises users to check with certified experts before taking any investment decisions.</em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_356x200_4046_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-03 12:22:54</Entry_Date><Category>Brokerage Recos - Others</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>