<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-insurance-industry-seeks-tax-sopspremium-payments_8360521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Insurance industry seeks tax sops on premium payments]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Insurance penetration, which refers to insurance premiums as a percentage of gross domestic product (GDP), stands at 3.4 percent in India according to the Swiss Re sigma report]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>In order to promote insurance, companies are seeking tax incentives on the premium paid. Further, the life insurance sector has also sought a basic term insurance to be made mandatory for all citizens.</p>
<p>Insurance penetration, which refers to insurance premiums as a percentage of gross domestic product (GDP), stands at 3.4 percent in India, according to the Swiss Re sigma report. The insurance density, which is premium per capita, stands at USD 55 in India compared to USD 621.2, globally.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Insurance as a product is still not understood properly by the masses,&rdquo; says Arijit Basu, MD &amp; CEO, SBI Life. &ldquo;So, we need some incentives like tax sops for the life insurance industry.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Kotak Securities in a report said that there is an expectation that income tax will be increased for life insurance companies to 30 percent from 12.5 percent, currently. This, they said, will negatively impact profitability of all life insurance companies.</p>
<p>There has been a demand to also remove service tax for insurance. However, it is unlikely that this demand would be considered.</p>
<p>V Manickam, Secretary General, Life Insurance Council, which is the umbrella body for all life insurers, said that currently Section 80C under which tax exemptions for life insurance are classified already has many categories including fixed deposits and public provident fund.</p>
<p>&ldquo;We would prefer a separate category for insurance premiums with tax deduction of Rs 50,000 and are hoping that our demand would be considered,&rdquo; he said.</p>
<p>Currently, segments like home insurance have low policy sales even after natural disasters causing heavy damage to property and contents every year. Insurers have also sought some form of tax support so that this product becomes more attractive among customers.</p>
<p>The health insurance industry wants India to start saving for health at a younger age. Ashish Mehrotra, MD &amp; CEO, Max Bupa Health Insurance said that to encourage people to insure themselves for longer period, tax exemption should be available each year based on the number of years covered.</p>
<p>&ldquo;A welcome move would be if the government can provide relief by removing the 15 percent service tax on health insurance premium and further increase the deduction limit under section 80D for individuals and families from Rs 25000 to Rs 50000. Tax benefits will help boost penetration of health insurance as well as help nurture a culture of preventive healthcare in India.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>What Iindustry wants:<br /></strong>Higher exemption limits for insurance premium payments</p>
<p>--Making some form of protection insurance compulsory</p>
<p>--Additional exemption limit for health insurance and health savings products</p>
<p>--Separate exemption window for home insurance products</p>
<p>--Incentivise digital transactions</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/i/insurance_buying_356X200_4849_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 15:47:09</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>