<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/budget-2017-lackimpetus-disappoints-pharma-industry_8400421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Lack of impetus disappoints pharma industry]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The pharmaceutical industry was expecting some fiscal incentives to make it stay competitive at a time when it’s facing pricing pressures both within India and abroad.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Viswanath Pilla</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />At a time when the pharma industry is facing pricing pressures both within India and abroad, the pharmaceutical sector had great expectations from Budget 2017.&nbsp;<br /><br />The industry was expecting some fiscal incentives to make it stay competitive. <br />However, other than the government's intention to eliminate certain non-communicable diseases and improve health indicators, focus on wellness and creating more clinical staff and medical infrastructure, there isn't much in the budget for the sector to cheer about.<br /><br /> Overall a safe and balanced budget, which could have been bolder,&rdquo; said Kiran Mazumdar-Shaw, chairperson and managing director of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/biocon/BL03">Biocon</a>. <br /><br />&ldquo;Some incentives for MSMEs but Corporate Tax reduction linked to job creation and investments was missing which would have spurred much needed private sector investment. Removal of FIPB is a good move which will ease FDI inflow. Sadly no impetus for exports, science &amp; technology, manufacturing sector which would have boosted the &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo; initiative,&rdquo; Mazumdar-Shaw added.<br /><br /> "We had some expectations from the Union Budget 2017-18, given the government&rsquo;s past stated intentions of improving access to healthcare. Yesterday&rsquo;s World Economic Forum said that that India&rsquo;s public spending on healthcare is much lower than the global average,&rdquo; said Kanchana TK, Director General, Organisation of Pharmaceutical Producers of India (OPPI) - that represent multinational drug makers.<br /><br />&ldquo;It is unclear whether the allocations will adequately address current healthcare challenges. We also hoped for some reform announcements on the regulatory front in the form of weighted deduction on R&amp;D, incentives for patents, exemptions of certain duties and taxes, etc,&rdquo; Kanchana said.<br /><br />&ldquo;The life sciences sector had great expectations from the budget not only from a fiscal incentives perspective but also from a regulatory angle; more so, given the government&rsquo;s vision of making India one of the top-three pharmaceutical markets by 2020,&rdquo; said Utkarsh Palnitkar, National Head &ndash; Life Sciences practice, at KPMG in India.&nbsp;<br /><br />&ldquo;In order to stay competitive in the overseas market and given the uncertain global climate, it was expected that specific impetus or incentives would be given to innovation in the form of weighted deduction on R&amp;D, incentives for patents, exemptions of certain duties and taxes, etc. These demands remained largely unaddressed, giving no specific reason to cheer for the sector as a whole in 2017&ndash;18,&rdquo; Palnitkar said.<br /><br />&ldquo;While we were hopeful that healthcare would be accorded a national priority sector status, the structural reform in medical education, in particular the increase in the number of post graduate medical seats and DNB courses is praiseworthy as it was long-awaited,&rdquo; said Prathap Reddy, chairman of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/hospitalsmedicalservices/apollohospitalsenterprises/AHE">Apollo Hospitals</a>. <br /><br />]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/g/Gland_Pharma_356_1536_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 20:46:25</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,BL03,AHE,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>