<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/steel-psus-scalecapex-plans-by-9-after-cutbacksfy17_8407621.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Steel PSUs scale up capex plans by 9% after cutbacks in FY17]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[There are nine undertakings under the ministry of steel and together they plan to spend Rs. 12637.71 crores in 2017-18, higher by nearly 9 percent from the Rs. 11604.94 crores they see themselves spending in the year that ends next month.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Dhirendra Tripathi</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol</strong><br /><br />Government-owned steel manufacturers expect to incur almost 9 percent more as capital expenditure in 2017-18 (April-March) after cutting back on the same for the ongoing financial year, according to the Union Budget presented on Wednesday. &nbsp;<br /><br />There are nine undertakings under the ministry of steel and together they plan to spend Rs 12637.71 crore in 2017-18, higher by nearly 9 percent from the Rs 11604.94 crore they see themselves having spent in the year that ends next month.<br /><br />This comes after the collective 2016-17 capital expenditure plan of the nine companies was reduced by 5.7 percent from its original estimate of Rs 12,308.53 crores to Rs 11,604.94 crore.<br /><br />If one compares the 2017-18 target to the original 2016-17 figure, it is only a 2.7 percent increase in spending that steel PSUs are targeting.<br /><br />To put this in perspective, take the case of Steel Authority of India, the largest steel manufacturer in the public sector. The steelmaker plans to spend Rs 3,500 crore in 2017-18, lower by Rs 500 crores from the expenditure it expects to incur in the ongoing financial year.<br /><br />Now the Rs. 4,000 crore that it is targeting to spend in 2016-17 is itself 33 percent lower from its original aim of Rs 6000 crore that was set in the 2016-17 Budget.<br /><br />The scaling back of plans by <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/steel-large/steelauthorityindia/SAI">SAIL</a> indicates the company could be estimating some over-capacity in the sector and hence a go-slow approach on expansion plans.<br /><br />Rashtriya Ispat Nigam, another public sector undertaking, plans to spend Rs 1,891.65 crore in 2017-18. This is 38 percent more than the 2016-17 revised estimate but only 13 percent more than the original targeted figure of Rs 1,678 crores. The Visakhapatnam-based company cut back its 2016-17 capital expenditure plans by around 18 percent from the original target.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/s/steel-duty-356_3003_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 13:55:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,SAI,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>