<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-find-out-how-much-tax-super-rich-payindiaelsewhere_8345001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Find out how much tax super rich pay in India and elsewhere]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The best tax systems are those where the richest pay the highest rates of tax. In India, those with an annual taxable income of more than Rs 1 crore pay an effective tax rate of 35.6 percent.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>As Finance Minister Arun Jaitley prepares to present his Union Budget for 2017-18, everyone will want to know where income taxes are headed &ndash; more down than up. While the common man won&rsquo;t complain if the exemption limit isn&rsquo;t raised beyond the Rs 2,50,000 level, the wealthy will be happier if there is a reduction.</p>
<p>So, what does it mean to be &ldquo;super-rich&rdquo;? It depends on which country you belong to.</p>
<p>The best tax systems are those where the richest pay the highest rates of tax. In India, those with an annual taxable income of more than Rs 1 crore pay an effective tax rate of 35.6 percent.</p>
<p>It is a different matter that only 48,000 people have disclosed an annual income of more than Rs 1 crore, signifying thousands continue to dodge taxmen. There is mismatch between many Indians&rsquo; spending abilities and disclosed income.</p>
<p>The wealthy in Spain pay a hefty tax of 52 percent on income of USD 3,94,390.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In 2013-14, the then Finance Minister P Chidambaram levied a surcharge of 10 percent on Rs 1 crore income and above.</p>
Later, Jaitley hiked it to 12 percent in 2015 and still further to 15 percent in 2016.<br /><br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2017/i/Infographic49.png" alt="" />]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/m/money_5949_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 13:33:51</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>