<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/trinamool-congress-not-to-attend-parliamentbudget-day_8365381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Trinamool Congress not to attend Parliament on Budget day]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Trinamool will also not attend the all-party meeting convened by Lok Sabha Speaker Sumitra Mahajan this evening ahead of the Budget session of Parliament beginning tomorrow.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Trinamool Congress, which is angry over the arrest of its two MPs by CBI in connection with the chitfund scam, will not attend Parliament on February 1 when the Budget is presented, citing Saraswati Puja on that day as the reason.</p>
<p>Trinamool will also not attend the all-party meeting convened by Lok Sabha Speaker Sumitra Mahajan this evening ahead of the Budget session of Parliament beginning tomorrow.</p>
<p>"Trinamool will not attend Parliament on February 1 because of Saraswati Puja which is a big day in Bengal," party leader and MP Derek O'Brien told PTI.</p>
<p>He said that on Saraswati Puja, day, there is a custom of keeping away from work and not even touching the tools.</p>
<p>"Saraswati Puja is beyond a religious festival. It is a socio-cultural festival of Bengal," he added.</p>
<p>Budget will be presented by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Wednesday.</p>
<p>About not attending this evening's all-party meeting, he said this was because Trinamool supremo and West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banshee had called a meeting of party MPs for today "10 days back".</p>
<p>Asked whether the party was "boycotting" these proceedings or just skipping, he replied, "It is open for your interpretation".</p>
<p>Trinamool Congress has been angry over the arrest of its two MPs Sudip Bandyopadhyay and Tapas Pal by CBI in connection with the Rose Valley Group chit fund scam.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/m/mamatabanerjee_356_0402_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 11:18:03</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>