<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/budget-2017-startups-play-nationalism-card-demand-more-sops-survey-says_8369441.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Startups play nationalism card, demand more sops, survey says]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[While startup CEOs and tech world echoed against protectionism, the survey conducted two months after the controversy paints a different picture]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Chaitanya Gudipaty and Pulkit Gupta</strong></p>
<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>The idea of &lsquo;nationalism&rsquo; prevailing amongst India's startups became one of the hottest topics of discussion in November, last year when India&rsquo;s unicorn entrepreneurs Flipkart's co-founder Sachin Bansal and Ola cofounder Bhavish Aggarwal supported the idea of favourable policies for home-grown startups.</p>
<p>While both Bansal and Aggarwal got flak on social media for their open stance favoring protectionism, in a Moneycontrol Survey a whopping majority of startup CEOs seem to support the idea. In a survey conducted by Moneycontrol.com, a majority of respondents (78 percent) believed that government should offer additional benefits to home-grown startups over international counterparts.</p>
<p>Among others, roughly 17 percent felt that they don&rsquo;t need any protectionist laws and 3 percent were not decisive on the issue.</p>
<p>Raising the banner of protectionism against foreign rivals, Ola CEO Bhavish Aggarwal had argued that it's much easier for non-Indian companies to raise capital because they have profitable markets elsewhere. Ola's larger rival Uber has readied a cash pile to be invested in Indian market after it closed its China operations last year.</p>
<p>Echoing similar sentiments, Flipkart&rsquo;s Sachin Bansal had said "What we need to do is what China did (15 years ago) and tell the world we need your capital, but we don't need your companies.&rdquo; Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos has committed an additional USD 3 billion to be invested in India even as Flipkart is scouting for funds.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Taking a dig at Aggarwal, Uber CEO Travis Kalanick on a visit to New Delhi said that he will apply for Indian citizenship if push comes to shove. He had added that majority of Ola and Uber was owned by foreign investors.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&ldquo;I will apply for Indian citizenship if this gets me over the hump," Kalanick joked in a fire-side chat session with NITI Aayog CEO Amitabh Kant.</p>
<p>While startup CEOs and tech world echoed against protectionism, the survey conducted two months after the controversy paints a different picture as majority of the startups are now asking for protectionism, even as MNCs dump huge amounts of capital in Indian market attracting customers.</p>
<p><strong>Survey methodology</strong></p>
<p>Moneycontrol.com conducted a survey to review Budget wish-list of various startups across India. Startups were questioned on a variety of issues ranging from tax holiday to startup policies. About 50 startup CEOs participated in the survey which included multiple choice questions. The survey was carried out between 25th January, 2017 and 29th January, 2017.<br /><br /></p>
<p>Also Read:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/budget-2017-startup-indiaflop-need-5-year-tax-break-reveals-survey_8369001.html">Startup India a flop, need 5 year tax break, reveals survey</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/budget-2017-what-startups-feel-about-modi-government%E2%80%99s-initiatives_8369481.html">What startups feel about Modi government&rsquo;s initiatives?</a></p>
<p><br /><br /> <a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/startup_18" data-show-count="false">Follow @startup_18</a>
<script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" type="mce-no/type"></script>
</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/boom_0828_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 14:00:47</Entry_Date><Category>SME</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>