<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/pm-modi-terms-budget-as-futuristic_8393521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[PM Modi terms Budget as 'futuristic']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["This is a Budget for the future - for farmers, underprivileged, transparency, urban rejuvenation, rural development, enterprise," Modi said while commenting on the document presented by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in the Lok Sabha.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today described the Budget as "futuristic" with an aim on fulfilling the "dreams" of every section, including the poor, the farmers and the under-privileged while focussing on job creation, transparency, urban rejuvenation and rural development.</p>
<p>He said the Budget is a key link between the work done by his government over the last two-and-a-half and the steps that it will be taking in the future as part of its vision to take the country on the path of development.</p>
<p>"This is a Budget for the future - for farmers, underprivileged, transparency, urban rejuvenation, rural development, enterprise," Modi said while commenting on the document presented by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in the Lok Sabha.</p>
<p>Lauding Jaitley for presenting a "good" budget, he said it will speed up the development of the country, create new employment opportunities, double farmers' income.</p>
<p>It will bring a big change in the financial condition of the villages, Modi said.</p>
<p>It also attempts to raise middle class incomes without any increase in fiscal deficit.</p>
<p>This Budget focusses of farmers, agriculture, villages, dalits, oppressed and suppressed, the Prime Minister said.</p>
<p>"This Budget is yet again devoted to the well-being of the villages, farmers and the poor," the Prime Minister said, adding the government's commitment towards taking the country forward is clearly visible.</p>
<p>"From railway modernisation to economic reforms, from education to health, from entrepreneurship to industry, the aim at fulfilling the dreams of all is clearly visible in the Budget," he said.</p>
<p>He said a record allocation has been made for MNREGA as well as women's welfare.</p>
<p>Asserting that the Budget reflects commitment to eliminate corruption and black money, Modi said it provides for a comprehensive package of digital economy which will reduce tax evasion and help control black money.</p>
<p>With regard to the reduction of tax for people with lower incomes, the Prime Minister said it was a "courageous step" that will provide relief to the middle class.</p>
<p>He also referred to the provision on political funding, saying it was an important step to clean politics of corruption.</p>
<p>The merger of the Railway Budget with the general budget will give an impetus to the transport sector's growth, he said.</p>
<p>The housing sector stands to gain immensely from the Budget, Modi said.</p>
<p>About tax reduction for MSME sector, he said it will help small businesses to become competitive in the global market, he said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_Budget17_356x200_3456_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 15:00:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>