<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-tax-terms-that-may-figurebudget-might-change_8364481.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Tax terms that may figure in Budget & what might change]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley might announce some major changes in the tax landscape. Here, we explain a few taxation terms that might crop up and what is likely to change relating to them.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />The Union Budget 2017-18 is around the corner. During the run-up, there have been speculations that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley might announce some major changes in the tax landscape. We bring you some terms that might crop up in Jaitley&rsquo;s speech on February 1 and explain to you what they mean and what is expected to change related to them.<br /><br /><strong>Tax Exemption &amp; Tax Deduction</strong><br /> <br /><strong>Exemption:</strong>&nbsp;The portion of income of the tax payer which does not form part of the taxable income or is exempt from tax.<br /><br /><strong>Deduction:</strong> These are items, mostly investments that are allowed to be deducted from the tax-payer's gross total income for calculation of tax payable. Most of the items for which deduction is allowed against permissible investments are listed under Chapter 6A of the Income Tax Act, 1961, with the most popular ones under Section 80C. <br /><br /><strong>What might change:</strong> There is talk that the Budget may reinstitute Standard Deduction which was discontinued from assessment year of 2006-07 to provide some relief to tax payers. Standard deduction is available to taxpayers with income up to a certain level to meet their salary-related expenditure, such as skill enhancement and purchase of books. <br /> <br /><strong>EEE &amp;&nbsp;EET Tax Structure</strong><br /><br /><strong>EEE or Exempt, Exempt, Exempt</strong>: An investment&rsquo;s lifecycle has three stages: investment, accumulation and withdrawal. Each &lsquo;E&rsquo; in EEE refers to the respective stage. In EEE all the three stages of an investment cycle is exempt from tax. In India, EPF and PPF are instruments which enjoy this benefit.<br /><br /><br /><strong>EET or Exempt, Exempt, Taxable</strong>: Under this, while the first two stages are exempt from tax, the final act of withdrawal is taxable. The National Pension System (NPS) falls under this category.<br /><br /><strong>What might change</strong>: There is hope that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley might agree to the longstanding demand of making NPS also an EEE scheme, thereby bringing about a level-playing field with EPF and PPF. The primary goal of all three schemes is to provide retirement income.<br /><br /><strong>Short-term &amp;&nbsp;Long-term capital asset</strong><br /><br /><strong>Short-term capital asset</strong>: A capital asset that is held for not more than 36 months before sale/transfer. However, for certain capital assets, such as equities and equity mutual funds the period of holding is 12 months. <br /><br /><strong>Long-term capital asset</strong>: Capital assets that are held for a period of over 36 months are considered long-term assets. However, shares and equity mutual funds are considered long term capital assets if they are held for over 12 months.<br /><br /><strong>Capital gains:</strong> This refers to profits or gains made from sale or transfer of a capital asset.<br /><br /><strong>What might change?</strong> At present long-term capital gains on equities and equity mutual funds is nil while short-term capital gains are taxed at 15 percent. It is understood that the government is considering increasing the holding period of equities and equity mutual funds to get long-term capital gains exemption to 36 months from the present 12 months.<br /><br /><strong>Tax and Cess</strong><br /><br /><strong>Tax:</strong> A tax is a levy imposed upon a taxpayer, be it an individual or a corporate entity, on their profits by the government to fund its various expenditures.<br /><br /><strong>Cess:</strong> A cess is a levy, similar to tax, but is aimed at a specific purpose. Thus, collections under the Krishi Kalyan Cess has to be specifically used for welfare of the farming community or Swacch Bharat Cess is for keeping the country clean.<br /><strong><br />What might change:&nbsp;</strong>It is understood that the government might levy a specific cess for improvement of Railway services in the coming Budget. This might be a small expenditure by taxpayers.<br /><br />Also read: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-a-video-guide-to-some-key-terms-usedthe-budget-speech_8368621.html?utm_source=ref_article" target="_blank">A video guide to some key terms used in the Budget speech</a><br /><br />]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/t/TAX_shutterstock_356x200_2715_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 11:00:05</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>