<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-fm-sets-aside-rs-10000-cr-to-recapitalise-banks_8382121.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: FM sets aside Rs 10,000 cr to recapitalise banks]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In an effort to ease of the pressure on banks that are reeling from record bad debts, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech Wednesday announced Rs 10,000 crore to recapitalise banks. Doubles lending target at Rs 2.44 lakh crore. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Maryam Farooqui</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol</strong><br /><br />In an effort to ease the pressure on banks that are reeling from record bad debts, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech Wednesday announced Rs 10,000 crore to recapitalise banks. "Additional allocation would be made if required," he&nbsp;added.&nbsp;<br /><br />Jailtey also proposed&nbsp;to double the lending target of Pradhan Mantri Mudra Yojana (PMMY) and set it up at Rs 2.44 lakh crore for 2017-18.<br /><br />The government&rsquo;s plan to recapitalise banks continues, despite the deluge of deposits in public sector banks (PSBs) following demonetisation.<br /><br />The need for capital requirement was reiterated during a pre-Budget meet with Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, where the banks had pitched for recapitalisation in the current and next financial years.<br /><br />In 2016-17 Budget, the government had announced to provide Rs 25,000 crore for infusion into public sector banks and by July, Rs 22,915 crore were allocated to recapitalise 13 public sector banks, including State Bank of India (SBI). The amount is 92 percent of the budgeted Rs 25,000 crore allocation under this head for the year 2016.<br /><br />Public sector banks have been seeking higher recapitalisation from the government. PSBs are in need of capital not only to meet current adequacy standards but also for Basel-III capitalisation norms, which come into effect from 2018.<br /><br />Of Rs 1.8 lakh crore required by banks under Basel-III norms, the government has promised to pay Rs 70,000 crore over four years till 2018-19 and has asked state-owned banks to raise Rs 1.1 lakh crore from the market. The infusion will boost the government's shareholdings in the banks, which are under-capitalised relative to their private sector rivals because of restrictions on their ability to sell equity to raise money. In 2015-16, the government provided Rs 25,000 crore in three tranches to public sector banks, and 40 percent went to banks that needed support.<br />
<p><strong>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/budget-2017-game-changing-taxes-will-provide-sense-of-direction-edelweiss_8388701.html" target="_blank">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES<br /></a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" target="_blank">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></strong></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/f/FM_Finmin_Jaitley_Arun_356x200_0402_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 12:37:21</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>