<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-interview/nilesh-shahrbiupcoming-budget_8295701.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Nilesh Shah on RBI and upcoming Budget]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Speaking to CNBC-TV18 Nilesh Shah, Managing Director at Kotak Mahindra Asset Management, said he hopes the Budget to be good. He wants the FM to honour his word on fiscal discipline. 
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Speaking to CNBC-TV18 Nilesh Shah, Managing Director at Kotak Mahindra Asset Management, said he hopes the Budget to be good. He wants the FM to honour his word on fiscal discipline. <br /><br />&ldquo;We want this belief to be reconfirmed that good economics is equal to good politics and we want good monsoon. And we want the RBI to keep adequate liquidity at lower rates.&rdquo;</p>
<p>On the global front, he hopes that global stable oil prices and China to remain stable.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Nilesh Shah&rsquo;s interview to Ritu Singh on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: What are you predictions for calendar year 2017?</strong><br /><br />A: We expect US Fed to increase rates between one and two times rather than three, as they have indicated in December, 2016. We expect crude to remain range bound between USD 40 and 60. We expect RBI to cut policy rates between 25 and 75 basis points. We expect RBI to provide adequate liquidity in the banking system for the rest of calendar year 2017. We expect rupee to behave orderly and appreciate between 3-5 percent in calendar year 2017. And most importantly, we expect equity market to end calendar year 2017 at higher level than what it is today.<br /><br /><strong>Q: What could be some of the key triggers for that to happen?</strong><br /><br />A: Essentially, if markets have to go up from current level, we need some support globally and some support locally. If we look at local factors, one, we need a good budget where Finance Minister honours his commitment on fiscal prudence, yet is innovative enough to cut tax rates to put money in the hands of consumers to spend. And also, give money for infrastructure investment. Post that, in some of the state elections, we want this belief to be reconfirmed that good economics is equal to good politics. You can win elections by development, job creation and growth. Post that, we want a good monsoon and throughout this period, we also want RBI to keep adequate liquidity and lower interest rates. On the global side, some of the events which should support us is obviously stable oil prices and US Fed not increasing as per their prediction, but a little less. Most importantly, we also want China to remain stable.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/n/nilesh_shah_356x200_3537_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-18 16:49:05</Entry_Date><Category>MF-Interview</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>