<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-fasal-bima-yojana-scheme-getsadditional-boost_8392481.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Fasal Bima Yojana scheme gets an additional boost]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[“The Fasal Bima Yojana launched by our Government is a major step in this direction. The coverage of this scheme will be increased from 30 percent of cropped area in 2016-17 to 40 percent in 2017-18 and 50 percent in 2018-19,” said Jaitley in the Budget speech.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />The Pradhan Mantri Fasal Bima Yojana (PMFBY) has received an additional impetus with the government allocating Rs 9000 crore for the scheme. In 2016-17, they were allocated Rs 5500 crore. Finance minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech said that the coverage under the scheme will be increased to 50 percent of cropped area in 2018-19.<br /><br />&ldquo;The Fasal Bima Yojana launched by our government is a major step in this direction. The coverage of this scheme will be increased from 30 percent of cropped area in 2016-17 to 40 percent in 2017-18 and 50 percent in 2018-19,&rdquo; said Jaitley in the Budget speech.<br /><br />The Budget provision of Rs 5,500 crore for this Yojana in Budget estimate for 2016-17 was increased to Rs 13,240 crore in the revised estimate for 2016-17 to settle the arrear claims.<br /><br />The sum insured under this Yojana has more than doubled from Rs 69,000 crore during kharif or summer sowing season in 2015 to Rs 1,41,625 crore in 2016.<br /><br />Farmers have been paid Rs 13,240 crore in arrears during 2016-17.<br /><br />More than 1 million farmers have been given cover under this scheme, making India the third largest agriculture insurance market in the world after US and China.<br /><br />The scheme, approved by the Cabinet in January 2016, has a uniform premium of 2&nbsp;percent to be paid by farmers for all kharif crops and 1.5 percent for all rabi crops. For commercial and horticultural crops, the farmers&rsquo; premium is five percent. The rest of the premium is paid by the government.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_farming_agriculture_356x200_3555_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 14:15:18</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>