<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-make-thispublic-expenditure-budget-says-jk-fm-haseeb-drabu_8335381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Make this a public expenditure Budget, says J&K FM Haseeb Drabu]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[All eyes are on Budget which is just round the corner and Haseeb Drabu, Finance Minister of Jammu and Kashmir, suggests that Arun Jaitley should focus on public expenditure.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[All eyes are on Budget, which is just round the corner, and Haseeb Drabu, Finance Minister of Jammu and Kashmir, suggests that Arun Jaitley should focus on public expenditure. <br /><br />He says that there are schemes that are pushing the consumer demands but now the time is to spur the industrial demand. According to him, the government should look at non-tax revenues as a source of funding.<br /><br />On the other hand, Kavita Rao, Professor, NIPFP believes that the Indian economy needs consumption-led stimulus as investment is a long cycle. She also said that the government should accept that the economy is slowing down.&nbsp;<br /><br />Koushik Chatterjee, Group ED, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/steel-large/tatasteel/TIS">Tata Steel</a> is of the view that investments in research and development (R&amp;D) is a necessity and Indian companies must take on the R&amp;D path as a critical business objective.<br /><br />He says that there should also be sops for climate change capex and companies should invest in climate related equipments.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Koushik Chatterjee &amp; Haseeb Drabu's interview to Latha Venkatesh.<br /><br /></strong></em><strong>Q: This Budget also comes in the wake of the Finance Minister having promised grandfathering or phasing out of exemptions and reduction of taxes. All the exemptions have not been phased out so is it legitimate to expect tax cuts?<br /><br /></strong><strong>Chatterjee:</strong> It is reasonable o expect that the exemptions should come down and should be eliminated if we have to move towards a lower rate of taxation in India which is expected to enhance both compliance and widen the tax base. I would only request the finance minister if there were some exemptions which should have longer transition life, for example, investments into the research and development (R&amp;D) and innovations because as a country we need a more competitive positioning as far as R&amp;D is concerned.
<p>We are a country which is going to grow. We have a huge population and therefore, the consumptions will increase and therefore, Indian companies must take on the R&amp;D path as a critical business objective and incentives, which are already in place, should be extended for a longer period of time.</p>
<p>The second is incentives like on climate change. There were exemptions which were given for missionary equipments which were targeted towards reducing pollution and if India is to achieve its climate targets as a signatory to the COP21 last year, then it is important for companies to aggressively invest in climate related equipments. Therefore, they should be incentivised to make those investments. These are the two that comes to my mind as needs a timeline rather than be abrupt in stuffing those incentives in the future. Other than that, a gradual or even a systematic elimination is fine.</p>
<p><strong>Q: The other question is whether the economy desperately needs stimulus and has the government been very successful in stimulating so far?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Chatterjee:</strong> Absolutely. If you really look at the Indian economy relative to the rest of the world, we would certainly say that we are doing extremely well. But that we can say, we have been doing well in the last few years and in fact, post the global financial crisis; India has weathered it better than most other developing economies and indeed the developed economies. So, that is not the question. It is whether India is performing to its potential and if you need to grow at a much higher rate; if the aspiration is to grow at about 8-9 percent then we need momentum of investments which will generate a significant amount of economic value for the country. And it has to be investment led, it has to be employment led and then consumption led. So, people are all searching for that big breakaway phase of investments where both private capital and public capital or government spending will go hand-in-hand and create that economic phase where the country will employ more people, will throw up more consumption surplus, people will spend more and that is the kick-start people are looking for and that has been the expectation for the last couple of years. So, we have been seeing a fair amount of public spending, but we have not seen private capital being put onto the ground.</p>
<p>The other aspect is there are some sectors of the economy where there is significant amount of capacity which is impacted by financial constraints or oversupply and things like that or even regulatory issues which is latent and people are waiting for policy changes and demand kickers coming in so that that capacity can be put to productive use. So, it is a combination or a balance. It is not so much a stimulus as such but it is A] the objective of performing to our potential and often Budget announcements take one-one-and-a-half year to actually fructify.</p>
<p>As you rightly said that there are issues on the ground which needs to be overcome, but if the policy direction is on that on an investment focused growth rather than consumption focused growth, then we will be on a much more solid pedestal than the rest of the world. And that is what we need to do because we have manufacturing competitiveness across many sectors. We just need to ensure that those investments flow in and make India a more competitive nation.<br /><br /><strong>Q: In this Budget should the finance minister stay pat on indirect taxes altogether since it is now the preserve of the goods and services tax (GST) council?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Drabu:</strong> I would imagine so, now that we are pretty certain that you will move on to the GST regime from July 1. This period should be used to focus on the systems and all and ideally, I would imagine, one should do a vote on account for these six months and then present the Budget sometime in May with full details on the taxation regime because in this Budget itself you cannot do much on the indirect tax regime and then you are moving to a fairly different system which will have its own issues; operational fitment, macroeconomic implications. Ideally one choice is vote on account and then a full-fledged Budget.<br /><br /><strong>Q: But is it not possible that the finance minister can stay pat on indirect taxes probably even tweaks the service taxes closer to the known GST rates and do something dramatic on direct taxes like phasing out exemptions and bringing down rates, no?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Drabu:</strong> Yes, what you could do is make a transition from between now and July, move into those rate bands but I do not know that's how other states would also want to do it. I just presented my budget about a week-ten days back and initially I thought that I will also move to four or five band regime in preparation for the application of GST, but doesn't quite work because in this period you will be out of line with what has been agreed upon in terms of earlier regime, so it becomes little more difficult. However, one option is to funnel the current rates into broadly speaking the four or five rates of 0-5-12-18-28 percent, you could do that but with that kind of numbers and that kind of commodities only for a period of six months, not worth the effort and you will disturb the system much more than even benefit from it. So on balance my own thing would be to go for the vote on account and second preference is that leave the taxes as it is perhaps focus more on indirect tax or the direct tax regime.<br /><br />However, when I look at the overall macroeconomic situation, I would much rather make this Budget a public expenditure Budget rather than a Budget in terms of taxations and stuff, so that one can control the overall economic growth in the system at least give it some degree of fiscal stimulus on the expenditure side. So I would much rather focus on the expenditure part because going forward you will have to at some point reinvent the entire ritual of the Union Budget as also state Budgets because post July there is very little that we would be doing on the indirect taxes; it's all been done by the GST council with or without the approval. So you might as well start preparations of making Budget a far more public expenditure policy document.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: If you wear your economist hat as well, if you do think the economy needs a stimulus, are you convinced of that in the first place? And secondly, how can you make it a public expenditure Budget? You mean he can raise taxes or increase the tax base in any which way, direct tax base so as to be able to increase the amount of money available for expenditure?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Drabu:</strong> That is the funding part of it. I would first primarily focus on the level and the structure of expenditure. If you notice, over the last 3-4 years, it has really become, the Budget has a public expenditure policy in terms of spending on major schemes like Mahatma Gandhi National Rural Employment Guarantee Act (NREGA) and others where you are really pushing up consumer demand in a big way. So, the focus of expenditure has been that. I would, this time around, think that more than that kind of consumption demand, what needs to be spurred is industrial demand and you may want to go back to an expenditure strategy of, if you want to call it the 50&rsquo;s perhaps, where public investment is a lot more than public expenditure though public investment is a subset of public expenditure. <br /><br />So, what I am saying is move away from the regular public expenditure which is your current expenditure to more a capital expenditure (Capex) based Budget this year. And perhaps, now start looking at public investment and agriculture and so on and so forth. So, in terms of the structure of expenditure. And then financing it, perhaps, you could live with a higher degree of deficit as well. I would not be averse to the idea of a pure play classical kind of fiscal stimulus where you have a slightly higher fiscal deficit and also perhaps, look at non-tax revenues as a source of funding than tax sources. <br /><br />The thing today, is to go back to a very classical Budget which we used to have earlier where the public investment and expenditure would drive the economy because post 1990&rsquo;s it really has not been public investment, it has been private investment. And Budget had lost its place in the macroeconomic context of India because the levels were not so high. Maybe for a year so, we do need to go back to an old style, good old Budget of heavy expenditure.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Two quick questions. One, a higher deficit would also mean that there will be a higher cost of money and therefore, private investment which is already weak could be scared away. Would that not worry you?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Drabu:</strong> I would still think, as I said, this should now be seen as a deliberately expansionary fiscal and monetary policies right now. It just states at this point of time, the transmission mechanisms are not so strong that you would see an increasing cost of money. In any case, the demand for money is very low at this point of time and I would also want some degree of monetary tweaking to supplement the fiscal expansion. So, you would really want joint action of fiscal and monetary policy expansion over the next 6-8 months to ride the dampening that has happened and the uncertainty that could peg the growth at a lower rate.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Secondly, there is a doubt among several people whether government is really capable, does it really have the bandwidth, administrative, bureaucratic bandwidth for the kind of investment that you are talking about. Witness for the current year, they have 15,000 road kilometres as the National Highway Authority of India&rsquo;s (NHAI) aim. This far, they have bid out just 5,000 km. Bandwidth lacking is it not?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Drabu:</strong> Yes, that is the biggest constraint and I see it honestly now that one is also involved in direct policy making. The institutional capability to spend is rather low. In my case, in Jammu and Kashmir, I find it is very low. It is not about you want to spend the money, but the capability to spend is very low. At some point, this is also reflecting nationally that the institutional capacity to spend money in these kind of infrastructure areas is becoming a constraint and we need to focus on that as one of the things. But I think this Budget should see some of that happening. And this Budget should also see some degree of nudging of the banks which will be corresponded by a monetary policy that actually gets banks to become more active now again because I am sensing that there is some kind of reluctance and also the emergence of a certain degree of things in the banks about the quality of assets.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_budget_356x200_5221_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-24 19:45:27</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,TIS,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>