<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/brokerage-recos-others/union-budget-2017-2018-review-hdfc-securities_8404801.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-2018 Review: HDFC Securities]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Good, even if not inspiring Mr Jaitley has yet  again delivered an elaborate and meticulous Budget, mostly within stated policies. It laboured more than it inspired. India still awaits a transformative and inspiring follow-through after demonetisation.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">Good, even if not inspiring: Mr&nbsp; Jaitley&nbsp; has&nbsp; yet&nbsp; again&nbsp; delivered an elaborate and meticulous Budget, mostly&nbsp; within&nbsp; stated&nbsp; policies.&nbsp; It laboured more than it inspired. India still&nbsp;&nbsp; awaits&nbsp;&nbsp; a&nbsp;&nbsp; transformative&nbsp;&nbsp; and&nbsp; inspiring&nbsp; follow-through&nbsp; after demonetisation.<br /><br /></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">The&nbsp; Union&nbsp; Budget FY18 is sufficiently powered (to accelerate the creation of both hard and soft public infrastructure), pragmatically constructed (by the&nbsp; mandarins&nbsp; of&nbsp; North&nbsp; Block,&nbsp; who&nbsp; have&nbsp; adopted&nbsp; a&nbsp; revenue &amp; capital expenditure&nbsp; format)&nbsp; and&nbsp; rightfully&nbsp; leans&nbsp; towards&nbsp; &lsquo;Bharat&rsquo; rather than &lsquo;India&rsquo;&nbsp; (with&nbsp; higher spends on agriculture, rural &amp; social welfare, small housing,&nbsp; SME&nbsp; and&nbsp; vulnerable&nbsp; segment&nbsp; relief).&nbsp; This stance will pull up median&nbsp; incomes&nbsp; (and&nbsp; mass confidence) quicker than the arithmetical mean, which is quite apt for India's skewed demographics.<br /><br /></div>
<p><strong>To&nbsp; rewind a bit, we had hoped to see the following six pillars (or themes) in this year's Budget:</strong></p>
<div style="text-align: justify;">1. The push to make the economy more ORGANISED</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">2. SUBSIDY REFORMS, especially the adoption of technology/Aadhar</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">3. INFRASTRUCTURE creation and urbanisation</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">4. SOFT INFRASTRUCTURE creation</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">5. A SIMPLE, FIRM and pragmatic government</div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">6. Rapid&nbsp; adoption&nbsp; of TECHNOLOGY to improve speed and effectiveness of governance.<br /><br /></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">To&nbsp; be&nbsp; fair,&nbsp; Mr&nbsp; Jaitley has scored moderately well across this list. But nowhere&nbsp; has&nbsp; he hit the boundaries that could have brought the audience to its&nbsp; feet&nbsp; in&nbsp; applause.&nbsp; Not&nbsp; one&nbsp; brave&nbsp; new&nbsp; measure&nbsp; cashed&nbsp; in&nbsp; on the mass-support&nbsp; for&nbsp; the&nbsp; politically&nbsp; risky&nbsp; move&nbsp; of&nbsp; demonetisation. Beedi barons,&nbsp; rich farmers and smaller parts of the informal (cash) economy will breathe&nbsp; a&nbsp; bit&nbsp; easier&nbsp; for now. There is still some time left for them to enjoy their direct and indirect rents.<br /><br /></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">On&nbsp; the&nbsp; brighter&nbsp; side,&nbsp; the&nbsp; Fiscal discipline is praiseworthy and subtly nudges&nbsp; the RBI to consider a rate cut in the upcoming policy. The decision to&nbsp; abolish&nbsp; the FIPB and the conscious decision not to increase the number of&nbsp; Central Schemes are confirmations of this Government's rational intent.<br /><br /></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">SMEs&nbsp; will&nbsp; benefit&nbsp; from&nbsp; the&nbsp; (small)&nbsp; income&nbsp; tax&nbsp; relief&nbsp; and&nbsp; so&nbsp; will individuals&nbsp; in the first taxable bracket of Rs 250-500k. Marketmen reacted with&nbsp; glee&nbsp; to&nbsp; the&nbsp; absence&nbsp; of&nbsp; LTCG and the reliefs for FPIs. Corporates mostly got indirect benefits only.<br /><br /></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">This&nbsp; Budget&nbsp; has&nbsp; come in the wake of the demonetisation-induced&nbsp; shock to economic&nbsp; activity.&nbsp; It rightly seeks to provide fiscal and policy stimulus to small-ticket economic activity. While the intent to widen the tax net is commendable,&nbsp; the results may not be easily forthcoming as soon as aspired.<br /><br /></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">We&nbsp; see&nbsp; moderate&nbsp; risk&nbsp; to&nbsp; direct&nbsp; tax&nbsp; collections, and hence, to fiscal discipline (or capital expenditure) as the year progresses. Global factors, as&nbsp; always, will throw in uncertainty.<br /><br /><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The views and investment recommendations expressed by investment experts/broking houses/rating agencies on moneycontrol.com are their own, and not that of the website or its management. Moneycontrol.com advises users to check with certified experts before taking any investment decisions.<br /><br /></em></div>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/a/Arun_jaitley_budget_2017_economy_356x200_0134_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 12:40:03</Entry_Date><Category>Brokerage Recos - Others</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>