<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-shotthe-arm-for-real-estate-sector_8295861.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Shot in the arm for real estate sector?]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The recent demonetization and proposed amendment to Benami Properties Act seems to have added to the woes of the industry in the short term with a slack in housing and office space demands. However, there are hopes of these yielding long term benefits with falling interest rates and anticipated government thrust to the sector]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Prashanth Bhat</strong><br /><strong>BMR &amp; Associates LLP</strong> <br /></em>
<p>The recent demonetization and proposed amendment to Benami Properties Act seems to have added to the woes of the industry in the short term with a slack in housing and office space demands. However, there are hopes of these yielding long term benefits with falling interest rates and anticipated government thrust to the sector.</p>
<p>With relaxation of Foreign Direct Investment (&lsquo;FDI&rsquo;) norms, introduction of the Real Estate Investment Trust (&lsquo;REIT&rsquo;) regulations, the Government&rsquo;s mega housing mission 2022, there have been significant reforms in this sector over the last few years.&nbsp; While one would have expected this to create an upward momentum, the reality is different with not a single prospectus for REIT being filed and even the real estate FDI reflecting a declining trend during 2015-16 and 2016-17.</p>
<p><strong>From a home buyer&rsquo;s perspective</strong>, enhancing interest deduction on self-occupied properties and scope of the tax incentives under section 80EE of the Income-tax Act, 1961 would incentivize home buyers in key metros holding maximum unsold inventories.</p>
<p><strong>For the Developer,</strong> easing of policies and a thrust to the real estate economy would be the obvious agenda to boost housing demand. On the supply side, significant measures are needed such as support in terms of rationalization of land acquisition policies, project based financial support from governmental agencies, extension of special status benefits (currently limited to affordable housing projects) to the overall construction sector. From a tax perspective, widened scope of affordable housing projects qualifying for tax holiday is required for new project investments. <u>&nbsp;</u></p>
<p>Additionally, the need of the hour is to further rationalize the REIT regime. There have been amendments in the taxation regime for REITs in the past and SEBI has recently further liberalized REIT regime allowing multiple level SPV structures, relaxation of holding under construction properties, etc. <br /><br />However, there are still some concerns that the Government should seek to address in this Budget such as extending exemption from Dividend Distribution Tax to multiple level SPV structures (now permissible under SEBI regulations), tax exemption on transfer of assets by sponsors to REIT, clarity on deductibility of expenses in the hands of REITs, applicability of the tax exemption provisions on the contribution of the shares of the SPVs by sponsors into REIT, amongst others.</p>
<p>Significant time, efforts and costs are being incurred by the industry to defend litigations relating to key tax issues pertaining to taxation of joint development contracts and characterization of income from commercial properties developed and leased. <br /><br />Similarly, while &lsquo;transfer of title in immovable property&rsquo; is excluded from service tax, there persists confusion whether transfer of development rights in land, agreement of sale, revenue share of developers in plotted developments, transactions in the secondary market by investors, can be treated as transfer of title in immovable property, in sync with business practice, and hence outside the scope of service tax.&nbsp; <br /><br />Clarity is required by way of necessary amendments or explanations to existing tax provisions and a comprehensive guideline issued after considering the different aspects of these transactions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>A critical deficiency to be rectified under the current regime is non-availability of construction related credits for commercial projects, which coupled with higher tax rate has an adverse impact on corporates due to higher rental costs. &nbsp;-</p>
<p><strong>For Special Economic Zones (&ldquo;SEZs&rdquo;),</strong> once perceived to be attractive investments by both investors and tenants have slowly lost their sheen and demand due to non-committal tax policies of the government.&nbsp; The removal of exemption from Minimum Alternate Tax (&ldquo;MAT&rdquo;) in 2012 followed with the sunset of March 2017 for developers and March 2020 has accelerated declining interest.&nbsp; The industry has been pleading for a relaxation on both aspects.&nbsp; While rationalization of MAT provisions is expected which should provide some relief, the Government should rethink extending sun set clause to ease the burden. &nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>In summary</strong>, the industry is all set for greater challenges and expectedly the Budget 2017 wish list is a long and demanding one. It is the fervent hope that with a fulfilling Budget coupled with the revolutionary transformation with the onset of Goods and Services Tax and Real Estate Regulation Act is the shot in the arm the Real Estate sector have been waiting for.<br /><br /><em>with inputs from Nidhi Lukose, Director, Indirect Tax, BMR &amp; Associates LLP</em></p>
<p><em>Author is&nbsp;Prashanth Bhat, Partner, Indirect Tax, BMR &amp; Associates LLP</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_India_GDP_Growth_inflation_rise_down_economy_real_estate_infrastructure_home_house_356x200_1517_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-18 18:37:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>