<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/politics/budget-2017-enddirty-moneypolls-jaitley-sets-stage-for-reforms_8397521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: End of dirty money in polls? Jaitley sets stage for reforms]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Elections in India has largely been a game of cash, with parties spending on through cash for a variety of purposes including renting a chair for a public meeting that comes for Rs 10 a day, festoons for Rs 600 apiece and helicopter rides that cost upto Rs 500,000 an hour.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[India took a big first step towards reforms in electoral funding on Wednesday with Finance Minister Arun Jaitley proposing changes in rules under which political parties can only receive up to Rs 2000 in cash from a single source.
<p>Political parties will be entitled to receive donations by cheque or digital mode from their donors.</p>
<p>As an additional step, an amendment is being proposed to the Reserve Bank of India Act to enable the issuance of electoral bonds in a special scheme that the government would frame.</p>
<p>Under this scheme, a donor could purchase bonds from authorised banks against cheque and digital payments only. They shall be redeemable only in the designated account of a registered political party. These bonds will be redeemable within the prescribed time limit from issuance of bond.</p>
<p>India&rsquo;s electoral funding is largely opaque. According to the Association for Democratic Reforms (ADR) parties receive up to 75 percent of their funds from unknown sources.</p>
<p>According to the Stockholm based International Institute of Democracy and Electoral Assistance (IDEA), India is among very few countries in the world to &ldquo;allow political parties or candidates to receive anonymous donations&rdquo;.</p>
<p>In the US, there is cap on spending, but contributions above certain limits must be disclosed. In the UK, policy development grants of 2 million pounds a year are given, while in Canada, parties get reimbursed 22.5 percent of election expenses if it gets at least 2 percent of the votes polled. In France, the State reimburses almost 50 percent of campaign spends to candidates who get more than 5 percent of votes and campaign finance strictly regulated.</p>
<p>Elections in India has largely been a game of cash, with parties spending on through cash for a variety of purposes including renting a chair for a public meeting that comes for Rs 10 a day, festoons for Rs 600 apiece and helicopter rides that cost upto Rs 500,000 an hour.</p>
<p>&ldquo;This reform (the new rules) will bring about greater transparency and accountability in political funding, while preventing future generation of black money,&rdquo; Jaitley said in this speech for Budget 2017-18.</p>
<p>Despite stringent penalties and rules, allegedly offering bribes and cash to voters, sometimes as small as Rs 500, is a commonly-used strategy to attract votes.</p>
<p>In the last Lok Sabha elections, the Election Commission had seized more than Rs 300 crore of rupees, more than the double the hat was seized during previous elections five years ago.</p>
<p>Coming as it does just before high-octane elections in Assembly polls in UP, Punjab, Uttarakhand, Goa and Manipur scheduled for the next few weeks for early 2017, the latest move could force political parties to redraw their spending strategies that operate outside regulatory boundaries.</p>
&ldquo;An effort, therefore, requires to be made to cleanse the system of political funding in India,&rdquo; Jaitley said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/e/elections_vote_party_356x200_5123_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 16:29:32</Entry_Date><Category>Politics</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>