<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-govt-to-levy-10-concessional-taxincomecarbon-credit_8401521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Govt to levy 10% concessional tax on income from carbon credit]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Income-tax Department has been treating the income on transfer of carbon credits as business income which is subject to tax at the rate of 30 percent.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />The Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today proposed to provide a concessional tax rate of 10 percent in case of income arising from transfer of carbon credit, in a bid to provide green growth.</p>
<p>The tax would be levied from April 1, 2018, over along with additional surcharge and cess.</p>
<p>Income-tax Department has been treating the income on transfer of carbon credits as business income which is subject to tax at the rate of 30 percent.</p>
<p>Carbon credits is an incentive provided to industries to encourage reduction of the emission of green house gases, including carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>This done through several ways such as by switching over to wind and solar energy, forest regeneration, installation of energy-efficient machinery, landfill methane capture, etc.</p>
<p>The Kyoto Protocol commits certain developed countries to reduce their GHG emissions and for this, they will be given carbon credits.</p>
<p>A reduction in emissions entitles the entity to a credit in the form of a Certified Emission Reduction (CER) certificate. The CER is tradable and its holder can transfer it to an entity which needs Carbon Credits to overcome an unfavourable position on carbon credits.</p>
<p>However, divergent decisions have been given by the courts on the issue as to whether the income received or receivable on transfer of carbon credit is a revenue receipt or capital receipt.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/e/eu-air-pollution-bill356_3520_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 21:42:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>