<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/budget-2017-budget-key-trigger-for-market-psu-banks-to-rally-further-pros_8277241.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Budget key trigger for market; PSU banks to rally further: Pros]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Tulsian expects the rally in PSU banks to continue up until the Budget. Most of the public sector banks are expected to report Q3 numbers post-Budget, so there is no negative trigger as such.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>It was a good day for the Indian equity benchmark indices despite weak global cues at the start of the trading session. Nifty held the 8400 mark and Bank Nifty was up 1 percent at 19,096.<br /><br />The Sensex was up 50.11 points or 0.2 percent at 27288.17, and the Nifty up 12.45 points or 0.1 percent at 8412.80.</p>
<p>Market experts Anand Tandon, Ashwani Gujral, ashwanigujral.com, SP Tulsian, sptulsian.com and Mitesh Thacker, miteshthacker.com in an interview to CNBC-TV18 shared their views on the way forward for the market in terms of earnings, Budget and stock-specific performances.</p>
<p>For the banks per se, demonetisation could have been positive initially but focus should be on whether credit growth will pick up or will the banks try to maintain margins only by lowering deposit rates, says Tandon.</p>
<p>The consumer space, according to Tandon, could see the impact of demonetistaion. Moreover, if one were to go by the PMI data then expect some slowdown in January and February, says Tandon.</p>
<p>However, Budget remains key for the market in terms of how the government proposes to support growth, says Tandon.</p>
<p>Stock/sector specific, Tulsian expects the rally in PSU banks to continue up until the Budget. Most of the public sector banks are expected to report Q3 numbers post Budget, so there is no negative trigger as such, he adds.</p>
<p>From the midcap space, Tulsian is not so upbeat on Havels and does not see much upside for the stock.<br /><br /></p>
<p><em><strong>For full discussion, watch video...</strong></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Sensex_BSE_Stockmarket_bulls_bear_356x200_3005_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-16 16:29:47</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>