<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/pacefiscal-consolidation-key-to-india-ratings-upgrade-sp_8342661.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Pace of fiscal consolidation key to India ratings upgrade: S&P]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The comments from S&P's India analyst Kyran Curry come as Finance Minister Arun Jaitley faces pressure to cut taxes and hike spending in his annual budget next week - even at the cost of an earlier promise to trim the fiscal gap to 3 percent of GDP in 2017/18 from the 3.5 percent budgeted this year.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The pace of India's fiscal consolidation is vital to the country's prospects of a ratings upgrade, Standard &amp; Poor's told Reuters on Wednesday, flagging its concerns over high and rising debt levels.
<p>The comments from S&amp;P's India analyst Kyran Curry come as Finance Minister Arun Jaitley faces pressure to cut taxes and hike spending in his annual budget next week - even at the cost of an earlier promise to trim the fiscal gap to 3 percent of GDP in 2017/18 from the 3.5 percent budgeted this year.</p>
<p>Curry said India needed to make greater efforts to quickly lower the country's sovereign debt-to-GDP ratio to below 60 percent to boost its case for an upgrade. While India's government debt is largely domestically held, the debt-to-GDP ratio, at 66 percent, is high for an emerging-market economy.</p>
<p>"What we mainly focus on is the change in the pace of the debt accumulation and the debt stock," Curry said in a telephone interview. "And for the moment, they remain quite high."</p>
<p>S&amp;P last November affirmed India's rating at "BBB-minus" with a "stable" outlook, putting Asia's third-largest economy at the bottom rung of investment grade despite calls for an upgrade by government officials.</p>
<p>Ahead of the annual budget, due to be delivered on February 1, a government-appointed panel has advocated pursuing an expansionary fiscal policy to sustain growth in difficult circumstances, opening a window for higher capital spending to ease the pain from the government's decision to scrap high-value banknotes.</p>
<p>Curry, however, said that India's economic growth remained "very strong" despite the fallout from the banknote ban, and the government would do well to avoid pursuing an expansive fiscal policy.</p>
<p>"We would say that the government has limited scope to provide fiscal stimulus because its balance sheet is stretched already," he said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/2/2017-01-25T084017Z_1_LYNXMPED0O0IB_RTROPTP_2_INDIA-BUDGET_356.JPG]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-25 14:29:40</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>