<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/domestic-air-pax-trafficnearly-24december-2016_8287081.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Domestic air pax traffic up nearly 24% in December 2016]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Domestic air passenger traffic rose nearly 24 percent in December 2016 to 95.52 lakh from 77.09 lakh registered during the same period of 2015 even as IndiGo continued to deliver poor on time performance besides losing market share by almost 2 percent in the month.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Domestic air passenger traffic rose nearly 24 percent in December 2016 to 95.52 lakh from 77.09 lakh registered during the same period of 2015 even as <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/transportlogistics/interglobeaviation/IA04">IndiGo </a>continued to deliver poor on time performance besides losing market share by almost 2 percent in the month.</p>
<p>According to the DGCA data, the number of passengers flown by the 11 local carriers stood at 95.52 lakh in December 2016 as against 77.09 lakh a year ago, thereby registering a growth of 23.9 percent.</p>
<p>However, domestic travel demand in 2016 touched nearly 100 million mark, with the Indian airlines flying a total of 998.88 lakh ((99.88 million) passengers between the January-December period of 2016 as compared to 810.91 lakh in 2015, an increase of 23.18 percent over 2015.</p>
<p>The DGCA data showed that Gurgaon-based budget carrier IndiGo's markets declined to 40.3 percent in December last year as against 42.1 percent in November 2016 despite carrying more number of passengers at 38.48 lakh in the month.</p>
<p>Also, the airline's on time performance from four major private airports stood at a poor 61.6 percent where as the rival SpiceJet delivered the best OTP for the third consecutive month at 70 percent.</p>
<p>Significantly, national carrier Air India increased its market pie by over one percent to 14 percent in December, having flown 13.35 lakh passengers in the month.</p>
<p>For the 21 consecutive months, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/transportlogistics/spicejet/SJ01">SpiceJet</a> registered a seat factor of more than 90 percent in December at 93.7 percent.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/a/Airlines_aeroplane_air_aircraft_356x200_5130_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-17 18:16:03</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,IA05,ML04,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>