<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/pm-hopes-for-comprehensive-discussions-during-budget-session_8378941.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[PM hopes for comprehensive discussions during Budget session]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[There should be comprehensive discussion for welfare of society, Modi told reporters outside Parliament.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of the start of the Budget session, Prime Minister Narendra Modi today hoped for a comprehensive discussion in Parliament.</p>
<p>He noted that in the last few days, the government has held discussions with all political parties to ensure that House proceedings are not disrupted.</p>
<p>There should be comprehensive discussion for welfare of society, Modi told reporters outside Parliament.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister said he has faith that all factions will come together in Parliament for welfare of society.</p>
<p>He said it is the first time that the Union Budget is being presented on February 1. Modi recalled that while budgets were earlier presented at 5 in the evening, it was former Prime Minister Atal Bihari Vajpayee who advanced it to morning.</p>
<p>"Today, a new tradition will begin. First, the budget is being advanced by nearly a month. And second, Rail Budget in being incorporated into this. There will be discussion on this also and the benefits that it will have in the coming times," he said.</p>
<p>After the Winter Session was washed out due to protests over demonetisation, Modi had yesterday reached out to the opposition at an all-party meeting called here yesterday.</p>
<p>The meeting was attended by all major parties except Trinamool Congress, which has been unhappy over the note ban and arrest of its MPs in chit fund cases.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/n/Narendra_Modi_Prime_minister_MPO_356x200_3204_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 12:00:03</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>