<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-govt-begins-process-to-divest-entire-stakeferro-nigam-scrap_8434041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Govt begins process to divest entire stake in Ferro Nigam Scrap]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The steel ministry has appointed the transaction advisor for strategic sale of FSNL, along with three units of Steel Authority of India Ltd (SAIL) and NMDC Ltd’s Nagarnar steel plant]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Shreya Nandi</strong><br /><br /><strong><strong>Moneycontrol<br /><br /></strong></strong>
<p>The government has initiated the process to divest its entire stake in Ferro Nigam Scrap Ltd (FSNL) through strategic sale, a move that would bring the Centre closer to its ambitious disinvestment target of Rs 72,500 crore for the next financial year 2017-18.</p>
<p>FSNL is a subsidiary of MSTC Ltd, which falls under the administrative control of the steel ministry.</p>
<p>The steel ministry has appointed the transaction advisor for strategic sale of FSNL, along with three units of Steel Authority of India Ltd (SAIL) and NMDC Ltd&rsquo;s Nagarnar steel plant, a senior government official told Moneycontrol.</p>
<p>However, the official said that the sale is unlikely to materialise in the current financial year (2016-17).</p>
<p>&ldquo;These things take time. The valuation of these units will be done, which would then require the Cabinet&rsquo;s approval. A two-stage bidding process for sale would follow thereafter,&rdquo; the official said.</p>
<p>Later, the Centre may instruct the state-owned company buy back government shares for an amount equivalent to the value realised from the sale. Alternatively, it may ask the company to issue special dividend, the official added. <br /><br /> Last year, the Cabinet had given in-principle nod for strategic sale of three loss-making units of SAIL&mdash;Salem steel plant in Tamil Nadi, Ferro Alloy plant in Durgapur and Visvesvaraya iron and steel plant at Badrawati.</p>
<p>The Cabinet had also approved selling off country&rsquo;s largest iron ore miner NMDC&rsquo;s Nagarnar steel unit that was aimed to be commissioned in December, 2016.</p>
<p>Last week Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said that the government has budgeted a disinvestment target of Rs 72,500 crore in 2017-18, including Rs 15,000 crore from strategic disinvestment.</p>
<p>Senior officials from steel ministry has met the principal secretary to the Prime Minister Narendra Modi to discuss issues related to the strategic sale. &nbsp;In addition, the finance ministry has asked steel ministry to stick to the timeline of 180 days for the completion of the process of stake sale, the official said.</p>
<p>The Department of Investment and Public Asset Management (DIPAM) has so far realised about Rs 31,000 crore of disinvestment revenues. Earning extra revenues through state-controlled companies&rsquo; dividends and selling equity in such companies is critical for next year&rsquo;s central Budget math.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/s/steel-3566_2420_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-06 14:14:35</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>