<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/telecom-fee-collection-target-hints-at-no-spectrum-auction_8397141.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Telecom fee collection target hints at no spectrum auction]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The target is 44 percent lower from the Rs. 78,715 crore the government expects to collect under the same heads in 2016-17.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>The 2017-18 Union Budget's target of collecting Rs. 44,342 crore as entry fees, telecom licence fees and spectrum charges pretty much rules out any spectrum auction in the coming financial year. The target is 44 percent lower from the Rs. 78,715 crore the government expects to collect under the same heads in 2016-17.</p>
<p>The 2016-17 estimated collection includes the money the government mopped up from the spectrum auction in October. Telecom companies had then bid Rs. 65,789 crore for 964.80 Mhz of spectrum. Not all this money was supposed to come to the government in one go.</p>
<p>In case of spectrum bands over 1 Ghz--1800 Mhz, 2100 Mhz, 2300 Mhz, and 2500 Mhz--the successful bidder paid 50 percent of the bid amount upfront. In case of bands below 1 Ghz--700 Mhz, 800 Mhz and 900 Mhz--25% of the bid amount was paid up front.</p>
<p>The balance would come in 10 annual instalments after a two-year moratorium. <br /><br />A target that is 44 percent lower from the 2016-17 mop-up pretty much rules out a spectrum auction in the coming financial year. Telecom companies -- with their stretched balance sheets, plans for consolidation and entry of a large operator in the form of Reliance Jio Infocomm Ltd -- would not really mind this.</p>
<p>Rajan S Mathews, Director General of telecom industry body Cellular Operators Association of India, said while the Budget had positive provisions related to funding and ease of doing business, the industry's expectation of getting a waiver on 15 percent service tax on spectrum allocation was not met.​</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/t/telecom_356x200_4320_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 16:17:16</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>