<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-arun-jaitleys-fourth-budget-could-signalbreakout-year_8387941.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Arun Jaitley's fourth Budget could signal a breakout year]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The pre-Budget Economic Survey, tabled in Parliament on Tuesday, said that India will at grow at 6.75 to 7.5 percent in 2017-18, hinting that turnaround in the broader economy, still reeling under the effects of cash crunch, will take longer than expected.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Gaurav Choudhury<br />Moneycontrol</strong><br /><br />Finance Minister Arun Jaitley is set to present his fourth Budget on Wednesday, amid growing expectations that he will unveil measures to raise people&rsquo;s spending power, boost farm income, revive investment activity and expand welfare schemes to soothe the demonetisation pain, ahead of state Assembly polls.<br /><br />The pre-Budget Economic Survey, tabled in Parliament on Tuesday, said that India will at grow at 6.75-7.5 percent in 2017-18, hinting that the turnaround in the broader economy, still reeling under the effects of cash crunch, will take longer than expected.<br /><br />He may have some good news for the salaried and the middle class.<br /><br />The government is learnt to be examining an overhaul of India&rsquo;s income tax regime. On the cards: a restructuring of tax slabs and increasing the income tax exemption limit from the existing Rs 250,000 to more than Rs 400,000 &mdash;a move that would leave more money in the hands of people.<br /><br />He may also bring back the concept of &ldquo;Standard Deduction,&rdquo; a base amount that is not subject to tax in addition to the basic exemption limit, providing relief to every tax payer. The Easwar-panel on income tax simplification, in a recent report, had recommended the re-introduction of standard deduction, 12 years after it was removed in 2005-06.<br /><br />The move is part of the broader strategy to reward honest taxpayers who have endured the pain of demonetisation.<br /><br />Jaitley is also widely expected to raise tax breaks offered under the popular &ldquo;Section 80 (C)&rdquo; limit by Rs 50,000 to Rs 2 lakh a year&mdash;a move aimed at weaning people away from stocking up cash and parking surplus funds in banks and mutual funds.<br /><br />That said, the Finance Minister may hike the service tax from 15 percent to close the gap with 18 GST rate. This will make most services &mdash; from eating out to telephone bills costlier. A higher service tax now will, however, prevent a greater price shock after GST kicks in from July 1, 2017.<br /><br />It will also help the Centre partially offset the revenue loss from forgoing exclusive rights over service tax that accounts for 14 percent of total central revenues currently.<br /><br />While the government is unlikely to introduce long-term capital gains tax, the &ldquo;long-term&rdquo; rule may change to 3 years. Definition of long-term could be widened to align the investment lock-in threshold with many matured economy markets.<br /><br />Also, the corporate income tax rate could be cut by 1.25-1.5 percentage points from 30 percent currently, with Jaitley likely to announce the overhaul of India&rsquo;s corporate tax structure by slashing the statutory rate and removing layers of exemptions, incentives and deductions that had made the system complex and prone to misuse.<br /><br />The Finance Minister, however, may reintroduce a proposal to tax cash withdrawals from banks above a threshold, on the lines of banking cash transaction tax (BCTT) that was implemented during 2005-2009.<br /><br />Apart from keeping a trail on people&rsquo;s attempt to hoard cash through repeated high-value cash withdrawals, a BCTT-type of a levy will also make it less rewarding for people to transact in cash.<br /><br />Jaitley may also introduce a super-rich tax slab of 35 percent on all individuals with a taxable income of Rs 1 crore per annum.<br /><br />On the savings front, Jaitley might agree to the long-standing demand of making National Pension System (NPS) also an exempt-exempt-exempt (EEE) scheme, bringing about a level-playing field with employees&rsquo; provident fund (EPF) and public provident fund (PPF).<br /><br />He will likely give a big push in Budget 2017 to &ldquo;Mission Antyodaya&rdquo;&mdash;an ambitious programme aimed at lifting 10 million families out of poverty through a raft of schemes including the Mahatma Gandhi National Rural Employment Guarantee Scheme (MNREGS), pitching the programme as NDA&rsquo;s response to UPA&rsquo;s Bharat Nirman initiative.<br /><br />Jaitley is widely expected to widen income tax holiday for startups to five years from three years.<br /><br />Easier exit norms for founders, simpler rules for government supplies among measures being examined; industry ministry pushing for service tax exemption for start-ups and more funds for Atal Innovation Mission are also expected.<br /><br />As part of the government&rsquo;s efforts to usher India into a &ldquo;less-cash&rdquo; economy, a Jaitley may announce a special fund to aid spread of digital payment infrastructure.<br /><br />Jaitley may also propose a package of tax incentives for the labour-intensive leather, gems and jewellery sectors as part of the government&rsquo;s signature &ldquo;Make in India&rdquo;&nbsp; initiative to boost manufacturing, create jobs and sustain the revival in exports.<br /><br />
<p>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/j/Jaitley_Fm_Fiance_Minister_Arun_356x200_0847_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 08:04:21</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>