<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-impact-insurance-agents-may-not-want-to-call-it-quits-after-tax-relief_8405881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget impact: Insurance agents may not want to call it quits after tax relief]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The finance minister in his budget speech said that agents will be exempt from TDS subject to their filing a self-declaration ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Insurance agents can now breathe a sigh of relief after Finance Minister Arun Jaitley&nbsp;in his Budget speech removed the 5 percent tax levied&nbsp;on their commission fees. This move&nbsp;will keep insurance agents, who have been complaining of low remuneration, from exiting the industry.<br /><br />As on today, a TDS (tax deducted at source) of 5 percent is being levied on commission fees payable to individual insurance agents even on income that is below the taxable limit. The Finance Minister in his Budget speech said that they will be exempt subject to their filing a self-declaration form that their income is below taxable limit.</p>
<p>While exact numbers are not available, industry estimates suggest that an average agent&rsquo;s annual income ranges between Rs 2 lakh and Rs 2.5 lakh, whereas the most active agents selling higher ticket policies could earn as much as Rs 25 lakh to Rs 30 lakh every year including commissions and other incentives.</p>
<p>For every insurance policy sold by them, agents earn a commission in the range of 10-30 percent depending on the type of product and its policy term. The first year is when the agents receive the highest commission which gets reduced after every renewal. For instance, a policy may help an agent earn 20 percent in the first year, which may go down to 8 percent in the second year and 5 percent in the third year and so on.</p>
<p>However, the insurance agents do not have any steady source of income since they are not paid any fixed salaries. Even whatever little they earned attracted a TDS of 5 percent which has now been removed above a bracket.</p>
<p>Vignesh Shahane, Wholetime Director &amp; CEO, IDBI Federal Life Insurance, said that doing away with this tax on insurance agents&rsquo; commissions is a great step forward in attracting and retaining right talent in the sector.</p>
<p>On an average, 40,000-45,000 agents exit the insurance every year. In FY16, 40,150 agents left the insurance industry as per data from the Life Insurance Council.</p>
<p>Even the latest data from the Council shows that while there has been a marginal improvement in the number of life insurance agents, several private insurers have been losing agents. Life Insurance Corporation of India, which has the largest number of agents, saw a marginal growth of 3 percent from April to December period of this financial year.</p>
<p>While Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (IRDAI) had earlier suggested having some form of a fixed remuneration for the agents, insurance companies had said that they were not in the position to pay all agents a monthly salary. However, insurers have slowly begun to incentivise their agents and offer them specialised courses for career enhancement and development.</p>
<p>Further, the regulator has also proposed commission rates as high as 50 percent for the first year for longer tenure-term policies in order to make this profession attractive for agents. Now, this will also be exempt from TDS if it falls below a certain limit.</p>
<p>With 70 percent new business premium in the life insurance industry coming through insurance agents, both the industry as well as the regulator have been pushing to get more such individuals into the sector. Now with tax sops being added in, the numbers are expected to swell atleast by 20 percent, said company officials.<br /><br /><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2017/i/Insurance_Agent_Dec31_2016.png" alt="" /><br /><br /><br /></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/l/life-insurance_2351_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 13:02:59</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>