<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-affordable-housing-push-to-boost-cement-steel-demand-kochhar_8402081.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Affordable housing push to boost cement, steel demand: Kochhar]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Budget 2017 has achieved balance between focus on investment & fiscal prudence, said Chanda Kochhar, MD and CEO of ICICI Bank.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[After the Finance Minister Arun Jaitley presented the Union Budget, Chanda Kochhar, MD and CEO of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/icicibank/ICI02">ICICI Bank</a>, said Budget 2017 has achieved balance between focus on investment and fiscal prudence.<br /><br />&ldquo;The push for affordable housing will improve demand for cement and steel&rdquo;, she added.<br /><br />Speaking to CNBC-TV18 Kochhar said that the Budget attempts to move the needle ahead for investment and consumption. She also said the push on investments will create multiplier impact on the economy and that the current push towards investment has to start from government spending.<br /><br />&ldquo;Continuous push on digital payments will expand the formal economy substantially,&rdquo; she added.<br /><br />Deepak Parekh, Chairman of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-housing/housingdevelopmentfinancecorporation/HDF">HDFC</a> said Budget 2017 is very good for urban Housing and that the Budget has done a lot for rural and infra sectors. He added that the Budget still has more room left for bank recapitalisation if needed.<br /><br /><strong>Watch the videos for statements from:</strong> Mohandas Pai, Chairman, Manipal Global Education; Naina Lal Kidwai, Chairperson, Max Financial Services, Harish Salve, Senior Advocate and Manish Chokhani, Enam Holdings<br /><strong><strong><br /></strong></strong>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/a/Arun_jaitley_budget_2017_economy_356x200_0134_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 22:46:36</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,ICI02,HDF,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>