<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-easingtaxing-effectsind-as-adoption_8371901.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Easing the taxing effects of Ind AS adoption]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[If the Finance Ministry decides to scrap ICDS, then it must certainly introduce an alternate mechanism for Ind AS companies to compute their taxable income.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Sai Venkateshwaran</strong><br /><br />For several large Indian companies, reporting under the new Indian Accounting Standards (Ind AS) is now a reality, having made the changeover from April 1, 2016.&nbsp; While companies have embraced the use of these standards that are converged with International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS), the taxation related uncertainties that come with the use of Ind AS still remain to a large extent. &nbsp;<br /><br />Considering that tax related issues were one of the key issues that led to derailing the IFRS convergence efforts in 2011, the Finance Minister, clearly recognizing that a framework for addressing the taxation challenges had to go hand in hand with the adoption of the Ind AS, in his maiden budget speech in 2014 announced the adoption of Ind AS and the notification of separate tax standards, which are now called as Income Computation and Disclosure Standards (ICDS). &nbsp;<br /><br />Since then there has been significant progress only on ICDS front, with the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) notifying 10 ICDS, although these have also been subsequently amended and deferred by one year.&nbsp; However, the final position on the computation of minimum alternate tax (MAT) and also the interplay with the VAT and service tax provisions still remains to be addressed.&nbsp; Some of the key outstanding issues, which need to be addressed either through the Finance Bill 2017 and / or other legislative and executive actions, are discussed below. &nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>MAT computation</strong><br /><br />The MAT &ndash; Ind AS Committee has submitted its report to the CBDT with its recommendations on how companies that report under Ind AS should compute MAT, wherein they have addressed what adjustments need to be made annually as well as those that relate to the onetime adjustments made to the opening retained earnings at the date of transition to Ind AS.&nbsp; The relevant amendments to the MAT provisions will need to be introduced in this year&rsquo;s Finance Bill, as companies using Ind AS would be required to compute MAT liability for the year ending March 31, 2017 using the amended provisions. &nbsp;<br /><br />While these recommendations address many of the issues, one key issue that remains open is the starting point for computation of MAT &ndash; as per this Committee report, MAT is computed using the profits as reported under Ind AS, and no further adjustments are to be made to exclude items of unrealized or notional fair value gains and losses that are included in the Ind AS profit other than those already envisaged in Section 115JB of the Income Tax Act.&nbsp; As a result companies may end up having to pay MAT on fair value gains, which maybe notional or temporary and could potentially reverse in another period.&nbsp; With the Committee going by the principle that profits that can be distributed as dividend should also be subject to MAT, this matter can be satisfactorily addressed only if the CBDT and Ministry of Corporate Affairs (MCA) work together as this is also closely related to the provisions on distributable profits under company law. &nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>Other income tax provisions</strong><br /><br />While the ICDS addresses many of the areas where Ind AS differs from older accounting standards, there are still a few areas where both ICDS and income tax law currently don&rsquo;t provide explicit guidance.&nbsp; Therefore, there may be diversity in practice in areas such as accounting for service concessions, embedded lease arrangements, financial instruments, etc, if additional guidance isn&rsquo;t provided.&nbsp; Further, the deductibility of adjustments being made to opening reserves on the date of transition to Ind AS is another area that requires clarification. &nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>Indirect Tax: VAT, Service Tax and GST</strong><br /><br />The adoption of Ind-AS brings several changes to the way companies reported revenues: there are changes to the quantum of revenues, timing of its recognition as well the characterization of such revenues.&nbsp; All of these would have an impact on the related indirect tax payments, which are currently more aligned to the older accounting standards. &nbsp;<br /><br />Considering the extent of these changes, the indirect tax authorities would need to provide some guidelines to be followed in bridging the Ind AS revenues with the amounts to be considered for payment of VAT and service tax and also for GST going forward.&nbsp; This would provide clarity and also help avoid unnecessary litigation. &nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>The fate of ICDS</strong><br /><br />There have been recent discussions on the merits and demerits of ICDS, with some quarters calling for its repeal.&nbsp; One can certainly debate whether ICDS is the best way to address the direct tax related issues that come with the adoption of Ind AS, but one certainly can&rsquo;t deny the need for a framework that brings in horizontal equity between tax payers, irrespective of the accounting framework that they use, i.e., Ind AS and the older accounting standards.&nbsp; A mere change in accounting framework cannot result in a change to the taxable income generated by an entity. &nbsp;<br /><br />Therefore, if the Finance Ministry decides to scrap ICDS, then it must certainly introduce an alternate mechanism for Ind AS companies to compute their taxable income. <br /><br />A short term solution could be to maintain status quo and continue using old Indian GAAP framework for computing taxable income.&nbsp; However, a longer term and sustainable alternative solution maybe to make suitable amendments to the income tax law recognizing the differences between Ind AS and older accounting standards and to require additional reconciling adjustments between reported income and taxable income, for companies using Ind AS. &nbsp;<br /><br />Considering that the first year end for companies reporting under Ind AS is just around the corner, the Ministry of Finance needs to act fast and work with the various stakeholders to arrive at an equitable and practical solution to all of the above issues, and one would expect that the Finance Bill 2017 will provide clarity on many of these areas. &nbsp;<br /><br /><br /><em><strong>The author is Partner and Head &ndash; Accounting Advisory Services, KPMG in India</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>All views and opinions expressed herein are those of the author and do not necessarily represent the views of KPMG in India.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_Budget17_356x200_3456_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 16:08:19</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>