<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-cleanslate-for-financial-services-before-gst-goes-live_8353761.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Clean the slate for financial services before GST goes live]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[EY enlists the expectations of the financial industry from Union Budget 2017]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Anish Thacker</strong><br /><br />It is budget time again. With large expectations from a populace that still is coming to grips with many disruptive events in 2016, the financial services industry is again at the forefront. Tax and particularly income- tax, is always a key focus area when it comes to looking at the expectations from the government at this time. A few key asks of the financial services industry in the forthcoming budget are given below:-<br /><br /><strong>Banking -</strong> The banking industry has reportedly been the beneficiary of demonetisation. With full coffers from the deposit of notes, the opportunity for them to clean up their balance sheets by providing for bad debts and bad loans is irresistible. Unfortunately however, they are unable to claim a full tax deduction of the provisions so made. Provisions made for doubtful debts are deductible only to the extent of seven and a half percent of average advances (this is increased to ten percent in case of rural advances). Banks therefore are quite expectant that some relief (even a one- time relief for this year would be welcome) should be given such that there is alignment and no mismatch between their accounting and tax results. Another potential area of mismatch between the two (i. e. accounting and tax) is the Income Computation and Disclosure Standards (ICDS) which are made applicable for the financial year 2016- 17 and beyond. Though upon the representation of the banks, the disclosure requirements were tweaked and some standards made inapplicable, there still exists mismatches which would create differences. There has been a huge outcry that these standards (which apply to all taxpayers) be scrapped. There is considerable hope that this will be acceded to, in the forthcoming budget, though strictly speaking, the rescinding of the notification can also be done outside of the budget initiatives.<br /><br /><strong>Non-Banking Financial Companies ( NBFCs)</strong> - Non banking finance companies are more concerned about timing difference in terms of recognition of interest on non- performing assets (NPAs). Unlike banks which can recognise income on NPAs only when they receive it, NBFCs need to recognise the income as soon as it becomes due. Of course, when ultimately the advance is written off as irrecoverable, the interest recognised upfront is also deductible as a bad debt in the year of the write- off but, in an era where tax rates are expected to drop in the next few years, an upfront recognition of income followed by a subsequent write off results in a permanent tax loss and not a timing difference to the extent of the reduction in the tax rate. NBFCs are thus disadvantaged in this regard when compared to banks. Another area where the difference in tax treatment disadvantages NBFCs is the applicability of Tax Deduction at Source (TDS or withholding tax) to interest paid by a customer to them. Whereas a customer making a payment of interest to a bank is not ordinarily required to deduct tax at source therefrom, a customer paying interest to a NBFC is, in fact, required to deduct tax. This results in a significant cash trap for the NBFC which in order to avoid the trap, has to approach its tax officer for a certificate which would authorise the customer either to not deduct tax or deduct tax at a lower rate. This certificate is not, unfortunately easy to obtain. ICDS and timing differences impact NBFCs more than the banks as certain standards are specifically made inapplicable to banks but not to NBFCs. NBFCs therefore would welcome the withdrawal of these standards more than the banks would.<br /><br /><strong>Mutual Funds -</strong> Mutual Funds&rsquo; ability to invest in pass through certificates (PTC) was eased last year with erstwhile distribution tax being replaced by tax at the investor level and the securitisation trust being required to deduct appropriate tax at source. The provisions as they are presently enacted only refer to &lsquo;securitisation trust&rsquo; which would be the special purpose vehicle that could issue the PTCs. In reality, the vehicle could assume any other legal character such as a limited liability partnership or a company. Plus, in the litigation on this issue for earlier years (which is still ongoing) the tax department has questioned as to whether the trust which is a pooling vehicle for the PTC holders&rsquo; investment is a valid trust. To obviate this uncertainty, the suggestion is that the tax law be amended to refer to a securitisation special purpose vehicle rather than to a securitisation trust.<br /><br />A couple of other issues which mutual funds would expect something from the government would be participation in the increased tax concession (deduction) for savings and certain rationalisation where savings instruments issued by banks, mutual funds and insurance companies are afforded similar tax treatment if they are similar in character.<br /><br /><strong>Insurers and Reinsurers</strong> -&nbsp; Taxation of insurance companies is complex and not easily understood by many. Life insurers are taxed at a concessional rate on the difference between the actuarial surplus determined by the actuary in accordance with the Insurance Act, 1938 (the law prevailing prior to the guidance in this regard provided by the Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority i.e. IRDA) as on the last day of the financial year minus the surplus determined in the same manner on the last day of the immediately preceding financial year. This method of computation was prescribed way back in 1976 post which the accounting practices have changed post the setup of IRDA as the regulator. <br /><br />The accounts now comprise of two separate profit and loss accounts, one where the results of the policyholders&rsquo; funds are shown and the other which shows the results of the shareholders&rsquo; funds. The question that has been the subject matter of uncertainty for the tax officers in the field is whether the results of the shareholders&rsquo; funds are also subject to the concessional tax rate. There are other issues such as what is included in the actuarial surplus and what is not, for example whether payments to policy holders which participate in profits of a policy should be deductible from the actuarial surplus- plus the procedural compliance of deduction of tax at source from policies where the maturity proceeds are not treated as exempt, keep the life insurance companies on their toes. <br /><br />Non- life companies, though their taxable income is based on the profit as per the Profit and Loss Account submitted to the IRDA, a provision drafted when deduction for timing differences did not exist in the Income- tax Act, 1961 (Act) (other than depreciation), now comes in the way of claiming the deduction in the year of compliance with the prescribed requirements. To illustrate, if a taxpayer has not paid bonus to its employees before the due date of filing its income- tax return, but has paid it later, ordinarily it would have been allowed a tax deduction in the subsequent year in which the bonus was actually paid to the employees. By virtue of a peculiar restrictive provision, non-life insurance companies do suffer a disallowance in the year in which the bonus becomes payable but are not able to deduct it in the year in which the bonus is actually paid. This is an anomaly that should be addressed as soon as possible. Reinsurance is an area where no specific tax rules are now codified. Their codification would ease life for the cedents as well as the reinsurers. <br /><br /><strong>Foreign Institutional Investors and Alternate Investment Funds:</strong> These investors have in the recent past been continuously lobbying for address of certain peculiar tax issues and have been to a great extent, successful. Some points in their ask, still remain unaddressed like specific clarifications on General Anti Avoidance Rules, Indirect transfers, etc. These being special subjects of their own are not dealt with here.<br /><br />In conclusion, the financial services Industry has a lot to look up to the government to do for it on the direct tax front. With GST all set to roll, the financial services players hope to start afresh with a clean slate from the date when GST goes live. The addressing of the above enumerated direct tax issues will help them by easing up their operations and will go a step further towards a stable and progressive tax regime. <br /><br /><em><strong>The author is Tax Partner for Financial Services of EY India</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>(Views expressed are personal)</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/bank_Budget_2017_rupee_356x200_3046_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-27 13:45:11</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>