<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rbi-may-hold-rates-this-year-after-25-bps-cut-next-week-nomura_8429881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[RBI may hold rates this year after 25 bps cut next week: Nomura]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Budget is positive for the medium-term inflation outlook which may lead to a 25 bps rate cut at the monetary policy meet next week, but RBI is expected to keep it on hold for the whole of 2017, says a report.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Budget is positive for the medium-term inflation outlook which may lead to a 25 bps rate cut at the monetary policy meet next week, but RBI is expected to keep it on hold for the whole of 2017, says a report.</p>
<p>According to Japanese financial services major Nomura, though the Reserve Bank might go for a policy easing on February 8, it would be a "close call" considering some global factors like higher oil prices and narrowing interest rate differentials.</p>
<p>"On the monetary policy front, with the government sticking to fiscal consolidation and headline CPI likely to undershoot the RBI's March 2017 target of 5 per cent, we are pencilling in a final 25 bps repo rate cut to 6 per cent on February 8," Nomura said in a research note adding with global factors turning negative (higher oil prices, narrowing interest rate differentials), "this is a close call".</p>
<p>Thereafter, Nomura expects both growth and inflation to accelerate, keeping the RBI on hold throughout 2017.</p>
<p>On December 7, the central bank kept interest rate unchanged despite calls for lowering it. It also lowered the economic growth projection by half a percentage point to 7.1 per cent in the first policy review post demonetisation.</p>
<p>The central bank will hold its next monetary policy meet on February 8.</p>
<p>The report further noted that the Budget is positive for the medium-term inflation outlook but the pending increase in housing allowances, likely to be implemented from April 2017, is a near-term upside risk to inflation.</p>
<p>"This is a statistical impact, but higher house rent allowances can add 100-150 bps to headline CPI inflation," it said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/r/RBI_0050_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-05 11:58:13</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>