<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-corporate-tax-cut-likely-warygaar-implementation-says-pwc_8273561.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Corporate tax cut likely; wary of GAAR implementation, says PwC]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Ketan Dalal, Senior Tax Partner at PwC India, said while the general anti-avoidance rule should not be feared as people are already familiar with the contours of it, its implementation needs to monitored closely.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Ketan Dalal, Senior Tax Partner at PwC India, said on Monday that he expects corporate tax rate to be reduced to 27-28 percent in the Union Budget for 2017-18.</p>
<p>Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Dalal said apart from special economic zones (SEZs), the majority of exemptions and tax holidays had been phased out or a roadmap had been put in place to do away with them.</p>
<p>The existing corporate tax rate is 30 percent, which effectively works out to 34.6 percent after surcharge and cess.<br /><br />Dalal also said while the general anti-avoidance rule should not be feared as people are already familiar with the contours of it, its implementation needs to monitored closely.</p>
<p>In his 2015 budget speech, Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley had said corporate tax rate will be reduced from 30 percent to 25 percent over the next four years, together with the phasing out of exemptions and deductions. The Confederation of Indian Industry (CII) has urged a reduction in the corporate tax rate to 18 percent.</p>
<p>Corporate tax accounted for a little less than a fifth (19 percent) of the government's receipts last fiscal whereas income tax receipts accounted for just 14 percent of total receipts.<br /><br /><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Ketan Dalal&rsquo;s interview to Latha Venkatesh &amp; Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong><br /><br /><strong>Sonia: Before I ask you your views on the survey I wanted to just check with you on the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) clarifications that came at the end of December which ruled out tax relief for large foreign portfolio investors (FPIs) under the indirect tax provisions norms. Can we expect any further clarification in the Budget with respect to this?</strong><br /><br />A: That CBDT clarification which came at the end of December as you mentioned was actually interpreting the law as is to today as you know post Vodafone this law was put in place and a 5 percent threshold was later introduced at the offshore level. As I said the CBDT circular was simply outlining and articulating the position in law, but I don&rsquo;t think that the CBDT is saying it can&rsquo;t be changed. <br /><br />In fact lot of representations has been made to say that only 5 percent threshold at the offshore level for transfer is too low. There have been some positive noises coming out from the government end and honestly I do expect an amendment to that. Maybe the 5 will go to 26, we are hopefully even to 51, but I would say minimum to 26 is what I expect.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: From CFO or from a P&amp;L angle what is the most realistic expectations? Realistically will exemptions be phased out and tax rates be brought down as the survey seems to indicate?</strong><br /><br />A: Honestly, other than special economic zone a majority of the exemptions have either been phased out or roadmap has been put in place. So, for example there are exemptions on certain infrastructure elements where they say if you don&rsquo;t start before 31st or you do not commission or do not operationalise before March 31st 2017 then the exemption is gone. Of course if you do that if you do operationalise before it continues for some year. <br /><br />However you do have an end in sight so to speak, so in a sense exemptions phase out roadmap is already there and if you remember when the FM had said that we will announce an exemption phase out and a tax rate phase out he did not say it together but he had implied that. I think it actually was time last year but it is now time that the tax rate phase out is announced. I think we must talk little bit probably about the tax rate because the 25 is inked to 30 whereas including surcharge it is 35, maybe if you have time we can talk about that as well. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: What is the most realistic positive expectation for these CFO&rsquo;s and what is the big thing that you fear? Is it GAAR?</strong><br /><br />A: In terms of the first part of your question, I think the reduction in corporate rates I think we will have to one as I said it is not 30 including surcharges it is 35 percent. I expect it to be something like 27 or 28 percent because I think that is really expected.<br /><br />In terms of what I fear, I think I would not fear the coming in of GAAR because people are already expecting it. However, what I am fearing is the way GAAR would be implemented. I am not saying it is the most feared thing but since you did pick on GAAR I am mentioning really the heart of the matter is implementation rather than the provision which by itself people are now reconciled too.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Why I asked you about the tax googly is last year there was no googly and the market just sprang up. The year before there was a tax googly. So this year what should we be afraid of?</strong><br /><br />A: It depends which angle you are looking at, but if you see from capital market stand point I think you do remember that the PM&rsquo;s speech at the end of December did spook the market when he made a reference which sounded like long-term capital gain, taxation will come back on listed securities so that could be one thing which could spook the market. <br /><br />However, I think we have to look at the whole Budget in totality, so far example if there are positive changes around the corporate tax rates for example as they mentioned, increase in exemption limit etc I think we will have to look at this whole thing as a package and one would find it difficult to look at it in isolation.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget2017_Budget_2017_Feb1_356x200_4203_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-16 15:42:13</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>