<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-experts/budget-2017-infra-mf-should-be-allowed-as-investments-under-sec-54ec_8346141.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Infra MF should be allowed as investments under Sec 54EC]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[To provide further thrust to infrastructure investments, long term capital gains invested in mutual fund schemes with underlying investments in the infrastructure sector and with lock-in period of three years may be covered under section 54EC.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>G Pradeepkumar</strong><br /><em>Union&nbsp;Mutual Fund</em><br /><br />In general, mutual funds as a category offer significant tax efficiency for investors. The treatment of long term capital gains on equity and the exemption to the gains generated by the schemes make mutual funds an attractive investment option. However, certain steps could be taken that could increase the retail participation in mutual funds which in turn could contribute to a more stable capital market in India.<br /><br /><strong>1) ELSS to be allowed exemption under Section 80CCG (Instead of Sec. 80C)</strong>&nbsp;<br /><br />Currently, Equity Linked Savings Schemes (ELSS) investments are exempted under Section 80C of the Income Tax Act wherein deductions up to Rs 150,000 are allowed for investments in various products such as EPF, PPF, NPS, LIP, ULIP, Tax Saving FDs, and home loan repayment etc. In such an over-crowded provision, there is very little scope for investments in ELSS for availing tax benefit amongst Section 80C options. In spite of this, ELSS has been an attractive option for retail investors to avail tax benefits as well as to participate in the capital markets. The average AUM for the month of December 2016 for ELSS schemes was Rs 49,705 crore. This is a stable, long term investment in our equity markets and has contributed to the growth of the markets. Hence, offering an altogether dedicated section for ELSS will make it more attractive and can attract significant retail participation in equity markets in a healthy way. This will bring the much needed domestic funds to the capital markets and also allow retail investors to participate in the growth of the markets.<br /><br /> <strong>2) To increase the deduction limit under Section 80C.-</strong><br /><br />If a separate section cannot be carved out for ELSS, the next best option is for the government to increase the deduction limit under section 80C for specified investments from Rs 1.5 Lakh to Rs 2 Lakh which will be extremely helpful for the salaried class people.<br /><br /><strong>3) Mutual fund units to be included among the specified long-term assets</strong> <strong>qualifying for exemption on long-term capital gains under Sec. 54 EC:</strong><br /><br />The need for more infrastructure financing in our country is well recognised. Mutual funds could play an important role in this. To provide further thrust to infrastructure investments, long term capital gains invested in mutual fund schemes with underlying investments in the infrastructure sector and with lock-in period of three years may be covered under section 54EC along with bonds issued by Rural Electrification Corporation (REC) or the National Highways Authority of India (NHAI) as qualifying investment eligible to claim exemption on long term capital gain.<br /><br /><strong>4) Reduction of securities transaction tax (STT) :</strong><br /><br />The reduction of STT across financial instruments will provide a boost to the capital market and will also lead to significant reduction of transaction costs to investors.<br /><br /><strong>5) Need for harmonizing the tax treatment on investments in debt-oriented MFs and direct investments in debt securities: </strong><br /><br />Minimum holding period for debt mutual funds to qualify for long term capital gains tax was increased from 12 months to 36 months whereas, direct investment in listed debt securities continue to have minimum holding period of 12 months to qualify for long term capital gains tax. This leads to an arbitrage in the market. This can be avoided by introducing a uniform holding period to become eligible for long term capital gains between direct investment in listed debt securities and through debt mutual funds.<br /><br /><strong>6) Rationalisation of short term capital gain tax:</strong><br /><br />Currently short term capital gain is taxed at 15% in respect of equity shares and equity oriented mutual fund schemes. This provision is more beneficial to taxpayers with 20% -30% tax brackets and not to taxpayers with a 10% tax bracket. To rationalise this, short term capital gain tax rate may be redefined as 50% of applicable tax slab to the respective taxpayer.<br /><br /><strong>7) Deduction of dividend received from debt scheme under section 80TTA:</strong><br /><br />Interest earned in saving bank account is deductible under section 80TTA upto Rs. 10,000. Similar treatment may be given to dividend received from debt schemes of mutual fund. <br /><br /><em><strong>The views expressed or statements made in this document are purely the views of the author and do not necessarily represent the views of either the Company or its affiliates. </strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>MUTUAL FUND INVESTMENTS ARE SUBJECT TO MARKET RISKS, READ ALL SCHEME RELATED DOCUMENTS CAREFULLY.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_Budget17_356x200_3456_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-25 20:09:27</Entry_Date><Category>MF Experts</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>