<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-sunset-clause-for-real-estate-should-be-extended_8323961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Sunset clause for real estate should be extended]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In the coming few months, the real estate sector is set to undergo a revolutionary transformation with the onset of Goods and Services Tax (‘GST’) and the Real Estate Regulation Act (‘RERA’), both of which are expected to be significant game changers.  ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>BMR Advisors</strong><br /><br />The real estate sector has been in the limelight of reforms over the last few years with the relaxation of Foreign Direct Investment (&lsquo;FDI&rsquo;) norms, introduction of the Real Estate Investment Trust (&lsquo;REIT&rsquo;) regulations, the Government&rsquo;s mega housing mission 2022 and other initiatives. <br /><br />While one would expect these reforms to have created significant momentum in the sector, the on-ground picture does not seem to reflect it thus far with not a single prospectus for REIT being filed and even the real estate FDI reflecting a declining trend during 2015-16 and 2016-17. <br /><br />The demonetization and proposed amendment to the Benami Properties Act seem to have added to the woes of the industry in the short term, with the housing and office space demands having slacked though there are hopes of these yielding long term benefits with the falling interest rates and anticipated government thrust to the sector. <br /><br />In the coming few months, the real estate sector is set to undergo a revolutionary transformation with the onset of Goods and Services Tax (&lsquo;GST&rsquo;) and the Real Estate Regulation Act (&lsquo;RERA&rsquo;), both of which are expected to be significant game changers. It is anticipated that these changes will result in significant consolidation in the industry with the small unorganized players being washed away and the larger organized players taking greater market share. Especially with GST around the corner, it is the fervent hope that the inefficiencies in the current indirect tax system would be removed, thereby aiding the optimization of cost of construction for the common man. <br /><br />In summary, the industry is all set for greater challenges in financial year 2017-18 and expectedly, the union budget 2017 wish list of the real estate sector is a long and demanding one; a few key ones are noted below.<br /><br /><strong>Key expectations</strong><br /><br /><strong>Policy reforms</strong><br /><br />Housing demand<br /><br />&bull; Easing of policies and giving a thrust to the Real Estate demand creation would be the obvious agenda items to revive the sector. <br /><br />&bull; On the supply side, the industry requires support in terms of rationalization of land acquisition policies, project based financial support from governmental agencies, and extension of special status benefits (some of them being, priority sector status, interest rate subventions, eligibility to access External Commercial Borrowings), which are currently limited to affordable housing projects, to the overall Construction Development sector. <br /><br /><br /><strong>Direct tax</strong><br /><br />Housing demand<br /><br />&bull; The scope of affordable housing projects qualifying for the tax holiday needs to be widened to make it attractive for new project investments. <br /><br />&bull; On the demand side, enhancing the interest deduction on self-occupied properties needs to be considered to help the industry clear surplus inventories. Also, scope of the tax incentive provisions under section 80EE of the ITA needs to be enhanced to incentivize home buyers in the key metros which have the maximum unsold inventories. <br /><br />REITs<br /><br />&bull; While some amendments in the taxation regime for REITs have been announced in the past and SEBI has recently further liberalized the regime for REITs allowing multiple level SPV structures, relaxation of holding under construction properties, increasing the number of sponsors to the REITs amongst other changes. However, there are still some unaddressed concerns in respect of the taxation regime that the government should seek to address in this budget to provide the much required kick-start; the key ones being:<br /><br />- Extending the exemption from Dividend Distribution Tax (&lsquo;DDT&rsquo;) to multiple level SPV structures, given that they are now permitted under the SEBI regulations; <br />- Tax exemption on the transfer of assets by sponsors to the REIT;<br />- Clarity on deductibility of expenses for the REITs; and <br />- Applicability of the tax exemption provisions on contribution of shares of the SPVs by sponsors into the REIT.<br /><br />Joint development contracts and income from commercial properties<br /><br />&bull; Two of the key tax issues which have been hounding the real estate fraternity pertain to taxation of joint development contracts and characterization of income from commercial properties developed and leased. Significant time, efforts and costs are being incurred by the industry to defend litigations on these matters. <br /><br />&bull; Need of the industry is to obtain clarity on these taxation issues by way of necessary amendments or explanations to the existing provisions of the ITA. <br /><br />SEZs<br /><br />&bull; SEZs which were once perceived to be attractive investments by both, investors and tenants, have slowly lost their sheen and demand due to the non-committal tax policies of the government. Removal of the exemption from Minimum Alternate Tax (&lsquo;MAT&rsquo;) in 2012, followed with the sunset of March 2017 for developers and March 2020 for units, has been the major cause for the declining interest. <br /><br />&bull; The industry has been pleading for a relaxation on both aspects. While there seems to be an expectation for rationalization of the MAT provisions in general which if comes through should provide some relief to the real estate sector, the government may also consider extending the sunset to soothe the brunt being faced by the real estate sector. <br /><br /><strong>Indirect tax</strong><br /><br />Joint development contracts and income from commercial properties<br /><br />&bull; On the service tax front, there remains ambiguity on valuation for payment of service tax and timing of such payment, and what is required is a comprehensive set of guidelines after considering the whole gamut of transactions and their different aspects. <br /><br />&bull; Also, a critical deficiency under the current regime is the non-availability of construction related credits for commercial projects, which coupled with higher rate of taxes has an adverse impact on the corporates due to higher rental costs &ndash; the construction related credits should be again made available for commercial projects as the said restriction leads to cascading effect of taxes. <br /><br />Taxability of certain immovable property transactions<br /><br />&bull; While the &lsquo;transfer of title in immovable property&rsquo; is excluded from service tax, there persists confusion as to whether transactions, such as, transfer of development rights in land, agreement of sale, revenue share of developers in plotted developments, transactions in the secondary market by investors, etc, can be treated as transfer of title in immovable property, in sync with business practice, and hence outside the scope of service tax. These aspects need immediate attention to avoid high stake litigation.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget_2016_budget2016_real_estate_smart_city_fiscal_deficit_356x200_2331_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-23 15:55:19</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>