<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-will-it-be-big-bang-ordud-question-divides-market-masters_8389801.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Will it be big bang or a dud? Question divides market masters]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In a panel discussion on CNBC-TV18 Ashok Wadhwa , Group CEO, Ambit said that the market is expecting some tinkering in the long term capital gain (LTCG) tax and might see a 5 percent tax on the same.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Will this be a game-changing Budget or will it have no impact at all, before the announcement of the Union Budget 2017-18 today? Market experts have quite contrary expectations from the the biggest policy event of the year.</p>
<p>In a panel discussion on CNBC-TV18 Ashok Wadhwa, Group CEO, Ambit said that the market is expecting some tinkering in the long-term capital gain tax (LTCG) and might see a 5 percent cess on the same.</p>
<p>He is of the opinion that this will a game-changing Budget.</p>
<p>In the same interview market expert Sameer Arora said that from a market point of view this won't be a 'big bang' Budget.</p>
<p>He said that the capital inflow into domestic mutual funds is supporting the market.</p>
<p>It will be appreciable if corporate taxes are reduced by 1 to 1.5 percent in the Budget, he&nbsp;added.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch video for more...<br /><br /></strong></em></p>
<p>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>
<p><em><strong>&nbsp;</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/BSE_Sensex_Budget_2017_volatile_356x200_0925_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 10:45:00</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>