<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/india-economic-survey-2017-companies-flouting-rules-to-employ-casual-staff_8385041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[India Economic Survey 2017: Companies flouting rules to employ casual staff]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Economic Survey 2016-17 said that multiple labour laws are allowing companies to circumvent laws to engage people on contract and casual basis]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><strong>Moneycontrol bureau<br /></strong></strong><br />The Economic Survey for the ongoing financial year (April-March) points out to a shift in nature of employment towards contract labour. The Survey, tabled today by the government, said employers were circumventing laws to employ casual staff.
<p>"This has adverse implications on the level of wages, stability of employment, social security of employees owing to the temporary nature of employment," the Survey said.</p>
<p>The Survey, prepared by the country's Chief Economic Advisor Arvind Subramanian, blames multiplicity of labour laws and the difficulty in implementing them for employers resorting to contractual employment.</p>
<p>"At present, there are 39 Central labour laws which have been broadly proposed to be grouped into four or five Labour Codes on functional basis with the enactment of special laws," the Survey pointed out.</p>
<p>It also talked about more people going towards secondary and tertiary sectors.<br /><br />The Survey pointed out that states with low levels of unemployment were typically those that had a higher level of manufacturing activity. It suggested linking incentives for states to be linked to number of jobs created as a means to increase employment.</p>
<p>The Survey also called for introducing a biometric system to check teacher absenteeism. It has suggested a pilot project in one district of every state for six months to gauge the effectiveness of the suggested model. This could be expanded to all districts in three years, it said.</p>
<p>As a word of caution, the Survey said the scope of implementation should leave room for flexibility at the local level so the schools did not end up as top driven &lsquo;Model Schools&rsquo;. It suggested following up the biometric system with an evaluation of learning outcomes.</p>
<p>The Survey also pointed out to bridging the gap between infant mortality rates of urban and rural areas--41 per 1000 live births for urban and 25 per 1000 live births for rural. It also drew attention to focusing on states with maternal mortality ratio higher than the national average of 167. These states are Uttar Pradesh, Bihar, Rajasthan, Odisha, Madhya Pradesh.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/l/labour_3905_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 16:17:35</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>