<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-gives-individualsmarginal-hikenet-take-home_8399581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Gives individuals a marginal hike in net take home]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[A small cut in income tax rate and many minor tweaks that make it a fine balancing act.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Mayur Shah</strong><br /><br />The demonetization move last year proved to be a bold and decisive step by the government to eradicate black money, diminish counterfeit currency and curb terrorism. While this initiative led to more money being infused in the banking systems leading to traceable transactions thereby widening the tax net, it did cause chaos and short-term disruption in the economy slowing down demand and consumption. <br /><br />Keeping in mind the need to transform India to a formal economy, the following changes are brought about in the budget:<br /><br /><strong>Personal tax rates</strong><br /><br />In order to move towards a more tax compliant society, widen the tax net and reduce the tax burden on honest taxpayers and salaried class, the finance budget has reduced the tax rate from 10% to 5% for the income slab of INR 250,000 to INR 500,000.Tax rebate has now been reduced to INR 2,500 from the earlier limit of INR 5,000 for individuals earning a taxable income below INR 350,000. <br /><br />Further, to balance reduction in rate of tax, individuals earning income between INR 5 million to INR 10 million will now pay surcharge at10% of tax while those earning over INR10 million continue to pay surcharge at 15%. <br /><br /><strong>TDS on house rent and loss on let out property</strong><br /><br />Loss on let out property upto INR 200,000 will be allowed to be set off against other income. Excess loss can be carried forward for set-off against house property income in the next 8 years. <br /><br />Further, 5% TDS to be deducted by an individual/ HUF paying monthly rent more than INR 50,000 by way of annual TDS compliance, with no requirement to obtain TAN or filing separate return.<br /><br /><strong>Capital gains tax</strong><br /><br />The period of holding for long term capital gains on sale of immovable property is reduced to two years. Cost of acquisition for an asset purchased before 1 April 2001 to be considered as cost or fair market value as on 1 April 2001 whichever is higher. Cost of acquisition to only include capital expenses incurred after 1 April 2001. Similarly, the base for cost inflation index would be taken as 1 April 2001. Exemption from long term capital gains would be allowed on investments in bonds notified by Central Government which are redeemable after three years. <br /><br />For unquoted equity shares, if the fair market value is less than consideration received, such fair market value shall be deemed value of consideration. <br /><br />In order to control sham transactions, long term gains on sale of listed shares will be exempt if security transaction tax (STT) was paid on acquisition made after 1 October, 2004 and on other notified transfers in case of genuine purchase of shares outside the stock market.<br /><br /><strong>Tax returns and processing</strong><br /><br />To bring about simplification in the return filing process, a simple one-pager tax return is introduced for individuals earning non-business taxable income upto INR 500,000. In order to increase tax compliance, a fee of INR 5,000 would be levied on returns filed after due date but before 31 December and INR 10,000 in other cases. This fee would not exceed INR 1,000 for income below INR 500,000. Tax officers would now have to obtain approvals to not issue refunds in cases where scrutiny has been initiated and issuing a refund is detrimental to the interest of revenue.<br /><br />In an effort to move towards technology and reduce human interface in processing of tax returns, time limits for assessment and due dates for filing belated and revised returns are reduced considerably.<br /><br />With a focus to encourage people to voluntarily contribute towards nation building, first time taxpayers will not be subject to scrutiny in the first year unless there is evidence of high value transaction. <br /><br /><strong>National Pension Scheme</strong><br /><br />In line with employed individuals, self-employed individuals can claim deduction of upto 20% of gross total income for contribution to National Pension Scheme subject to the overall limit of INR 150,000. Exemption is available on partial withdrawal from NPS not exceeding 25% of the contribution. <br /><br />Overall, this budget would benefit individuals by a marginal increase in the net take home. While most expectations remain unfulfilled, the finance minister tried to balance these with needs of the exchequer. The government is expected to capitalise the use of digital transactions in the coming months to formalize and increase transparency in the economy. The cash crunch and hardship faced by the common man in the past couple of months would be countered by this progressive budget. <br /><br /><em><strong>(Mayur Shah is a Partner with People Advisory Services at EY India)</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/budget-2017_union_356x200_0305_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 18:56:07</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>