<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/india-economic-survey-2017-increasetax-payers-to-be-biggest-successdemonetisation_8384841.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[India Economic Survey 2017: Increase in tax payers to be biggest success of demonetisation]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Survey has cautioned the government that it should use any windfall arising out of unreturned Rs 500 and Rs 1000 notes for capital expenditure rather than current expenditures like salaries and subsidies]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />The Economic Survey 2017 feels that the long term gains of demonetisation should start trickling in a year from now.<br /><br />Following are the three areas in which the Survey expects a marked improvement.<br />(Edited excerpts from the Survey document)<br /><br />* First, changes in the use of digital payment methods across the three categories of digital access identified earlier, namely, smart phone users, regular phone users and the phoneless, respectively. The early signs are encouraging.<br /><br />* Second, the cash-GDP ratio, which should decline as more saving is channeled through the formal financial system and black money falls. On one estimate of black money, the cash-GDP ratio could decline permanently by about 2 percentage points.<br /><br />* Perhaps the most important marker of success will be taxes. The number of new income tax payers as well as the magnitude of reported and taxable income should go up over time. That will be the surest sign of success.<br /><br />The Survey has cautioned the government that it should use any windfall arising out of unreturned Rs 500 and Rs 1000 notes for capital expenditure rather than current expenditures like salaries and subsidies.<br /><br />&ldquo;Since the windfall will be one-off its use should be one-off and not lead to entitlements that create permanently higher expenditures,&rdquo; the note says.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/t/Tax_government_356x200_4543_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 16:00:48</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>