<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-interview/budget-2017-govt-may-spend-morerural-economy-infra-says-sundaram-mf_8340661.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Govt may spend more on rural economy, infra, says Sundaram MF]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Sunil Subramaniam, CEO, Sundaram Mutual believes 2017 the government will focus on rural economy and infrastructure space in the upcoming Union Budget as they will aim to kick-start the economic growth. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>in the upcoming 2017 Union Budget the government will focus on rural economy and infrastructure with an aim to kick-start the economic growth that had slowed down due to demonetisation and other global factors like Trump's protectionist policies, says Sunil Subramaniam, CEO, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/mutual-funds/amc-details/SN">Sundaram Mutual</a>. &nbsp;<br /><br />Subramaniam&nbsp;sees 60-70 percent chance of deficit spending. Instead of improving the fiscal deficit, the government would&nbsp;use the increased wallet to spend on the economy, he says.</p>
<p>While foreign institutional investors may not react well to this, the government is likely to&nbsp;remain focussed on&nbsp;infrastructure spending. He notes the FII allocation in India has already waned on account of dollar strengthening and shifted more to commodity-intensive markets like Brazil and Russia.</p>
<p>He thinks there is 50 percent chance of easing off of corporate taxes, which are at a high level. Moreover, with the unorganised sector moving towards organised sector, the tax pool will go up, which leaves room for government to ease corporate taxes, says Subramaniam.</p>
<p>Overall, over the long-term he expects the government to do away with tax free avenues.</p>
<p><em><strong>For the entire discussion, watch video</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/i/infrastructure_Budget_2017_rupee_356x200_2459_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-25 13:06:44</Entry_Date><Category>MF-Interview</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>