<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-mission-antyodaya-may-be-nda’s-response-to-upa’s-bharat-nirman_8355981.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Mission Antyodaya may be NDA’s response to UPA’s Bharat Nirman]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance minister Arun Jaitley likely to offer a substantial jump in budget allocations for the rural development ministry; Mission Antyodaya will act as an umbrella programme aimed at offsetting demonetisation’s negative fallout in villages, while also addressing longer-term poverty alleviation issues.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Finance minister Arun Jaitley will likely give a big push in Budget 2017 to &ldquo;Mission Antyodaya&rdquo;&mdash;an ambitious programme aimed at lifting 10 million families out of poverty through a raft of schemes including the Mahatma Gandhi National Rural Employment Guarantee Scheme (MNREGS)</p>
<p>Mission Antyodaya will act as the overall integrated structure for addressing multi-dimensional poverty issues through programmes such as MGNREGS, National Rural Livelihood Mission (NRLM), the Deen Dayal Upadhyaya Grameen Kaushalya Yojana, National Social Assistance Programme, the Pradhan Mantri Gramin Awas Yojana (PMGAY) and the Pradhan Mantri Gram Sadak Yojana (PMGSY) among others.</p>
<p>The economy-wide drain out of the old notes have hurt many landless rural households. The cash-crunch had slowed down production forcing factories and construction companies to retrench semi-skilled and unskilled employees who have returned to villages in search of work.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;Mission Antyodaya&rdquo; push in Budget 2017 is aimed at offsetting demonetisation&rsquo;s negative fallout in villages, while also addressing longer-term poverty alleviation issues.</p>
<p>This will be done through addressing all the parameters of poverty and constantly measuring them on a scale of multiple indices based on data collated through the Socio-Economic Caste Census (SECC).</p>
<p>According to the SECC data, which was released in 2015, nearly one of three 180 families in India&rsquo;s villages&mdash;or about 31.2 percent of the rural population&mdash;are poor with an income hardly enough to buy even the bare essentials.</p>
<p>The SECC analysis used an &ldquo;exclusion-inclusion&rdquo; method count the poor, different from the erstwhile Planning Commission&rsquo;s consumption and calorie intake-based estimates.</p>
<p>A family that owns a land-line phone or a three-room house with concrete walls and roof is automatically excluded from the list of poor people. There were several such threshold indicators that kept a family out of the poor and deprived headcount.</p>
<p>Similarly, there were &ldquo;inclusion&rdquo; parameters, like a household without shelter, that are automatically counted as poor.</p>
<p>The SECC also listed rural households on "deprivation" indicators. A household headed by a woman with no working age man was listed as a deprived household.</p>
<p>The SECC data showed that about 275 million people in rural areas live in &ldquo;deprivation,&rdquo; where people struggle even for subsistence living.</p>
<p>The budget allocation for the rural development ministry, which will pilot &ldquo;Mission Antyodaya,&rdquo; will likely jump by more than 20 percent from Rs 86,000 crore in 2016-17.</p>
<p>Jaitley will likely earmark a record sum for MGNREGS, about 15-20 percent higher than Rs 38,500 crore allocated in 2016-16.</p>
<p>Funds for NRLM will also see a big jump from the current year&rsquo;s Rs 3,000 crore, while allocation from the Pradhan Mantri Gramin Awas Yojana (PMGAY) could see allocations rise to about Rs 20,000 crore from Rs 15,000 crore in 2016-17.</p>
<p>Likewise, the Pradhan Mantri Gram Sadak Yojana could also see its budget allocations rise from Rs 19,000 crore in 2016-17, as also funds for the National Rural Drinking Water Programme and the Swachh Bharat Abhiyan for rural sanitation from the current Rs 5,000 crore and Rs 9,000 crore respectively.<br /><br /></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/m/mnrega_356x200_1804_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-27 15:18:45</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>