<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/india-economic-survey-2017-growth-forecast-indicates-u-shaped-recoverythe-cards_8383261.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[India Economic Survey 2017: 'Growth forecast indicates U-shaped recovery on the cards']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Pranjul Bhandari, Chief India Economist at HSBC, said the Economic Survey’s forecast of a 6.75 percent to 7.5 percent growth in the Indian economy was realistic.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Economic Survey&rsquo;s forecast of a 6.75 percent to 7.5 percent growth in the Indian economy is an indication that recovery post the November note ban will be U-shaped and not V-shaped as was widely expected, said Pranjul Bhandari, Chief India Economist at HSBC.</p>
<p>Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Bhandari said that the midpoint of the projected Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth was 7.1 percent, which she called a &ldquo;realistic number". The economy was expected to grow at 7.6 percent in 2016-17 but was later revised to 7.1% taking into consideration the effects of the government&rsquo;s decision to do away with 86 percent of the currency in circulation last November.<br /><br />Siddhartha Roy, Economic Advisor at Tata Group said the growth forecast displayed a sentiment of cautious optimism, adding that the government was trying to &ldquo;whittle down expectations.&rdquo;<br /><br />Ajit Ranade, Chief Economist at Aditya Birla Group, said that caution should be exercised given the wide range of the GDP estimates, and the fact that oil prices are going up.</p>
<p>Soumya Kanti Ghosh, Chief Economic Advisor at <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/statebankindia/SBI">State Bank of India</a>, said that markets would be happy to note that fiscal deficit is being contained as they are currently expecting it to be on the higher side.</p>
<p>India has budgeted to control fiscal deficit to 3.5 percent of GDP in 2016-17, bring it down to 3 percent next year and maintain it at that level the year after. Pranjul Bhandari said some headroom should be given for the introduction of the Good and Services Tax as it would affect tax collections.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch videos for more.</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/g/GDP_Gross_domestic_price_economy_Growth_inflation_Growth_356x200_5239_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 15:43:38</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,SBI,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>