<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/growth-to-droprebound-likelyh2-2017-nomura_8291881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Growth to drop, but rebound likely in H2 2017: Nomura]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Japanese financial services major has lowered its January-March 2017 GDP forecast to 5.7 percent and that of April-June to 6.8 percent, from 7 percent.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>India's growth numbers are likely to slide in the next two quarters, but a sharp rebound is expected in the second half of 2017 as the demonetisation impact will be transitory and not long lasting, says a Nomura report.</p>
<p>The Japanese financial services major has lowered its January-March 2017 GDP forecast to 5.7 percent and that of April-June to 6.8 percent, from 7 percent.</p>
<p>For 2016-17, Nomura expects GDP growth of 6.5 percent as against 7.6 percent in 2015-16, lower than the official advance estimate of 7.1 percent. For 2017-18, it expects the figure to be at 7.4 percent.</p>
<p>"While we expect a sharp slowdown in the next two quarters, we also expect a V-shaped recovery in the second half of 2017," it said in a research note.</p>
<p>According to Nomura, the factors responsible for a V-shaped recovery in the second half of this year include release of pent-up demand, minimal wealth destruction post demonetisation and fiscal gains for the government that are likely to accrue in 2017-18.</p>
<p>"We expect a sharp rebound due to the release of pent-up demand post-remonetisation, stronger consumption due to large fiscal gains for the government (around 1 percent of GDP), wealth distribution towards poorer households, and sharply lower lending rates," the report noted.</p>
<p>It added that while much of the effect of the cash ban will be transitory, others will be longer lasting -- formalisation of the economy, less corruption, boost to government tax revenues and higher financial savings.</p>
<p>"Over time, we expect these benefits to outpace the short-term growth disruptions," it added.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the International Monetary Fund has revised India's GDP growth forecast on note ban woes by one percentage point to 6.6 percent for the current fiscal.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/g/GDP_Gross_domestic_price_economy_Growth_inflation_Growth_356x200_5239_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-18 12:30:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>