<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-fm-may-widen-google-tax-net-to-include-songs-games-films_8329401.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: FM may widen 'Google Tax' net to include songs, games, films]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Equalisation levy of 6 percent, introduced in 2016-17, may be widened to account for downloading of songs, books and other online consumption such as news and the movies; rate likely to be kept unchanged]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gaurav Choudhury<br /></strong><strong>Moneycontrol<br /></strong><br />The government may spread the net of the Equalisation Levy (EQL) or the so-called &ldquo;Google Tax&rdquo; wider, bringing in its ambit a raft of activities including online sale of goods and services, copying or downloading of software, books, songs, games and movies, and streaming of news.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley may announce new rules in the Budget 2017.</p>
<p>An EQL of 6 percent, charged only on online advertisements, was first introduced last year aimed at nullifying the advantage of foreign ecommerce firms, 'without a physical presence in India'&nbsp;over its local competitors.</p>
<p>The EQL is currently limited to business-to-business transactions, primarily affecting internet giants such as Google and Facebook that earn significant revenues from online advertisements.</p>
<p>A Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) committee on taxation of e-commerce companies has suggested an EQL of 6-8 percent for business-to-business deals on 13 broad categories of services based on the Organisation of Economic Cooperation&rsquo;s and Development (OECD&rsquo;s) Base Erosion and Profit Shifting guidelines (BEPS).</p>
<p>Jaitley, however, is unlikely to raise the rate from the existing 6 percent.</p>
<p>Under current rules, an Indian client has to &ldquo;withhold&rdquo; 6 percent as equalisation levy if it makes a payment of more than Rs 1 lakh a year to an overseas technology company.</p>
<p>This is done in a bid to tap a tax on the foreign ecommerce companies&rsquo; income earned from clients in India.</p>
<p>According to the government, in the digital domain, businesses may be conducted without regard to national boundaries and may dissolve the link between an income-producing activity and a specific location.</p>
<p>These new business models have created new tax challenges. The typical direct tax issues relating to e-commerce are the difficulties of characterising the nature of payment and establishing a nexus or link between a taxable transaction, activity and a taxing jurisdiction, the difficulty of locating the transaction, activity and identifying the taxpayer for income tax purposes.</p>
<p>The government has earned more than Rs 100 crore from the equalisation levy so far in 2016-17.</p>
<p>BEPS norms, which India has adopted, were announced by the OECD countries in October 2015 and are aimed at reducing tax evasions and plug loopholes in rules and laws among countries.</p>
<p>Globally, such tax evasion by transcontinental companies are estimated to result in tax revenue loss of USD100 billion (Rs 6.8 lakh crore) annually.</p>
<p>OECD&rsquo;s BEPS norms have fixed a minimum revenue threshold of 750 million euros (about Rs 5,500 crore). Companies that have global revenues exceeding this level will have to be migrated to the new accounting and disclosure norms.<strong> <br /></strong></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/t/tax_356X200_0900_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-24 10:11:08</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>