<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-experts/budget-2017-transfer-between-optionsa-mf-scheme-should-be-tax-exempt_8332181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Transfer between options of a MF scheme should be tax exempt]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Long term capital gain tax rules may change and dividends may become taxable.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Abhinav Angirish</strong><br /><em>Investonline.in</em><br /><br />Budget 2017 is a unique event in its own way. While many think that it is important because it comes after the decision of demonetization, it is not entirely true. It is the government&rsquo;s stance to make policy decisions as and when required and not to wait for budget that makes us believe the proverbial &ndash; this time it is different. While the pessimists may frown on the slowing economic growth, the government has decided to change a sea change in our country and has unfurled a battery of changes that has accentuated the expectations of the common man. <br /><br />Here are a few of them -<br /><br /><strong>Digitalization of all processes</strong><br /><br />With the demonetisation announcement in November leading to massive inconvenience for the common man, we expect all registration processes and renewal process to be digitalized in the upcoming Budget leading to faster and improved growing environment.<br /><br /><strong>Speed-up the consumption cycle</strong><br /><br />At the moment, the immediate priority of the government should be to revive the consumption demand which can be done by huge public expenditures in infrastructure. This will increase demand for jobs and raw materials and which at-last will increase consumption cycle.<br /><br /><strong>Modification in income tax slabs and rates</strong><br /><br />Everyone is expecting the government to increase the tax exemption slab from Rs 2.5 lakh to Rs 3.5 lakh after the massive inconvenience for the common man during demonetisation. Also, a higher tax exemption slab and a reduction in tax rates may encourage more people to file taxes. Currently, only around 5.5% of India&rsquo;s population files taxes.<br /><br /><strong>Strict rules for cash withdrawal</strong><br /><br />We expect prevailing cash withdrawal limits to prevail for some time now. As more cash will be made available, then the cash withdrawal limits will be relaxed further. We also expect government to impose rules for cash withdrawal where reasons will be asked for any cash withdrawal above a certain amount.<br /> <br /><strong>Lower tax rates for everyone</strong><br /><br />Lower tax rates brings in greater revenues as they broaden tax base. One of the reasons for this is that people will stop evading taxes if they find the risk unworthy.<br /><br /><strong>Service Tax</strong><br /><br />Service tax limit may be enhanced to 15.5% + .5% +.5% from the existing 14% + .5% +.5%. This move is quite possible as finance ministry would want to move the tax rate close to GST which is expected to roll out this year by July 2017.<br /><br /><strong>Increase in taxes on capital gains from equity investments</strong><br /><br />There is widespread speculation that the government, in Union Budget 2017-18, may introduce new rules for taxing capital gains from investments in stocks. Currently, there is no tax for capital gains earned from equity that have been held for a year or more. This minimum holding period, may be raised to two years. There is also no limit on the tax-free gains, which might be capped at a high amount.<br /><br /><strong>Removal of taxes on switching between schemes:</strong><br /><br />At the moment switching from one option to another option even though within same mutual fund scheme is considered as &ldquo;transfer&rdquo; as per I-T act 1961 and is liable to pay capital gain tax. Since it is a switch within same scheme it should not be regarded as &ldquo;transfer&rdquo; and should be exempt from capital gain tax. When you are just transferring your investments from one option to another doesn't earn any capital gain in investor&rsquo;s hands.<br /><br /><strong>Tax on dividend</strong><br /><br />There is a strong possibility to tax the dividend earned on stocks and MFs which is currently exempt. This move is quite possible considering Finance Ministry&rsquo;s ongoing effort to make investments at par with bank deposits.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_demonitisation_356x200_5312_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-24 15:16:44</Entry_Date><Category>MF Experts</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>