<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/market-rally-could-stretch-further-as-budget-nears-udayan_8272341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Market rally could stretch further as Budget nears: Udayan]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Post the Budget there is no rush for foreign money to flood in to the market, instead even if the source of FII selling dries up and domestic investors remain emboldened, encouraged due to the Budget provisions, there is a reasonable chance that the market might have put in a bottom, he further added.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The recent rally in the Indian equity market is not surprising and looking at the momentum the upswing could further stretch near the Budget announcement, says CNBC-TV18's Udayan Mukherjee.</p>
<p>Foreign institutional investor (FII) selling in emerging markets (EMs) has been relentless recently and among EMs, fund managers are trying to figure out which are expensive and which deserve to be expensive, he said.</p>
<p>Post the Budget, there is no rush for foreign money to flood in to the market and instead even if the source of FII selling dries up and domestic investors remain emboldened &mdash; encouraged due to the Budget provisions &mdash; there is a reasonable chance that the market might have put in a bottom, he further added.</p>
<p>On the rally in the metal space, he said that the sector remains volatile and advised investors to buy on dips and not chase the price for metal stocks.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Udayan Mukherjee's interview to Latha Venkatesh, Sonia Shenoy and Anuj Singhal on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Give us your thoughts on <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software/infosys/IT">Infosys</a> and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software/tataconsultancyservices/TCS">Tata Consultancy Services</a> (TCS), both came out with numbers over the last couple of days and the market reacted quite negatively. Of course for TCS, it was more a case of N Chandrasekaran moving out but your thoughts on TCS and Infosys numbers?</strong><br /><br />A: I thought Infosys was quite unexciting. The stock perhaps came off because it had moved up a bit before the results. However, I didn't see too many analyst upgrades coming in post the results. The topline guidance was very muted and it is a testimony for the kind of low expectations that we have in the market right now. I read a lot of analysts calling it a solid result when they had reported a decline in their dollar revenue and had marked down their full year revenue forecast.<br /><br />So expectations are probably at their lowest for Infosys in many quarters now and that is the only silver lining that I can see. Otherwise the stock&rsquo;s valuations are not expensive but if you look at most of the analysts forecast, they are talking about around 9 percent growth in earnings per share, which is the core metric for 2018 and 2019. So I find it difficult to get terribly excited by a single digit growth in EPS which most people are factoring in. So it is more a valuation play rather than a growth play at this point in time. So it is unexciting but having said that, I should also say that it is possible that Infosys has made its valuation bottom over the last three months or so, it has been grinding lower for a while now and I suspect it will probably trade in a range between Rs 900 and Rs 1,050 for the foreseeable future in bouts of optimism, it might go up to those 1,040-1,050 kind of levels and pessimism might drag it back to that lower end of around Rs 900. But it will be pinging between these kind of levels having probably already made its valuation low.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: What about TCS? That is the more interesting stock. Besides the numbers, change in management, do you think that it will trade at a premium to Infosys at all?</strong><br /><br />A: Time will tell. It is difficult to say. The proof of the pudding is in the eating. We can speculate when the cows come home about whether Gopinathan can do a Chandra over the next three-four years or whether one should be right in being nervous and anxious at this point because it is a point of transition in many ways for the It sector and whether Chandra&rsquo;s departure at this point in time leaves the company vulnerable. You could argue both ways about which way TCS investor should move right now.<br /><br />In its favour, I should submit that TCS being the biggest cash cow of the group, it is most unlikely that Chandra will take his eye off the ball at least for the next year or a year and a half because this is the business that he understands, it delivers most of the group&rsquo;s profits and I think he is more than anybody else would be keenly aware that this is a point of transition. So I don&rsquo;t think he will let the ball slip on TCS quite so easily till the other group companies stabilise and till the transition at TCS is complete. These are blue-blooded managers, they are aware of all these transition risks. So I would not be too pessimistic with Chandra at the helm.<br /><br />Had he moved out of TCS and moved out of the group quite a big hit but his stewarding hand will still be around and his mentorship will ensure that TCS -- the boat is not rocked too alarmingly.<br /><br />On his impact on the rest of the group, again you can argue both ways and whether they can stand up to the towering presence of Ratan Tata and question some of the more debatable strategic decisions that have been taken in the group but having seen how this Cyrus Mistry episode has panned out, I think the Tata group did not want an outsider who would raise more questions and rock the boat even more. We need some stability and calm at Bombay House right now and Chandra is probably the man.<br /><br />So TCS probably gets into a bit of a trading range for the next couple of quarters, till we get evidence that all is well and nothing is amiss at the group. So I think it calls probably for a rangebound kind of a stock for the next few quarters.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: What about the market as a whole, how have you read the tenure so far and as we head into the Budget, there are so many variables, lot of sectors rallying, expectations are high, how should the street approach it?</strong><br /><br />A: This rally has not been very surprising. We spoke about the possibility of such a rally time before last we spoke because of Budget expectations and the global backdrop. My expectation was that the Nifty might rally up to these kind of levels but now looking at the momentum in the market, it is conceivable that around the Budget, you could stretch this rally.<br /><br />With a pause, last couple of days we have seen some domestic selling, so it is conceivable that people might be feeling a little vertigo because we have come very quickly from 7,900 to 8,400. That is not a very small rally and lot of midcaps have come up quite significantly. So there could be some profit taking but before the Budget -- which is just a couple of weeks away -- expectations might still remain quite warm about the kind of moves that the government might take.<br /><br />Let us hope, many of those things come through. Maybe just as we get close to the Budget, it is possible that we get a little bit of nervousness creeping into the market on three accounts &ndash; one is the capital gains tax, you will recall that last time too before the Budget, that dominated a large part of the discourse and created some kind of nervousness in the market.<br /><br />Finally, it did not come through but this time maybe the chances are higher. So that will come back on the discussion table as we get closer to the event. You could get some fears on the FII taxation front, which is also doing the rounds and if we don&rsquo;t get clarifications leading up to the Budget, that could create a bit of a nervousness.<br /><br />Finally what the Budget document or speech might hold in terms of whether the government&rsquo;s crackdown on black money will continue with the same intensity during the course of the year and if the answer to that is yes, that might have growth implications and market implications. So these things may also come back to create or inject some degree of uncertainty or nervousness into the market and therefore volatility. So maybe a bit of extension of the rally and then some give and then depending on the Budget we will see whether we can hold around these kind of levels, we need to go back to 8,000 or we can rally on to 8,700 kind of levels too.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: It is more the tax googlies rather than anything that will hold the key in the Budget?</strong><br /><br />A: Nothing else moves the needle too much. The rest is as you have seen over the Budgets down the year, every Budget you can say this time it is different but you will know as well as I do that many of these matters pertain to sentiment. It is all very fine to talk about firing up the rural economy, galvanising infrastructure but token changes of 8-10 percent on last year&rsquo;s outlay tweaking around some of these vehicles for putting money in, I don&rsquo;t think move the needle too much. Given our taxable base also or the base of taxation in the country -- maybe there would be some changes in income tax but given how few of us pay taxes, will it be big enough to galvanise consumption in a country where people hardly pay taxes, I don&rsquo;t know.<br /><br />The date might spark a rally but we have to look through that fine print and see how much of that is sentiment and how much of that changes growth trajectory and earnings trajectory. That is the yardstick, which I always use to just ask a lot of the heads of research after the day of the Budget -- did you have reason to change your earnings forecast for next year or the year after that because of what the Budget document had and I find in most years, the changes are minimal if any. So we will have to see whether materially things change but sentiment will be quite key because of these taxation changes one way or the other so we need to be cognisant of those.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: We have seen return of FII flows into emerging markets, not yet in India, but even in India, selling has come down. If we do not have these googlies post Budget or in the Budget, is there a reasonable chance that we will get a lot of inflows because the sentiment may have turned towards emerging market over the last couple of weeks?</strong><br /><br />A: It is a little better, so there is a bit of a mean reversion that is happening towards emerging markets, because in the last two or three months the selling has been quite relentless. Within emerging markets, fund managers are trying to figure out, which are expensive, which deserve to be expensive, where there are local issues which countries are wading through like we are at this point in time. So, we do not need a lot of money to come in post the Budget. If only the selling were to dry up completely and you get days of Rs 100 crore or Rs 200 crore plus, you do not need billions of dollars immediately into the market.<br /><br />But if the source of selling dries up and domestic investors remain quite encouraged and emboldened because of the Budget provisions and there are none of these tax things that one spoke about, then there is a reasonable chance that the market might have put in a bottom.<br /><br />With one caveat. I know there is a lot of optimism right now, after looking at some of the economic numbers and earnings numbers that demonetisation has not scarred the economy or earnings as much as people thought or feared earlier. The January-March, current quarter that we are going through would be a far better indicator of the what the reality on the ground is and if in April, we find that the impact has not been severe, we could say with a fair degree of certainty then that the markets might have put in a bottom or a double bottom around 7,900.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: A quick comment on how to approach metal names, the big gainers this month.</strong><br /><br />A: Some positive news is coming in because the news from China has improved. The capacity closures there are clearly going to help prices. So, you could see metals being supported. They have gone up quite a lot, they are trending nicely, there is momentum out there, so stocks like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/steel-large/tatasteel/TIS">Tata Steel</a> and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/aluminium/hindalcoindustries/HI">Hindalco</a> among the blue chips probably might give you more during the course of 2017. The only thing, which I would point out is that metal stocks by nature are quite volatile. Therefore, you should probably wait for dips to accumulate them.<br /><br />I will give you two examples. Given that Tata Steel has been a strongly trending stock, at least twice in the last one month, the stock has gone back to Rs 380, now at Rs 450. So, you are getting those opportunities or those dips to buy into given that it is a strong stock. Even Hindalco, in the last 10-15 days has gone back to Rs 150. So, buy dips, do not chase the price.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: I wanted your thoughts on how to approach the financials as well because I know that the first part of earnings season generally is clean. We have seen good numbers from <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/indusindbank/IIB">IndusInd Bank</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/dcbbank/DCB01">DCB Bank</a>, etc. But the important takeaway from what Romesh Sobti told us is that there was no impact of demonetisation, at least in this quarter on their books. Do you think that will be taken well by the street and more upside seen on that stock perhaps?</strong><br /><br />A: IndusInd Bank was an extraordinary set of numbers, I thought. In an environment like this to come out with that kind of number was nothing short of spectacular. So, let us see what the rest of the banks do because not only are the demonetisation led issues prominent in the sector for this quarter at least for half of the sector, there might be some legacy asset quality issues, including the one, which is reporting this week, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/axisbank/AB16">Axis Bank</a>. So, let us see how those play out because those are not strictly to do with demonetisation per se.<br /><br />All of you have seen the credit growth numbers, which have come in since demonetisation. So aggregate, as a sector, I do not think banking will deliver great numbers -- then something is wrong. Either the credit growth numbers are wrong or the banks are not reporting something right. So I do not know whether the entire sector will report great numbers. But, the one thing, which I was trying to allude to earlier is that take what you are seeing this quarter in terms of results with a pinch of salt because there have been a lot of irregular transactions in practically every sector in the current quarter, which will get normalised in the January-March quarter.<br /><br />A simple example is if people had black money or cash with them, old currency notes, they might have preponed purchases, they might have spent the money rather than go out and deposit in banks, which might show up in various ways as artificial demand spurts in the current quarter. So, because the event was so unexpected, the kind of outcomes that you see for November-December might also be aberrations in many senses. But December 31 was a sunset for all of that. So, January-March, good or bad, will give you a much more pure analysis of what demonetisation means for the economy and earnings.<br /><br />So, this is the current quarter where you will get a much better assessment and will be able to judge whether it was good or bad or ugly and then take a call. The market will come around. It will not wait for April to see the results, it will get enough feedback from the street or from companies to make up its mind by the time the Budget is over as we wade into February and the market will make up its mind then. But this quarter&rsquo;s numbers, do not get too despondent or do not get too excited by the numbers you see because the numbers might frankly be a bit misleading.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: That is a fair point though -- the trade numbers that came for December were very good. Now, there it is not too much of hanky-panky, I would think. They were excellent, some of them. Over November, the readymade garments, textiles, gems and jewellery, all of them showed almost no impact at all and of course, destination countries have also been better off now because of the higher crude prices. So, that gave me the sense that perhaps the demonetisation blues that we saw anecdotally, were overstated. You do not feel that way?</strong><br /><br />A: I do not know. Every piece of data, anecdotal evidence, etc you could swing either way depending on what data you are seeing and who you are talking to. So, my sense is in this, it might be best to see how things pan out. We are almost in the middle of this quarter. We do not have to wait too much longer and I do not think stock prices or markets will run away to the extent that if you do not buy today, taking a call on demonetisation impact, you will never be able to catch the bus. There are enough uncertainties around for the markets to be anchored around these kind of levels. So, I would rather wait to see rather than take a call or a leap on what the impact has been. If it has not been that bad and India has moved on, fantastic! Then 7,900, at least locally, would certainly be a bottom and we can all celebrate. But, I would say let us hold the bubbly for a few more weeks.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/BSE_SENSEX_Nifty_Stock_Market_Sensex_Sensex_356x200_2423_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-16 10:14:44</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,IT,TCS,TIS,H,IIB,DCB01,UTI10,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>