<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-govt-to-launch-swayam1500-courses-for-students_8390901.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Govt to launch SWAYAM with 1500 courses for students]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In his Budget speech, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said that to leverage Information Technology, a new platform called Swayam will be launched. Students will have access to more than 1500 courses. The government will also tie-up with DTH channels for the same. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /><br /></strong>The Budget Estimates for the education sector have been&nbsp;pegged at Rs 79,685 crore for 2017-18. The government has proposed to introduce annual learning outcome with an aim to encourage and emphasis on science education and innovation. <br /><br />In his Budget speech, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said that to leverage Information Technology, a new platform&nbsp;called SWAYAM will be launched. Students will have access to more than 1500 courses. The government will also tie-up with DTH channels for the same. <br /><br />"SWAYAM platform for free of cost digital learnings launched to bridge the digital drive for students, especially girls, who have not been able to join the mainstream of the knowledge economy," Finance Minister said.<br /><br />A skill acquisition and knowledge fund called Sankalp, at the cost of Rs 4000 crore, will be formed to enhance market skills. On Skill India, the government will promote the Pradhan Mantri Kaushal Kendra to 600 districts and will set up centers.<br /><br />The government has also proposed to form a National Testing Agency, which will conduct entrance exams like JEE and CAT and subsequently reduce pressure from other boards like Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE).<br /><br />Jaitley also proposed establishing 100 international skill centers in 2017-18. <br /><br />The government also plans to undertake reforms in the UGC, and will identify colleges on basis of ranking and accordingly, give autonomous status. <br /><br />A special scheme for employment in textile has been launched already. Similar schemes will be launched for leather and footwear sectors also.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_356x200_4046_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 12:01:15</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>