<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/budget-2017-game-over-for-defaulters-like-mallya-govt-plans-tougher-laws_8398901.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Game over for defaulters like Mallya? Govt plans tougher laws]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[More trouble could be in store for Kingfisher Airlines promoter Vijay Mallya as Finance Minister Arun Jaitley looks at legislative changes to bring to book loan defaulters absconding the country.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Beena Parmar</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />More trouble could be in store for Kingfisher Airlines&nbsp;promoter Vijay Mallya as Finance Minister Arun Jaitley looks at legislative changes to bring to book loan defaulters absconding the country.<br /><br />In his Budget speech today, the FM said that the government is &nbsp;&ldquo;considering introduction of legislative changes, or even a new law, to confiscate the assets of such persons located within the country, till they submit to the jurisdiction of the appropriate legal forum&rdquo;.<br /><br />In the past there have been instances of big-time offenders, fleeing the country to escape the reach of law.&nbsp;<br /><br />"We have to ensure that the law is allowed to take its own course," Jaitley said.<br /><br />Since 2013, former liquor baron Mallya has been in the media glare after his financially troubled airline defaulted on dues worth Rs 9000 crore including loans to 17 lenders and penalties to service tax department.<br /><br />Last year in March, Mallya fled to the UK as the Supreme Court suspended his passport while other legal agencies including the CBI (Central Bureau of Investigation) and Enforcement Directorate made life more miserable for him. &nbsp;CBI issued a non-bailable warrant last year while&nbsp;ED, which has attached some of its assets, is looking to file a charge cheet.&nbsp;<br /><br />Mallya is now fighting the case from London.<br /><br />Large corporate borrowers have defaulted on loans to banks taking advantage of the legal loopholes of the system. This has left banks under heavy bad loans thereby impacting their profitability.<br /><br />The Budget also announced listing and trading of Security Receipts issued by a securitisation company or an asset reconstruction company (ARC) under the SARFAESI Act to be permitted in SEBI registered stock exchanges.<br /><br />&ldquo;This will enhance capital flows into the securitization industry and will particularly be helpful to deal with bank NPAs,&rdquo; the announcement said.<br /><br />At present, banks sell their bad loans to securitisation companies or ARCs against security receipts which can be monetised only after a certain period.<br /><br />]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/v/Vijay_Mallya_Kingfisher_Mallya_london_356x200_0426_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 17:49:28</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>