<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/international-markets/budget-2017-india-needs-to-keep-its-taxes-competitive-says-limaberdeen_8305181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: India needs to keep its taxes competitive, says Lim of Aberdeen]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[India needs to keep its taxes competitive with those of others in the region but the pace of competitiveness is important because that attracts foreign investors, said Adrian Lim  of Aberdeen Asset Management.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Hope it balances social &amp; fiscal discipline with no negative surprises.</p>
<p>Budget 2017 should not have any negative surprises and should balance both social and fiscal discipline is the word coming in from Adrian Lim of Aberdeen Asset Management.</p>
<p>He expects consistency from the Budget on February 1.</p>
<p>Demonetisation was a very interesting exercise and most watchers of the Indian equity market believe it has a good motive which will play over the longer-time. <br /><br />Although in the short to near-term one could see some pain in spaces like consumer discretionary and consumer-retail which were cash-driven, says Lim in an interview with CNBC-TV18's Latha Venkatesh.</p>
<p>It does not hurt the long-term growth story of India but going forward as well execution remains key. Government should be applauded for this move, says Lim.</p>
<p>With regards to goods and services tax (GST), he believes the key benefits of that will pan out in 3-5 years.</p>
<p>On the taxation front, he says India needs to keep its taxes competitive with those of others in the region but the pace of competitiveness is important because that attracts foreign investors.</p>
<p>However, putting the CBDT circular on indirect tax in abeyance shows that the government is keenly looking at FII issues, which is very encouraging.</p>
<p>Talking about the sectors and stocks that the house likes, he says they will continue to hold <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software/tataconsultancyservices/TCS">TCS</a> and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software/infosys/IT">Infosys</a> form IT space because they are in good position to tackle changes in US policy.</p>
<p>From the cement space, they like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/diversified/grasimindustries/GI01">Grasim</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/cement-major/ultratechcement/UTC01">UltraTech</a>. The house looks at companies that have good managements like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personalcare/emami/E06">Emami</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/cigarettes/itc/ITC">ITC</a>, Godrej and some multinationals like Lever (<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personalcare/hindustanunilever/HU">HUL</a>).</p>
<p>From the financials, he expects <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/hdfcbank/HDF01">HDFC Bank</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/kotakmahindrabank/KMB">Kotak Mahindra Bank</a> to outperform. Slower pace in credit growth witnessed in the space is not due to note ban, says Lim.<br /><br /><strong><em>Below is the transcript of Adrian Lim&rsquo;s interview to Latha Venkatesh on CNBC-TV18.</em><br /> <br />Q: First up, what is your view of India, coming as it does, after demonetisation? Do you think it has jarred the India story for the near-term? Just, what is its impact on Indian equities?<br /> <br /></strong>A: The demonetisation exercise was an interesting exercise. If you ask most economists and most watchers of the Indian market, not just the economics, but the social side. What it is trying to achieve is actually pretty good over the long-term. The issue and the main challenge is that there are not many precedents for something like this and execution is pretty important. It is also important to keep quiet about it. So the amount of plans that can be made ahead of the execution of an exercise like this quite constrained as well. The short-term and the near-term pain has been quite acute. And if you look at the economic indicators, not all of the impact, both negative and positive are measurable just yet. So, we still continue to monitor the situation, but the end objective is a good one. That is something that the government should be applauded on. But, they need to make this work. And at the moment, there is still quite a bit of pain.<br /> <strong><br />Q: So, at the moment, as a long-term India investor, has it altered your view of the India story or has it altered your view of any of the sectors? If yes, how?<br /> <br /></strong>A: Over the short-term there are some things that we remain watchful of. Where you have big ticket consumption items, we would not be surprised if an extended period of softness or weakness extends itself. This could be in the consumer discretionary items. This could be where there is a lot of cash driven transactions like consumer retail, but over the long-term, the story remains intact. <br /><br />We expect from India, a continued trajectory of growth over the long-term. As its middle class expands and as its government reforms not all of these reforms would be smooth. The other challenge over last year has been implementation of goods and services tax (GST). <br /><br />Having a statute sign in was very important. It is something that the country has been trying to do for a really long time. But, the key benefits will be extracted over the next 3-5 years. And it is in the details in the committees that form and govern the GST structures that most of the value would be extracted. So reforms, once in a while, you have some short-term pain, but for us, as you say, we are focused on the long-term and that trajectory remains attractive to us as long-term investors.<strong><br /> <br />Q: Let me come straight away to the Budget. Are there any specific expectations? What would you want or not want in the Budget?<br /> <br /></strong>A: The Budget is always quite tricky. In India, there are a lot of social issues to balance as well as a lot of issues on fiscal discipline to sort out as well. What we have expected over all these years is what we look for is consistency, what we look for is reasonable levels of consultations with business, with investors, and not too many surprises. Demonetisation was a surprise, but we can understand the reasons for an exercise like that being kept relatively quiet until it is to be done. In terms of the Budget itself, as long as there are no negative surprises, quite a lot of reform can also be announced outside the Budget season. So, we do pay attention to what the government tries to do, but that has to be over the cost, that is a continuous exercise. It is not something that we pay attention to just during Budget season, but throughout the whole course of its term.<strong><br /> <br />Q: There is a widespread expectation that there should be personal tax cuts or corporate tax cuts and or corporate tax. Will any of these alter the way you pick share and how much of it you will buy?<br /> <br /></strong>A: The corporate tax cuts was an idea that was mooted some years back and it has come from the thinking that India needs to look at everything, not just corporate tax cuts, but in the way, for example, the different taxes and subsidies and taxes are implemented as well. And it cannot look at these issues in isolation. Where India goes on corporate tax cuts has to do a lot also with where the region goes on corporate tax and India is very aware that it needs to be competitive. It needs to achieve the social gains that it sets itself out to do. The government needs to do that. But, ultimately, it needs to be competitive against other countries within the region as well. And although the long-term trajectory is driven by the need to be competitive, the pace, India has to decide on the pace of that development. That is something that we will watch with some interest.<strong><br /> <br />Q: One more tax question, there was a direct tax department&rsquo;s circular on how to tax indirect transfer of assets in India and some foreign institutional investors (FII) complained that it logically would lead to double or triple taxation of foreign investors. That circular has been held in abeyance just recently. Any comments on that?<br /> <br /></strong>A: We watched that space very closely. Just like corporate tax cuts, as foreign investors, we owe a duty of care to our investors to make sure that we invest in markets that are structured competitively. The fact that the circular was kept in abeyance for further study was very encouraging. It proves that the Indian authorities do listen to feedback and do consider and make sure that all interests are kept in balance. When the circular came out, there was still some unclear details on some of the implementation, finer points of implementation, so those are some things that need to be ironed out. But we welcome this dialogue. We do have people within Aberdeen that pay attention to this and it is something that we are watchful of to make sure that we know what we are doing, for our investors, are right.</p>
<p><strong>Q: Finally I wanted to ask you about how emerging markets and in particular India will fare in terms of fund flows. What&rsquo;s your best guess in 2017 the latter part of 2016 saw considerable outflows from EMs in general and India in particular, how will at least the first half of 2017 fare?</strong></p>
<p>A: I think sentiment is very much driven by international or global events. North America is something that and what Trump said in terms of economic policy is something that is foremost on people&rsquo;s mind. The actual impact is difficult to predict, but what he says or what he tweets that does definitely impact sentiment in global markets. The pace and the aggression of the Brexit exercise is also something that people pay attention to. It is often seen as an indicator of what Europe might do -- although I am not sure that is a fair surrogate. I suppose the Germany&rsquo;s elections that are coming up is also another key issue.</p>
<p>We basically have a lot of eyes when in emerging markets a lot of sentiment is driven by what happens in the developed world -- how protectionist their governments would be or how succession is their governments would be. I am afraid that is something that will continue to dominate sentiment in 2017. We will expect that volatility -- I think it is difficult to say that whether for the full year we will see net inflow or outflow into emerging market space. What we can do is we can just make sure that we pick companies and businesses that are smart and relatively resilient against these volatility and see it through the medium term.</p>
<p><em><strong>&nbsp;</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget2017_Feb1_356x200_4453_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-19 19:58:43</Entry_Date><Category>International Markets</Category><sc_id>,TCS,IT,UTC,GI01,ITC,E05,HL,KMF,HDF01,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>