<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/what-to-expect-about-gstunion-budget-2017_8345421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[What to expect about GST in Union Budget 2017?]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[A clear road map for implementation of GST should be announced.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Harpreet Singh</strong><br /><br />Number nine proved auspicious for the Goods and Service Tax (GST) Council as their ninth meeting turned out to be one of the most fruitful by resolving the long pending issue of dual control of assessee&rsquo;s, thus paving the way for smooth implementation of GST. <br /><br />With the Honb&rsquo;le Finance Minister, Arun Jaitley announcing 1 July 2017 as a more realistic date for implementation of GST, it is imperative that the Union Budget 2017-18 (Budget 2017-18) should be used as a preparation ground for the significant change to be achieved soon.<br /><br />Further, as the broad contours of GST are known and finalized, it is logical to slowly start transitioning towards the new regime rather than changing in one go and what better way than to initiate the process with the coming Budget. Thus, key GST expectations from Budget 2017-18 are:<br /><br />First, a clear road map for implementation of GST should be announced. The road map should spell out the following next steps:<br /><br />Likely date of passage of the SGST, CGST and IGST laws in the Parliament <br />Release of the GST rate schedules <br />Finalization of GST rate on services <br />Release of GST Rules including those on valuation and<br />Release of GST FAQs etc.<br /><br />Second, the current tax rates could be converged to the likely tax rates under GST which could mean increase in the Service Tax rate by few percentage points to bring it closer to the likely GST rate of 18%. <br /><br />Convergence of rate could also mean merging the current cess and surcharges on services such as &lsquo;Krishi Kalyan Cess&rsquo; or the &lsquo;Swach Bharat Cess&rsquo; into one service tax rate. The GST regime calls for one unified tax, and as most of the cess and surcharges on goods and services would be subsumed under GST, it makes sense to get rid of some of the current cess and surcharges under the current regime as well.<br /><br />Also, simplification of rate structure in sectors such as textiles, cement, automobiles which today have multiple excise duty rates dependent upon raw material component, size etc. is also desirable, as all products under these sectors are likely to attract one rate under GST.<br /><br />Third, the basic premise of GST is minimal exemptions. Accordingly, there is a need to further prune down the existing exemptions under excise in line with those currently available under Value Added Tax (VAT). Thus, an effort should be made to remove the excise exemptions on products which are likely to fall under 5 and 12% GST rates to bring them nearer to the likely GST rates.<br /><br />Similarly, as done during previous Budget, the negative list of services should be re-visited to bring into the tax ambit new services that are likely to be made taxable under GST. This can help ensure that the new service providers get used to undertaking the tax compliances of obtaining registrations, payment of taxes and filing of returns. <br /><br />One of the highlights of GST is free flow of credit. Accordingly, as a step towards alignment of the existing indirect tax laws with GST, restrictions/ negative list as regard to eligibility of credit under the current tax regime should be done away with. Therefore as a fourth step, FM may look at widening the ambit of current cenvat credit provisions to make it more liberal allowing credit of all goods and service which are used for business or furtherance of business. <br /><br />This would give an idea to the assessees of doing business under a liberal credit regime and help them understand how additional tax credits can positively impact their profits. Thus, the assessees may get time to strategize as to how much of this positive impact on their bottom line can be passed on to their customers. <br /><br />Fifth, the success of GST would also depend upon robust IT network that can track returns, transaction level data, etc. Government now needs to take steps to help ensure that the IT system at each and every range, ward of local state VAT departments (which are likely to convert to SGST departments) is functional well before the introduction of GST. Accordingly, as part of Budget 2017-18, the government may take necessary steps (including those for allocating of funds to States, release of funds etc.) to help ensure that all state VAT departments are IT ready for GST.<br /><br />To conclude, the Budget 2017-18 should be used as a budding ground for making the industry ready for subtle but important changes that GST is likely to bring in the indirect tax regime in India.<br /><br /><em><strong>The author is Partner- Indirect Tax of KPMG in India</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>All views and opinions expressed herein are those of the author and do not necessarily represent the views of KPMG in India.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_Budget17_356x200_3456_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-25 19:07:22</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>