<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-is-it-time-to-mediatethe-revenue_8305421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Is it time to mediate with the revenue?]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Considering the lengthy and time consuming litigation route and pendency rate in Indian courts, and to encourage a healthy business environment, it is time to create another viable option for the taxpayers.
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Paras S. Savla and Keerthiga R. Sharma</strong><br /><br />The Indian Income-tax Act has evolved; from the 1922 legislation to the frequently amended 1961 statute. For resolving disputes with the taxpayer, apart from the time-tested and time consuming appeal procedure, there are few alternate dispute resolution mechanisms. We have progressed from standard appeal procedure [beginning with the Commissioner of Income-tax (Appeals), followed by the Income-tax Appellate Tribunal, High Court and ending with the Supreme Court] to alternatives like Advance Pricing Agreements, Mutual Agreement Procedure, etc. <br /><br />However, these alternate dispute resolution mechanisms are more focused on foreign taxpayers or transactions with non-residents. The time-bound Dispute Resolution Panel is available only for foreign companies or in cases where there has been a Transfer Pricing adjustment. Advance Pricing Agreements can be entered by taxpayers desirous of &ldquo;mutually deciding&rdquo; the arm&rsquo;s length price of international transactions, and thereby avoid Transfer Pricing adjustments. Mutual Agreement Procedures are available through the Double Taxation Avoidance Agreements entered into by India with various countries. Even before actually making payment to a non-resident, an Indian payee can apply to the Income-tax Department to determine the rate at which tax ought to be deducted. Further, Advance Rulings are also available to non-residents to determine the taxability even before actually entering into a transaction in India.<br /><br />However, Indian residents have limited options available to them when it comes to income-tax disputes. If one desires to avoid the arduous litigation process, then one is left with very limited options. The option of Advance Rulings is available to public companies and to those whose question arises out of transactions exceeding Rs. 100 crore. The Settlement Commission was introduced as a forum to mediate with the Income-tax Department, but even this option is subject to a minimum disclosure of additional income of Rs. 10 lakh. Further, rather than a mutual settlement, this model has turned out to be a full-fledged detailed hearing before 3 members. <br /><br />Even the recently introduced Direct tax Disputes Resolution Scheme is only for certain kinds of disputes; subject to the nature appellate authority or the nature of dispute. Considering the lengthy and time consuming litigation route and pendency rate in Indian courts, and to encourage a healthy business environment, it is time to create another viable option for the taxpayers. While arbitration and conciliation have been adopted for resolving civil disputes, a similar mechanism can be introduced as an experiment to resolve disputes between the taxpayers and the Indian Income-tax Department.<br /><br />The Internal Revenue Service (&lsquo;IRS&rsquo;) of the USA has an option of Fast Track Mediation and the Fast Track Settlement for coming to a consensus with taxpayers and to avoid litigation. In the Fast Track Settlement (&lsquo;FTS&rsquo;) the taxpayer and the corresponding IRS officer settle disputes in the presence of an independent officer), who is trained in mediation. Most settlements are completed within 70-120 days, with the limit of 120 days being the maximum period as per the law within which the FTS has to be agreed upon. At the end of the mediation, a final agreement detailing the tax liability is signed by both parties. The biggest advantage to the taxpayer is that the option of litigation is available in case the FTS does not result in any solution. Consequently, an application for FTS has to be made 120 days before the expiry of period of limitation for filing an appeal.<br /><br />The FTS is available to small businesses, self-employed, large business and international taxpayers as well as tax exempt and government entities. Whilst the time period for completing an FTS is varied for each category of taxpayer, the option is not available for issues under litigation, or if the issues for which mediation would be inconsistent with sound tax administration, or if the resolution with one party will result in inconsistent treatment for another party without his participation. <br /><br />As with every initiative, this program too has its pros and cons, but it can be tweaked to work in India. However, mediation with the income-tax department may work when taxpayers are not inclined to go into litigation and would like an effective way to resolve their differences. The success of this program in the USA is partly due to the low cost and quick settlements while, litigation definitely involves a long period of time coupled with exorbitant fee of consultants and counsels. <br /><br />With the current wave of reducing pendency in Indian courts and making India a more investment-friendly nation, an initiative to mediate and settle disputes with the tax department may go a long way. The only caution to be taken is how to make this work effectively and efficiently while being corruption-free. With the Budget round the corner, this may as well be considered in it.<br /><br /><em><strong>The authors are advocates with Advaita Legal</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/t/tax_356X200_0900_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-19 20:50:27</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>