<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-subsidy-estimate-@-rs-24-lakh-cr3-yoy_8362281.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Subsidy estimate @ Rs 2.4 lakh cr; up 3% YoY]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The share of subsidies as proportion of total expenditure has been on a decline since 2012. Back then it stood at 18.23 percent and now it has fallen to 11.19 percent. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sidhartha Shukla</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol<br /><br /></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the Union Budget for 2017-18 the estimate expenditure on subsidies has been increased by around 3 percent to Rs 2,40,338.60 crore as compared to the revised estimate of FY17.<br /><br />Following the trend, expenditure on food subsidy has the highest share at Rs 1,45,338.60 crore (60.4%), followed by fertilizer subsidy at Rs 70,000 crore (29%) and petroleum subsidy stood at Rs 25,000 crore (10.4%).<br /><br />In FY17, the government&rsquo;s expenditure on subsidies decreased by 2.9 percent to Rs2,50,432.93 crore in the Budget estimate as compared to revised estimates of 2015-16.<br /><br />Expenditure on petroleum subsidy has been declining over the past few years, from Rs 60,269 crore in 2014-15 to Rs <span style="font-weight: 400;">25,000</span> crore in 2017 -18 (BE), mainly owing to a steep decline in global crude oil prices, from USD 111.9/bbl in 2011-12 to &nbsp;USD 45.63/bbl (average till December 2016) in 2016-17.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-weight: 400;">The share of subsidies as proportion of total expenditure has been on a decline since 2012. Back then it stood at 18.23 percent and now it has fallen to 11.19 percent. </span><br /><iframe style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Sid_Subsidy_Budget" src="//e.infogr.am/a79fccf1-ba6b-4b2d-8b1d-52975ee9b287?src=embed" width="550" height="645" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe><span style="font-weight: 400;">While tabling the Union Budget for FY18, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said,&rdquo;We have made a strong beginning with regard to Direct Benefit Transfer (DBT) to LPG and kerosene consumers. Chandigarh and eight districts of Haryana have become kerosene free. 84 Government schemes have also boarded on the DBT platform.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Narendra Modi led NDA government has been on the path to trim subsidies and plug leakages through better disbursement of social welfare. <br /><br />Maintaining a balance between welfare expenditure and fiscal discipline still remains a challenge for the government. On one hand, it cannot allow the fiscal deficit to increase, on the other it has to provide adequate subsidy which barely contributes to economic growth.<br /></span></p>
<a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/shukla_05sid" data-show-count="false">Follow @shukla_05sid</a>
<script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_farming_agriculture_356x200_5521_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 17:25:23</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>