<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-infrastructure-gets-rs-396-lakh-cr-80-more-compared-to-fy17_8362321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Infrastructure gets Rs 3.96 lakh cr; 80% more compared to FY17]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Wednesday announced a budgetary allocation of Rs 3.96 lakh crore for infrastructure projects for FY18. This is roughly 80 percent higher than the budget estimate of Rs 221,246 crore for FY17.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sidhartha Shukla</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol</strong><br /><br />Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Wednesday announced a budgetary allocation of Rs 3.96 lakh crore for infrastructure projects for FY18. This is roughly 80 percent higher than the budget estimate of Rs 221,246 crore for FY17.</p>
<p>The investment for National highway Authority of India (NHAI) is pegged at Rs 64,900 crore, an increase of 12 percent from FY17 budget estimate. <br /><br />The rural Pradhan Mantri Gram Sadak Yojana (PMGSY) allocation would be Rs 27,000 crore and for railways, an amount of Rs 1.31 lakh crore for FY18 has been proposed.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet tw-align-center" data-lang="en">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Total allocation for infrastructure in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BudgetforBetterIndia?src=hash">#BudgetforBetterIndia</a> stands at a record level Rs 3,96,135 crore in 2017-18 :<a href="https://twitter.com/arunjaitley">@arunjaitley</a></p>
&mdash; Ministry of Finance (@FinMinIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/FinMinIndia/status/826683925992919040">February 1, 2017</a></blockquote>
<script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script>
<p>While reading out the expenditure plans for infrastructure in the Budget, Jaitley said that despite the merger of the Rail and Union Budget, railways will be maintaining their functional autonomy.<br /><br />He further said that 3,500 km railway lines will be commissioned in 2017-18 as against 2,800 km in 2016-17.<br /><br />Listing plans for public transportation, Jaitley said that a&nbsp;A new 'Metro Rail Policy' will be announced with focus on innovative models of implementation and financing, as well as standardisation and indigenisation of hardware and software. <br /><br />"A new Metro Rail Act will be enacted by rationalising the existing laws. This will facilitate greater private participation and investment in construction and operation," he added.</p>
<p>To inculcate growth and development &mdash;&nbsp;the theme on which Prime Minister Narendra Modi led his election campaign &mdash;&nbsp;requires increased amounts of public and private funding.<br /><br />The Budget also stated that affordable housing will be given infrastructure status.<br /><br />"By granting Infrastructure status to affordable housing, the Government acknowledges that affordable housing industry is an important driver of the economy. Affordable housing developers will now be eligible for several Government incentives, subsidies, tax benefits and most importantly institutional funding. The status could also mean that the Government may release land specifically for affordable housing development in central locations of major urban centers in India," says Neeraj Bansal, Head of Real Estate and Construction, KPMG.<br /><br />Last year Arun Jaitley had coined infrastructure investment as the fifth support pillar in the transformation of India and had set aside a generous amount to achieve those goals. His speech appeared to affirm that the&nbsp;trend continues.<br /><br /><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;">Read more:</span></strong><span class="apple-converted-space"><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;">&nbsp;</span></strong></span><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;"><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/budget-2017-game-changing-taxes-will-provide-sense-of-direction-edelweiss_8388701.html" target="_blank">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES<span style="color: blue;"><br /> </span></a></span></strong></p>
<p style="font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; word-spacing: 0px;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;">Follow:</span></strong><span class="apple-converted-space"><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;">&nbsp;</span></strong></span><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;"><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" target="_blank">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></span></strong></p>
<a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/shukla_05sid" data-show-count="false">Follow @shukla_05sid</a>
<script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_Construction_356x200_5241_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 12:48:58</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>