<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2017-18-whyexperts-feelbudget-wont-stimulateeconomy_8396261.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Why these experts feel the Budget won't stimulate the economy]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Meaningful recovery in consumption unlikely as FM focuses targets spends towards rural poor.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Malini Bhupta</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol</strong></p>
<p>Budget 2017 was expected to be the balm for an economy grappling with the after effects of demonetisation. Also, the government was expected to make the right political noises ahead of key assembly elections, without straining its balance sheet too much. It has managed a balancing act, but the net result is that there is not much to fire up the economy.</p>
<p>Given that the pain of demonetization was felt more acutely by rural India, the maximum giveaways were for rural and farm sectors in the form of a 24 percent increase in capital spending to Rs 1.87 trillion.</p>
<p>A record Rs 48,000 crore has been allocated for MGNREGA as the government looks to put more cash in the hands of the rural population.</p>
<p>But it is clearly not the expansionary Budget everybody was hoping for.</p>
<p>Overall estimated Budget spending for FY18 is up 6.6 percent to Rs 21.47 trillion. This is a modest increase in spending as the Finance Minister did not want to stray too much from the path of fiscal consolidation. Fiscal deficit for FY18 has been targeted at 3.2 percent&mdash;higher than the 3.0 percent stipulated in the FRBM roadmap, but less than the 3.3-3.5 percent economists had penciled in.</p>
<p>Says Dhananjay Sinha, strategist and economist at Emkay Global, &ldquo;Overall the Budget may not stimulate the economy, which has taken a beating post demonetization, even though it has a pro-rural and poor bias.&rdquo;</p>
<p>No news was good news for the stock market which was bracing for an unfavourable change in the long term capital gains tax structure.</p>
<p>It was widely expected that the government would increase the holding period for long term capital gains tax to three years from one year at present. Shares rallied once it was clear that there would be no changes. Another relief was foreign portfolio investors being exempt from the indirect transfer tax rules.</p>
<p>Market experts called it a relief rally, as there were no major measures announced that would impact the listed universe in a meaningful way other than the affordable housing sector, which was given infrastructure status.</p>
<p>With the Budget out of the way, the focus is now expected to shift to corporate earnings and global cues.</p>
<p>Anshuman Magazine, chairman, India and South East Asia CBRE, says: &ldquo;While greater rebates were expected in individual tax rates, nonetheless the rebate for individuals earning up to Rs 5 lakh will help increase their disposable incomes. This might help spur consumption and also have a positive impact on demand for housing.&rdquo; The skepticism is clearly evident.</p>
<p>Ratings agency Moody&rsquo;s Investor Service said the Budget marked a continuation of the government&rsquo;s fiscal policies and objectives. Commenting on the government&rsquo;s spending plan, William Foster, vice president, Sovereign Risk Group at Moody&rsquo;s Investor Service, said: &ldquo;If effectively targeted, focused spending on the most vulnerable households through support to farmers, senior citizens and housing would help bolster economic resilience over the medium term.&rdquo; The Budget&rsquo;s focus on infrastructure was largely along expected lines.</p>
<p>Even though real estate was one the big beneficiaries of the Budget, the gains will be restricted to the affordable housing sector. But given that the sector is a generator of employment, the push to the sector would have some cascading effect on the broader economy. <br /><br />Anish Sanghvi, Partner, PwC India on Real Estate sector, said reduction of period of holding to two years to enjoy long-term gains rate as well as more avenues to save capital gains tax have been proposed. This would aid the shift of investments from real estate to financials assets. And by increasing the indexation from 1982 to 2001 will also lead to higher disclosure of income derived from sale of real estate assets.</p>
<p>Following the government&rsquo;s move to invalidate high currency notes, growth has taken a hit. The Budget was expected to ease some of the pain by giving away some goodies. But the balm may not be enough to revive private consumption in a meaningful away.</p>
<p>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBslQpB4onkHTB8Ei9quwBxDOyqg">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE3J8DU_uiR6ilTdJKHisn5k8cv_g">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/j/Jaitley_FM_budget_2017_budget_356x200_0324_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 16:16:01</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>