<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/brokerage-recos-others/union-budget-2017-2018-review-kr-choksey_8405121.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-2018 Review: KR Choksey]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance Minister Mr. Arun Jaitley in his budget 2017 speech addressed the governments mission to bring a transformative shift to the governance landscape of our country. The government has moved from a discretionary administration to a policy and system based administration; from favoritism to transparency and objectivity in decision making.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">Finance Minister Mr. Arun Jaitley in his budget 2017 speech addressed the governments mission to bring a transformative shift to the governance landscape of our country. The government has moved from a discretionary administration to a policy and system based administration; from favoritism to transparency and objectivity in decision making; from blanket and loose entitlements to targeted delivery; and from informal economy to formal economy.<br /><br /></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">IMF has projected India&rsquo;s GDP growth of 7.2% and 7.7% in 2017 and 2018 respectively with expectations of India to be one of the fastest growing world economies. The World Bank, however has a more optimistic outlook with GDP growth projected of 7% in FY17E, 7.6% in FY18E and 7.8% in FY19E. CPI inflation declined from 6% in July 2016 to 3.4% in December 2016 and is expected to remain within RBI&rsquo;s mandated range of 2% to 6%.<br /><br /></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;">India&rsquo;s Current Account Deficit declined from about 1% of GDP last year to 0.3% of GDP in the H1FY17. Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) increased from INR 1.07 Lakh Crs in H1FY16 to INR 1.45 Lakh Crs in H1FY17. This marks an increase by 36%, despite 5% reduction in global FDI inflows. Foreign exchange reserves reached USD 361bn as on 20<sup>th</sup> Jan 2017 which represents a comfortable cover for about 12 months of imports.<br /><br /><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The views and investment recommendations expressed by investment experts/broking houses/rating agencies on moneycontrol.com are their own, and not that of the website or its management. Moneycontrol.com advises users to check with certified experts before taking any investment decisions.<br /><br /></em></div>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_2000_356x200_3919_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 12:46:41</Entry_Date><Category>Brokerage Recos - Others</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>