<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/buzzing-stocks/budget-2017-psu-banks-gain-4rs-10000-cr-infusion-announcement_8391961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: PSU banks gain 4% on Rs 10,000 cr infusion announcement]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Union Bank of India jumped 4.34 percent, Bank of Baroda rose 3.27 percent, SBI went up 3.13 percent and PNB gained 3.12 percent on BSE.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Shares of PSU banks today rose by as much as 4 percent as the government announced infusion of Rs 10,000 crore in public sector banks in the next fiscal.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/unionbankindia/UBI01">Union Bank of India</a> jumped 4.34 percent, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/bankofbaroda/BOB">Bank of Baroda</a> rose 3.27 percent, SBI went up 3.13 percent and PNB gained 3.12 percent on BSE.</p>
<p>Among others, shares of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/syndicatebank/SB9">Syndicate Bank</a> gained 2.31 percent and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/bankofindia/BOI">Bank of India</a> rose 2.25 percent.</p>
<p>The government will infuse Rs 10,000 crore in public sector banks in the next fiscal and more will be provided if required, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said.</p>
<p>"As per the Indradhanush plan, the public sector banks will be provided with Rs 10,000 crore in the next fiscal.</p>
<p>Additional allocation would be made if required," he said while presenting Budget 2017-18.</p>
<p>Under Indradhanush roadmap announced in 2015, the government will infuse Rs 70,000 crore in nationalised banks over four years while they will have to raise a further Rs 1.1 lakh crore from the markets to meet their capital requirement in line with global risk norms, known as Basel-III.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/bank_Budget_2017_rupee_356x200_3046_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 13:16:03</Entry_Date><Category>Buzzing Stocks</Category><sc_id>,BOB,UBI01,BOI,SB9,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>