<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-expect-tax-leverages-for-cashless-payment-says-zebpay_8312601.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Expect tax leverages for cashless payment, says Zebpay]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[New developments in the Budget and economic interventions will open more avenues for Digital India. India has already started experimenting with the blockchain technology. Budget should also include special allotments for experimentation with innovations and technology, says Saurabh Agrawal,CEO and Co-founder of Zebpay .]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>India&rsquo;s Union Budget is a major event and it is often a highly anticipated one. Financial experts from various segments come together to express multiple opinions. The magnitude of Budget is high as weeks before and after the Budget speech, media discussions are covered with experts talk about expectations and ripple effects.</p>
<p>Our expectations from the Budget are high this year. With the recent historic step of demonetization, this year will stand out. We expect it to be a people friendly Budget. "Make in India" campaign has garnered a lot of attention on global and Indian platforms. Our PM's vision will steer the country to success with a special focus on the growth of start-ups.</p>
<p>We already know that government is deep diving to comprehend more about the start-ups. Levitation of special tax benefits will enhance the new growing companies.We expect the corporate tax should come down to 25 percent to encourage the people in the sector to work and grow better.</p>
<p>New developments in the Budget and economic interventions will open more avenues for Digital India. India has already started experimenting with the blockchain technology. Budget should also include special allotments for experimentation with innovations and technology. We expect tax leverages for cashless payment mediums like debit/credit cards. <br /><br />We are hopeful to see positive regulations being implemented in the bitcoins ecosystem in India. We also look forward to bitcoins being classified as a new asset class. This will amplify the whole cashless scenario in India and boost the financial health of the country.</p>
<p>Taxation is an area where major interventions are expected. The government should encourage people to pay more taxes by reducing tax slab. We look forward to real estate and various infrastructure projects announcements. This will result in direct employment and set the GDP soaring high.</p>
<p>CRR ratio should come down, leading to interest cost charged by banks coming down to 7 percent. It's tough for Indian companies to fight globally as the cost of finance is much higher compared to international competitors. With demonetization and enough bank balance, the government can reduce the interest cost. This will be a big booster to financial health of major sectors.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget_GDP_Growth_Economy_Growth_356x200_1221_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-20 17:00:21</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>