<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-jaitley-may-scrap-complicated-accounting-system-icds_8333421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Jaitley may scrap complicated accounting system ICDS]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Easwar-panel on I-T simplification is also believed to have favoured replacing the ICDS with a simpler system. Industry bodies say this has increased compliance costs]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gaurav Choudhury &amp; Shreya Nandi<br /></strong><strong>Moneycontrol<br /></strong><br />Finance Minister Arun Jaitley may scrap the Income Computation and Disclosure Standards (ICDS), which companies have complained as complicated and riddled with drawbacks.</p>
<p>The RV Easwar-headed panel on income tax (I-T) simplification is also believed to have favoured replacing the ICDS with a simpler system. ICDS, which has been adopted since 2016-17, has resulted in multiple accounting systems&mdash;one for tax purposes and the other for books of accounts as mandated by the Companies Act.</p>
<p>Industry bodies and tax experts have pointed out that this has increased compliance costs and resulted in multiple interpretation of tax rules and business laws.</p>
<p>Large listed companies have adopted the &ldquo;Indian Accounting Standards (IndAS)&rdquo;&mdash;an globally accepted accounting standard introduced by the ministry of corporate affairs in India. The scope of IndAS will be widened from April 1, 2017.</p>
<p>Experts point out that the accounting system for tax and corporate filing purposes should be identical, arguing that there was no specific purpose that ICDS can achieve.</p>
<p>"It will be a good move if the government decides not to implement ICDS as it leads to additional compliance requirements," Prashant Khatore, Partner at E&amp;Y said.</p>
<p>"People will have to maintain two different set of accounting records in order to arrive at a taxable income because their book results may be as per their accouting standards and they will have to adjust accounting difference and then arrive at a taxable income," Khatore said.</p>
<p>Arvind Srivatsan, Partner at Pricewaterhouse Coopers also echoed similar views.</p>
<p>According to Srivastsan, it has to be seen that whether ICDS is consistent with the government's overall theme of ease of doing business.</p>
<p>"...if the governmment were to implement this, what would be the impact of ICDS on tax collection? It does not have any impact on the organised sector," he said.<br /><br /><strong><br /></strong></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_India_GDP_Growth_inflation_rise_Inflation_Service_Tax_356x200_4840_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-24 16:45:53</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>