<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-non-populistdevelopment-oriented-says-ap-cm_8402841.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget non-populist, but development-oriented, says AP CM]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Chief Minister thanked Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Jaitley for granting exemption from capital gains tax to farmers, who contributed their land for building AP's new capital Amaravati.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister N Chandrababu Naidu said the Union Budget presented by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley was "non-populist", but development-oriented.</p>
<p>"It is not a populist budget. It is development-oriented and that is good," Chandrababu told reporters here.</p>
<p>He welcomed the curbs on funding to political parties saying it should usher in a reform in the system.</p>
<p>"I have been advocating reforms in the electoral system for long. Some parties exist only to collect funds, but now that will go," he said.</p>
<p>He also supported the move to hold simultaneous elections and said it should be from the village panchayat up to Parliament.</p>
<p>"We can then focus on development for five years without worrying about elections," the Telugu Desam Party chief noted.</p>
<p>The Chief Minister thanked Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Jaitley for granting exemption from capital gains tax to farmers, who contributed their land for building AP's new capital Amaravati.</p>
<p>He also welcomed the allocation of funds for various projects announced by the Centre as per the AP Reorganisation Act, but wanted "legal sanctity" for the special economic package announced for the state.</p>
<p>Also, he wanted the Centre to release funds towards bridging the state's revenue deficit caused by bifurcation.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_356x200_4046_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 08:34:02</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>