<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/confidentachieving-40-kmday-target-by-next-yrnitin-gadkari_8296241.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Confident of achieving 40 km/day target by next yr:Nitin Gadkari]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Confident of his ministry achieving the target of 40 km of road per day by next year. By end of December 2016, they had reached 30 km per day, said Road Transport & Highways and Shipping Minister Nitin Gadkari.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Road Transport &amp; Highways and Shipping Minister Nitin Gadkari is very optimistic of his ministry contributing 2-3 percent to the GDP of the country and create 5 crore jobs by end of his 5-year term. The ministry will be a big contributor to the double-digit growth of the country, he said.<br /><br />In the forthcoming Union Budget on February 1, he expects the Finance Minister to give high priority to infrastructure investments. "Budget is an economic vision for the whole country," he said.<br /><br />He is also confident of his party (BJP) doing well in the elections in Uttar Pradesh, Goa and other states.<br /><br />Speaking to CNBC-TV18 from the sidelines of WEF at Davos, he said there has been a lot of investor interest in road and infrastructure sectors. Foreign investors have a good opinion of the Indian economy, especialy investment-friendly policies, he said. The Canadian Pension Fund has promised huge investments.&nbsp;<br /><br />He is also confident of his ministry achieving the target of 40 km of road per day by next year. By end of December, last year they had reached 30 km per day, said Gadkari. He is also looking at 12 more express highways.<br /><br />The government will now also focus on the agriculture sector.<br /><br /><strong><em>For full interview, watch video</em></strong>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/n/Nitin_Gadkari_Road_highways_minister_356x200_2543_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-18 19:39:57</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>