<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-indradhanush-scheme-to-help-psu-banks-may-getrejig_8377341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Indradhanush scheme to help PSU banks may get a rejig]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The initial plan had envisaged out of the total requirement, the government will make available Rs 70,000 crore out of budgetary allocations for four years]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>The <em>&lsquo;Indradhanush&rsquo;</em> scheme that was announced in August 2015 for the revamp of public sector banks is likely to get rejigged in this year's Union Budget.</p>
<p>&ldquo;We have been allocated Rs 10,000 crore for financial year 2017-18 as per the original plan. We expect that amount to be revised upwards,&rdquo; said a senior public sector executive.</p>
<p>The initial plan had envisaged, out of the total requirement, the government will make available Rs 70,000 crore out of budgetary allocations for four years. The scheme was allocated Rs 25,000 crore each for financial years 2015-16 and 2016-17.</p>
<p>Again for the financial years 2017-18 and 2018-19, the allocation of Rs 10,000 crore each was fixed. Bankers expect this to be increased atleast by 15-20 percent, considering that the provisioning and non-performing asset (NPA) situation has worsened.</p>
<p>The executive director of a mid-size public sector bank added that while raising additional capital from the market was also considered by the ministry while making these allocations, market conditions had also prevented some of them to raise funds through various instruments.<br /><br />About Rs 70,000 crore aid for public sector will come from the government out of a total of Rs 1,80,000 crore envisaged for the ailing nationalised lenders. &nbsp;</p>
<p>During the launch of this scheme, the ministry had said that improved valuations coupled with value unlocking from non-core assets as well as improvements in capital productivity, will enable PSBs to raise the remaining Rs 1,10,000 crore from the market. It had also said that the government is committed to making extra budgetary provisions in FY18 and FY19, to ensure that PSBs remain adequately capitalized to support economic growth.</p>
<p>Over and above, the human resource issues are also expected to be tackled. While the<em> &lsquo;Indradhanush&rsquo;</em> scheme had proposed an employee stock ownership plan (ESOPs) for top management, the framework for the same is yet to be finalised.</p>
<p>Human resource consultants were also approached by banks when the scheme was introduced. However, PSU banks are yet to implement the system of giving out ESOPs on a wider scale. Private banks already have a system of giving out stock options to senior management.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_356x200_3553_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 11:32:01</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>