<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/union-budget-2017-18-railway-safety-fund-metro-rail-policy-few-reforms_8399901.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-18: Railway Safety fund, metro rail policy & a few reforms]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Few new initiatives that the government has proposed in this year budget include development of a new metro rail policy and rationalization of railway tariffs on the basis of cost, social obligation and competition.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Abhaya Agarwal</strong><br /><br />In order to continue the growth momentum of the country, government has again emphasized on the role of infrastructure through higher budgetary allocation for the infrastructure sector than ever before. Railways is an important sub-sector under the infrastructure sector. Out of total allocation Rs. 3.96 lakh crore for infrastructure sector, government plans to spend Rs. 1.31 lakh crore on railways in FY18 (33% of the total infrastructure budget estimates) with a focus on capacity addition, passenger safety, cleanliness and overhauling accounting practices.<br /><br />As per the budget speech, railway line of 3,500 km will be commissioned in FY18 as against targeted 2,800 km in FY17. Further, government plans to eliminate all the unmanned railway level crossings by 2020. It is further planned to award station re-development contracts for at least 25 stations in FY18. While the intentions of the government is highly appreciable, implementation of projects might be challenge to overcome. Gross budgetary support (GBS) for railways in FY 2016-17 was Rs. 45,000 crore, of which only 54% had been spent till Q3 as per an estimate. It is expected that total spending in this fiscal year will reach around 75% of the GBS. In the 2017-18 union budget, Rs. 55,000 crore of GBS has been allocated for the railways sub-sector. Hence, it would be worthwhile to observe how Ministry of Railways intends to build upon its existing capabilities to overcome execution challenges. Key to overcome execution challenge would be to selection of right set of projects. New variants of PPPs in highways (i.e. Hybrid Annuity etc.) may be explored to expedite the execution of railways projects.<br /><br />In the 2017-18 union budget, government has proposed to create a railway safety fund with a corpus of Rs. 1 lakh crore over five years. Government will provide the seed capital and remaining amount would be raised through other sources. One source could be levying of safety cess from passengers. Raising remaining amount from the market could be a challenge.<br /><br />Few new initiatives that the government has proposed in this year budget include development of a new metro rail policy and rationalization of railway tariffs on the basis of cost, social obligation and competition. New metro policy would enable easier financing and implementation of metro projects. Tariff rationalization reforms would go a long way in reduction of financial burden on the government as well as reduction in cargo tariffs resulting in increase in railways freight traffic. On reforms front, government has proposed yet another initiative that would increase transparency of the railways financials. <br /><br />Government has proposed to roll out the accrual based accounting system by March 2019. This will increase investors&rsquo; confidence in bidding for the projects.<br /><br /><em><strong>Abhaya Agarwal is a Partner and PPP Leader with EY India. </strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>Views expressed are personal.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/r/railway_Budget_2017_railways_356x200_2722_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 19:22:19</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>