<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-news/sebi-pitches-for-tax-rationalisationcapital-markets_8331881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Sebi pitches for tax rationalisation in capital markets]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In its budget proposal to the Finance Ministry, Sebi has recommended reducing the securities transaction tax (STT) on stock trading, sources said.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of the Union Budget, markets regulator Sebi has asked the government to consider rationalisation of taxes in capital markets including that of mutual funds and other products.</p>
<p>In its budget proposal to the Finance Ministry, Sebi has recommended reducing the securities transaction tax (STT) on stock trading, sources said.</p>
<p>Presently, all stock market transactions attract STT in the range of 0.017 to 0.125 per cent.</p>
<p>It has also suggested lowering the period of holding in respect of long term debt fund units to 12 months from 36 months.</p>
<p>Besides, the regulator has sought an increase in the investment limit for tax-saving equity mutual fund schemes to Rs 2 lakh from the current Rs 1.5 lakh.</p>
<p>These suggestions are aimed at attracting more investors.</p>
<p>Further, mutual fund industry body Amfi has also proposed that debt-linked savings scheme should be given tax benefits under Sec 80 CCC of Income Tax Act, the sources said.</p>
<p>Only equity-linked savings schemes (ELSS) qualify for tax benefits under Section 80 CCC of the Income Tax Act, for an investment limit of up to Rs 1.5 lakh in a fiscal year.</p>
<p>Also, the Association of mutual funds in India (Amfi) made a proposal to extend the tax benefits available under Rajiv Gandhi Equity Savings Scheme (RGESS) to all equity fund investors.</p>
<p>To promote investments in equities, the government had introduced RGESS in 2012 for first-time investors with annual income below Rs 12 lakh a year.</p>
<p>Further, AMFI has proposed for extending Sec 54 EC benefit for mutual fund schemes with lock-in period of 3-5 years.</p>
<p>Section 54 EC of Income Tax Act, 1961 provides an option to save tax on capital gain arising from transfer of long-term capital asset subject to certain conditions.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/s/sebi_1_356x200_2822_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-24 14:52:05</Entry_Date><Category>Market news</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>