<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-targeted-tax-cuts-good-economics-even-better-politics-(comment)_8399481.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Targeted tax cuts good economics, even better politics (Comment)]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Finance Minister added that there was a “legitimate expectation” post demonetisation that the tax burden on honest individuals be lowered and if the nominal tax rate is lower for the lowest slab, more people would prefer to come into the tax net.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Madhuchanda Dey</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol Research</strong><br /><br />On expected lines, the targeted beneficiaries of this Budget were the group that mattered the most in terms of sheer numbers and Arun Jaitley made no mistake in appeasing the income category between Rs 2.5 lakh and Rs 5 lakh per annum. <br /><br />The most significant giveaway pertaining to personal income tax has been the reduction in the tax rate from 10 percent to 5 percent for income in the Rs 2.5-5.0 lakh bracket. As per the data gathered from the Budget documents, out of the total tax assessees of 37 million, more than half belong to this group. Hence, the impact of this move would be significant both from the perspective of consumption multiplier and the vote bank.<br />
<div><br /><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2017/t/TaxSlab_newFeb1Chart1.png" alt="" /></div>
<br />The Finance Minister added that there was a &ldquo;legitimate expectation&rdquo; post demonetisation that the tax burden on honest individuals be lowered and if the nominal tax rate is lower for the lowest slab, more people would prefer to come into the tax net.<br /><br />To facilitate compliance, the government has proposed a simple one-page form for individuals with an income up to Rs 5 lakh, anyone filing income tax return for the first time will not be subject to any income scrutiny in the first year unless there&rsquo;s specific information with the taxman about high-value transactions.<br /><br />The fine print of the Budget suggests that the tax measures even for the middle class are not an unmixed blessing - Section 87A that provided for a rebate up to Rs 5,000 from the income-tax payable to a resident individual with income not exceeding Rs 5 lakhs has been amended to reduce the rebate to Rs 2,500. Moreover, the rebate would be applicable to income not exceeding Rs 3.5 lakhs.<br />
<div><br /><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2017/n/New_TaxSlab_Chart2.png" alt="" /></div>
<br />The move nevertheless benefits the &lsquo;middle class&rsquo;. An individual with an annual earnings of Rs 5 lakhs will enjoy Rs 7,500 reduction in tax outgo &ndash; 1.5 percent of his/her gross earnings. One can reasonably conclude that this should boost consumption at the margin while perhaps falling short of the large consumption stimulus of last year.<br /><br />So is it good economics with good politics? Perhaps yes, as the move translates to revenue loss of Rs 15,500 crore - 0.09 percent of GDP. The loss would be partially compensated (Rs 2,700 crore) by imposing a surcharge of 10 percent in the income category of Rs 50 lakh to Rs 1 crore. The net stimulus of Rs 12,800 crore, should nonetheless keep small-ticket consumption companies happy.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/t/Tax_investors_stock_market_356x200_4609_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 18:15:53</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>