<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-government-projects-1175-nominal-gdp-growth-for-2017-18_8390361.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Government projects 11.75% nominal GDP growth for 2017-18]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[With a relatively benign inflation trend, the projection could push India’s real or inflation adjusted economic growth to about 7-7.5 percent. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>The government today projected 11.75 percent nominal gross domestic product (GDP) growth for the next financial year 2017-18.</p>
<p>&ldquo;On balance, and, in line with the projections for&nbsp; strengthening&nbsp; of&nbsp; India&rsquo;s&nbsp; growth&nbsp; by&nbsp; multi-lateral institutions,&nbsp; the&nbsp; nominal&nbsp; growth&nbsp; of&nbsp; the&nbsp; economy&nbsp; is expected to&nbsp; be 11.75 percent in&nbsp; the&nbsp; financial&nbsp; year 2017-18,&rdquo; the finance ministry said in &ldquo;The Macro Economic Framework Statement,&rdquo; tabled in Parliament as part of the budget documents.</p>
<p>With a relatively benign inflation trend, the projection could push India&rsquo;s real or inflation adjusted economic growth to about 7-7.5 percent.</p>
<p>The government said that the prospects for Indian economy for the year 2017-18 need to be assessed in the light of emerging global and domestic developments.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Indications are that global economic growth is gradually picking up. This augurs well for Indian exports, which are highly responsive to the dynamics of global economic activity.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the increasing global prices of oil and other key commodities may exercise an upward pressure on the value of imports.&nbsp; Uncertainty on account of significant external political developments, global interest rate behaviour and capital flows pose potential downsides.</p>
<p>Domestic demand is expected to get a boost from accommodative monetary policy and the unleashing of domestic trade and consumption as&nbsp; the&nbsp; economy&nbsp; gets&nbsp; remonetised&nbsp; to&nbsp; the&nbsp; required levels, it said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/g/GDP_Gross_domestic_price_economy_Growth_inflation_356x200_5201_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 17:51:23</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>