<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/buzzing-stocks/itc-hits-record-high-after-lower-than-expected-excise-duty-hike_8394921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[ITC hits record high after lower-than-expected excise duty hike]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Cigarette major ITC shares hit record high of Rs 269.50, up 4.5 percent intraday Wednesday as excise duty hike was within the analysts' expectations limit.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>Cigarette major <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/cigarettes/itc/ITC">ITC</a> shares hit record high of Rs 269.50, up 4.5 percent intraday Wednesday as excise duty hike was within the analysts' expectations limit.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley, in his fourth Budget speech, hiked excise duty by 2.5-6 percent on various lengths of cigarettes, which was far below the market expectations of 8-10 percent.</p>
<p>The government also increased additional duty on unmanufactured tobacco to 8.3 percent from 4.2 percent.</p>
<p>Additional duty on non-filter cigarettes of length not exceeding 65mm has been raised to Rs 311 per thousand sticks from Rs 215 earlier and for non-filter cigarettes of length exceeding 65mm but not exceeding 70mm duty increased to Rs 541 per thousand sticks from Rs 370 earlier.</p>
<p>For filter cigarettes of length not exceeding 65mm, the government raised additional duty to Rs 311 per thousand sticks (from Rs 215 earlier) and for cigarettes length exceeding 65mm but not exceeding 70mm, the duty increased to Rs 386 per thousand sticks (from Rs 260 earlier).</p>
<p>Additional duty for other cigarettes increased to Rs 811 per thousand sticks from Rs 560 earlier.</p>
<p>Moreover, the government also raised additional duty on pan masala to 9 percent from 6 percent and that for chewing tobacco (including filter khaini), jarda scented tobacco &amp; pan masala containing tobacco (gutkha) increased to 12 percent from 6 percent each.</p>
<p>Even excise duty on handmade and machine made paper-rolled beedi increased to Rs 28 per 1,000 units (from Rs 21 earlier) and Rs 78 (from Rs 21), respectively.</p>
<p>The rally in the stock price may also be on hopes of stake sale by the government to meet its divestment target of Rs 72,500 crore fixed for FY18 against Rs 56,500 crore in previous financial year.</p>
<p>The government through Specified Undertaking of the Unit Trust of India held 11.12 percent stake in the cigarette-hotel-to-FMCG major, as of December 2016.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in the quarter ended December 2016, ITC's cigarette volumes fell 1 percent YoY, supported by higher growth in the sub-65mm segment. Gross cigarette revenue grew 2.2 percent YoY, while calculated net sales declined 1 percent YoY. Cigarette EBIT rose 1.7 percent YoY, with margin expansion of 190 basis points.</p>
<p>While cigarette volume performance has been commendable, the base becomes less favorable going forward (Q4FY16 and Q1FY17 base of 0 percent and 3 percent, respectively), Motilal Oswal said in its report dated January 27.</p>
<p>At 15:26 hours IST, the stock was quoting at Rs 270.00, up Rs 11.95, or 4.63 percent on the BSE.<br /><br /><em>Posted by Sunil Shankar Matkar</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/c/cigarette_smoking_jpg_356x200_1746_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 15:29:02</Entry_Date><Category>Buzzing Stocks</Category><sc_id>,ITC,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>