<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-strikes-balance-between-fiscal-prudence-growth-boost_8407841.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA['Govt strikes balance between fiscal prudence, growth boost']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[According to the global financial services major, fiscal consolidation in 2017-18 is mainly driven by a reduction in expenditure, particularly current spending.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Government has struck a balance between prioritising capital spending and being fiscally prudent and the 'favourable expenditure mix' should support 2017-18 growth, says a Goldman Sachs report.</p>
<p>According to the global financial services major, fiscal consolidation in 2017-18 is mainly driven by a reduction in expenditure, particularly current spending.</p>
<p>"Overall, we believe the government has maintained a balance between prioritising capital spending and being fiscally prudent," Goldman Sachs said in a research note.</p>
<p>The government, in its annual Budget, called for a reduction in fiscal deficit to 3.2 percent of GDP in 2017-18, from a projected 3.5 percent in 2016-17 and an estimated 3.9 percent in 2015-16.</p>
<p>"The budgeted fiscal consolidation takes place via a decrease in total expenditure as a percentage of GDP, especially current expenditure, while capital spending remains high," the report said.</p>
<p>It added that the revenue targets look "achievable", with any downside risk to disinvestment target potentially offset by somewhat higher tax revenue growth.</p>
<p>The Economic Survey forecasts GDP growth at 6.75-7.50 percent in 2017-18.</p>
<p>"The budgeted primary deficit net of disinvestment proceeds is unchanged at 0.6 percent of GDP in 2017-18 versus 2016-17, suggesting limited negative impulse on growth from the proposed fiscal consolidation in 2017-18," it said adding, the favourable expenditure mix should support 2017-18 growth.</p>
<p>The report further noted that though the recent fall in headline inflation along with fiscal consolidation, supports the possibility of a rate cut by the RBI at its next policy meeting, several other factors warrant a cautious approach.</p>
<p>"Our base case remains for a 25 bps rate cut by the RBI at its meeting on February 7-8, but we acknowledge that this will be a close call," it added.</p>
<p>The central bank will hold its next monetary policy meet on February 8.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/f/FM_Finmin_Jaitley_Arun_356x200_0402_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 14:02:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>