<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-edge/budget-2017-marketsrejoicingherescan-puncture-stock-rally_8394321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Markets are rejoicing but here's what can puncture stock rally]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Tax relief, which the Budget provided to the stock market, alone cannot sustain the rally, growth is needed to fuel it]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Shishir Asthana</strong><br /><strong>Moneycontrol</strong><br /><br />Market participants are a relieved lot since finance minister did not tinker with tax changes. Expectations were that the finance minister would either introduce long-term capital gains tax (LTCG) or increase the holding period from the present one year to two years.</p>
<p>There was also a sigh of relief from the foreign investors after the finance minister officially annulled the notification on &lsquo;retrospective tax&rsquo;.</p>
<p>But tax relief alone cannot sustain the rally, growth is needed to fuel it.</p>
<p>The biggest takeaway for the market is a focus on growth has come with at the cost of lower interest rates in future. Borrowing target by the government has been reduced signaling a fall in interest rate. <br /><br />Banks account for nearly one-third of the broad market indices will be in focus, especially since the minister has increased allocation for capital infusion and tweaked the NPA norms for tax benefits.</p>
<p>Lower interest rate will help boost consumption and also divert money from debt market that will generate lower returns, to equity markets.</p>
<p>Sector specific benefits are there for the housing sector, especially those companies directly or indirectly engaged with affordable housing where Jaitley has given the sector an infrastructure status and increased the calculation of carpet area. Housing finance companies, banks, developers, cement and steel players will gain from this push.</p>
<p>Overall increase of 25.4 percent in capital expenditure is largely focused on infrastructure and transportation sector (includes road, rails and shipping). Auto and banking sectors are an indirect beneficiary of the spending.</p>
<p>India&rsquo;s GDP has been robust despite a slowing export growth due to tepid pace of global economy and slowing pace of manufacturing sector in India only on account of a rural push. <br /><br />Agriculture sector has been robust and would continue to outperform given government&rsquo;s focus. As a result agriculture inputs, consumers, consumables, automobile (mainly 2 wheelers) and textiles can see increased offtake.</p>
<p>Abolishing FIPB is also a big positive for corporate India, especially in the listed space as foreign investments prefer to come in listed companies since there is an automatic exit possibility.</p>
<p>Markets have reacted positively to the budget announcement, sustaining the rally will depend on implementation of the schemes. The first visibility of rollout will be in announcements of new projects and unclogging the existing ones. The second sign of actual implementation will be visible in non-food credit offtake, which has remained poor for some years.</p>
<p>Markets have rallied on hopes but they can fall swiftly if reality does not catch up with it fast.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/BSE_Sensex_Budget_2017_stock_market_bse_356x200_3438_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 15:16:38</Entry_Date><Category>Market Edge</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>