<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/brokerage-recos-others/union-budget-2017-2018-review-way2wealth_8407021.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2017-2018 Review: Way2Wealth]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[To create a strong foundation for the nations sustainable growth through job creation, empowering the weaker sections of society, encouraging a healthy investment climate and providing necessary framework to enable foreign invest, ease of business and tax
compliance.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">To create a strong foundation for the nations sustainable growth through job creation, empowering the weaker sections of society, encouraging a healthy investment climate and providing necessary framework to enable foreign invest, ease of business and tax compliance.</div>
<br /><strong><strong>KEY HIGHLIGHTS - MACRO<br /></strong></strong>
<p>1. GDP growth for 2015-16 was revised from 7.6% to 7.9%. FY17 GDP target revised to 7.1%. FY18 estimates pegged at 6.75%-7.5%.</p>
<p>2. CPI inflation has come down to 3.4% in December 2016 from 6% in July 2016.</p>
<p>3. Foreign exchange reserves touched highest ever level of about US&#36; 360bn, covering 12 months of imports.</p>
<p>4. Fiscal deficit 2016-17 and 2017-18 BE at 3.5% and 3.2% of GDP. The Government aims to keep achieve a 3% fiscal deficit target by FY19 .</p>
<p>5. Revenue Deficit target improved from 2.3% to 2.1% in RE 2016-17 with estimates for 2017-18 at 1.9%.</p>
<p>6. Net market borrowing of government to be restricted at Rs 3.48 lakh crores vs. Rs 4.25 lakh crores in previous year.</p>
<p>7. Fixed investment as a % of GDP is estimated to be 26.6% in 2016 vs 29.3% in 2015-16. Government is mindful of the decline in this no. since the last few years and believes its important to reverse this trend for driving growth in the medium to long term. &nbsp;</p>
<div style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The views and investment recommendations expressed by investment experts/broking houses/rating agencies on moneycontrol.com are their own, and not that of the website or its management. Moneycontrol.com advises users to check with certified experts before taking any investment decisions.</em></div>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/budget-2017_budget_356x200_0426_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 13:56:42</Entry_Date><Category>Brokerage Recos - Others</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>