<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-heresyou-need-to-know-about-corporate-taxes_8357741.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Here's what you need to know about corporate taxes]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[To help tide over the impact of demonetisation-induced slowdown on business, India Inc. is heftily pitching for a relief on corporate taxes in the upcoming Union Budget for 2017-18.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[To help tide over the impact of demonetisation-induced slowdown on business, India Inc. is heftily pitching for a relief on corporate taxes in the upcoming Union Budget for 2017-18. <br /><br />However, a look at some key data points reveal two interesting facts; Indian corporate income tax rates have dropped significantly from 50 percent in 1991 to less than 30 percent now. Also, while Indian companies appear to be taxed at a rate higher than global peers, the `effective rate&rsquo; in India, net of exemptions, is far lower at 22.44 percent. This is the lowest after Singapore and UK where rates are at 17 percent and 21 percent, respectively. But, when compared with others like the United States with 40 percent rate and Japan with 35.64 percent, Indian corporates seem to be well-off.<br /><br /><strong>Corporate Taxes</strong><br /><br />India&rsquo;s domestic companies now pay far less tax than those of the previous generation. Corporate income tax rates have fallen from 50 percent in 1991 to less than 30 percent.<br /><br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2017/i/Infographic11.jpg" alt="" /><br />
<p>On the face of it, Indian companies are taxed at a higher rate than their global peers. Over the years, the pitch for lower taxes has grown louder. The 'effective rate&rsquo; rate of corporate income tax rate in India, net of exemptions is, however, far lower at 22.44 percent compared to the headline rate of 30 percent.<br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2017/i/Infographic12.jpg" alt="" /></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_budget_356x200_5221_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-30 13:47:00</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>