<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/poll-heresindia-inc-expectsbudget-2017_8335341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Poll: Here's what India Inc expects from Budget 2017]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ahead of the Budget, CNBC-TV18, Forbes India and BMR Advisors conducted pre-budget poll of select CEOs to ascertain the expectations of India Inc from Budget 2017.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of the Budget, CNBC-TV18, Forbes India and BMR Advisors conducted a pre-Budget poll of select CEOs to ascertain the expectations of India Inc from Budget 2017. <br /><br />The poll was conducted in December this year, just a month after demonetisation. Top executives stretching across 17 sectors were polled just a month after demonetisation. Every executive was sent an online link to respond the questions and it was anonymous in nature.<br /><br />As per the poll, 64 percent of the respondents believe that India will see 7-8 percent GDP growth in FY18 while 8 percent feel that the&nbsp;growth number could cross 8 also.<br /><br />Streamlining policies will be the government's focus in this Budget according to 52 percent respondents. &nbsp;<br /><br />Mukesh Butani, Managing Partner at BMR Legal said that Budget expectations are high on back of the demonetisation drive. While reforms have been done, government still has a long way to go. <br /><br />Sourav Majumdar, Editor of Forbes India believes that demonetisation clearly signals government&rsquo;s intent to fight against black money in the economy.<br /><br />India Inc believes that the Goods &amp; Services Tax (GST) Bill will boost the economy. Majumdar said that over time, GST could impact the economic growth by 100 basis points. <br /><br />Backing the view, Gokul Chaudhri of BMR &amp; Association said that demonetisation followed by GST is likely to push India to higher tax-GDP ratio. <br /><br />Here are the findings of the poll:</p>
<p><strong>FY18 GDP estimate</strong></p>
<p>- 64 percent of the respondents think FY18 GDP will grow in the 7-8 percent range.<br /><br />- 32 percent see growth of below 7 percent.<br /><br />- 8 percent believe it will cross 8 percent.</p>
<p><strong>Will interest rates ease</strong></p>
<p>- 85 percent of the respondents&nbsp;think interest rates will ease going ahead.<br /><br />- 9 percent responded&nbsp;no.<br /><br />- 6 percent can&rsquo;t say.<br /><br /><strong>Key theme of the Budget</strong></p>
<p>- 52 percent believe the&nbsp;Budget will focus on simplify and streamlining policies<br /><br />- 33 percent believe in infrastructure development <br /><br />- 15 percent believe in accelerating flagship schemes,</p>
<p><strong>Ease of doing business</strong></p>
<p>When asked about best steps the government has undertaken to ease doing business in the country, CEOs rated the following:<br /><br />1 - Ease of starting business (39 percent respondents)<br /><br />2 - Resolving insolvency (38 percent)<br /><br />3 - Paying taxes (30 percent)<br /><br />4 - Enforcing contracts&nbsp;(23 percent)<br /><br />5 -&nbsp;Construction permits (21 percent)<br /><br />6 - Registering property (20 percent) <br /><br />7 - Trading across borders (18 percent)</p>
<p><strong>Government's most successful flagship programmes</strong></p>
<p>When asked about most government's successful flagship programmes, CEOs rated the following:<br /><br />1 - Smart Cities (58 percent respondents)<br /><br />2 - Jan Dhan Yojana (45 percent)<br /><br />3 -&nbsp;Skill India (44 percent) <br /><br />4 - Digital India (35 percent)<br /><br />5 - Start-Up Mission (27 percent) <br /><br />6 - Make In India (21 percent)</p>
<p><strong>How will GST rate slabs impact your industry</strong></p>
<p>- 47 percent believe GST rate to have a positive impact<br /><br />- 21 percent believe to have a negative impact<br /><br />- 20 percent believe to&nbsp;have neutral<br /><br />- 12 percent have no view on it</p>
<p><strong>India Inc ready for GST rollout in April</strong></p>
<p>On the question of GST rollout<br /><br />- 62 percent think that India Inc is partially prepared<br /><br />- 30 percent think not prepared<br /><br />- 5 percent think fully prepared<br /><br />- 3 percent have no opinion.</p>
<p><strong>Will GST provide for the expected boost to economy</strong></p>
<p>- 79 percent think that GST will provide the boost to the economy<br /><br />- 12 percent think unlikely<br /><br />-&nbsp;9 percent can&rsquo;t say.</p>
<p><strong>Does demonetisation validate government&rsquo;s commitment to fight black money</strong></p>
<p>On the question of demonetisation validate government's commitment<br /><br />- 52 percent respondents&nbsp;said that demonetisation will help government in fighting black money<br /><br />- 42 percent of them somewhat agree<br /><br />- 4 percent disagree <br /><br />- 2 percent have no view.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/f/forbes_356_3103_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-24 19:22:00</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>