<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-balanced-deal-for-private-equity-funds_8371501.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Balanced deal for private equity funds]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[It has been clarified that the clarification provided in Budget 2016 on benefit of concessional rate of 10% on transfer of shares of a private company (being long term capital asset) shall apply from 1st April, 2013.  ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Narendra Rohira</strong><br /><br />The Union Budget 2017 seems to be well balanced, bringing in a mixed bag of reforms in the Indian Direct Tax Law for private equity funds. &nbsp;<br /><br />The much awaited relief from indirect transfer provision has been provided to investors holding shares / interest in Category I and II Foreign Portfolio Investors (&ldquo;FPIs&rdquo;).<br /><br />The long existing ambiguity on whether conversion of preference shares to equity shares would be taxable transfer has been brought to rest by this budget.&nbsp; It has been proposed to include conversion of preference shares to equity shares in the category of &lsquo;transactions not regarded as transfer&rsquo; and the benefit of period of holding and cost of acquisition of preference shares should be available to equity shares.<br /><br />It has been clarified that the clarification provided in Budget 2016 on benefit of concessional rate of 10% on transfer of shares of a private company (being long term capital asset) shall apply from 1st April, 2013. &nbsp;<br /><br />With a view to align the India tax laws with OECD&rsquo;s Base Erosion and Profit Sharing and to prevent tax abuse on account of structured financing arrangements, thin capitalisation norms have been proposed by the Finance Minister.&nbsp; As per the proposed norms, allowability of interest expenses, where such interest exceeds INR one crore, claimed as deduction by a company (other than banks and insurance companies) and is paid to its associated enterprise shall be restricted to lower of 30% of its earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization (EBITDA) or interest paid or payable to associated enterprise.&nbsp; Balance interest, if any, will be allowed to be carried forward for a period of 8 years and will be allowed as a deduction in subsequent years to the extent of maximum allowable interest expenditure. <br /><br />At present, exemption from capital gains tax has been provided on transfer equity shares of a company if such equity shares qualify as long term capital asset and the transfer is subject to Securities Transaction Tax (&ldquo;STT&rdquo;).&nbsp; To prevent sham transactions and tax abuse, it has been proposed that the exemption shall be available only if the acquisition of share was subject to STT.&nbsp; However, to protect the exemption for genuine cases where the STT could not have been paid like acquisition of share in IPO, FPO, bonus or right issue by a listed company acquisition by non-resident, it is also proposed to notify transfers for which the above condition shall not be applicable.&nbsp; We would need to wait till the notification to understand which transfers are not covered and whether any conditions are attached to such notification. &nbsp;<br /><br />With a view of rationalise the provisions relating to deeming full value of consideration for computation of income under the head &lsquo;capital gains&rsquo;, it has been proposed to introduce a new provision wherein if the shares of a company (other than quoted shares) are transferred at a value lower than Fair Market Value (&ldquo;FMV&rdquo;) of such share, then the FMV shall be deemed to be the full value of consideration for the purpose of computing income.&nbsp; FMV shall be determined in a prescribed manner.<br /><br />The taxation on receipt of assets without or inadequate consideration proposed to be extended to all taxpayers (including companies, trusts and institutions) and to all assets (including immovable properties) w.e.f 1 April 2017. <br /><br />Separately, the areas that have not been touched upon in the Budget include clarifications of applicability of General Anti Avoidance Rules (GAAR) and clarifications on Place of Effective Management (POEM).&nbsp; Therefore, it appears that for now the clarification provided through a recently issued guidelines, circulars shall be the only guide.&nbsp; This leaves some other issues around availability of treaty benefits, etc open to discussion and interpretation.<br /><br />From an overall perspective, for private equity funds, the Budget 2017 seems to be a balanced one.<br /><br /><em><strong>The author is Tax Partner at EY India.</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>(Views expressed are personal)</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_2000_356x200_3919_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 15:57:10</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>