<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-passagegst-bill-markstectonic-policy-shift-fm_8373721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Passage of GST Bill marks a tectonic policy shift: FM]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Wednesday said that the government will stick to its GST rollout date on July 1.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sandeep Sinha<br />Moneycontrol</strong></p>
<p>FM informed the house that GST Council has finalised recommendations on all issues based on consensus following debate and discussion and added that the government will reach out to trade and industry bodies starting April 1, 2017 making them aware of the new taxation system.</p>
<p>He also said GST implementation will bring more taxes to the Centre and the states due to widening of tax net and that no changes will be made to excise and services as they will be replaced by GST soon. At the start of his speech, Jaitley said the country had undergone a transformational reform with the passage of the constitutional amendment to GST Bill and the progress for its implementation.</p>
<p>The Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Wednesday said that the government will stick to its goods and services tax (GST) rollout date of July 1.</p>
<p>GST aims to create a common national market by combining a web of local and central taxes into a single levy. Under this system, state governments had demanded that administrative, auditing and assessing powers be split between itself and central government. The latter subsequently agreed to this &ldquo;dual control&rdquo; or cross empowerment.<br /><br />The GST Council has agreed to a 4-tier tax structure of 5, 12, 18 and 28 percent. An additional cess would be levied by the Centre on luxury goods and harmful products like tobacco.</p>
<p>A total of 9 meetings have been held by the GST Council starting from September 22, 2017. The first GST Council meeting was held on September 22-23 in which the Centre and states agreed to set a timetable for deciding the tax rate and completion of legislative framework. In the last round of meetings held on January 16, the GST Council arrived to a consensus on the crucial issue of dual control and taxing rights of goods moved through high seas.</p>
<p>Some states like West Bengal, Tamil Nadu and Kerala were demanding full administrative control for taxpayers having revenue less than Rs 1.5 crore and seeking an equal share for taxpayers above Rs 1.5 crore.</p>
<p>Under dual control the Centre agreed to share in the ratio of 90:10 in favour of states and Centre on small taxpayers having revenue of Rs 1.5 crore or below. The next GST Council meeting is proposed on February 18 which is likely to cover some of the pending issues and hopefully able to resolve them.<br /><br /></p>
<p>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/Arun_jaitley_Finance_Minister_FM_356x200_4941_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 13:38:16</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>