<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-key-takeawaysfinance-minister-arun-jaitleys-speech_8389841.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Key takeaways from Finance Minister Arun Jaitley's speech]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley on Wednesday presented perhaps the most eagerly watched Budget in the recent past. Here are the key takeaways from his Budget speech.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong>&nbsp;<br /><br />Finance Minister Arun Jaitley present, perhaps the most eagerly watched budget in recent past. Here are the key takeaways on the implication from his budget speech:<br /><br />* Rising crude price, multiple interest rate hikes by the US Federal Reserves among the risks to the Indian economy<br /><br />* India still a bright spot in the global economic landscape. India expected to be among the fastest growing economies in 2017.<br /><br />* India has enough forex reserves to buy 12 months of imports<br /><br />*&nbsp;The effects of demonetisation is not expected to spill over next year. GDP growth though might be subdued in FY18 fiscal, growth can pick up in FY19 ahead of the next general election.<br /><br />*&nbsp;Focus will be on rural economy and poverty alleviation<br /><br />*&nbsp;Agriculture credit for 17-18 &ndash; Rs 10 lakh crore. Underserved areas will be focus. Expect the banking sector to be under pressure on account of increased outgo as this comes under priority sector<br /><br />* Fasal Bima Yojana &ndash; coverage to be increased from 30% to 40% in tcurrent year and 50% next year. Outlay has been more than doubled. Expect increased agriculture activity which will be good for seeds, fertilisers and pesticides companies.<br /><br />* A dedicated micro-irrigation fund with an initial corpus of Rs 5,000 crore. A good move to increase farm productivity and reduced water dependency. Step in increase contribution of agro economy to the overall GDP.<br /><br />* Modern law on contract farming will encourage corporate farming and bring in retailers and agri companies in the field<br /><br />*&nbsp;To bring 1 crore households out of poverty by attempting to increase livelihood. Good for consumer companies. <br /><br />* MNERGA outlay &ndash; 100 lakh ponds as against 5 lakh have been dug up. This is expected to remain at 5 lakh in the current year. MNERGA fund increased Rs 48,000 crore from Rs 38,500 crore (spent Rs 47,000 crore). Rural focus continues.<br /><br />* Positive for housing sector &ndash; Government has increased rural houses target to 1 crore and increased outlay to Rs 15,000 crore to Rs 23,000 crore <br /><br />* Rural expenditure has shot up by 24&nbsp;percent from Rs 1,87,223 crore &ndash; consumer and consumable companies should be happy with the increased allocation<br /><br />* Current account deficit declined to 0.3 percent of GDP &ndash; it has more to do with slowing imports and slowing domestic economy. Not something to be happy about. Rising crude oil prices can distort this figure going forward<br /><br />*&nbsp;Focus of government continues to be on skill training which should help overall employment and employability of youths. Positive for the overall economy.<br /><br />*&nbsp;Affordable housing will be given infrastructure status. Big positive for developers, banks and housing finance companies<br /><br />* Infrastructure status to housing finance companies would help reduce interest rates. This coupled with interest subvention scheme can go a long way in pushing low cost housing demand<br /><br />*&nbsp;Amendment of drugs and cosmetic rules for use of generic drugs. Medical devices will also be included under price control. Will impact pharma companies as prices of drugs goes down.&nbsp;<br /><br />*&nbsp;Senior citizen Aadhar based health card will be introduced. Though good for the elderly, it may not be taken well by pharma companies as geriatrics account for a significant portion of these companies sales.<br /><br />* Railway outlay at Rs 1.31 lakh crore of which only Rs 55,000 crore will be from the Budget. Not too good for the railways as they were facing issues raising funds. However, merging the rail budget with the Union Budget can give it some leeway, especially the savings on the special dividend paid to the government.
<p>* 25 stations to be redeveloped. Good for developers and infrastructure companies, though the size is too small in the overall scheme of things<br /><br />*&nbsp;Railway will introduce end-to-end solutions for some commodities. This can bring back traffic to railway but impact heavy commercial vehicles. LCVs will benefit as they will be involved in the last mile connectivity<br /><br />*&nbsp;Road sector &ndash; allocation increased from Rs 64000 crore to Rs 57676 crore. Good for the road sector as the surface transport ministy intends to speed up implementation from 30 km/day to 40 km/day.</p>
*&nbsp;Higher outlay for transport sector at&nbsp;Rs 24,1387 crore. Will benefit the overall sector which has a bigger multiplier effect<br /><br />* 20 GW of solar capacity to be installed. This will slowdown thermal power plant installations which have anyway taken a beating. However, the issue of base load purchases has not been addressed<br /><br />* Infrastructure outlay at Rs 3.96 lakh crore &ndash; positive for the sector. Implementation is key as projects are held up. No announcements of easing hurdles and getting some of the stalled projects moving<br /><br />*&nbsp;FIPB to be abolished. A big move for FDI investments in the country. Insurance, infrastructure and financial sector companies should benefit<br /><br />*&nbsp;Listing of PSUs &ndash; a revised mechanism to have a time bound listing. IRCTC, IRCON and IRFC to be listed. Positive for merchant bankers and good for the overall market and brokers as it increases depth<br /><br />* ETF will continue to be used as the vehicle of divestment. This is a good step as it helps cushion spikes in PSU stocks<br /><br />*&nbsp;Banks &ndash; Government commits an additional capital infusion of Rs 10,000 crore for state-owned banks over and above the Indradhanush scheme. &nbsp;The amount is too small given the stress in public sector banks<br /><br />* PM Mudra Yojana allocation to be doubled to Rs 121000 crore. This scheme has become one of the main source of funding in the economy as banks have stopped funding on account of stress in their banking system<br /><br />*&nbsp;Did the finance minister just hint at an oil sector merger by announcing a public sector mega oil entity? It is unlikely to go down well as centralized decision making had impacted performance of these companies earlier, since each company sources oil from different oil fields. Further oil companies in any case are picking up stakes in oil fields.&nbsp;<br /><br />* No more will offenders be allowed to flee as government introduces a law to confiscate assets of these offenders. Some teeth to the banking sector struggling to recover money.<br /><br />* Capital expenditure increased by 25.4 percent. States and UT transfer to the states is increased from 3.6 lakh crore to Rs 4.11 lakh crore. Focus is on decentralized growth, but implementation is key.<br /><br />* Defence expenditure at Rs 2.74 lakh crore is positive for the sector as the number excludes pensions. <br /><br />* Fiscal deficit target of 3.2 percent for FY18 and 3 percent in the following year is slightly better than expectation where analysts were expecting no change at 3.5&nbsp;percent<br /><br />* Net market borrowing lowered to Rs 3.48 lakh crore from Rs 4.25 lakh crore. Interest rates should fall as borrowing goes down. Good for banking stocks, particularly state own banks which will gain from the rise in bond prices&nbsp;<br /><br />* Demonetisation impact &ndash; base of tax payers to be widened as data reveals higher deposits of old currency notes as compared to returns filed. <br /><br />* Growth rate in net tax revenue is 17%, with 34.8% increase in advance tax &ndash; clear impact of demonetisation<br /><br />*&nbsp;Affordable housing funding &ndash; size increased to carpet area of 30-60 sq meters and extended to 5 years. Tax on unsold housing to be&nbsp;taxed at rental rates. Real estate price can come down as hoarding is being disincentivised<br /><br />* Witholding tax extended to ECBs and masala bonds till 2020<br /><br />* For startups there is good news as they will be taxed for 2 years out of 7 as compared to 5 years earlier<br /><br />* MAT credit extended to 15 year from 10 years positive for companies involved in higher gestation period<br /><br />* SME tax reduced to 25% for companies below Rs 50 crore sales -- to take care of GST impact. This will impact 96% of all companies in the country <br /><br />* Banking sector can disclose more NPAs as they will get tax exemption from 7.5% to 8.5%.<br /><br />* LNG import tax reduced &ndash; good for GAIL and Petronet<br /><br />* Focus on lower cash transaction &ndash; donations reduced to Rs 2000 and no transaction above Rs 3 lakh will be allowed. Good for digital economy with added benefit in widening tax net<br /><br />* Transparency in political funding takes a step forward &ndash; maximum cash donation to receive is Rs 2,000. Political parties will be entitled to receive donations in cheques. New electoral bonds to be introduced redeemable in a political parties name. A great step forward in cleaning up black money and tax avoidance<br /><br />*&nbsp;Personal income tax &ndash;Rate of taxation for those earning between Rs 2.5-5 lakh has been halved to 5 percent from 10 percent. Surcharge of 10 percent on those earning between Rs 50 lakh to Rs 1 crore. Not much relief given by the finance minister.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_356x200_4046_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 11:00:37</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>