<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/indian-factory-activity-returns-to-modest-growthjanuary-pmi_8389741.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Indian factory activity returns to modest growth in January: PMI]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Compiled by IHS Markit, the Nikkei Manufacturing Purchasing Managers' Index rose to 50.4 in January from 49.6. A reading above 50 indicates expansion.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Indian factory activity returned to modest growth in January, bouncing from a contraction in December triggered by the government's scrapping of high value banknotes, a business survey showed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Compiled by IHS Markit, the Nikkei Manufacturing Purchasing Managers' Index rose to 50.4 in January from 49.6. A reading above 50 indicates expansion.</p>
<p>In a sign factories have started the year on a better footing, a sub-index measuring new orders also nudged back above the breakeven mark, with domestic demand driving the pace as export orders remained in contraction.</p>
<p>"January saw only modest increases in order books, production and buying levels, but the quick rebound will be welcome news to policymakers," said Pollyanna De Lima, economist at IHS Markit.</p>
<p>"Improving confidence among firms bodes well for the outlook, with the expansion in manufacturing output likely to pick up pace in coming months."</p>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi's demonetisation drive in November banned 500 and 1,000 rupee bills, removing 86 percent of cash in circulation, in a bid to fight corruption and tax evasion.</p>
<p>The cash crunch is expected to hurt the economy in the October-December quarter of 2016, with economists predicting growth slowing to a near 3-year lows of 6.5 percent.</p>
<p>In December, the Reserve Bank of India unexpectedly left its key policy rate unchanged at 6.25 percent, opting to wait before judging the full effects of the currency ban.</p>
<p>But India's central bank is expected to go through with a rate cut in its meeting next week, with 29 of 46 economists in a poll conducted over the last few days expecting a 25 basis points cut.</p>
<p>India's government will unveil its Budget on Wednesday and is expected to try and boost economic growth through reducing personal income and corporate tax as well as higher public investment.<br /><br />Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBslQpB4onkHTB8Ei9quwBxDOyqg"> LIVE UNION Budget 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486012259354000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE3J8DU_uiR6ilTdJKHisn5k8cv_g"> Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/2/2017-02-01T050320Z_1_LYNXMPED101N8_RTROPTP_2_INDIA-ECONOMY-PMI_356.JPG]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 10:48:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>