<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2017-should-resolve-gst-issues-to-bring-back-growthreal-estate_8384961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Should resolve GST issues to bring back growth in real estate]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The government should make its policies centric to the affordable housing segment for the end use consumer.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Avinash Narvekar</strong><br /><br />Ever since coming into power in 2014, the Modi led government has not shied away from introducing reforms aimed at providing the much needed boost to the Indian Economy. Transformational reforms such as the Real Estate Regulation and Development Act (RERA), Foreign Direct Investment relaxations, Goods and Services Tax (GST), Benami Transactions (Prohibition) Amendment Act, 2016, relaxations in the Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs) regulations saw light of the day, making it imminent that the implementation of these reforms would result in building an Indian real estate sector which is more transparent, credible and attractive. Along with these radical reforms, digitisation of land records, change in arbitration norms for construction industry and setting up of a government committee to look into the strategic sale of government assets that include land and manufacturing units, could also play a pivotal role in positively impacting the Indian real estate sector. <br /><br />During the festive season, post the Income Declaration Scheme, the Modi government once again managed to steal the thunder through implementation of the highly controversial, demonetization initiative aimed at curbing &ldquo;black money&rdquo; in the economy. It may be recognized that while the jury is out on the long term impact on the economy, the short-term impact for the residential real estate sector was a reduction in overall transaction volume. <br /><br />With this backdrop, the Budget 2017 needs to walk the talk and show execution intent towards the government&rsquo;s objective of truly making it easier to do business in India. There is also a need to bring in a single authority to ease &lsquo;Digital India&rsquo; implementation and a well-structured innovation agenda/policy for &lsquo;Digital India&rsquo; to be a reality.<br /><br />The government should make its policies centric to the affordable housing segment for the end use consumer. While a regulator for the housing sector is long overdue, it needs to be ensured that the eventual State wise regulations are neither significantly diluted nor create unnecessary restrictions on ease of doing business for developers as this has the potential to ultimately increase the costs to the customer. Policies on standardization of major construction material also need to be addressed. Commencement of single window clearance for all requisite approvals could be one of the most vital initiatives for real estate sector.<br /><br />Though Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs) have been introduced, since they are still in the evolving phase, they have not yet been able to catch the investor&rsquo;s eyes. Budget 2017 could incentivize the sector by providing income tax exemption on swap of assets akin to swap of shares of asset company, removal of dividend distribution tax in two tier holding structures, allowing carry forward and set off of past business losses, stamp duty concessions on transfer of immovable properties (will require state government initiatives), thereby making REITs a viable and preferred investment platform. Ambiguity in respect of characterization of rental income has been a subject matter of prolonged litigation. With contradictory judicial decisions, law surrounding the same is not yet settled. The Finance Minister should introduce amendments addressing the issue and put an end to the controversy. <br /><br />Real Estate companies are presently evaluating the impact of the Goods and Services Tax (GST), which is likely to be implemented from June, 2017. Though it seems the Revised Model GST law has addressed certain aspects on taxability / valuation for various supplies, aspects concerning the real estate sector have still not been adequately addressed. The primary concern for the real estate sector is that while sale of under construction flats is made liable to GST, there is no mechanism provided to exclude the value of land for the purpose of determining taxable value as GST should not be applicable on portion relatable to sale of land. This deduction / abatement along with the rate of GST applicable for sale of flats would be a deciding factor for real estate companies and needs clarity.<br /><br />Further, while the construction of flats attract GST and there appears to be a free flow of input tax credit basis the revised model GST Law against the output tax liability, there are restrictions of availability of input tax credit against output tax liability on rental income from commercial properties. Since the GST regime is expected to provide for a free flow of input tax credit against output taxes, it is expected that the Government would address this issue.<br /><br />Implementation of these policies and addressing the open matters should give a boost to the currently struggling Indian real estate sector and aid in achieving a transparent real estate market in India coupled with strong economic growth. <br /><br /><em><strong>The author is Tax Partner of EY India</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>Himanshu Doshi, senior tax professional, EY also contributed to the article</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>(Views expressed are personal)</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/GST_356x200_2055_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 16:18:50</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>