<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rbi-may-effect-25-bps-rate-cutfeb-8april-bofa-ml_8292361.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[RBI may effect 25 bps rate cut on Feb 8, in April: BofA-ML]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[According to the global financial services major, further easing is likely as demonetisation is hurting growth while inflationary pressure is benign and the government is expected to target a conservative fiscal deficit of 3.5 percent of GDP.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Reserve Bank of India is expected to go in for a 25 bps rate cut at its next monetary policy meet on February 8 -- as also in April -- says a Bank of America Merrill Lynch (BofA-ML) report.</p>
<p>According to the global financial services major, further easing is likely as demonetisation is hurting growth while inflationary pressure is benign and the government is expected to target a conservative fiscal deficit of 3.5 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>"We grow more confident of our call of a 25 bps RBI rate cut on February 8 (and April) after release of latest CPI/WPI/ IIP data," BofA-ML said in a research note.</p>
<p>Incoming data show that demonetisation is impeding growth, BofA-ML said, adding that "old series GDP growth is already languishing at 4-4.5 percent".</p>
<p>BofA-ML has slashed its March inflation forecast to 4.6 percent (from 5.1 percent), which is well below RBI's 5 percent target and noted that an RBI rate cut will support the rupee by attracting foreign capital flows.</p>
<p>"We continue to expect CPI inflation to meet RBI's 5 percent March 2017 target. In fact, we have cut our March 2017 forecast to 4.6 percent from 5.1 percent," it added.</p>
<p>Retail inflation eased further to nearly 3-year low of 3.41 percent in December, reflecting weak demand as consumers grappled with cash crunch following demonetisation.</p>
<p>Rising prices of petrol and diesel fuelled WPI inflation to 3.39 percent in December 2016.</p>
<p>On December 7, the central bank kept interest rate unchanged despite calls for lowering it and lowered the economic growth projection by half a percentage point to 7.1 percent in the first policy review post demonetisation.</p>
<p>The central bank will hold its next monetary policy meet on February 8.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/r/RBI_0050_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-18 13:00:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>