<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/sensex-nifty-continue-to-drag-economic-survey-tabled_8380481.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Sensex, Nifty continue to drag; Economic Survey tabled]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The market continues to see selling pressure even after Economic Survey is tabled in the Parliament. The Sensex is down 93.26 points or 0.3 percent at 27756.30, and the Nifty down 40.70 points or 0.5 percent at 8592.05. 
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /><br />1:55 pm Economic Survey:&nbsp;</strong>Labour and tax reforms are needed to boost employment creation in apparel and leather sectors as the two segments can become vehicles for broader social transformation in the country, the Economic Survey for 2016-17 said today.<br /><br />Noting that in both apparel and footwear sectors, tax and tariff policies create 'distortions' that impede India gaining export competitiveness, the Survey said that there is a need to undertake 'rationalisation' of domestic policies which are inconsistent with global demand patterns.<br /><br />It noted that India has an opportunity to push exports from apparel and leather sectors since rising wage levels in China have resulted in China stabilising or losing market share in these products, recommending labour and tax reforms to make the country globally competitive.<br /><br /><strong>1:50 pm Economic Survey:&nbsp;</strong>The Economic Survey 2017&rsquo;s remarks on fiscal policy indicates that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley may stick to the fiscal consolidation roadmap in his Budget due tomorrow.<br /><br />The fiscal deficit target for FY18 is 3 percent of GDP, but most economists are expecting Jaitley to set a target anywhere between 3.0-3.5 percent, as the government looks to revive demand in the wake of demonetization.<br /><br />&ldquo;India&rsquo;s experience has reaffirmed the need for rules to contain fiscal deficits, because of the proclivity to spend during booms and undertake stimulus during downturns,&rdquo; the Survey notes.<br /><br /><strong>1:45 pm Result: </strong>State-run oil retailer Indian Oil Corporation's (IOC) Q3 profit grew by 28 percent sequentially to Rs 3,995 crore but missed analysts' expectations due to higher other expenses, excise duty and tax cost.</p>
<p>Revenue during the quarter increased 15.3 percent to Rs 1,15,644.92 crore from Rs 1,00,273.94 crore in September quarter, which was ahead of estimates.</p>
<p><strong>1:40 pm European markets:</strong> Markets in Europe opened lower Tuesday as investors focus on data and earnings while keeping an eye on U.S. President Donald Trump's immigration policy.</p>
<p>The pan-European Stoxx 600 was 0.02 percent lower.</p>
<div class="group-container ">
<div class="group">
<p>Trump's immigration ban continues to create public outcry across the world. Overnight, Trump fired the federal government's top lawyer after she denied implementing the travel restrictions. The tech giant Amazon said it is considering a legal challenge against the ban.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><strong>1:30 pm Result:</strong> Pune-based two-wheeler maker Bajaj Auto said profit in October-December quarter fell 4.7 percent to Rs 924.6 crore compared with Rs 970.6 crore in year-ago period. Better-than-expected operational performance and other income supported bottomline.</p>
<p>Revenue during the quarter declined 9 percent year-on-year to Rs 5,354.13 crore on lower sales volumes due to demonetisation.</p>
<p>The company sold 8.51 lakh units in the quarter ended December 2016, down 10.5 percent compared with 9.51 lakh units sold in same quarter last year as domestic as well as exports sales were down 5 percent and 17.5 percent, respectively.</p>
<p><strong>1:20&nbsp;pm Whats in Rail Budget?&nbsp;</strong>Reeling under a series of derailments, the Budget is likely to announce creation of a separate safety fund of about Rs 1 lakh crore over the next five years out of which Rs 20,000 cr will be earmarked for 2017-18, according to sources.</p>
<p>Railways will also miss the operating ratio target of 92 per cent and is likely to settle at about 94-95 per cent.</p>
<p>The Budget 2017-18 is likely to announce setting up of Rail Development Authority, a regulatory authority for the public transporter. The formation of High Speed Rail Authority with the selection of its managing Director and other directors is also likely to be announced.</p>
<p><strong>1:15 pm Rail Budget expectations:</strong> A safety fund of Rs 20,000 crore for railways reeling under a series of deadly derailments, development of new lines, station redevelopment and setting up of Rail Development Authority and High Speed Rail Authority will be in focus as Finance Minister Arun Jaitley presents the first Rail Budget subsumed in the General Budget tomorrow.</p>
<p>Going ahead with the government's reform agenda, Jaitley will discard the 92-year-long tradition of presentation of a separate Rail Budget and instead make it part of the General Budget earmarking a few paragraphs on the public transporter's finance, projects and the road map for the next fiscal.</p>
<p>Jailtley is likely to give more focus on infrastructure development such as new lines, doubling, station redevelopment, safety upgradation.</p>
<p><strong>1:10 pm Economic Survey: </strong>The Survey's GDP growth figure for the current fiscal is lower than 7.1 per cent the Central Statistics Office had forecast earlier this month.</p>
<p>The Survey lists some of the challenges that might impede India's progress. These include ambivalence about property rights and the private sector, deficiencies in state capacity, especially in delivering essential services and inefficient redistribution.</p>
<p><strong>Don't miss: <a class="bl_14" title="Tech Mahindra tanks 10% as visa wage hike may up earnings risk" href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/buzzing-stocks/tech-mahindra-tanks-10-as-visa-wage-hike-mayearnings-risk_8380221.html">Tech Mahindra tanks 10% as visa wage hike may up earnings risk</a><br /></strong></p>
<p>The market continues to see selling pressure even after Economic Survey is tabled in the Parliament. The Sensex is down 93.26 points or 0.3 percent at 27756.30, and the Nifty down 40.70 points or 0.5 percent at 8592.05. <br /><br />IT stocks are under pressure on visa reform bill. Stocks like TCS, Infosys and Wipro fell 3-5 percent while Tech Mahindra tanked 10 percent intraday Tuesday as minimum salary of H-1B visa holders is proposed to be more than double.<br /><br />The annual Economic Survey 2016-17 tabled in Parliament said India will at grow at 6.75 to 7.5 percent in 2017-18.&nbsp;The Economic Survey has also stated that India&rsquo;s fiscal experience has underscored the fundamental validity of the fiscal policy principles enshrined in the Fiscal Responsibility and Budget Management Act (FRBM) Act 2003.<br /><br />Data released at the beginning of the month showed that the economy will likely grow at 7.1 percent in 2016-17, 0.5 percentage points slower than the previous year&rsquo;s 7.6 percent expansion, underlining fears of an economy-wide cash-crunch due to demonetisation.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/BSE_Sensex_Budget_2017_sensex_nifty_356x200_0756_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-31 13:00:45</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>