<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-must-plan-for-income-transfer-to-lower-levels-pronab-sen_8313721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget must plan for income transfer to lower levels: Pronab Sen]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Adi Godrej, Chairman, Godrej Group, feels that cutting individual and corporate taxes is quintesential to stimulating the economy after the demonetisation led to consumption plummeting in the economy.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The upcoming Union Budget must plan for an income transfer from the rich to the lower levels, said Former Chief Statistician, Pronab Sen. He says the cash ban was the first attack on the privileged. He suggests the government not touch taxes this year as the implementation of the goods and services taxes is not very far ahead.<br /><br />'We need to keep income taxes where they are for now,' he says.<br /><br />He says there is a possibility that corporate taxes may be lowered, but, he is of the opinion that cutting corporate taxes may not help widen the tax base.<br /><br />However, Adi Godrej, Chairman, Godrej Group, feels that cutting individual and corporate taxes is quintesential to stimulating the economy after the demonetisation led to consumption plummeting in the economy.<br /><br />"The private sector lacks the funds to help revive the investment cycle," says Godrej.<br /><br />He expects the government to increase infrastructure spending and introduce more agriculture incentives to stimulate the country's rural economy.<br /><br />Sheshagiri Rao, Joint MD and CFO, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/steel-large/jswsteel/JSW01">JSW Steel</a> says a revival of the investment cycle is going to take time and the private sector alone cannot revive it. He adds that public expenditure is key to the revival of the economy. <br /><br />He opines that this year, the fiscal deficit is going to be a range and not a number.<br /><br />"Keeping the fiscal deficit low has a long-term advantage," says Godrej.<br /><br /><em><strong>Latha Venkatesh: This budget comes in the wake of an unprecedented currency swap or demonetization that has pained some sections and that has slowed an already sluggish economic recovery. So the questions we are asking in this three part series is should the fisc stimulate the economy? How can it stimulate the economy? How much can it stimulate the economy? Joining me today are two top corporate honchos, Adi Godrej, Chairman Godrej Group and Sesagiri Rao, Joint MD and Group CFO, JSW Steel. We will also be joined by well-known economist Pronab Sen, Former Chief Statistician and Advisor to the Planning Commission. <br /> <br /> Q: First up do you think growth has come back after a brief dip in November or do you think the economy is desperately in need of stimulus?<br /> <br /> Godrej: I think the fisc in the next financial year will be excellent for two major reasons. One is, the GST will come into play from July 1 and GST should in my view add tremendously to government revenues. I know they have estimated that they have to subsidise the states to a certain extent but we must remember that the way the GST is structured, it will lead to huge collections because evasion of indirect taxes will become extremely difficult. So, I think that will help the fisc. <br /> <br /> Secondly the collections post demonetisation into the banks have been very large. A lot of it will be found to be not money that was officially tax paid with the concerned persons. So the new schemes will come into play and I think the government will get a lot of revenue from that. Perhaps the Finance Minister in his income tax calculations could put that approximate amount in and that could then be spent to stimulate the economy. I think the economy needs tremendous stimulation because the GDP growth rate has slowed down. It needs to be revived very quickly. <br /> <br /> General economic conditions need to be revived to create employment and I think the Finance Minister will do that by both cutting taxes and raising government expenditure.<br /> <br /> Q: A lot of corporate honchos tell us that the government should do public investment to stimulate the economy. However just look at the record in the current year, the government announced that it would do 15000 kilometres of roadways but as of today the NHAI has been able to bid out only around 5000 kilometres. Maybe by end of the year it will be 7000 kilometres but still it is less than half of what was intended. Do you think there is a bandwidth issue over here?<br /> <br /> Rao: If you see the investment cycle for the last two years, it is yet to pick up. Private sector will take some more time. So, therefore pump-priming of economy through public expenditure is the need of the hour. So, government has to increase the outlays on the infrastructure spending. I feel that is essential to bring back the private sector gradually over a period of time. So, that is why everybody is looking forward to the government in the next Budget that they will put more outlays on the government spending either directly or through public sector undertaking.<br /> <br /> Q: Even in the year currently underway, the government had put in a lot of outlay on railways and on road sector. By far the road sector was seen as the more efficient sector with Nitin Gadkari in charge. However at the start of the year the NHAI told us that they intended to build 15000 kilometres. As of date they have actually bid out less than 5000 kilometres. So, it is extremely unlikely that they will go past probably 7000 kilometres, which means not even half. There is a bandwidth issue here. Do you still think that FY18 can deliver what FY17 has not?<br /> <br /> Rao: If you compare year after year there is definitely an acceleration and improvement. So, it is an upward sloping curve. So, increase in expenditure if it has to be translated into execution and the investment cycle coming back, that will take some time. Private sector is not in a position today to commit additional funding for bringing back the investment cycle and also due to some structural issues in each of the sectors in India, there is a need for public sector to spend that amount. However it is showing an improvement, I don&rsquo;t say that 2015-16 versus 2014-15, there is definitely an improvement even in the road sector. It may not translate to the extent which we all desire it to happen.<br /> <br /> Q: Precisely in these kind of areas the companies which ought to be participating &ndash; contractor companies, developer companies, are themselves fairly heavily laden with debt. Under such circumstances would you say that it should be entirely driven by the PWD departments of the government, state or centre? Considering that private sector is not in any position to take over more leverage?<br /> <br /> Rao: Here also I think there is a transformation which is happening in the construction sector. The established players in those segments, there are certain issues for them to take the projects and then commit more funding pending release of money by the government, whereas new players are coming into those areas. So, I don&rsquo;t think that will be a problem for the contractors to come in. What the contractors either existing or new players are looking to the government is to release the payments in a timely manner, thereby their dependency on the external banking sector or any other source of funding will be limited and their interest costs will not go up. That is what the sector is expecting. <br /> <br /> I don&rsquo;t think there is any problem in the new players coming in. We are seeing a huge amount of interest coming in in the construction sector from the new players.<br /> <br /> Q: Since you alluded to the GST, should you expect an increase in service taxes because you want to bring it on par with the GST?<br /> <br /> Godrej: It could be but it is only 3 months to go or 4 months to go for the GST. So, I think he will raise service taxes to a certain extent because the GST rates on service taxes will be higher than they are at present. While I expect the GST rates on goods to be considerably lower than the current sum of the excise duty plus the state VAT. <br /><br />Q: Since you believe that the economy needs stimulus and the government will have the elbow room for stimulus, let me come to the next question. How would you want it to be given? Would it be more investments in roads and railways, basically public investments, public utilities or would it be that you would prefer them to boost consumption in some form? If yes, which way? <br /> <br /> Godrej: Both. A combination of both. Clearly, boosting consumption will be important and that could be done by reducing the taxation rates, both individual taxation and corporate taxation. That will lead to a lot of stimulation of the economy, both in terms of investment and consumption. But, expenditure can also help tremendously and the government might add to infrastructure expenditure and could do something to stimulate the rural economy by incentives for agriculture.<br /> <br /> Q: Would you mind if the deficit reduction timetable is violated? If the deficit were to be higher than last year, you think the government should go that far to stimulate?<br /> <br /> Godrej: Keeping the deficit down is of great long-term advantage, both in terms of ratings for the country, also in terms of interest rates, inflation, etc. it is a good path to follow. But from what I understand, they are going to have a range for the fiscal deficit target rather than an exact fiscal deficit target which I think, is a positive change.<br /> <br /> Q: What is your sense? Do you think the government should stick to fiscal discipline no matter what the urge to stimulate?<br /> <br /> Rao: I have a different view as far as the fiscal deficit is concerned. As I mentioned to you, entire India Inc or any Indian today, looking towards the government to pump-prime the economy, either in social sectors or in the investment sectors. If that is the need of the hour, instead of focusing on 3 percent, managing the fiscal deficit for 2017-2018 or restricting the government borrowing to 46 percent of the total GDP, I do not think that should be the focus. <br /> <br /> The way Reserve Bank of India is giving the range of inflation targeting like plus-minus 2 percent, in my view, as per the recommendation of one of the committees that even fiscal deficit should be in a range instead of looking at a number that it should be 3 percent or 3.25 percent. If it is in the range of 3-3.5 percent, they will have enough fiscal space to meet the requirements of the current environment. That is what I feel the government is likely to do in the Budget than looking at exactly the 3 percent they would manage. Based on the flow of tax revenues and also other revenues of disinvestment or non-tax revenues, increase or reducing the expenditure, this they will continue to manage. But this space should be available by having a range, in my view, as regards to fiscal deficit. That is what the government would do, in my view.<br /> <br /> Q: In our previous edition of mapping the stimulus, I did have a member of the Fiscal Responsibility and Budget Management (FRBM) panel. While he obviously did not divulge anything that they are going to recommend, that will be privy to the government, he did indicate that it does not make sense to borrow and stimulate the economy. He seemed personally opposed to the idea. But from your own personal point of view, JSW Group and companies like yours are big borrowers from the market. If the government were to become a big borrower, a bigger borrower than it was last year and so would the state government, would it not make money expensive for you? So is it in your own interest that fiscal deficit targets be violated?<br /> <br /> Rao: Raising is not a bad idea either for a company or for a government, as long as that additional funding is being used for creating productive investments and there is a return on that investment.<br /> <br /> Q: But will it not make money expensive for people like you if the government were to borrow big?<br /> <br /> Rao: The point is it is not necessary that the pool of total savings are remaining same. Today, financial savings in my view will grow going forward. More and more money coming into the banking system and into the organised sector. So with that kind of money, I do not think there will be a crowding out effect. And also, the global savings, India is very attractive. There is another source of funding which would be available. So, with that in view, I do not think there would be a problem with fiscal deficit if it increases. Government borrows a little more than what generally they do. That will crowd out entire private sector investment. I do not think that may be a right assumption.<br /> <br /> Q: In terms of taxes, what would be your top expectations or requests?<br /> <br /> Rao: As regards to overall tax policy is concerned, structurally we should move more towards direct taxes than towards indirect taxes. That shift has to happen. Instead of increasing the indirect taxes every time and then burdening even the common man, therefore direct tax collection should increase by increasing the base. And at the same time, direct tax collection to increase does not mean that the taxes will have to go up, only base has to increase. So, as corporate India is concerned, what we are expecting is a reduction in the corporate taxes, removing all the cesses and also rationalisation of indirect taxes. This is what the India Inc is looking at, but the base and monitoring system and ease of monitoring the collection of taxes, that should facilitate going forward. <br /><br />Q: We just spoke to two corporate honchos and they see a strong rationale for corporate taxes getting lowered in the Budget. The main reason being that industry&rsquo;s sentiment is running low, especially after demonetisation. Do you agree that there is a case for lower corporate taxes?<br /> <br /> Sen: Lower corporate taxes, yes. But, the point is that is it politically feasible? After all, what has happened has essentially been an attack on the rich and the privileged. Now, to announce a corporate income tax cut would probably be running against the stream. The question that really should be asked is whether or not personal income taxes be cut. Frankly, if the objective is to widen the tax base, this is not the time to do it. You let the tax base widen and then take a call on revising the exemption limit, possibly in next year&rsquo;s Budget.<br /> <br /> Q: So your point is stay pat on taxes for the moment, watch how GST plays out, watch how demonetisation and its impact on direct taxes and corporate taxes plays out and then play your cards next year?<br /> <br /> Sen: It is not how it plays out. The real benefit of demonetisation is an enormous increase in the amount of information that is available with the tax authorities. The point is that between now and the Budget, the tax authorities will simply not be in a position to process the data and actually start issuing notices to people for taxes. So, you need to first have a feel for what is the expansion of the tax base and it is better done from ground zero than change the goal post and then do not really know whether you have expanded your tax base or not.<br /> <br /> Q: In that case, what is your advice to the government or expectation from the government on the tax front in this Budget?<br /> <br /> Sen: On the tax front, the Finance Minister had indicated that there was, in the new terminology, a glide path to lower corporate taxes. That is not a bad thing to follow, but keeping in mind as I said the political repercussions of that, which I am not qualified to judge.<br /> <br /> On income taxes, I would say keep them where they are. On indirect taxes, you need to be a lot more careful because GST has to happen by September and the sensible thing to do is to align at least the central taxes with the GST rates so that the central government at least is ready to kick off the GST whenever it thinks appropriate. So, on the tax front, that is pretty much what I would do and stop. In so far as expenditures are concerned, that we can debate endlessly.<br /> <br /> Q: I was coming to that. What would your advice be on expenditure? There is one set which wants the government to stimulate expenditure. You just spoke about the lower echelons of society suffering because of demonetisation. What kind of expenditure therefore, would you ask for or advise?<br /> <br /> Sen: Again, all expenditures, much more so than tax have a huge political message that goes with it. If I were the Finance Minister, I would really think seriously about some new direct benefit transfer (DBT) form. It does not have to be the universal basic income, but some form of income transfer is legitimate and would mitigate the kind of pain that people have suffered.<br /> <br /> That apart, the question really depends upon what you want to do on the infrastructure side. Clearly, infrastructure has to be strengthened. You could do it one of two ways. One is, you could put money in large, high visibility projects like the superfast trains and so on or the national highway development or you could put it into smaller quick turnaround localised projects like rural housing, like the rural roads programme and so on. Now which way the coin drops, I do not really know because that is a political call. It is not really an economic call.<br /> <br /> Q: But, if it were a pure economic advice, what would it be?<br /> <br /> Sen: I would say go for quick turnaround projects where you can support the demand side. At the moment, there are some voices which say that you do not need to do a demand stimulus, what you need to do is to clean up the supply side. I am completely in sympathy with that point of view. The problem of course is that the demand side is broke as well, so you have to do both. You cannot do one and not the other.<br /> <br /> Q: Then comes the mother of all questions. Can the government afford to set aside the fiscal deficit timetable? Can it go from 3.5 percent deficit to 3.6 percent deficit?<br /> <br /> Sen: All of these timetables are contingent on the assumption of continuity that things are moving smoothly. Let us face facts. The demonetisation has been a serious discontinuity in the system. There are other discontinuities that are happening around the world which are going to play out. Therefore, at this point in time to be a stickler for fiscal rules would be silly. It would be much more sensible for the government to take a call on saying that given the situation today, what is it that we should be doing in order to get the economy back to normal. Once you are normal, then let the fiscal correction play out. <br /></strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget2017_Budget_2017_Feb1_Budget2017_356x200_4248_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-20 18:32:53</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,JVS,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>