<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-nda’s-mission-antyodaya-to-lift-10-million-outpoverty_8388381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: NDA’s Mission Antyodaya to lift 10 million out of poverty]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[“Over Rs 3 lakh crores are spent in rural areas every year, if we add up all the programmes meant for rural poor from the Central Budget, State Budgets, Bank linkage for self-help groups, etc,” Jaitley said in his budget speech.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>Finance minister Arun Jaitley on Wednesday announced the introduction of the &ldquo;Mission Antyodaya&rdquo;-- an ambitious programme aimed at lifting 10 million families out of poverty.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Over Rs 3 lakh crores are spent in rural areas every year, if we add up all the programmes meant for rural poor from the Central Budget, State Budgets, Bank linkage for self-help groups, etc,&rdquo; Jaitley said in his budget speech.</p>
<p>&ldquo;With a clear focus on improving accountability, outcomes and convergence, we will undertake a Mission Antyodaya to bring one crore households out of poverty and to make 50,000 gram panchayats poverty free by 2019, the 150th birth anniversary of Gandhiji,&rdquo; he said.</p>
<p>The government, Jaitley said, will utilise the existing resources more effectively along with annual increases. This mission will work with a focused micro plan for sustainable livelihood for every deprived household.</p>
<p>A composite index for poverty free gram panchayats would be developed to monitor the progress from the baseline.</p>
<p>This will be done through addressing all the parameters of poverty and constantly measuring them on a scale of multiple indices based on data collated through the Socio-Economic Caste Census (SECC).</p>
<p>According to the SECC data, which was released in 2015, nearly one of three 180 families in India&rsquo;s villages&mdash;or about 31.2 percent of the rural population&mdash;are poor with an income hardly enough to buy even the bare essentials.</p>
<p>The SECC analysis used an &ldquo;exclusion-inclusion&rdquo; method count the poor, different from the erstwhile Planning Commission&rsquo;s consumption and calorie intake-based estimates.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;Mission Antyodaya&rdquo; push in Budget 2017 is aimed at offsetting demonetisation&rsquo;s negative fallout in villages, while also addressing longer-term poverty alleviation issues.</p>
<p>The economy-wide drain out of the old Rs 500 and R1,000 notes have hurt many landless rural households. The cash-crunch had slowed down production forcing factories and construction companies to retrench semi-skilled and unskilled employees who have returned to villages in search of work.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/n/NArendra_Modi_Switzerland_qatar_356x200_4219_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 20:04:48</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>