<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-to-bring-positive-structure-to-economy-anil-sardana_8403341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017 to bring positive structure to economy: Anil Sardana]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Anil Sardana, MD & CEO, Tata Power is of the view that the efforts that the government has undertaken to bring a positive structure into the economy by moving towards a policy based administration with an increased focus on digitisation.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Anil Sardana, MD &amp; CEO, Tata Power</strong></p>
<p>"We commend the efforts that the government has undertaken to bring a positive structure into the economy by moving towards a policy based administration with an increased focus on digitisation. The government&rsquo;s commitment to rural electrification and the announcement of an additional 20,000 MW of solar target is a welcome step that gives a much needed boost to the renewable sector. However, we believe that for renewable sector to achieve its potential strengthening the Renewable Purchase Obligations (RPO) mechanism is essential and should be part of government&rsquo;s larger vision for renewable energy."</p>
<p>"The move towards improving electricity access to rural India will be instrumental in contributing to the social and economic development of the country. Tata Power will also continue to amplify government&rsquo;s initiatives for rural development, as we partner with surrounding communities. The increased budget for the Deen Dayal Gram Jyoti Yojana will strengthen and uphold the ongoing work of feeder separation and sub-transmission &amp; distribution infrastructure. This is a positive step towards augmenting the reliability and quality of supply distribution network which is affected due to poor financial health of discoms."</p>
<p>"We are hopeful that our long pending demand that the electricity sector will be included in the GST regime will soon set into a roll-out stage."</p>
<p>"Further, the reduction of individual taxation rates and provision to increase taxation net alongside clarity in taxation processes are also positive moves and we applaud the government&rsquo;s efforts in initiating these reforms. We are also in support of this government&rsquo;s reforms directed towards curbing corruption and bringing about a transparent system."</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_356x200_4046_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 09:13:17</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>