<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-i-t-officials-get-more-teeth-track-tax-evaders_8401301.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: I-T officials get more teeth track tax evaders]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[This Budget has also given authority to more income tax officials to exercise their power in case of any inquiry or probe, "without seeking prior approval of higher authorities".]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>The government on Wednesday said income tax officials will now have greater authority to track down tax evaders, in its attempt to clamp down on black money.</p>
<p>An official from income tax department may carry out "search and seizure", if he has "reason to believe" or "reason to suspect", according to budget document for 2017-18.</p>
<p>The government, in addition, has widened the scope of tax authorities' power to survey, any place, including, where any charitable activity is being carried on.</p>
<p>"The existing provisions empower an income-tax authority to enter any place, at which a business or profession is carried on...for the purposes of conducting a survey. It is proposed...to include any place, at which an activity for charitable purpose is carried on," the government said.</p>
<p>This change will come into effect from April 1, 2017.</p>
<p>This Budget has also given authority to more income tax officials to exercise their power in case of any inquiry or probe, "without seeking prior approval of higher authorities".</p>
<p>From April 1, a joint director, deputy director and assistant director can conduct inquiries, even without the prior approval senior officials such as the Principal Director or Director or the Principal Commissioner.</p>
<p>In addition, the government has empowered the Central Board of Direct Taxes to issue notice asking information and documents required for verification of tax payer's information in its possession.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/t/tax_356X200_0855_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 20:25:15</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>