<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/india-favourite-investment-destination-eye-budget-well-fargo_8347141.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[India favourite investment destination, eye Budget: Well Fargo]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Brain Jacobsen of Well Fargo Funds Management is expecting tax cuts, income transfer to poor as well as boost for consumption and investment both in the Budget slated for February 1. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[India continues to be Well Fargo Funds Management&rsquo;s favourite investment destination. Brian Jacobsen of Well Fargo&rsquo;s is hopeful that in the upcoming Budget, Prime Minister Narendra Modi will be able to rekindle economic enthusiasm. <br /><br />Jacobsen is expecting tax cuts, income transfer to poor as well as boost for consumption and investment both in the Budget slated for February 1. <br /><br />&ldquo;If they (government) do not have an eye on the near-term to prop-up consumption and do transfers to the poor and keep another eye on the long-term to make those long-term investments, this Budget might be viewed as a failure of it does not accomplish all of those goals,&rdquo; he added. <br /><br />Globally, he said that the US dollar is likely to strengthen in 2017. Growth in emerging markets is looking better than the weak global growth. <br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Brian Jacobsen&rsquo;s interview to Latha Venkatesh on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: First up, I want to remind you that I spoke to you in February, 2016 and at that time, the Indian markets were in the doldrums. Despite a global recovery, the Indian markets did not recover up until March. But you said that you would bet big on India. The bet worked. Now, we are about one week from the Indian Budget. What is your sense? Will India pay investors well this year in 2017?</strong><br /><br />A: Yes, believe it or not, India still remains one of my favourite areas to invest, not just in the emerging markets but even just in the global markets. Everybody is hotly waiting for the Budget to be unveiled on February 1. <br /><br />There are some expectations that we are going to see a little bit of some subsidy or tax cuts for the working class individuals who were hit hard by the recent demonetisation programme. So, we will have to see what some of the details are as far as what it is that Prime Minister Modi is going to do to try to rekindle some of the economic enthusiasm that may have been dampened a little bit as a result of demonetisation.<br /><br /><strong>Q: You are right that expectations are running high, but what would your idea be of what the Budget ought to do? Should it go the consumption way and cut taxes at the lowest level so people spend? Should it do some kind of an income transfer for the economically deprived or should it go big on investment?</strong><br /><br />A: I actually, unfortunately think that they need to take in all hands on deck sort of an approach here meaning that it has to do a little bit of all of it. It has to be not only cuts in taxes for consumption as a result of the slowdown that resulted because of demonetisation. Also, some income transfers for those most poorly off in the society, but still make room for investment. <br /><br />So, in a way, unfortunately, Prime Minister Modi has to give the best of all possible worlds to investors and to the country. I think it is actually somewhat encouraging that with demonetisation, it is likely that they will have increased revenue in order to actually meet some of these objectives. <br /><br />But, if they do not have an eye on the near-term to prop up consumption and do transfers to the poor and keep another eye on the long-term to make those long-term investments, this Budget might be viewed as a failure of it does not accomplish all of those goals.<br /><br /><strong>Q: What if he were to renege on the fiscal deficit timetable? The fiscal deficit target for the current year, year underway, was 3.5 percent and looks like the government will meet that. Next year, for FY18, it is expected that they have to bring it down to whatever 3-3.2 percent. If he did not, would you take that badly?</strong><br /><br />A: I personally would not only because almost everything is changing in India&rsquo;s result of demonetisation. Also, we have to keep an eye on what is going on with trade policy globally that if they back away a little bit from some of the fiscal prudence in lowering the deficit, people might give them a little bit of a pass provided that part of the reason why they are missing is because there is that long-term investment for growth and that there is a longer term plan to get the deficit under control. <br /><br />A 3.5 percent fiscal deficit is not the greatest thing, but it is also not the end of the world when it comes to Budget deficits across the global economies here. So, if he has to back away from that a little bit, investors might give him a pass.<br /><br /><strong>Q: But, would you buy India debt in that case assuming the fiscal deficit is at 3.5 percent, there would be more bonds out there from the government? Will you back India bonds? Is it likely that market rates or yields go up?</strong><br /><br />A: We would see yields move up and as a result, I would shy away from the debt. However, if you think about the RBI, they just recently announced that they were going to be purchasing some of those perpetual bonds that were outstanding. The coupon there was around 9.4 percent. <br /><br />So, there is the possibility that they could do some refinancing of some of the debt. But my personal preference is to look at equities as opposed to the debt. And it is not just in India. It is actually across all emerging markets mainly because this is outside of India&rsquo;s control. Globally, yields are just going to slowly march higher here for the next year or two.<br /><br /><strong>Q: That is a good point at which I can ask you about the financial ambience as well. The last quarter of 2016 did see this long developed markets (DM) and short emerging market (EM) trade. Is it turning with the dollar index (DXY) now dipping towards 100? Do you think that trade is now over or has it only taken a breather?</strong><br /><br />A: It has taken a little bit of a breather here. It is possible that the US dollar is going to continue to trade a little bit stronger for the balance of the year. I do not see a lot of downside for the value of the US dollar. However, the going long developed markets and going short emerging markets, I do think that that has turned and it is not simply because it is a strong dollar versus weak dollar story. It is a strong growth versus a weak global growth story. <br /><br />The evidence is building that emerging markets, their growth is beginning to accelerate. Obviously, you have a little bit of an exception as far as the fourth quarter, with demonetisation and the hit that is going to have on the Indian economy. But I think they will bounce back pretty handsomely from that. A lot of the policies being pursued in many emerging markets and even in the US should further economic growth and build economic momentum as the year goes on.<br /><br /><strong>Q: So, you might see net foreign institutional investor (FII) inflows this year, the first half itself into India, into emerging markets?</strong><br /><br />A: I do think that we could see that and obviously a lot of it depends on investor sentiment which is a difficult thing to gauge, but we are seeing early indicators at least from US investors when you look at the flow of money going into whether it is developed markets or emerging markets that people are developing more of an appetite for emerging market equities. <br /><br />We are seeing that in some of the aggregate data and India is going to be a beneficiary of that. One of the key reasons is if you look at the conversation that Prime Minister Modi and President Trump had, President Trump referred to Prime Minister Modi and the people of India as good friends and partners and any sort of changes in trade policies that we are going to see in the US are not necessarily going to adversely affect the Indian economy. If anything, India might be kind of close to the front of the line as far as being able to negotiate favourable trade deals with the US.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Then what would you bet on in India? What sectors? What stocks?</strong><br /><br />A: The two specific sectors that I really like in India would be the industrials and healthcare and for somewhat different reasons. Like industrials, mainly because I think Prime Minister Modi is going to continue on with infrastructure development and trying to improve productivity growth in India. <br /><br />So industrial companies are probably going to reap the benefit of that. They also have the opportunity to export more to the US. A lot of emerging markets were hit hard with the prospect of having the borders of the US closed to them. But that border is not going to close to Indian exports, especially on the industrial side. <br /><br />Now, healthcare is another area that I like because healthcare is going to require further investment with public health expenditures in India, so sort of domestic led, people are demanding better service from hospitals and from pharmaceutical companies, biotechnology and the such. <br /><br />But also, President Trump has said that he wants to open up the US market to more negotiation with pharmaceutical prices. And Indian companies might be able to position themselves to help keep costs under control in the United States. So, it is both a domestic and an exports story for healthcare companies in India.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Why not financials? There are some people who even are betting on one or even some rate cuts from the RBI.</strong><br /><br />A: I do think that financials are interesting. It is just one of those things where once bitten and twice shy as far as with looking at the financials. I was expecting that we would see some recapitalisation programme dealing with the non-performing loans and we have not seen that yet unfortunately. <br /><br />Even if there is a rate cut, the rate cut itself might not be enough to sustained change the trajectory of the prices of a lot of the financials. They really have to deal with those non-performing loans on their balance sheets. A rate cut could be beneficial, but that might be more of a flash in a pan than a change in the trajectory.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_356x200_3121_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-25 22:30:14</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>