<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-divestmentidbi-bank-is-not-offtable-says-anjuly-duggal_8400101.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Divestment of IDBI Bank is not off the table, says Anjuly Duggal]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Going ahead all profit making CPSEs are expected to go to the market and that there is a lot of appetite for new exchange traded funds (ETFs), says Neeraj Kumar Gupta, Secretary, DIPAM.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The government today announced in the Union Budget that it hopes to raise Rs 72,500 crore in FY18 by divesting stakes in public sector firms. Compared to the revised estimate of Rs 45,500 crore for FY17, this is an increase of around 60 percent.</p>
<p>This financial year the government plans to achieve the target amount by raising Rs 46,500 crore via minority stake sale, Rs 15,000 crore through strategic stake sale and Rs 11,000 from the listing of various insurance companies.<br /><br /><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-fm-sets-fy18-divestment-target-at-rs-72500-crore_8374881.html">Govt seeks to raise Rs 72,500 cr via divestment, up 60% YoY</a></p>
<p>In an interview with CNBC-TV18, Neeraj Kumar Gupta, Secretary, DIPAM said that the current divestment figure stands at Rs 31,000 crore for FY17.</p>
<p>He further said that going ahead all profit making CPSEs are expected to go to the market and that there is a lot of appetite for new exchange traded funds (ETFs).</p>
<p>In the same interview, Anjuly Chib Duggal, Secretary, Financial Services said that the divestment of IDBI Bank is not off the table as banking is included in the merger and acquisitions activity FM Arun Jaitley spoke of.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch video for more.</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/a/Arun_jaitley_budget_2017_economy_356x200_0134_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 20:18:05</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>