<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-provides-impetus-to-manufacturing-export-infra-nirmala_8402861.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget provides impetus to manufacturing, export infra: Nirmala]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Budget "provides renewed impetus to manufacturing and Make in India, export infrastructure and government e-marketplace," she said in a statement.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Budget 2017-18 has provided an impetus to manufacturing, export infrastructure and government e-marketplace, Commerce and Industry Minister Nirmala Sitharaman said.</p>
<p>She said that Finance Minister Arun Jaitley has announced several measures for the ministry.</p>
<p>The Budget "provides renewed impetus to manufacturing and Make in India, export infrastructure and government e-marketplace," she said in a statement.</p>
<p>The measures include proposed scheme for creating employment in leather and footwear industries, further liberalisation of FDI policy and abolition of the Foreign Investment Promotion Board (FIPB).</p>
<p>"The long standing demand of startups has been accepted and the profit (linked deduction) exemption available to them for 3 years out of 5 years is changed to 3 years out of 7 years," she added.</p>
<p>MAT (minimum alternate tax) credit is allowed to be carried forward up to a period of 15 years instead of 10 years at present.</p>
<p>She said: "For creating an eco-system to make India a global hub for electronics manufacturing, a provision of Rs 745 crores in 2017-18 in incentive schemes like M-SIPS and EDF. The incentives and allocation has been exponentially increased following the increase in number of investment proposals".</p>
<p>She also said that inverted duty has been rectified in several products in the chemicals, petrochemicals, textiles, metals and renewable energy sectors.</p>
<p>Infrastructure a key pillar under the Make in India programme has been strengthened with a large budgetary allocation, the minister said, adding measures for MSMEs would make them more competitive.</p>
<p>The outlay for the department of commerce for 2017-18 has pegged at Rs 4,465.83 crore, down from Rs 4,562.74 crore in the revised estimate for the current fiscal.</p>
<p>However, in case of the Department of Industrial Policy and Promotion (DIPP), the outlay has been increased to Rs 3,608.87 crore for 2017-18 as compared to Rs 2,016.26 crore in the revised estimate for the current fiscal.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/e/export-356_5702_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-02 08:34:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>