<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-focusfiscal-consolidation-key-skepticaltransaction-tax_8388321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: Focus on fiscal consolidation key; skeptical of transaction tax]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Economist, Jahangir Aziz, Asia Economic Research, JPMorgan thinks the government will stick to the path of fiscal consolidation of around 3.2 to 3.3 percent. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Today is government&rsquo;s D-day, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley will unveil Union Budget 2017 at 11 am.Market is watching is watching with baited breath on what will be the government&rsquo;s fiscal deficit target, divestmentplans,announcement on the taxation front and a lot more.
<p>Minister of State for finance, Santosh Gangwar is of the view government stick to consensus expectations. Speaking to CNBC-TV18 he said all decisions will be made for the benefit of people</p>
<p>Economist, Jahangir Aziz, Asia Economic Research, JPMorgan thinks the government will stick to the path of fiscal consolidation of around 3.2 to 3.3 percent. However, he is very skeptical of transaction taxes because he thinks it will mess up transmission process as the intention is to change the economy based on cash transaction to digital transactions.<br /><br />The market will be disappointed if there are changes in the tax structures, said Arvind Sanger of Geosphere Capital. <br /><br />He said the other challenges that the government faces are bad debt, recapitalizing the banking system. There is a fear among investors regarding the possibility of the classification of sshort-termcapital gains as business income. Sanger says that the market will react negatively on this and this is not the time to throw such headwinds at investors. <br /><br />According to Sanger, the biggest challenge for the government is global headwinds- US protectionism, UK leaving European Union (EU). The government, this Budget and beyond that, has to work on how to make India's internal growth robust when global backdrop is not favourable, he said.&nbsp;<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch accompanying videos for more details.<br /></strong></em></p>
<p>Read more: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/live-union-budget-2017-18-rural-wages-unaffected-by-demonetisation-says-nomura_8387981.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486010854175000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEdyKoKLx2Og6E-8WMONHUL67FUZw"> LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES</a></p>
<p>Follow: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1486010854175000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFWl3cZRaK3xhZKvcIwFsgoiElU_Q"> Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></p>
<p><em><strong>&nbsp;</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_rupee_budget_356x200_5221_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 08:38:58</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>