<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/sensex-nifty-jittery-as-budget-countdown-starts-maruti2_8389781.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Sensex, Nifty jittery as Budget countdown starts; Maruti up 2%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Shares of Maruti Suzuki, the country's largest car maker, touched a record high of Rs 5,980, up 1.4 percent intraday after showing a 27 percent increase in January sales despite demonetisation.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>The market is jittery ahead of Budget speech. The final countdown to the Budget begins and all eyes are on how Finance Minister Arun Jaitley projects taxes and spending post demonetisation. Most analysts feel the Budget 2017 is likely to have a pro-poor focus. The market will watch for govt's FY18 fiscal deficit target, divestment plans, announcement on the taxation front among others. The market expects govt to relax its FY18 fiscal deficit target of 3 percent.</p>
<p>The Sensex is down 1.26 points at 27654.70, and the Nifty down 7.40 points at 8553.90. About 1159 shares have advanced, 964 shares declined, and 180 shares are unchanged.</p>
<p>Shares of Maruti Suzuki, the country's largest car maker, touched a record high of Rs 5,980, up 1.4 percent intraday after showing a 27 percent increase in January sales despite demonetisation.</p>
<p>The company sold 1.44 lakh units in the month gone by, against 1.13 lakh units sold in year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>The growth was driven by exports as well as domestic sales.<br /><br /><strong>Posted by Nasrin Sultana</strong><br /><br /><strong><a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/NasrinzStory" data-show-count="false">Follow @NasrinzStory</a></strong>
<script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script>
</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/BSE_Sensex_Budget_2017_jaitley_Sensex_356x200_0605_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 10:30:23</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>