<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2017-fm-proposes-agri-sector-outlayrs-10-lakh-cr-for-fy18_8369821.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2017: FM proposes agri sector outlay of Rs 10 lakh cr for FY18]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley Wednesday, announced a spate of initiatives in the agriculture sector with an increased outlay of Rs 10 lakh crore for FY18 as he presented the Union Budget for 2017-18.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau&nbsp;</strong><br /><br />Finance Minister Arun Jaitley Wednesday announced a spate of initiatives in the agriculture sector with an outlay of Rs 10 lakh crore for FY18 as he presented the Union Budget for 2017-18.<br /><br />Focus will be on providing adequate and seamless flow of credit to farmers, particularly the small and marginal ones, Jaitley said. Towards this objective the government will work towards computerisation of NABARD.&nbsp;</p>
<p>To cover farmers from losses due to&nbsp;natural calamities the crop insurance coverage under the Fasal Bima Yojna will be increased from 30 percent of cropped area to 40 percent in FY18 and 50 percent&nbsp;the year after.&nbsp;<br /><br />The government&rsquo;s demonetisation exercise in November had proved detrimental for farmers, many of whom were left stranded with little or no cash to buy seeds right in the middle of the sowing season. While it later allowed buying of seeds with the old Rs 500 notes from outlets administered by the government and public sector units, the damage was done.</p>
<p>As agriculture together with allied sectors like livestock, forestry and fishery accounts for over 15 percent of the country&rsquo;s gross value added, experts were anticipating steps to revive demand.</p>
<p>The FM also reiterated on the other initiatives that had already been&nbsp;announced over the last&nbsp;few months. To trim final borrowing rates for farmers, NABARD's lendable corpus pool was expanded by Rs 20,000 crore from the current Rs 20,000 crore to allow the refinance agency to lend at cheaper rates to rural banks. More than 40 percent of small and marginal farmers' loan needs are met through the cooperative credit structure, which will benefit through this additional resources.</p>
<p>Besides, in his post-demonetisation address on New Year&rsquo;s Eve, Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced transformation of 3 crore Kisan Credit Cards to RuPay debit cards in the next three months. The government also waived off the interest for 60 days on existing farm loans for the latest Kharif and Rabi crops. The waived amount will be directly transferred to the farmers' bank accounts.</p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;">Read more:</span></strong><span class="apple-converted-space"><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;">&nbsp;</span></strong></span><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;"><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/budget-2017-game-changing-taxes-will-provide-sense-of-direction-edelweiss_8388701.html" target="_blank">LIVE UNION BUDGET 2017-18 UPDATES<span style="color: blue;"><br /></span></a></span></strong></p>
<p style="font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; word-spacing: 0px;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;">Follow:</span></strong><span class="apple-converted-space"><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;">&nbsp;</span></strong></span><strong><span style="font-size: 10.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; color: black;"><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/budget-2017/" target="_blank">Moneycontrol Budget Page</a></span></strong></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/Budget_2017_Budget17_356x200_3456_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-02-01 11:35:48</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>