<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/post-budget-mergerwill-fm-havestore-for-railways_8250181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Post Budget merger, what will FM have in store for Railways?]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The proximate reason for the abandoning the 92-year-old practice of a separate railway budget from 2017-18 may have been hastened by the state-transportation giant's delicate balance sheet.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The government has approved plans to merge the railway budget from 2017. By making the railway budget a part India's main budget, the government has signalled its intent to walk the talk on freeing the state-owned behemoth from having to deal with stressed finances and political populism.<br /><br />The proximate reason for the abandoning the 92-year-old practice of a separate railway budget from 2017-18 may have been hastened by the state-transportation giant's delicate balance sheet.<br /><br />A combined budget could imply that the Indian Railways can avoid setting aside funds for dividends of about Rs 10,000 crore to the government every year.<br /><br />Once the budgets are merged, the financial stress can be moved to the Centre's overall annual financial plan.<br /><br />Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu has been arguing that a combined budget will allow a seamless national transportation policy, insulating the railways from political pressures.<br /><br />Passengers may have to shell out more for travelling by train as the railway ministry may impose a specific cess on train tickets to fund the Rs 1.20 lakh crore safety fund-- Rashtriya Rail Sanraksha Kosh.<br /><br />While fares for AC one-tier and two-tier are likely to see a marginal increase, passengers travelling on second class and AC three-tier could be hit harder because of a proportionately lower fare base.<br /><br />An announcement on imposing a safety cess on train fares is likely to be announced in the budget for 2017-18]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Railways_Railways2016_suresh_prabhu_356x200_3259_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-01-11 20:59:07</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>