<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/cong-to-launch-week-long-anti-gst-campaigndelhijul-30_9320961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Cong to launch week-long anti-GST campaign in Delhi on Jul 30]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[It will stage demonstrations at all the 42 major markets across Delhi to "raise awareness on the adverse effects" of the Goods and Services Tax (GST) on the people, Delhi Congress chief Ajay Maken said at a press conference.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Delhi Congress will launch a week-long anti-GST campaign on July 30 at all the major markets of the city, intensifying its agitation against the "wrong implementation" of the new tax regime, it said today.<p></p>It will stage demonstrations at all the 42 major markets across Delhi to "raise awareness on the adverse effects" of the Goods and Services Tax (GST) on the people, Delhi Congress chief Ajay Maken said at a press conference.<p></p>He claimed that the implementation of GST in its present form by the Narendra Modi government had "adversely affected" the small and medium traders as well as consumers.<p></p><p></p><strong>How GST Will Change Your Life</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>Treatment in hospitals would become costlier and education expenses would also go up under the new tax regime, which was rolled out on July 1, claimed the Congress leader.<p></p>The cost of building houses would increase by one-thirds, the tax on the sale of old vehicles would go up by 43 per cent and prices of fertilizers would also witness a rise, he claimed.<p></p>"The Wrong implementation of GST will not only put an additional tax burden on the people but also lead to price rise and large-scale unemployment," said Maken.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-24 22:29:21</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>