<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/gst-launch-is-outcomecommitment-to-federal-structure-bjp-chief-amit-shah_9193601.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST launch is outcome of commitment to federal structure: BJP chief Amit Shah]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[With the help of the GST, the backward states, the poor and the oppressed will help get uplifted. I hope the people of the country will welcome it open heartedly, he said.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[BJP president Amit Shah tonight said the "historic" launch of the GST was an outcome of commitment to the country's federal structure under the leadership of Prime Minister Narendra Modi.<p></p>Congratulating the prime minister, finance minister Arun Jaitley and the state governments, he said the GST will not just bring in one tax across the country, but also give a big boost to the economy, reduce burden on citizens and help the poor immensely. The important tax reform which the country has been waiting for a decade-and-a-half is beginning today, he said after attending the midnight function in Parliament organised for rollout of the Goods and Services Tax (GST).<p></p>"Congratulations to PM Narendra Modi and FM Arun Jaitley for implementing the historic, long pending and much needed tax reform - GST.<p></p>"'One Nation-One Tax' is today a reality, an outcome of commitment to India's federal structure under leadership of PM Narendra Modi," he tweeted.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p></p><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Congratulations to PM Shri <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi">@narendramodi</a> and FM Shri <a href="https://twitter.com/arunjaitley">@arunjaitley</a> for implementing historic, long pending and much needed tax reform - GST. <a href="https://t.co/z3nlNbkEFI">pic.twitter.com/z3nlNbkEFI</a></p><p></p>— Amit Shah (@AmitShah) <a href="https://twitter.com/AmitShah/status/880857303615913984">June 30, 2017</a></blockquote><p></p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script><p></p>He also congratulated all chief ministers and governments along with Modi and Jaitley.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p></p>"One Nation-One Tax" is today a reality, an outcome of commitment to India's federal structure under leadership of PM Shri <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi">@narendramodi</a>.<p></p>— Amit Shah (@AmitShah) <a href="https://twitter.com/AmitShah/status/880857406728581120">June 30, 2017</a><p></p></blockquote><p></p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script><p></p>"With this, India has become one market of 125 crore people now. With the help of the GST, the backward states, the poor and the oppressed will help get uplifted. I hope the people of the country will welcome it open heartedly," he said.<p></p>The GST, the biggest tax reform of the country since independence, was ushered in at midnight, marked by a programme in Parliament which was attended by President Pranab Mukherjee, Vice President Hamid Ansari, Modi, Lok Sabha Speaker Sumitra Mahajan and a host of ministers, and MPs.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/a/amit-Shah_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-01 02:45:12</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>