<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/sushil-modi-led-panel-to-investigate-gstns-technical-hiccups_9688421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Sushil Modi-led panel to investigate GSTN&#39;s technical hiccups]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[This panel was formed after many state ministers, also members of the GST Council, had pointed the distress caused y the taxpayers of their states when filing their return under GSTN.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>A five-member panel led by the Bihar deputy chief minister Sushil Kumar Modi will meet on Saturday to examine why the IT system of the Goods and Services Tax Network (GSTN) could not handle tax filings during July, <a href="http://www.livemint.com/Politics/6oPxnkGmNYXQbtoicY1IeO/Sushil-Modiled-panel-to-look-into-GSTNs-technical-troubles.html">reports</a> the <em>Mint</em>.<p></p>Due to technical snags, the council had to extend the deadline for filing July returns by a month to October 10. Many businesses and traders could not see the taxes paid on the system and were not even able to change certain information.<p></p>These are major issues which need to be resolved as the matching of invoices to ensure appropriate placement of credits can only happen after such issues are fixed.<p></p>The panel was formed after many state ministers, also members of the GST Council, had pointed the distress caused to the taxpayers of their states when filing their return under GSTN.<p></p>The Council has given extra four more months for filing a summary return for the month of July, the original deadline for which was the August 25.<p></p>Sushil Modi told <em>Mint </em>the focus is on identifying main issues in the system and finding solutions for them. However, a finance ministry official said that the problem encountered are just teething issues and not any issue with the GSTN system.<p></p>Chhattisgarh minister for commercial taxes Amar Agarwal, Karnataka agriculture minister Krishna Byregowda, Kerala finance minister Thomas Isaac and Telangana finance minister Etela Rajendar are also a part of the panel.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/D/Deal-1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-09-15 12:00:21</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>