<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/govt-directs-packaged-goods-manufacturers-to-solve-gst-led-mrp-puzzleads-revised-price-stickers_9210941.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt directs packaged goods manufacturers to solve GST-led MRP puzzle with ads, revised price stickers]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In case the price of the prepackaged commodity increases due to GST, manufacturers will have to publish advertisements to intimate masses about the MRP revision]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The Narendra Modi government is leaving no stone unturned to ease confusion and allay fears prevailing among the masses pertaining to the implementation of the Goods and Services Tax (GST).<p></p><strong>Smooth Rollout</strong><p></p>Day after Cabinet Secretary PK Sinha held a meeting to review market situation after GST’s rollout, Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia reiterated that the government has asked secretaries to constantly monitor the supply of essential commodities. A 15-member Central Monitoring Committee to assess the situation and report anomalies, Adhia said.<p></p>A feedback and action room has been set up in the North Block where the Committee will oversee a reports from about 175 joint secretary and additional secretary-level officers. These officials assess how GST implementation is faring across the country with each supervising a block of 4-5 districts.<p></p>GST Explained In 30 Seconds<p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_hGu28LswM" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life After July 1<p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p><strong>Solving the MRP Puzzle<p></p></strong>The new tax regime, the biggest economic reform since Indepedence, leads to revision of commodities such as packaged foods — the MRP for some going up, while reducing for others. The government has said that manufacturers should intimate masses about any revision in MRP, Consumer Affairs Secretary Avinash Srivastava said.<p></p>In case the price of the prepackaged commodity increases due to GST, manufacturers will have to publish advertisements to intimate masses about the MRP revision, Srivastava said. Thereafter, manufacturers will have to promptly send sticker which has the new MRP to retail outlets where the commodity is sold, he added.<p></p>When GST reduces the price of a commodity, no advertisement is required, Srivastava said. Manufacturers will only have to send stickers with revised prices, he added.<p></p><strong>GST Registration</strong><p></p>Adhia said the government has cleared 39,000 of the 2.29 lakh applications it received for GST registration till Tuesday. The remaining applications will be "deemed approved" in the next three working days, he added.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/H/Hasmukh_Adhia_revenue_Secretary_Adhia_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-04 16:44:47</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>