<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/gstinternational-freight-to-make-air-cargo-non-competitive-industry-body_9294301.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST on international freight to make air cargo non-competitive: Industry body]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Freighters were not liable to pay any tax under the service tax regime, while now they have to pay 18 per cent GST.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Levying GST on international freight is likely to make air cargo "non-competitive", an industry body said.<p></p>Freighters were not liable to pay any tax under the service tax regime, while now they have to pay 18 per cent GST.<p></p>"Subjecting international freight at 18 per cent GST is totally unfair as it will stifle the growth of air cargo.<p></p><p></p><strong>Air India On A Wing And A Prayer</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0AamaokM-rA" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>"Why would the Government of India want Indian exporters to pay extra 18 per cent GST on freight and make our goods non-competitive in international market," PHD Chamber of Commerce and Industry said in a release.<p></p>The release was issued after an Air Cargo Summit organised by it here today.<p></p>PHD Civil Aviation Committee's co-chairman Vipin Vohra said air cargo service providers cannot claim input tax credit for freight from overseas paid for in foreign currency whereas exporters can.<p></p>"This has led to a lot of confusion," Vohra, who is chairman of Continental Carriers, told PTI.<p></p>He also said the industry has made several representations to the ministries of civil aviation and finance on the issue but is yet to get any clarification.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/c/cpec-china-pakistan-economic-corridor-xi-jinping-nawaz-sharif-pakistan-china_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-20 08:05:29</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>