<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/form-to-claim-past-credit-under-gst-expectedtomorrow_9502321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Form to claim past credit under GST expected from tomorrow]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[As GST return forms did not have a column for claiming transitional input credit, the government yesterday gave some breather to such taxpayers by giving them an extra week till August 28 to file returns.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[GST tax portal is likely to offer from tomorrow forms to claim credit on sales made before the rollout of GST which the taxpayers have to file by August 28, a government official said today.<p></p>As GST return forms did not have a column for claiming transitional input credit, the government yesterday gave some breather to such taxpayers by giving them an extra week till August 28 to file returns.<p></p>These taxpayers will, however, have to pay taxes by August 20 on the portal of the GST Network (GSTN)- the IT infrastructure provider for the new indirect tax regime.<p></p>While GSTR 3B is the form for filing GST return, TRANS I is the form in which the businesses will have to give the details of credit that they are claiming for payment of taxes before the rollout of GST.<p></p>"The transitional form is almost ready and we are working to upload it by tomorrow so that businesses can start filing TRANS I," a senior revenue department official said.<p></p>Yesterday, the finance ministry had said the TRANS I form will be available on the GSTN website from August 21.<p></p>Giving relaxation to the businesses that need to claim transitional input tax credit, the ministry yesterday allowed them to deposit taxes on the basis of self-assessment by August 20, but gave them one more week till August 28 to file return.<p></p>The taxpayers who do not claim any transitional input tax credit will have to necessarily pay tax and file return in Form 3B before the due date of August 20.<p></p>Over 71.30 lakh excise, service tax and VAT payers have  migrated to the GSTN portal. Also, 15 lakh fresh registrations have happened on the portal.<p></p>For an easy compliance, the GST Council has allowed businesses to initially file their returns on self-assessment basis in the first two months of the GST rollout.<p></p>So, GST returns for July and August will be filed on GSTN portal by filling GSTR 3B form. Return filing commenced on August 5.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/shutterstock_549852313_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-18 15:39:13</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>