<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/businesses-can-edit-august-september-gstr-3b-returnsnovember-20_10082581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Businesses can edit August, September GSTR-3B returns from November 20]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The initial sales return in the Goods and Services Tax (GST) regime is filed by businesses in form GSTR-3B.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[GST Network will launch a facility for businesses to make changes to their August and September GSTR-3B return forms beginning November 20, Bihar Deputy Chief Minister Sushil Modi said today.<p></p>The Modi-led Group of Ministers (GoM), set up to look into GSTN glitches, also met <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software/infosys/IT">Infosys</a> Chairman Nandan Nilekani.<p></p>Nilekani assured them that GSTN will work smoothly, Modi said after the fourth meeting of the GoM here today.<p></p>He said Infosys has added 100 engineers for the project in the last one month. Now, 621 Infosys IT engineers are working on GSTN.<p></p>Besides, the technology major has deployed 30 resident engineers all over the country to coordinate between state commissionerates and GSTN.<p></p>The GoM has tasked GSTN, the company handling the IT backbone for the new indirect tax regime, to develop taxpayer friendly utilities so that they are interactive in nature.<p></p>Every utility should have the option for preview, edit, validation, pop-ups, specific error message and print and the GSTN along with Infosys will develop it, Modi said.<p></p>The initial sales return in the Goods and Services Tax (GST) regime is filed by businesses in form GSTR-3B.<p></p>While taxpayers were allowed to make changes in July GSTR-3B return form, the facility was not available for subsequent months.<p></p>About 2 lakh return filers were stuck because of this non-availability.<p></p>It has been decided that by November 20 the editing facility for GSTR-3B returns for August and September will be launched by GSTN, Modi said.<p></p>He said after the last GST Council meeting in Guwahati, about 80 per cent of the issues relating to rates have been resolved.<p></p>Now, simplification of processes and procedures needs to be done which GSTN will do in collaboration with Infosys, Modi added.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-11-18 18:28:05</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,IT,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>