<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/fearinspector-raj-making-small-businesses-waryregisteringgstn_9224661.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Fear of Inspector Raj making small businesses wary of registering on GSTN]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Simple requests by distributors to retailers for their Aadhaar card number submission for registration is seen with suspicion.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Anubhav Sahu</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol research</strong><p></p>Since the beginning of this month, the FMCG sector has been realigning operations with Goods and Services Tax integration requirements and grappling with new guidelines almost on a daily basis.<p></p><strong>Big boys ready</strong><p></p>In the run up to GST, large FMCG manufacturers and distributors had been working with various ERP vendors and consultants for about a year and this seems to have paid off partially. Most of the manufacturers have rolled out their ERP versions successfully on time and few have started billings and transactions.<p></p>Our interactions with the FMCG companies suggest that pre-GST de-stocking has reduced channel inventory to approximately 20 days across the sector (from usual 3 months). With systems in place, companies are hopeful on speedier restocking of goods from hereon.<p></p>However, our channel checks in the Tier-1 &amp; 2 cities and rural hinterland suggest that GST integration and the goods offtake is contingent on some key factors.<p></p>Downstream channels continue to grapple with issues related with integration to GST network, lack of awareness and a fear of “Inspector Raj”. A major <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personal-care/hindustanunilever/HU">HUL</a> agency owner from eastern UP expressed his helplessness over this issue. Inventory at the distributor level is 1/3rd of the average inventory level. While goods offtake from the registered big retailers, wholesalers have started, there is obviously no sale to retailers, many of whom are still not registered in GST network.<p></p><strong>Small traders – worried about the past</strong><p></p>Simple requests by distributors to retailers for their Aadhaar card number submission for registration is seen with suspicion. Particularly retailers who had not registered their TIN under state VAT, earlier, are fearful that old records and work practices would be questioned by the tax authorities. Others who had a TIN number but were under reporting sales or managing their way out of the tax network have their obvious concerns.<p></p>The general perception about a typical sales tax official is also not helpful. Small vendors, retailers fear that if they approach officers for help on GST, chances are that they may be asked to disclose earlier accounts thereby making them vulnerable to penalties.<p></p><strong>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>This widespread fear and apprehension would be detrimental to volume offtake. Distributors are getting new consignments but many of them may not be able to clock even 50 percent of their usual transactions in this month (July).<p></p><strong>GST clarification on transition stocks – important but impractical</strong><p></p>On the recent guidelines from the government on consumer goods sector, reaction of the industry is mixed. While government has allowed for the phasing out of old stock by end of September, it has puts in few conditions if the new MRP rate is higher – advertisements in two newspapers, use of stickers etc.<p></p>FMCG companies are taking stock of the guidelines which may be favorable in cases where tax rates have increased. However, this has to be weighed in terms of logistical challenge of labelling millions of stock units already in the supply chain. Some players like Godrej Consumers and Bajaj Corp are revisiting their pricing strategies. Interestingly, HUL has reportedly declined to take this relaxation and would continue with old prices for the old stocks. Thus, it is ready to bear the higher tax incidence for categories where tax has increased which may be partially offset through adjustments in sale offers.<p></p>@anubhavsays]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/shutterstock_549852313_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-06 20:31:52</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,HL,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>