<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/politics/pm-narendra-modi-hits-out-at-congress-for-criticising-gst_10136301.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi hits out at Congress for criticising GST]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Resuming his campaign for the assembly polls in his home state, Modi also accused the Congress of taking credit and political mileage over minor schemes, like providing hand-pumps, while saying that the BJP rule brought major projects like the Narmada project for the benefit of the people.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Attacking Congress vice president Rahul Gandhi for calling GST 'Gabbar Singh Tax', Prime Minister Narendra Modi said here today that those who looted the country could only think of dacoits.<p></p>Resuming his campaign for the assembly polls in his home state, Modi also accused the Congress of taking credit and political mileage over minor schemes, like providing hand-pumps, while saying that the BJP rule brought major projects like the Narmada project for the benefit of the people.<p></p>"Those who have looted the country can only think of dacoits," he said addressing a rally at Morbi in Saurashtra, which votes in the first phase of state Assembly elections on December 9.<p></p>Gandhi had earlier dubbed the Goods and Services Tax 'Gabbar Singh Tax', recalling the iconic villain in the Bollywood blockbuster "Sholay".<p></p>Attacking the opposition party, Modi said, "The Congress' development model was giving hand-pumps. For BJP it is the SAUNI scheme (the Narmada water project for Saurashtra region), where we will fill dams of Saurashtra through huge pipelines."<p></p>Modi had on Monday pushed the BJP's campaign in Gujarat into high gear by addressing four back-to-back rallies.<p></p>The elections to the 182-member Gujarat Assembly will be held in two phases on December 9 and 14. The counting of votes will be on December 18.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/N/Narendra-Modi_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-11-29 12:41:11</Entry_Date><Category>Politics</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>