<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/durable-makers-may-not-passhigher-tax-burden-to-consumers_9196341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Durable makers may not pass on higher tax burden to consumers]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The consumer durables industry is expecting only a marginal price revision despite the category being placed under the highest tax slab of 28 percent under GST, as players look forward to the festive season in the coming months.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The consumer durables industry is expecting only a marginal price revision despite the category being placed under the highest tax slab of 28 percent under GST, as players look forward to the festive season in the coming months.<p></p>The festive season accounts up to 35 percent of the consumer durables sales.<p></p>"In the short-to-mid-term, I see the fundamentals remaining the same. Though consumer durables industry is being taxed at 28 percent, which is slightly more than what the previous tax structure, I don't anticipate any major price increases in the coming months," BSH Household Appliances MD Gunjan Srivastava told PTI.<p></p>The tax rate for the sector was around 25-27 percent, which has been hiked to 28 percent under GST.<p></p>"I expect the prices to remain constant at least in the initial period before people understand what how much is the additional cost. But, that would take some time for people to accurately measure. We are also approaching the festival season, so the industry will like to moderate it," he added.<p></p>Godrej Appliances business head Kamal Nandi expects prices to go up by 1-2 percent which could impact demand in the short-run but expects it to pick up during the festive season.<p></p>"Home appliances have become a necessity now with evolving consumer lifestyle and a lower tax slab would have made appliances more affordable in a low-penetrated market.<p></p>"With 28 percent tax under the GST, we expect the consumer price of home appliances to marginally go up by 1-2 percent. This could have an impact on demand in the short- run," he said.<p></p>"Normal monsoons and the resultant boost to the agricultural economy and hike in allowances to government employees will propel demand during the forthcoming festive season," he added.<p></p>Panasonic India Chief Financial Officer Manish Gupta said they expect a revision in prices of a select category.<p></p>"We are expecting the primary sales to retailers from companies to pick up from the second week of July," he said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/G/GST_Goods_and_Services_Teax1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-02 14:58:13</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>