<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-clarifiesgstnewspaper-ad-space-sale_9536261.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt clarifies on GST on newspaper ad space sale]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[GST of 5 per cent will be levied if the advertisement agency works on principal to principal basis -- buys space from the newspaper and sells such space for advertisement to clients on its own account, a finance ministry statement said.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Space selling for advertisement in print media will attract 18 per cent GST if an agency does so as an agent of a newspaper on commission basis, the government said today.<p></p>GST of 5 per cent will be levied if the advertisement agency works on principal to principal basis -- buys space from the newspaper and sells such space for advertisement to clients on its own account, a finance ministry statement said.<p></p>As an illustration, if a newspaper sells a unit of space worth Rs 100 to an advertisement agency for Rs 85 (after a trade discount of Rs 15) and the agency sells the space to client at Rs 100, the newspaper would pay 5 per cent GST on Rs 85 and the advertisement agency a similar amount of tax on Rs 100.<p></p>However, if the advertisement agency sells space for advertisement as an agent of the newspaper on commission basis, 18 per cent GST would be levied on the sale commission it gets.<p></p>The newspaper would have to pay 5 per cent GST on the revenue earned from space selling but can avail of input tax credit for the tax paid by the advertisement agency on commission received.<p></p>"However, if the advertisement agency supplies any service other than selling of space for advertisement, such as designing or drafting the advertisement, and such supply is not a part of any composite supply, the same would be liable to tax at the rate of 18 per cent," the statement said.<p></p>If such supplies are part of any composite supply, the rate applicable for the principal supply shall apply.<p></p>"Therefore, everything depends on the terms of the contract between the newspaper, advertisement agency and the client," it added.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-24 09:05:07</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>