<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/view-how-gaar-gst-will-forever-changeway-indians-pay-tax_9359341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[View: How GAAR, GST will forever change the way Indians pay tax]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[This is how your employee compensation structure might be affected after the rolling out of the General Anti-Avoidance Rule (GAAR) and the Goods and Services Tax (GST)….]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The salaried class has a huge share in the individual income tax collection in India accounting more than 50% of the income declared in individual tax returns.<p></p>However, sometimes those who know the ropes end up evading tax by exploiting the loopholes of the system. And in order to avert it, the government has now introduced new provisions such as the General Anti-Avoidance Rule (GAAR) and the Goods and Services Tax (GST). These new game changers can have a significant effect on the way you are compensated.<p></p>General anti-avoidance rule (GAAR) is basically an anti-tax avoidance Rule framed by the Department of Revenue with an aim to counter the arrangements made for the avoidance of tax.<p></p>Every taxpayer of the country (from an individual to a company or a foreign investor) comes under the ambit of this rule. The income tax department has been endowed with the authority to forfeit any such arrangement which has been implemented with a sole purpose of saving tax and has right to even levy interest and penalty on the culprit.<p></p>On the other hand, goods and services tax (GST) is a comprehensive, multi-stage, destination-based indirect tax on services and goods that will be levied on every value addition.<p></p>However, the government has introduced some provisions that would definitely affect an employer-employee relationship and would have an on the way an employee is compensated.<p></p>This is how you were paid until now.<p></p>The most popular salary structure is the Cost To Company (CTC) which includes the gross salary (before any reduction) paid by the employer. It is then broken down into several parts like basic salary, Home Rent Allowance (HRA), Travel Allowance (TA), Dearness Allowance (DA), Children Education Allowance and many more.<p></p>Besides this, an employee might also be given a car, for personal as well as professional use, if he complies with the admissible rules under the law. Some components of the CTC are tax friendly and the employee can choose the ones as per his tax planning.<p></p>However the above category of salary structure is gaining popularity and is being adopted by various authorities, there is another type of compensation module which is currently in prevalence and that is the salary and perquisites. This type of salary structure is more popular in government and public sector enterprises, where perks are being paid as per the hierarchical position of the employee.<p></p>Nevertheless, no matter which of the above two methods have been adopted by your employer, it’s is quite certain that your compensation structure will be revamped now that these two long awaited changes have been made in the tax system.<p></p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e83AV2d3Uq8?ecver=1" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><p></p><strong>This is how you may get affected</strong><p></p>After much deferment by the government, the GAAR was finally implemented from the beginning of the current financial year to offset the losses that are borne by the country due to various arrangements made only with an aim to avoid tax.<p></p>However, most of the salaried individuals can still be allayed as the GAAR comes into play only when the aggregate Tax benefits to all the parties to the arrangement in a particular tax year overlap the limit of Rs 3 crore. Since, most of the tax benefits for an individual are within this threshold, it is quite unlikely to have an effect on employee subjected to these benefits. However, the employer can still be haunted by the revenue department and held responsible and even probed if any discrepancy is found in tax deduction.<p></p>Similarly, according to the finance ministry any gift, worth over Rs 50 thousand, made without consideration would be subjected to GST, when “made in course or furtherance of business”. However, the services provided by the employee to the employer will not attract any GST.<p></p>Besides this, the perks paid as per the contractual agreement will be out of the ambit of GST. Accordingly, benefits such as membership of club, fitness centre, gym etc. will not be taxed under the GST if the applicable tax has been paid by the employer at of procuring these services. Besides this, the housing facility provided by an employer to his employee will also be outside the purview of The GST.<p></p><strong>Conclusion</strong><p></p>As per the press release by the finance ministry, the benefits endowed to the employee which are clearly articulated in the contract will not attract any GST. However, the ambiguity regarding the treatment of the benefits which are not propounded in the employment contract still prevails.Nonetheless, the new rules buttress the accustomed principle of “substance over form” and it is really critical for an employee to be well versed of all the provisions of his contract to ensure that he is locked and loaded well in advance.<p></p>Nonetheless, the new rules buttress the accustomed principle of “substance over form” and it is really critical for an employee to be well versed of all the provisions of his contract to ensure that he is locked and loaded well in advance.<p></p><em>Written by CA Amit Mittal, Founder &amp; Chief Consultant Officer of eSilverbucks Consultants Private Limited</em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/i/indian-rupee-new-currency-money-banned-note-coins-rupee-versus-dollar-savings_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-30 19:55:10</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>