<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/gst-carmakers-express-disappointment-over-cess-hikesuvsluxury-cars_9426101.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST: Carmakers express disappointment over cess hike on SUVs and Luxury cars]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[NULL]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Yesterday GST council approved the proposal to hike cess on SUVs, mid-sized, large and luxury cars to 25%, from 15%. Also, hybrid vehicles with engine capacity of more than 1500 cc and mid segment hybrid cars of less than 1500 cc fall in the category.<p></p>Earlier all these vehicles became quite cheaper after the GST rollout on July 1. Under the new GST regime, these cars attract the top tax rate of 28%. On top of this, a cess of 1-15% is levied on them to create a corpus to compensate states for loss of revenue from GST implementation.<p></p>After the implementation of GST foreign luxury car makers were making their way into the Indian market but this sudden hike in taxes may force them think again. Here is what Roland Folger, MD and CEO, Mercedes-Benz Indian has to say on the new amendment in the GST law.<p></p>"We are highly disappointed with the decision. We believe this will be a strong deterrent to the growth of luxury cars in this country. As a leading luxury car maker, this will also affect our future plans of expansion under 'Make in India' initiative, which aims at making and selling world-class products in India, with the latest technology for end consumers.<p></p>We feel deprived as the leading manufacturer of luxury cars in India, who has been championing ‘Make in India’. This decision will also reverse the positive momentum that the industry wanted to achieve with the introduction of GST.<p></p>With this hike in cess, we expect the volumes of the luxury industry to decelerate, thus offsetting any growth in the potential revenue generation that could have come with the estimated volume growth."<p></p>Read More: <a href="http://www.news18.com/news/auto/gst-carmakers-express-disappointment-over-cess-hike-on-suvs-and-luxury-cars-1485423.html">http://www.news18.com/news/auto/gst-carmakers-express-disappointment-over-cess-hike-on-suvs-and-luxury-cars-1485423.html</a>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-08 09:35:39</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>