<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/government-exempts-small-exportersfurnishing-bank-guarantee_9786621.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Government exempts small exporters from furnishing bank guarantee]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The decision comes a day after exporters met Finance Minister Arun Jaitley for resolution of GST-related problems to boost overseas shipments.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[To give relief to small exporters, the government has decided to exempt them from furnishing bank guarantee for shipping goods and services, the finance ministry said today.<p></p>The decision comes a day after exporters met Finance Minister Arun Jaitley for resolution of GST-related problems to boost overseas shipments.<p></p>Under the Goods and Services Tax (GST), an exporter can get exemption from payment of IGST if he submits bonds or Letter of Undertaking (LUTs).<p></p>The finance ministry in a statement said that small exporters have brought to the notice of the government the difficulties in furnishing bond with requisite bank guarantee.<p></p>"To facilitate exports under GST, it has been decided that the facility of furnishing Letter of Undertaking, in place of a bond, for exporting goods or services or both shall be allowed to exporters and no bank guarantee will be required," the statement said.<p></p>The relevant notification will be issued in due course.<p></p>"The issue of cash blockage is expected to be partially addressed by this measure. More measures are under consideration," the ministry said.<p></p>The Federation of Indian Export Organisations (FIEO) has expressed fear that a staggering Rs 65,000 crore could get stuck in GST refunds and asked the government to fast-track the refund process.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/e/export-import-port-container-business_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-09-29 21:31:17</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>