<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/msmes-most-concerned-about-gst-ratescompliance-issues-ey_9327961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[MSMEs most concerned about GST rates and compliance issues: EY]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The help desk is driven by the largest pool of indirect tax professionals including over 800 GST practitioners across 14 cities]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Neha Alawadhi</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Consultancy EY, which launched a GST helpdesk for small and medium enterprises earlier this month, said that the most common queries it has received so far centre around the implications of the new tax regime on rates and compliance issues.<p></p>“We have received hundreds of queries mostly from small and medium size businesses. We have set-up a dedicated institutional framework internally to handle these queries. We try to address questions through emails and we also call up people where we need further clarity on the queries so that it becomes more effective and meaningful,” said Uday Pimprikar, tax partner at EY India.<p></p>The most common queries the help desk has received, according to Pimprikar, are around the implication of GST and the rates with reference to goods and services, registration requirement and transition provisions under GST, the applicability of composition scheme and various compliance procedures.<p></p><strong>How GST Will Change Your Life</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>EY launched the complimentary facility on July 10 for small businesses, traders and entrepreneurs to help them achieve a seamless transition to GST by posting their queries on EY India Tax Insights App, DigiGST website – www.ey.com/in/en/services/tax/ey-gsp-asp and EY India on Twitter.<p></p>The helpdesk is driven by the largest pool of indirect tax professionals including over 800 GST practitioners across 14 cities.<p></p>On the question of how small businesses and traders, who are usually n0ot very tech savvy will cope with GST, Pimprikar said: “EY will continue to work with these enterprises and shall provide assistance that they may require to understand and do the compliances. The Government is also in the process of developing the portal where the relevant data can be uploaded in excel sheets making it easier for small businesses to handle this compliance at a different level.”]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-25 18:11:41</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>