<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/markets-eye-poll-results-gujarat-outcome-will-be-taken-assamplemodis-popularity\_9978401.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Markets eye poll results! &#39;Gujarat outcome will be taken as a sample of Modi&#39;s popularity&#39;]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Gujarat outcome will be taken as a sample of Modi&#39;s popularity at the all-India level and may impact short-term market sentiments, JK Jain, Head of Equity Research at Karvy Stock Broking, said in an exclusive interview with Moneycontrol’s Kshitij Anand.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Gujarat outcome will be taken as a sample of Modi's popularity at the all-India level and may impact short-term market sentiments, <strong>JK Jain</strong>, Head of <strong>Equity Research</strong> at <strong>Karvy Stock Broking</strong>, said in an exclusive interview with <strong>Moneycontrol’s</strong> <strong>Kshitij Anand</strong>.<p></p><strong>Q) Markets @ fresh record highs! What is your call on markets for the rest of 2017? Are we likely to end 2017 with gains over 20 percent compared to a flat 2016?</strong><p></p>A) For any investor with a medium to long-term view, markets are still in the bullish trajectory as the two setbacks of GST and demonetisation are behind us.<p></p>At the current juncture, the market is discounting the future earnings growth followed by a lot of liquidity in the system from the domestic investors.<p></p>In GST of course, there is still some tweaking left and perhaps, the best results will start coming from January post settlement of the temporary glitches in the new tax regime.<p></p>Overall, the markets are placed in the sweet spot and any speedy recovery in the economic growth will add to the bullish sentiments ahead of the Union Budget in February 2018.<p></p>Though there are some other factors like global markets which are, of course, have to be tracked because any volatility there can dramatically affect Indian equities.<p></p>On the valuation front, it is true the markets are a bit overvalued at current levels but as the growth starts picking up, the current fear of overvaluations would also start getting addressed which would take a couple of quarters away.<p></p><strong>Q) The mid &amp; smallcap are also hitting record highs in line with benchmark indices? Is the rally likely to continue or investors are better off booking profits?</strong><p></p>A) In a typical bull market and an expected economic recovery, it is historically proven that smallcaps and midcaps tend to rally faster than large caps.<p></p>Besides, domestic investors’ flow is tilted towards the mid-cap segment, compared with FII flows that largely prefer large cap stocks. It is a vast ocean of stocks, and it will be unwise to categorise all of them as being expensive or cheap.<p></p>It is a case of evaluating individual companies and as long as high liquidity remains in the Indian markets, we expect valuations to remain stretch and recommend investors to book profits on regular intervals.<p></p><strong>Q) Bank recapitalization – a smart move by the govt? Do you think it reverses fortunes of public sector banks and could also lead to an upgrade by global rating agencies?</strong><p></p>A) The government’s recapitalization plan and new road-building program have boosted market sentiment and have fuelled growth recovery hopes.<p></p>The recapitalisation amount seems to be adequate and may create a supportive environment for growth, but it may not drive growth by itself. Currently, weak credit demand reflects economic activity, not just the capital adequacy of state-owned banks.<p></p>On the other hand, re-rating of the companies will depend further on the earnings and the asset quality status in the coming few quarters.<p></p>On the stock specific front, after recent sharp up move, we remain bullish on large PSU Banks like SBI, PNB &amp; Bank of Baroda which may be accumulated on any declines.<p></p>While mid and small PSU banks are betted avoided till the clarity of NPA and other reforms are announced by the government.<p></p><strong>Q) Post the recapitalisation – we saw money moving to PSU banks which are highly under-owned as private and NBFC stocks corrected while PSU stocks rallied. Do you think the trend will continue?</strong><p></p><strong> </strong>A) Banking stocks have been the leader in the market surge with private sector banks rated on the top by the fund managers while PSU Banks remained laggards. Government’s fund infusion may act as a catalyst for the PSU Banks while NBFCs, which garnered market share, would find competition intensifying from PSU banks which have access to low funds now.<p></p>Having said that, all NBFC aren’t likely to be impacted by competition from PSU Bank as PSU banks would mainly focus on Corporate lending or secured lending to retail, like housing finance. Thus, Commercial Vehicle and Consumer Finance NBFC still can see the good growth in the near future.<p></p><strong>Q) Two sectors which you think could emerge as a dark horse in the next 1-2 years and why?</strong><p></p>A) We believe growth story in consumption will continue going forward as pick up rural demand will be reflected in earnings in the coming quarters.<p></p>Sectors such as consumer durables are expected to be benefited from the rise in demand in the rural India. The other will be the infrastructure theme mainly involved in road construction and port development sector, which may be a direct beneficiary from the Bharatmala &amp; Sagarmala projects and many new orders are expected to flow into these sectors in the coming quarters.<p></p>Thus, with a boost in Infrastructure, Commodity ( Cement and Metals) will also see a boost in their sales going forward.<p></p><strong>Q) Recent data suggests that fund managers have started paring their position from stocks which have already more than doubled investors’ wealth in 2017? Is it a smart move and retail investors should also start doing that with respect to their portfolio?</strong><p></p>A) It is always a good choice to book profits in the bull market once an investor gets a decent return on the investment. However, the market direction is still expected to remain bullish for the next 3-4 years and any correction may be considered healthy for markets which can be utilized to accumulate quality stocks in the portfolio.<p></p>Thus taking some profit from the stocks which have run multiple times would be ideal and reduces the risk of the portfolio on an adverse condition in markets.<p></p><strong>Q) Any top five under-owned stocks which you think could generate wealth over the next 3-5 years?</strong><p></p>A) There are many opportunities in the midcap space which can look upon even at current levels among which Jain Irrigation, Greaves cotton, GMDC Ltd, GHCL &amp; Tata Elxsi will be our top picks for long-term perspective.<p></p><strong>Q) Will poll outcome in two major states have a bearing on markets? Do you think it will be a litmus test of the government ahead of 2019 general elections?</strong><p></p>A) I think markets at current levels are already pricing in a BJP victory to some extent and are likely to trade sideways till the final outcome is out.<p></p>Gujarat outcome will be taken as a sample of Modi's popularity at the all-India level and may impact short-term market sentiments, as political stability and the present government's thrust on the economic reforms are the basis for anticipation of long-term bull-run in the markets.<p></p>However, any negative outcome is likely to have a strong bearing on states such as Karnataka, Rajasthan, Madhya Pradesh and Chhattisgarh where elections will be held before the 2019 Lok Sabha elections.<p></p>For 2019 general election government would have good 15-18 months where things can change drastically and thus it is too early to take call currently.<p></p><strong>Q) How are earnings panning out in the September quarter? Do you think earnings will be back in double digits?</strong><p></p>A) There is no big expectation from September quarter numbers as it will first quarterly number post GST implementations. Earnings have been a mixed bag so far for the September quarter of FY18.<p></p>Private sector banks continued to report strong growth in retail loans but asset quality performance was mixed. Some reported higher gross non-performing loan formation due to divergence from the Reserve Bank of India’s audit.<p></p>A gradual recovery in the headline revenue numbers can be seen for consumer-related companies, as trade disruptions slowly abated since GST implementation.<p></p>We expect the earnings to pick up in the coming quarters amid a recovery in the growth post GST implementation and expected on the ground increase in the demand among all the sectors.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/sensex_NSE_BSE_Stocks_Stock_market1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-11-03 08:59:26</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>