<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/inspectiontax-evaders-later-first-priority-is-facilitationgst-subhash-varshney_9204061.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Inspection of tax evaders later, first priority is facilitation of GST: Subhash Varshney]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In an interview with Moneycontrol, Subhash Varshney, Principal Commissioner of GST, Mumbai Zone spoke in length on the landmark tax reform and shared his views on how the economic scenario will look in the short term.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Tarun Sharma</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>On July 1, India rolled out the goods and services tax (GST), the country's biggest tax reform since Independence.<p></p>Aimed to be a single national uniform tax levied across the country on all goods and services, it is expected that GST will strengthen India's fiscal health.<p></p>In an interview with Moneycontrol, Subhash Varshney, Principal Commissioner of GST, Mumbai Zone spoke in length on the landmark tax reform and shared his views on how the economic scenario will look in the short term.<p></p><em><strong>Below is the complete interview transcript.</strong></em><p></p><strong>Q: History has been made by the government, how do you see this move in terms of raising revenue of government?</strong><p></p>A: History has been made and we are very happy about that and our efforts are to implement this GST in a big way and try to reach to the expectation of the government and we are reaching to those expectations.<p></p>I hope the revenue of the government will increase and how much it will increase we are not sure at the moment because it has not been estimated by anyone. The positives which have been explained by all the papers and everybody, revenues are bound to increase.<p></p><strong>Q: But Mumbai and surrounding of Mumbai, there would be more taxes, so that tax will come down in the coming time, so what do you think, does the revenue of Maharashtra, how does it impact?</strong><p></p>A: Revenue of Maharashtra, definitely is going to increase, but so far as the states, as such revenue is concerned, because I am not sure how much Maharashtra was collecting earlier, but 100 percent their revenue is also bound to increase.<p></p><strong>Q: How many zones have you created in Mumbai and Maharashtra?</strong><p></p>A: We have three zones in Maharashtra. One is Mumbai zone, second is Pune zone and third is Nagpur zone. In each zone, we have various commissioners.<p></p>In Mumbai zone we have 21 commissioners. We have 11 field commissioners, five audit commissioners and five appellate commissioners. These field commissioners are given name as per the jurisdiction and area wise jurisdiction and each of the commissioners we have placed various pin codes in each of the commissioners and by that basis, if you know the pin code number, you will know commissioner, where you will fall. So we have a perfect system of locating people for our jurisdiction.<p></p><strong>Q: This is a big reform in taxation. The people are curious to know what the structure is and secondly, this is the time, there should be panic because they are trying to go at this point of time and trying to get registered. So what is the message from your side?</strong><p></p>A: They should not feel any panic, any difficulty and any problem in this area because we have our systems in place. We have CPC in Churchgate building where we receive applications for registration and those applications are immediately seen by the officers and wherever we have documents, we examine documents and give the registration.<p></p>The registration has to be given within three days. If by any chance, the documents are not there or the tax payer has not given the documents, then we wait for the documents. If the documents are not there, automatically, three days’ time registration is given.<p></p><strong>Q: When you will start the inspection of the books, not in terms of the registration, those who are not coming under the GST framework?</strong><p></p>A: That will take some time because at the moment, we are going for the facilitation. We want that everybody in the country, every tax payer in the country should be given the facility for registration, coming forward for the filing of the returns and doing the business. But this inspection, etc. that is to be taken care of later on, not at this stage.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/I/IMG-20170701-WA0046_1280_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-03 18:59:58</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>