<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/indian-november-factory-growth-fastest-since-late-2016-currency-shock-pmi_10149621.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Indian November factory growth fastest since late 2016 currency shock: PMI]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Responding to improving demand, manufacturers cranked up output for the fourth month in a row, and hired new workers at the fastest pace in five years.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[India's factory activity quickened in November at the fastest pace since just before the government's surprise cash clampdown late last year, driven by a surge in new orders, a business survey found.<p></p>Responding to improving demand, manufacturers cranked up output for the fourth month in a row, and hired new workers at the fastest pace in five years.<p></p>That suggests a drag on the economy caused by the shock removal of higher-value currency bills from circulation in November 2016 and the roll-out of a goods and services tax (GST) this July has faded.<p></p>November's Nikkei/IHS Markit Manufacturing Purchasing Managers' Index rose to 52.6 from 50.3 in October, above all forecasts in a Reuters poll which had predicted a more modest rise to 51.0. Anything above 50 indicates growth.<p></p>The reading was the strongest in 13 months.<p></p>A new orders sub-index bounced back into expansionary territory to 54.2 in November from 49.9 the month before. Export orders improved slightly after contracting in the previous two months.<p></p>The findings add to evidence that a recovery in Asia's third-largest economy is on track.<p></p>Data on Thursday showed growth rebounded to 6.3 percent annually in the quarter to September, from a three-year low of 5.7 percent in the previous period.<p></p>"India's manufacturing economy advanced on its path to recovery as disruptions from the recent tax reform (GST) continues to diminish," said Aashna Dodhia, economist at IHS Markit.<p></p>"Growth in output and new orders picked up to the fastest since October 2016, reportedly supported by reductions in GST rates and stronger underlying demand conditions."<p></p>In order to help reduce the burden and confusion of the new nationwide tax on businesses, the government moved most goods which had attracted the highest rate to a band lower.<p></p>But cost pressures remained strong in November, and may push inflation to breach the Reserve Bank of India's medium-term target of 4 percent.<p></p>"Underlying data indicated that the central bank is less likely to adopt an accommodative stance as input cost inflation intensified to the fastest since April," said Dodhia.<p></p>The Reserve Bank of India is likely to keep interest rates steady at its policy meeting next week, with stronger inflation expectations leaving it little room to ease, a recent Reuters poll of economists showed.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/G/GettyImages-693326554-e1506521925850_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-12-01 10:37:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>