<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/banks-ask-ac-holders-to-registergstinmidnight-messages_9193561.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Banks ask A/C holders to register with GSTIN with midnight messages]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[ICICI Bank, country&#39;s largest private lender sent an SMS: "Dear Customer, w.e.f. 1-Jul-17, ST of 15% is replaced by GST of 18%. To avail input tax credit, pls. visit nearest branch & update GSTIN for your account."]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Beena Parmar</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Banks are sending midnight messages to business account holders to register with the GSTIN (Goods and Services Tax Identification Number) to avail input tax credit.<p></p>Input credit means at the time of paying tax on output, a businessman can reduce the tax he or she has already paid on inputs.<p></p>For example, for a manufacturer –tax payable on output (FINAL PRODUCT) is Rs 450 tax paid on input (PURCHASES) is Rs 300.<p></p>One can claim INPUT CREDIT of Rs 300 and only needs to deposit Rs 150 in taxes.<p></p>To claim input credit under GST, one must have a tax invoice (of purchase) or debit note issued by registered dealer.<p></p>After the historic midnight launch, Arundhati Bhattacharya said, "SBI proudly announces its GST readiness. The biggest Indian Bank offers payment of GST online through internet Banking and SBI Debit cards.<p></p>GST upto Rs 10000 can also be deposited in cash/ cheque/draft at our 25,473 branches across the country. So, pay  online from the comfort of your home/office or  visit your nearest branch to pay GST."<p></p>Under financial services, the GST rates have increased from 15 percent to 18 percent.<p></p>For individuals, services charges on cash withdrawal, cash deposits and other services.<p></p>ICICI Bank, country's largest private lender sent an SMS: "Dear Customer, w.e.f. 1-Jul-17, ST of 15% is replaced by GST of 18%. To avail input tax credit, pls. visit nearest branch &amp; update GSTIN for your account."<p></p>SBI's SMS said, "The Govt. of India is proposing to implement GST from 1st July 2017. All business account holders are requested to visit our branches with their GSTIN and get it recorded at the branch. This will facilitate customers to claim GST input credits."<p></p>A manufacturer, supplier, agent, e-commerce operator and aggregator among others registered under GST, can claim input tax credit.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-01 01:40:33</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>