<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/hard-workperseverance-key-virtues-—-pm-narendra-modi-invokes-chanakya-einsteinbhagavad-gita_9193401.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Hard work and perseverance key virtues — PM Narendra Modi invokes Chanakya, Einstein & Bhagavad Gita]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[PM Modi quoted Chanakya, Lokmanya Tilak, Jawaharlal Nehru among others to explain the benefits of the new tax regime.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News </strong><p></p>The who’s who of India attended the Goods and Services Tax (GST) launch ceremony as India heralded into a new tax regime on midnight of July 1.<p></p>Addressing the gathering in the Central Hall of the Parliament, Prime Minister Narendra Modi highlighted the new tax system’s advantages and praised the GST Council for doing a commendable job.<p></p>The Prime Minister also invoked the likes of Albert Einstein, Sardar Vallabhai Patel, Jawaharlal Nehru, and Lokmanya Tilak and cited the Bhagwad Gita.<p></p>He quoted Chanakya saying: “Whatever is very distant or difficult to get, hard work and perseverance can make it achievable.”<p></p>Chanakya, also known as Kautilya was an Indian philosopher, economist and royal advisor between 371 BC and 283 BC. Arthashastra and Chanakya Niti are considered two of his most famous books.<p></p>Also Read —<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-impact-what-may-get-costlier-what-may-get-cheaper-2316013.html" target="_blank"> GST impact: What may get costlier, what may get cheap</a><p></p>Modi quoted famous scientist Albert Einstien later. "One wonders what Albert Einstein would have said if he had seen the multiplicity of taxes in India," Modi said.  Einstien had once said "income tax was most difficult to understand", he added.<p></p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p></p><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Amazed 2 c PM Modi invoking Gita Chanakya,Einstein,Patel in same breadth making <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GSTForNewIndia?src=hash">#GSTForNewIndia</a> as eco, integrating,spiritual at same time</p><p></p>— Monika Arora (@advmonikaarora) <a href="https://twitter.com/advmonikaarora/status/880850594180636672">June 30, 2017</a></blockquote><p></p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script><p></p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p></p>First Bhagvad Gita then Chanakya now a Shlokha mentioned by Modi where he proudly displays everything Indian. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/gstrollout?src=hash">#gstrollout</a><p></p>— Maya (@Sharanyashettyy) <a href="https://twitter.com/Sharanyashettyy/status/880853157621809152">June 30, 2017</a><p></p></blockquote><p></p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script><p></p>The GST is India’s most ambitious indirect tax reform plan. It aims to stitch together a common market by dismantling fiscal barriers between states. It is a single national uniform tax levied across the country on all goods and services. However, certain state taxes, VAT &amp; central excise will continue on some products such as petroleum products and alcohol.<p></p>Also Read: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/gst-impact-full-list-of-cars-bikes-that-will-become-cheaper-from-tomorrow-2315333.html">GST impact: Full list of cars, bikes that will become cheaper</a>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/M/Modi_PTI_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-01 01:01:58</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>