<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/real-estate/brokerages-retain-buyoberoi-realtyup-to-25-upside-despite-gstrera-impact_9369381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Brokerages retain buy on Oberoi Realty with up to 25% upside despite GST,RERA impact]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Citi has retained a buy on Oberoi Realty with a target price of Rs 470 while CLSA has also maintained a buy on the stock with a target of Rs 484 despite impact from GST and RERA.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Global research firms, Citi and CLSA has retained a buy on <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/construction-contracting-real-estate/oberoirealty/OR">Oberoi Realty</a> with up to 25 percent upside from the current level despite impact from GST and RERA. Citi has a target of Rs 470, while CLSA set a target of Rs 484.<p></p>Moneycontrol takes a look at the two research firms’ outlook on the scrip.<p></p><strong>Brokerage: Citi | Rating: Buy| Target: Rs 470</strong><p></p>Citi has come up with a report on real estate major Oberoi Realty with a retained buy rating on the stock, an estimated return of 20 percent from the current level for a target price of Rs 470.<p></p>According to the research firm, Oberoi Realty saw a sharp pick-up in leasing of office space Q1FY18 with occupancy jumping to 45 percent from 30 percent in Q4FY17 and just 13 percent in March 16. Oberoi has kept plans ready for the start of construction of the next phase of commercial space at Goregaon as Commerz-2 is expected to cross 70 percent occupancy in FY18. Other rental assets continued to operate at healthy occupancy with uptick in psf revenues. Pre-sales though got impacted by rollout of RERA and GST. Oberoi’s enjoys strong competitive position post-RERA, higher visibility, Mumbai-centric land bank and balance sheet position.<p></p>Pre-sales of 98,000 sft/Rs 290 crore were below against trends seen in the last few quarters, but still decent in the context of no new launches and regulatory changes (RERA applicable in Maharashtra with effect May 1, GST introduced with effective rate of 12 percent for under construction property). Oberoi has adjusted prices for Goregaon, Mulund and Borivali projects passing on the benefit of input tax credit on construction/raw materials such that existing and new customers are insulated from increase in GST rates to 12 percent from 5.5 percent earlier. However due to high prices/land value component, Worli project’s effective prices have increased. The research firm also noted that the company's working of RERA machinery/website has been smooth with registrations being issued in 4-7 working days post online submission, it said.<p></p>Citi also said that Q1 revenue recognition got impacted by Zero GST impact related price adjustment in project values. Post increase in Worli project’s area, revenue recognition may be delayed a bit. The firm has marginally trimed its FY18/19E estimates by 9 percent, largely incorporating slight push-back in revenue recognition assumptions.<p></p><strong>Brokerage: CLSA | Rating: Buy | Target: Rs 484</strong><p></p>According to CLSA, the impact of RERA and GST in Q1 is transitory. Oberoi’s Q1 was expectedly weak as the transition to RERA and GST took its toll on operating performance. Profits declined 16 percent YoY, pre-sales were down 29 percent YoY and customer collections were down 57 percent YoY. The worst though seems to be behind. With RERA registrations under process and pricing clarity emerging post GST, customer confidence should see a boost. A strong project portfolio, high P&amp;L visibility and rising industry organisation remain key reasons for CLSA's buy call.<p></p>While some revenue decline was expected due to lower pre-sales ahead of RERA rollout, 5 percent revenue impact was on account of GST-related value adjustments on prior pre-sales (driving earnings changes). EBITDA declined 19 percent YoY to Rs 135 crore with margins flat YoY. Lease income grew 26 percent YoY/9 percent QoQ to Rs 50.2 crore as occupancy in Commerz 2 office was up 15 percent QoQ.<p></p>Pre-sales were down 17 percent QoQ/29 percent YoY to Rs 290 crore. Ex of the lumpy Worli project, pre-sales were down 11 percent QoQ/17 percent<p></p>YoY to Rs 140 crore. On caution ahead of RERA transition and customer being unsure of pricing post GST, property sales were weak. Cash collections were down 78 percent QoQ/57 percent YoY, also due to RERA as customers now cannot be asked to pay more than 10 percent of contract value before registering the sales agreement. This led to net debt rising Rs 330 crore QoQ.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/h/housing_infra_construction_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-01 11:24:39</Entry_Date><Category>Real Estate</Category><sc_id>,OR,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>