<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/india-gate-not-registered-does-not-fall-under-gst-ambit-krbl_9289181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[&#39;India Gate&#39; not registered; does not fall under GST ambit: KRBL]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Rice producing companies are in focus as basmati rice that was earlier subject to vat or was tax free in some states is now included in branded cereals category under goods and services tax (GST) and taxed at 5 percent. KRBL in particular has seen a 20 percent rally this week. In an interview to CNBC-TV18, Anoop Gupta, Joint MD of KRBL spoke about the same.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Rice producing companies are in focus as basmati rice that was earlier subject to vat or was tax free in some states is now included in branded cereals category under goods and services tax (GST) and taxed at 5 percent. KRBL in particular has seen a 20 percent rally this week.<p></p>In an interview to CNBC-TV18, Anoop Gupta, Joint MD of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/food-processing/krbl/KRB01">KRBL</a> spoke about the same.<p></p>Five percent GST is on the registered brand but the brand ‘India Gate’ is not registered. So we do not fall under any 5 percent. We will be having zero taxability as far as India Gate brand is concerned, he said.<p></p>According to him, the company is at an advantage compared to peers and would like to increase its market share.<p></p>Our average realisation is around USD 1,200 and EBITDA is more than 20 percent for exports, he added.<p></p>Company has hardly any exposure to Europe of about Rs 30-40 crore in a topline of Rs 4,000 crore.<p></p>Current capacity utilisation of the company is 55-60 percent.<p></p>Iran will stop importing rice from next month, he said.<p></p>Coming year season looks to be very good.<p></p>We have lowered the price of India Gate by 3-3.5 percent, he further said.<p></p>KRBL is launching a new kind of food grain called Quinoa. It will be started in next 15 days by first week of August and the revenue expected from Quinoa in first year is Rs 100 crore.<p></p><em><strong>For full interview, watch video...</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/r/rice_reuters_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-19 13:29:04</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,KRB,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>