<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/gst-day-one-system-upgrades-force-small-merchantsbusinesses-to-manual-billing_9194961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST Day One: System upgrades force small merchants and businesses to manual billing]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The GST regime is being touted as replacing several central and state taxes, and bringing the concept of “single market”.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Neha Alawadhi</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The first day of the launch of the goods and services tax (GST) has not spelt joy for small traders, businesses and retails shops in Mumbai, with several switching to manual billing as their "system upgrades".<p></p>As this reporter went through Mumbai on Saturday, she saw some very interesting scenes play out on the first day of GST implementation in different parts of the Maximum City.<p></p>At the billing counters of a five star hotel in East Mumbai, checkout time (around noon) saw long queues and some errant customers.<p></p>"Allow us some time to process your bills, ma'am. We're working on manual billing as we switch to GST. Our systems are being upgraded. Apologies for the delay," the hotel staff was seen telling some guests who are used to prompt checkout services.<p></p>A similar scene was to be seen at some small shops in Linking Road in Bandra.<p></p>A seller of garments just off Linking Road was also handing out manual bills. The discounts, as are bound to be in this shopping haven, were great, but he didn't seem too pleased with making handmade bills.<p></p><em>Ab to do teen mahina aisa hi chalega, madam</em> (Now for two-three months it will be like this only, Madam)," he told this reporter.<p></p>The reason: system upgrade for GST.<p></p>Most eateries seemed to have no trouble handling bills in their automated systems on the first day of the rollout of the GST.<p></p>Customers were blissfully unconcerned,  until they ran into a queue caused by some small business that has not yet formalised the billing system with the new tax requirements.<p></p>The GST regime is being touted as replacing several central and state taxes, and bringing the concept of “single market”.<p></p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the GST at the stroke of midnight on July 1 in a special session of the Parliament.<p></p>Under GST, all goods and services have been placed under four slab structure – 5, 12, 18 and 28 percent – along with a cess on luxury and demerit goods such as tobacco, pan masala and aerated drinks. Most services, except those in the negative list of essential services such as healthcare and education, will come under GST.<p></p>When this reporter hailed an Uber to the airport, the driver was asked if the GST was likely to have an impact on his business.<p></p>"<em>All this is going to finish madam, Sab bakwaaas hai. Naa Ola rahega, naa Uber. Sab band ho jaayega (</em>Neither Ola will survive, nor Uber. They will all shutdown)<em>,</em>" he said, pained at the end of incentives from the cab aggregator platforms.<p></p>It's safe to assume GST hasn't made a noteworthy impact in his life or business yet.<p></p>The Mumbai Airport seemed to have handled the transition better.<p></p>A snacks vendor who sold this reporter a 500 ml water bottle for Rs 40 was quite amused when asked about the GST.<p></p>"<em>GST laga hai madam </em>(GST has been applied)," he said, pointing to the computerised bill.<p></p>Indeed, there is a 9 percent "CGST" (Central GST) worth Rs 3.05, a 9 percent "SGST" (State GST) worth another Rs 3.05. There is also a GST Number mentioned at the bottom.<p></p>"Full night we spent in system upgrade madam," the vendor added, and smiled again.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/shutterstock_549852313_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-01 20:25:28</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>