<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/for-nifty-to-scale-higher-large-stocks-need-to-participate-itc-to-outperform-pros_9203481.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[For Nifty to scale higher, large stocks need to participate; ITC to outperform: Pros]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[ITC may continue to outperform. It is one of the cheaper stocks relative to the sector, says Anand Tandon.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Indian equity market seems to have given a thumbs up to GST roll out, Sensex rose 300 points and FMCG led by ITC.<p></p>The 30-share BSE Sensex was up 300.01 points or 0.97 percent at 31,221.62 and the 50-share NSE Nifty gained 94.10 points or 0.99 percent at 9,615.<p></p>Ashwani Gujral ashwanigujral.com one has to wait and see how the goods and services tax (GST) is priced in because to go past 9700 and keep going you need participation from banks but so far they haven’t shown any mojo, IT is also sideways and flat. So market cannot keep going up with FMCG’s help.<p></p>So possible for couple of more days you could have this Nifty rally but for higher levels, large stocks will need to participate.<p></p>Market expert Anand Tandon believes rebound seen in the market from Friday is quite impressive after 6 days of down tick when it looked like it may crack up after GST. This shows that bulls are fighting back hard and technically also it appears it is at lower end of the channel. However, valuations will remain a concern and earnings may not be great but market may be looking at it in a more benign manner assuming that GST ruffles will sort themselves out in the next couple of months.<p></p>Stock specific, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/cigarettes/itc/ITC">ITC</a> is buy when things look bleak. Continue to remain an out performer because now there is greater stability on what taxes will be like on indirect taxes. Moreover, non-smoke portfolio of the company will also do well from here on. It is also one of the cheaper stocks relative to the sector.<p></p>Tandon also shared his views on oil and gas space.<p></p>Mayuresh Joshi Angel Broking in the same interview shared his view on aviation stock, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-lcvs-hcvs/ashokleyland/AL">Ashok Leyland</a>.<p></p><strong><em>For the entire discussion, watch video</em></strong>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/bull1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-03 16:45:14</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,AL, ITC,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>