<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/gst-narrowsgap-between-iphones-offlineonline-prices_9228381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST narrows the gap between iPhone&#39;s offline and online prices]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Earlier, online retailers used to supply the phones from states where Value Added Tax was lower, said a report by The Economic Times. However, with GST, there is a uniform tax rate across India.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The introduction of the Goods and Services Tax (GST) on July 1 has narrowed the difference between online and offline prices of iPhone to Rs 1,500-Rs 2,000 from Rs 5,000-Rs 8,000 earlier.<p></p>Earlier, online retailers used to supply the phones from states where Value Added Tax was lower, said a <a href="http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/services/retail/with-gst-ecommerce-loses-the-edge-in-iphone-pricing/articleshow/59480713.cms.">report</a> by <em>The Economic Times</em>. However, with GST, there is a uniform tax rate across India.<p></p>Retailers now can pass on only the savings in distribution and storage cost to the customers. Quoting executives, the report said that the distributors were resorting to a uniform margin across sales channels.<p></p>The same practice was employed by other e-retailers, especially, online-exclusive brands. Now, since the uniform tax regime is in force, prices of such commodities may go up.<p></p><strong>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life After July 1</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>Around half of the Apple phones sold in India are through e-commerce sites.<p></p>The offline business of iPhone is expected to grow faster now, according to retail chain Hotspot’s executive director Subhasish Mohanty, who was quoted in the report. Earlier, there was a drop of 35 percent in offline business for iPhone due to discounts in the online sphere.<p></p>Apple India overtook Micromax, with a 54 percent increase in turnover, to become the second largest smartphone company in the country in terms of revenue in 2015-16.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/a/apple_iphone_smartphone_showroom_720_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-07 15:01:14</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>