<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/crucial-gst-decisions-expert-views_9650261.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Crucial GST decisions: Expert views]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Here&#39;s how automakers, experts and tax gurus are viewing the crucial GST decisions.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley addressed the media after the third meeting of the goods and services tax (GST) council. The GST network glitches seem to have dominated the discussions.<p></p>Two exclusive reports from CNBC-TV18 have been confirmed - 1) the deadline to file the returns have been extended. Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister, Haseeb Drabu told CNBC-TV18 that GSTR can now be filed till October 10th and GSTR-3B, according to Drabu, can be filed in four months. 2) CNBC-TV18's Sapna Das broke the story that the cess on big cars may not be imposed immediately and that has also been confirmed, no decision has been taken by the council on the cess.<p></p><strong><em>Below are comments from automakers, experts &amp; tax gurus:</em> </strong><p></p><strong>RC Bhargava, Chairman, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-cars-jeeps/marutisuzukiindia/MS24">Maruti Suzuki India</a></strong><p></p>"I think what has happened is very much on the expected line - the status quo and I do not think anybody can object to this because the GST was not suppose to lower tax rates on anybody; it was suppose to keep it at the level which is existing. So that is what now been done."<p></p>"There has been no real impact of GST on demand. Demand continues to be good."<p></p><strong>Pratik Jain, PwC</strong><p></p>"I think the most important statement which I heard today was from the revenue secretary when he said that from August onwards there is no schedule as of now which has been laid out for filing GSTR-1, GSTR-2, and GSTR-3 which does indicate the fact that government wants to be very cautious now on this. I won't be surprised if filing the GSTR-1, GSTR-2, and GSTR-3 is further deferred. The fact that you are filing the 3Bs in summary and the fact that you are collecting on a monthly basis would be sufficient to my mind for the first six months. So, that indeed is very welcome move and I think hopefully next one month most of the systems and process related issues will be resolved and the fact that you have an inter-ministerial committee to monitor it would also be helpful."<p></p>"The other quick point which I am going to make was on registered trade mark, I think that is also excellent because the Finance Minister said that any brand or any right which businesses have for an actionable claim against others will deemed that it is branded and 5 percent tax will apply and that would mean anybody who chooses not to pay tax, will have to lose the right on that brand and that is precisely what we wanted to achieve. So, I think these two are very significant developments of the day."<p></p><strong>Ankit Merchant, Auto &amp; Ancillary Analyst at KR Choksey Securities</strong><p></p>"We were expecting about 15 percent of cess on luxury as well as sport utility vehicle (SUV) segment. I believe 7 percent is still possible considering what the demand outlook is."<p></p>"Currently, SUV demand has been pretty strong in the overall market. As such SUVs in the last two years has outperformed. So 5 percent cess is, I do not believe, is a very big amount which will impact the consumers and the buyers as such but it will definitely impact <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-cars-jeeps/mahindramahindra/MM">Mahindra and Mahindra</a> but not to an extent where they will be losing out on the market share as such."<p></p><strong>Abhay Firodia, President, Society of Indian Automobile Manufacturers (SIAM)</strong><p></p>"I think we should look at this one thing at a time. So far as the cars are concerned, that is the mid-sized, luxury, and the SUV cars, I think there is some merit in the government having not really taken the full plunge and push the prices up by levying the full 10 percent that they had said they would levy. So, this 2 percent on mid-size, 5 percent on luxury, and 7 percent on SUV to that extent is a moderate move by the government. They had threatened to do more but it is good that it has not been incremented fully. So, that is a bit of a relief for the automobile industry. However, at the same time, you have to look at two other aspects. The first is that there are now too many categories and the second aspect is that with this more or less the old levels of taxation reappear. So, whatever cost benefits were to occur as a result of the GST have been sort of taken away in this move. Therefore I don't see any price discounting happening; this is so far as the cars are concerned."<p></p>"However, my point is that one has to look at the tariff items. Tariff item 8702 is the one on which most of these cars come and it also includes vans, and it includes the vans with the seating capacity of 10-13 - the point is not status quo, the point is the status quo was skewed. There are two categories in which mini-buses come, category 8703 which is seated on par with buses and suffers 28 percent, and category 8702 with seating capacity only between 9 and 13, for some odd reason the government has singled this out, this 9 to 13 capacity, and treated it like cars and therefore it suffers already 15 percent more. So, if a 14 seat bus has a tax of 28 percent, then a 13 seat bus has a tax of 28 percent plus 15 percent i.e. 43 percent. So, this anomaly is something which needs to be addressed. World over 10 seats is the differentiation point. Any vehicle with more than 10 seats is treated as a bus and suffers a rate of duty which is levied on large vehicles for mass use. However, in India they have created this funny situation and therefore to that extent this does nothing to correct what is a major anomaly though the additional hike which was announced could be possible or which has been promulgated by the gazette, that has been applied a little more moderately and I think that is a bit of a relief."<p></p><strong>Rajan Wadhera, President-Automotive Sector, Mahindra &amp; Mahindra</strong><p></p>"There is some relief but nevertheless the increase is quite substantial for the end customer and therefore it does affect the buying sentiments of the customer. We do feel the numbers will get affected."<p></p>"Right now it is the festival season going on and typically we will take our own call in the next few days and then go ahead with it. It is quite bit of an increase, it is not a small amount, cannot be absorbed. We have not done the calculations yet, but on the range from various variants, typically XUV level it will go up from Rs 60,000 to Rs 75,000 depending upon the lowest variant to the highest variant, in that range it will be."<p></p><em><strong>For entire discussion, watch accompanying videos.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/c/car_sales_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-09-09 21:00:02</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,MU01,MM,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>