<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/arun-jaitley-urges-states-to-lower-vat-ratepetroleum-products-used-for-manufacturing_9500641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Arun Jaitley urges states to lower VAT rate on petroleum products used for manufacturing]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The letter by Finance Minister highlights a concern being raised by the manufacturing sector regarding the rise in input costs of petroleum products taking place on account of transition to Goods and Services Tax regime.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley has requested states to evaluate the possibility of reducing the Value-Added Tax (VAT) rate on petroleum products used for manufacturing products that attract GST, in a bid to end any disruption in the cost.<p></p>In a letter to state chief ministers, Jaitley said that concerns are being raised by the manufacturing sector regarding the rise in input costs of petroleum products due to transition to Goods and Services Tax (GST) regime from July, finance ministry said in a statement.<p></p>"The Union Minister of Finance Arun Jaitley has written to State Chief Ministers urging the States to reduce burden of VAT on petroleum products used as inputs in making of goods after the introduction of GST," the statement read.<p></p>Five petroleum products--crude oil, natural gas, aviation turbine fuel, diesel and petrol--have been not been included in the GST framework in order to alleviate the concerns of states' revenue loss.The date of inclusion of these commodities will be communicated by the GST Council at a later date.<p></p>Exclusion of these five items from GST has led to some disruption in costing of goods and has hit industries such as oil and gas and steel. Input taxes paid on the output of, say, natural gas or crude oil will not receive the credit, thereby, increasing the tax burden.<p></p>Before the implementation of GST from July 1, petroleum products as well as the final goods produced, attracted VAT. Therefore, input tax credit of petroleum products being used as inputs by manufacturers was allowed to varying extent by different states.<p></p>After July 1, the manufactured goods have come under the ambit of GST, while the inputs of petroleum products used in the manufacturing, attract VAT, which will bear the risk of cascading of taxes.<p></p>"In the pre GST regime, certain states had lower rate of 5 percent VAT on compressed natural gas used for manufacturing of goods. Some states also had lower rate of VAT on diesel being used for manufacturing sector," the statement said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/A/Arun_Jaitley_finance_Minister_FM_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-18 12:42:11</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>