<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/luxury-cars-to-get-dearer-as-gst-cess-may-soon-be-hiked-to-25_9516301.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Luxury cars to get dearer as GST cess may soon be hiked to 25%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The GST (Goods and Services Tax) Council had recommended an increase in the cap on cess of SUVs, large, mid-sized and luxury cars to 25 percent from 15 percent now.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>An ordinance allowing increase in cess on luxury cars is likely to be promulgated by the government within weeks, according to <a href="http://www.livemint.com/Industry/3SC4VM5cxFwTTf4pFN5iqO/Govt-all-set-to-hike-GST-cess-on-luxury-cars-via-ordinance.html" target="_blank">a Mint report</a>.<p></p>The GST (Goods and Services Tax) Council had recommended an increase in the cap on cess of SUVs, large, mid-sized and luxury cars to <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-council-recommends-raising-maximum-ceiling-of-cess-on-luxury-cars-suvs-to-25-2352735.html" target="_blank">25 percent from 15 percent</a> now.<p></p>The ordinance will make India's favourite sedans, such as <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/companies/honda-city-maruti-ciaz-among-50-cars-to-become-dearer-in-a-month-full-list-here-2353733.html" target="_blank">Honda City, Maruti Ciaz, and nearly 50 others</a>, dearer.<p></p>Prices of most of these vehicles had dropped 10-15 percent as excise, sales tax, VAT and other taxes like Octroi got subsumed under GST.<p></p>Under the new indirect tax regime, cars attract the top tax rate of 28 per cent. On top of this, a <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/suvs-luxury-cars-to-cost-more-as-gst-cess-hiked-to-25-2352613.html" target="_blank">cess of 1-15 percent is currently levied</a> to create a corpus to compensate states for loss of revenue from GST implementation.<p></p>The ordinance, meant to amend the Schedule to Section 8 of GST (Compensation to States) Act, 2017, will require the Finance Ministry's nod.<p></p>President Kovind will give the final nod and the ordinance will be taken up in the upcoming winter session.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/s/suv_69482080_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-21 15:00:41</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>