<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/gold/indian-gold-prices-at-discountweak-demand-pre-gst-purchases-to-blame_9265001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Indian gold prices at discount on weak demand, pre-GST purchases to blame]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Gold demand fell in India this week, with dealers offering a discount for the first time in one month despite a correction in local prices as consumers advanced purchases in June before the rollout of a new nationwide sales tax]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Gold demand fell in India this week, with dealers offering a discount for the first time in one month despite a correction in local prices as consumers advanced purchases in June before the rollout of a new nationwide sales tax.<p></p>Elsewhere in Asia, a spurt in buying was short-lived as global prices recovered from near four-month lows hit on Monday.<p></p>Bullion dealers in India offered a discount of up to  $1.20 an ounce this week over official domestic prices, compared with a premium of $2.00 last week. The domestic price includes a 10 percent import tax.<p></p>Consumers bought more gold in the last week of June to avoid paying a higher 3 percent rate under the Goods and Services Tax that came into effect from July 1.<p></p>"Retail demand is very weak. That's why even jewellers are trimming purchases," said Daman Prakash Rathod, director at wholesaler MNC Bullion in the southern Indian city of Chennai.<p></p>Gold prices in India are trading at near their lowest level in six months.<p></p>India's gold imports in June more than tripled from a year earlier to 75 tonnes, but it could fall below 35 tonnes in July, consultancy GFMS said.<p></p>"The market is oversupplied despite lower imports in the first week of July. There is ample stockpile from last month's imports," said a Mumbai-based dealer with a private bank.<p></p>In top consumer China, premiums were at $10.00 per ounce, compared with the $9.00-$10.00 range last week, while in Hong Kong, the premiums were at 70 cents to $1.00 against 50 cents-$1.00 in the previous week.<p></p>"There was quite a bit of physical buying when prices dropped, but with prices going back up slightly around the $1,220 level, demand has stabilised," said a Singapore-based dealer.<p></p>The international spot gold benchmark was little changed around the $1,218 per ounce level on Friday and was on track to register its first weekly gain in three, having recovered from Monday's $1,204.45, the lowest since mid-March.<p></p>Singapore premiums fell to between 80 cents and $1.10, compared with premiums of $1.20-$1.30 last week.<p></p>In Tokyo, prices were steady against benchmark rates.<p></p>"People are keeping the cash, especially in view of travel plans during the summer holidays," a trader in Japan said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/R/RTS16BLN_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-14 18:00:03</Entry_Date><Category>Gold</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>