<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/gig-economy-values-experienceup-to-6-fold-risefees-report_10072581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Gig economy values experience with up to 6-fold rise in fees: Report]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[According to Flexing It, a platform for independent consultants and flexible management talent in India and South East Asia, &#39;mature leaders&#39; with 16-20 years of professional experience command highest payouts, with 50 per cent charging over Rs 23,000 per day and 25 per cent charging as high as Rs 74,000.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The gig economy values experience handsomely with an up to six-fold increase in fee levels from 'explorer' to 'mature leader' phase, with some charging as high as Rs 74,000 per day, says a report.<p></p>Explorers are those with 1-5 years of experience while mature leaders have 15-20 years on their side.<p></p>According to Flexing It, a platform for independent consultants and flexible management talent in India and South East Asia, 'mature leaders' with 16-20 years of professional experience command highest payouts, with 50 per cent charging over Rs 23,000 per day and 25 per cent charging as high as Rs 74,000.<p></p>The report noted that organisations are increasingly getting comfortable with co-opting external talent and flexible work - 70 per cent projects analysed were of less than 6 months of duration.<p></p>"Three-fourths of projects were part-time in nature and 60 per cent had a remote and work-from-anywhere component indicating that organisations are getting more comfortable in bringing them on-board freelancers for short duration, tight delivery projects," the report said.<p></p>According to FeeBee, the fee-benchmarking tool from Flexing It, the top four in-demand management skills sought by companies offering flexible projects are strategy, marketing, HR and IT.<p></p>Gender pay gap is evident even in project work, with women consultants paid 45-50 per cent less than male counterparts at senior levels.<p></p>"As the gig economy gets more organised, we expect to see issues like the gender pay gap to get addressed too," Flexing It Founder and CEO Chandrika Pasricha said.<p></p>The report leveraged over 22,000 FeeBee benchmarks collected from over 50,000 professionals across experience levels in India, who have worked on projects with MNCs, large Indian corporates, start-ups, non-for-profits, consulting firms and government-run enterprises.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/e/economy-government-tax_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-11-16 15:59:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>