<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/politics/pm-narendra-modi-had-no-time-for-me-so-went-to-media-says-yashwant-sinha_9775921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi had no time for me, so went to media, says Yashwant Sinha]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Sinha has also maintained that demonetisation was an "unmitigated disaster" and that a badly implemented Goods and Services Tax was like "giving a half dead patient a deathly dose".]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Yashwant Sinha has said that Prime Minister Narendra Modi had no time to meet him, and hence he had no option but to air his views in a newspaper.<p></p>"The Prime Minister had no time for me. I had no forum left, so I had to go to a newspaper to air my views," the former Finance Minister said in an exclusive interview to CNN-News18.<p></p>Sinha has also maintained that demonetisation was an "unmitigated disaster" and that a badly implemented Goods and Services Tax was like "giving a half dead patient a deathly dose".<p></p>A day after writing a hard hitting OpEd piece in The Indian Express newspaper called "I need to speak up now" which apportions blame to Arun Jaitley for the state of the economy, Sinha's comments are aimed at defending his decision.<p></p>"Should I give up my national duties just to save the career of my son?" asked Sinha, whose son Jayant is the Minister of State for Aviation. Jayant Sinha today wrote a blog in The Times of India defending the government's economic record. He said that some "sweeping conclusions" were drawn from a "narrow set of facts", missing the "structural reforms" transforming the economy.<p></p><a href="http://www.news18.com/news/politics/pm-narendra-modi-had-no-time-for-me-so-went-to-media-says-yashwant-sinha-1530907.html">Read More</a>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/y/yashwant-sinha-e1506575084873_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-09-28 15:50:29</Entry_Date><Category>Politics</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>