<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/day-1gst-delhis-connaught-place-greets-customersmanual-bills_9194521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Day 1 of GST: Delhi&#39;s Connaught Place greets customers with manual bills]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Bigger brands undergo smooth transition while small traders yet to adopt GST structure]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Nikita Vashisht<p></p></strong><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Showroom owners and restaurateurs in New Delhi’s Connaught Place found themselves juggling with manual bill books as companies are yet to upgrade to the new Goods and Services Tax (GST) system that kicked in from July 1.<p></p>“We are issuing manual bills today as the system is not yet GST compliant,” said RS Shukla, store manager, Bata India, a footwear retail brand.<p></p>“The prices are as per previous maximum retail price (MRP),” he said, adding new prices are likely to be higher.<p></p>Overnight, the country launched the historic GST, which creates a national market by implementing a single tax structure by doing away with a bevy of indirect taxes that prevailed in the system until yesterday.<p></p>Many showrooms kept their shutters down while others refrained from undertaking any sales until procedures for the new tax structure were clear.<p></p>“We are not selling right now… permission for manual billing has not been received yet,” said Dinesh, manager, Baggit, a premium leather brand for bags.<p></p>He said that new prices are yet to be fixed even as “company has decided to bear the loss” for existing inventory.<p></p>“Sales are slow because of GST,” said Maninder, branch manager at a Vivo store. He said that stores are yet to receive information about new rates.<p></p>“Systems should be in place in a day or two… we are yet to understand GST,” said Rahul, store manager, Aurelia, fashion brand for women’s clothing. “Transition will be managed.”<p></p>While small traders shut shops half an hour early on Friday night ahead of the GST launch in the Parliament, high-end businesses ran as per regular timing.<p></p>“We closed our restaurant as per our regular timing,” said Ankita, manager, Lord of the Drinks, dine-in lounge in CP.<p></p>She added that system was in place to tax as per GST rates.<p></p>“There has been no major change in the prices…The new system is in place,” said Noor Saba, manager, Café Coffee Day.<p></p>“It’s a little early to talk about GST,” said Vishal, manager of PVR Plaza in Connaught Place.<p></p>He said that though no sale has been made, their system was up to date and that prices were likely to fall under GST.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/C/Connought-Place_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-01 14:28:44</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>