<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/get-ready-for-first-filing-deadline-says-gst-chief-navin-kumar_9438141.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Get ready for first filing deadline, says GST chief Navin Kumar]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Navin Kumar, chairman of the GST Network, also said barely half of the 34 service providers accredited to help firms bulk-file invoices online had received approval to go live.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Millions of companies in India are still not ready to file their first returns under the new Goods and Services Tax (GST) ahead of an August 20 deadline, a top official told Reuters, urging them not to leave things to the eleventh hour.<p></p>Navin Kumar, chairman of the GST Network, also said barely half of the 34 service providers accredited to help firms bulk-file invoices online had received approval to go live.<p></p>Yet he gave an assurance that the huge IT back end that is designed to crunch up to 3 billion invoices a month and calculate companies' taxes would be stable, even if there is a last-minute rush to file.<p></p>"It will not crash," he told Reuters in an interview. "We are working on the assumption that 50 percent of the people will come on the last day."<p></p>Billed as India's biggest-ever tax reform, the GST has replaced a slew of federal and state levies. It has also cleared barriers between India's 29 states, uniting its 1.3 billion people into a common market for the first time.<p></p>Yet the complexity of the tax - which has main rates of 5, 12, 18 and 28 percent and multiple exceptions - has raised concerns that companies will struggle to comply and file their monthly returns on time.<p></p>Even before the GST filings kick in, business surveys showed both the services and manufacturing sectors contracting at their fastest rate in years, heralding a likely dip in indirect tax revenues.<p></p>The government has allowed firms to file simplified, self-assessed GST returns by Aug. 20 for the month of July, when the tax was launched.<p></p>They will have to file complete returns in early September that itemise and reconcile every single sales invoice under a regime that, by comparison with other countries, is labour- and data-intensive.<p></p>More than 7 million existing taxpayers have activated accounts on the GST's portal - although around a third have yet to complete the form-filling required to file a full tax return, Kumar said.<p></p>Another 1.3 million new firms have registered to pay GST.<p></p>He waved away concerns that companies would not be able to cope, saying that those used to paying value-added tax - now abolished - were used to online filing.<p></p>Although companies can upload invoices directly into the GST portal, big businesses will rely on a new breed of service provider whose applications can format, reconcile and upload invoices in bulk.<p></p>Of a first batch of 34 services providers that have been accredited, only 18 have received permission to go live. "I have been urging them to speed up their work," Kumar said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/shutterstock_549852313_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-09 13:11:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>