<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/businesses-blindsided-by-unclear-gst-rules_9341321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Businesses blindsided by unclear GST rules]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ambiguous rules under the new, multi-rate sales tax that went into effect on July 1 have left firms confused on how to price their products. The tax&#39;s complex structure - four main rates ranging from 5 to 28 percent - has hurt sales and risks denting economic growth and government revenues in the months ahead.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[India's nationwide Goods and Services Tax (GST) was meant to unify the $2 trillion economy and make it easier for companies to transact across state borders. Nearly a month on, many are finding that doing business is more complicated than ever.<p></p>Ambiguous rules under the new, multi-rate sales tax that went into effect on July 1 have left firms confused on how to price their products. The tax's complex structure - four main rates ranging from 5 to 28 percent - has hurt sales and risks denting economic growth and government revenues in the months ahead.<p></p>Airlines, for example, are uncertain whether to tax premium economy seats as economy or business class - at rates of 5 percent or 12 percent, respectively. Auto repair shops face a similar quandary as GST rates vary for different jobs.<p></p>"People are either overcharging or undercharging for their work," said Surinder Paul, who runs one workshop in South Delhi.<p></p>Even computer maker HP Inc , which is marketing a laptop product to help small businesses comply with the new tax, is seeking clarity.<p></p>Under the GST, desktops and laptops are taxed at 18 percent, while multi-function printers and monitors attract a 28 percent charge.<p></p>"Monitors, CPUs and other parts of a computer are imported as a single unit," said Poonam Madan, a tax official at HP. "What rate do we charge - 18 or 28 percent?"<p></p>Billed as India's biggest tax reform since independence in 1947, the GST replaced more than a dozen federal and state levies and was meant to unify the country into a single market.<p></p>While teething troubles were expected, the ensuing chaos has some officials worrying about the repercussions for Asia's third-largest economy. Annual growth slowed in the January-March quarter to 6.1 percent, its weakest pace in more than two years.<p></p>If growth slows further, federal finances would face pressure. A big test will come in September, when a grace period on filing complete monthly GST returns ends.<p></p>A survey by tax software provider Tally Solutions found that more than 40 percent of small businesses were still not up to speed on how the GST works and two-thirds hadn't yet installed compliance software.<p></p><strong>TAX CRASH COURSE</strong><p></p>New Delhi has launched an active outreach programme to educate companies and explain different provisions of the new tax. The exercise has also become a crash course for tax officials in the anomalies of the new tax structure.<p></p>Officials have discovered that holiday tour operators are charging the new tax not only for services provided in India but also for those offered abroad.<p></p>While vegetable seeds remain tax exempt, paddy, cereal and corn seeds now attract 5 percent tax. This has hit sales at companies such as Monsanto , whose local seed merchants have no experience of paying tax.<p></p>"Our sales are getting hammered at a time when they would normally be booming," Arindam Lahiri, Monsanto's taxation lead in Asia &amp; Africa, told Reuters. "This anomaly needs to be fixed urgently."<p></p>Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia, overseeing the GST rollout, tweeted this week that nearly 8 million businesses were enrolled to pay the tax and the transition "is going on smoothly". He did not respond to a request for comment.<p></p>But for some companies it has been anything but smooth.<p></p>Tobacco firms such as ITC Ltd were blindsided by further rule changes after the GST went into effect. These firms lost more than $7 billion in stock market value last week after the government suddenly hiked cigarette taxes.<p></p>New Delhi's rationale for the increase was that the GST had unintentionally handed tobacco companies a windfall profit.<p></p>Adding to the pain, a couple of Indian states raised local taxes or imposed new levies in a challenge to Prime Minister Narendra Modi's 'one nation, one tax' mantra.<p></p>The GST was originally expected to boost India's economic growth by as much as 2 percentage points. But a convoluted structure has made many economists mark down their expectations.<p></p>If anything, growth dividends are expected to accrue only over time, and not even the government's chief economic adviser, Arvind Subramanian, is daring to estimate its near-term impact.<p></p>"GST in its current form fails to harmonise tax rates across products or enhance ease of doing business significantly," analysts at Jefferies said in a note.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-27 11:45:04</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>