<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/rajinikanth-makes-tweet-appeal-to-tamil-nadu-govt-amid-standoff-over-extra-tax\_9213461.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Rajinikanth makes tweet appeal to Tamil Nadu govt amid standoff over &#39;Extra Tax&#39;]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The issue has also been raised by veteran actor Kamal Haasan who hit out at the state government for not backing the "already beleaguered" film industry.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Superstar Rajinikanth on Wednesday made an appeal to the Tamil Nadu government to remove the 30 percent local body tax levied in addition to the Goods and Services Tax (GST) as nearly 1,000 cinema halls remain shut in the state due to the stand-off.<p></p>Tweeting in the early hours of Wednesday, Rajinikanth said:<p></p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p></p><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Keeping in mind the livelihood of Lakhs of people in the tamil film industry, I sincerely request the TN GOVT to seriously consider our plea</p><p></p>— Rajinikanth (@superstarrajini) <a href="https://twitter.com/superstarrajini/status/882344568728862720">July 4, 2017</a></blockquote><p></p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script><p></p>The issue has also been raised by veteran actor Kamal Haasan who hit out at the state government for not backing the "already beleaguered" film industry.<p></p>"Neighbouring states like Kerala have totally desisted from levying anymore state tax on cinema over and above GST.... Karnataka has gone even further to facilitate the well-being of the film industry. Telangana and Andhra Pradesh are also doing their best for their film industries. It is only the Tamil Nadu government that has brought it (entertainment tax) to 30%," the actor had said in a statement.<p></p>Read More: <a href="http://www.news18.com/news/india/rajinikanth-makes-tweet-appeal-to-tn-govt-amid-standoff-over-extra-tax-1451985.html">http://www.news18.com/news/india/rajinikanth-makes-tweet-appeal-to-tn-govt-amid-standoff-over-extra-tax-1451985.html</a>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/R/Rajnikanth_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-05 09:38:39</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>