<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/gst-slabs-rationalisation-will-dependrevenue-buoyancy-mos-finance-meghwal_9467001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST slabs rationalisation will depend on revenue buoyancy: MoS Finance Meghwal]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Meghwal said, while in pre-GST time only 80 lakh dealers were registered, another 13.2 lakh had been added post its introduction, of which 56,000 were from West Bengal only, the highest among the country.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Rationalisation of tax slabs under the newly-introduced GST would depend on the rise in revenue collection in the days to come, MoS for finance and corporate affairs Arjun Ram Meghwal said today.<p></p>Presently, there are five tax slabs including exempted category at 0, 5, 12, 18 and 28 percent.<p></p>Meghwal said, while in pre-GST time only 80 lakh dealers were registered, another 13.2 lakh had been added post its introduction, of which 56,000 were from West Bengal only, the highest among the country.<p></p>Regarding GST Network (GSTN), he said that it would be further improved.<p></p>"Registered dealers may be facing some teething problems. But the system is perfect", he said.<p></p>The dealers would also have to maintain computerised records with regards to input tax credit and reverse charge mechanism, Meghwal said at a seminar here.<p></p>He said, all these were required to eliminate the shadow economy.<p></p>Regarding tax incentives in areas like the north-east, HP and Uttarakhand after the introduction of GST, Meghwal said it would be decided by the GST Council.<p></p>Meghwal said that the government had introduced GST after consulting all the states and not on the basis of the majority.<p></p>Had there been an opposition from a single state, the government would not have introduced it.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/shutterstock_549852313_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-12 17:45:14</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>