<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/gst-impact-ultratech-cuts-cement-price-byto-3_9211481.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST impact: Ultratech cuts cement price by up to 3%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The company has started supply of batches on new rates from July 1 from its warehouses, when the new tax structure came into force.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Aditya Birla group firm Ultratech Cement on Tuesday said it has reduced prices of its products by 2-3 percent, extending benefits of tax reduction under the GST regime.<p></p>The company has started supply of batches on new rates from July 1 from its warehouses, when the new tax structure came into force.<p></p>"There will be somewhere 2 to 3 percent reduction in cement prices because of reduction in tax rates due to GST. We are extending our tax benefits to dealers who would then forward it to the end consumers," UltraTech Cement Chief Financial Officer Atul Daga told PTI.<p></p><strong>GST Explained In 30 Seconds</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_hGu28LswM" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>Cement has been taxed at 28 percent under the GST as compared to 30 to 31 percent in the previous system of taxation.<p></p>The reduction in prices would vary from state to state, he said, adding "whatever the difference in rates according to each market has been computed and the impact has been given the new prices."<p></p>In the national capital, a cement bag of 50 kg is currently available at around Rs 315.<p></p><strong>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life After July 1</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>When asked if cement demand would pick up following price reduction, he said it will be gradual depending on how housing construction and infrastructure development shape up.<p></p>Last month, ahead of GST implementation cement offtake by dealers had slowed down due to speculation over tax rates.<p></p>"That was a temporary reduction this will now convert into cumulative purchase," Daga added.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/c/cementbags-720_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-04 18:26:17</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>