<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/bankers-look-to-grow-sme-loans-as-sector-becomes-more-formalised-under-gst_9894341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Bankers look to grow SME loans as sector becomes more formalised under GST]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[GST will formalise the unorganised micro, small and medium sector enterprises (MSME), helping banks to get data on the borrowers&#39; cash flows and repayments thereby easing fund access to the segment.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Beena Parmar</strong><p></p><strong> Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>With more claims data becoming available following rollout of Goods and Services Tax (GST), the unorganised micro, small and medium sector enterprises (MSME) is getting fastracked into the formal system. Consequently, banks will be able to make a better assessment of the funding requirements and cash flow situation of these enterprises before they choose to lend.<p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-public-sector/statebankindia/SBI">State Bank of India</a> (SBI), country’s largest lender, recently launched a first-of-its-kind product ‘SME Assist’ to provide short-term working capital demand loans (WCDL) to the bank’s MSMEs for 9 months based on their input credit claims under GST, at a concessional rate of interest.<p></p>V Ramling, Chief General Manager (SME) at SBI said the bank has been at the forefront in hand-holding the SME sector. “This product will help them to manage their working capital requirement till the time they get input credit. It also supports the government’s GST initiative, as it will help stabilise the SMEs to run their operations without any hurdle.”<p></p>India’s biggest tax reform – GST – was rolled out on July 1 this year and works on a refund mechanism where the manufacturer can claim input tax credit for the tax it paid on the inputs which it has used in the manufacture of the final product to avoid repeating the tax payments at the final stage. However, this mechanism has strained the finances of the SMEs because of delayed refunds, leading to a rise in demand for working capital.<p></p>However, this has come to the aid of lenders as it provides important details of the MSME borrowers’ cash flow and GST compliance.<p></p>This was a major hurdle while lending as one of the key reasons for limiting the access to credit to MSMEs has been lack of documentation and the lenders’ ability to predict future cash flows was uncertain.<p></p>Currently, bank finance to MSMEs is mainly based on collaterals such as properties including land, buildings, securities, etc. Banks’ assessment of other assets such as capital stock or goods to ascertain cash flow to sanction credit to small companies can be misleading or uncertain.<p></p>Shyam Srinivasan, MD and CEO, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-private-sector/federalbank/FB">Federal Bank</a>, said: “MSMEs thankfully look stable and there are pockets undergoing pain because of their adjustment to GST but the sector will get realigned and it will only formalised and create more opportunities for them to get credit.” The MSME business for Federal bank constitutes about 45-50 percent of its book and Srinivasan says he sees growth in the segment going forward.<p></p>Bankers said that GST Council’s decision to allow SMEs with an annual turnover of less than Rs 1.5 crore to file GST returns on a quarterly basis, against the current practice of monthly returns, should help ease their compliance burden.<p></p>Further, the increasing loan availability for MSMEs by tweaking the MUDRA Yojana will allow more funds to them.<p></p>According to Romesh Sobti, Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer at<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-private-sector/indusindbank/IIB"> IndusInd Bank</a>, typically, small and medium enterprises disclose only 60 percent of their turnover, balance sheet or stocks.<p></p>“Now, (under GST) you are forced to disclose 100 percent, which means your balance sheet should become stronger and better. And, therefore, the ability to borrow from the banking system should grow,” he said in a post results press conference.<p></p>As per the latest Reserve Bank of India’s data, the micro &amp; small (Rs 357,100 crore) and medium sector enterprises (Rs 98,900 crore) saw year-on-year growth of 0.8 percent and de-growth of (-8.3) percent, respectively. The total credit to the MSME sector stood at Rs 456,000 crore as on mid-August, 2017.<p></p>Since the beginning of this financial year, the credit to the micro &amp; small and medium sector witnessed a negative growth of (-3.4) percent and (-5.7) percent, respectively.<p></p>In July, RBI’s then Deputy Governor SS Mundra had said, “The motivation for the bankers to lend to the MSME segment would probably come from relatively poor return on their advances to the large corporates… it would make sound commercial sense for the banks to look at the MSME sector as a potential growth area.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/M/Money_cash_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-10-20 11:30:05</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,SBI, FB, IIB,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>