<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/ganesha-idols-get-expensive-as-raw-materials-cost-more-post-gst_9422541.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Ganesha idols get expensive as raw materials cost more post GST]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[But the hike will not waver the faith of the devotees, as the number of idols bought remain the same as last year.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The arrival of Ganapati Bappa this year will see devotees stoically bearing the pinch on their pockets following an increase in raw material rates post GST rollout.<p></p>The goods and services tax (GST), levied since July 1, has increased the rates on plaster of paris from an earlier 13.5 percent to 18 percent.<p></p>Paints and Varnishes are now taxed at 28 percent from the earlier 13.5 percent. These two are the key raw materials that make up the Ganesha idols that will grace households all across the country on August 25.<p></p>A <em>Quint</em> article <a href="https://www.thequint.com/india/2017/08/02/ganpati-idols-gst-more-expensive" target="_blank">reported</a> that the increase in tax rate is leading to a price rise of more than 10 percent for small idols. The report also stated that the Ganesh Gully Mandal will shell an extra Rs 20-25 lakh to keep up with last year’s ostentation.<p></p><p></p><strong>Ganesh Chaturthi 2017: The Economics of Ganeshotsav</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VEtTcFH4Kes" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>But the hike will not waver the faith of the devotees, as the report also stated that the number of idols bought remains the same as last year the report quoted an idol maker.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/R/RTX135P3-e1503642507467_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-07 16:34:18</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>