<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/indian-finance-minister-says-india-istrack-to-grow-more-than-72018_10075441.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Indian finance minister says India is on track to grow more than 7% in 2018]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Indian economy grew at its slowest pace in three years between April and June at 5.7 percent. A Reuters poll conducted in October showed economists predict South Asia&#39;s largest economy will grow by 6.7 percent in the fiscal year ending March 2018.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[India should be able to return to its "normal" growth range by next year as the short-term fallout from a new goods and services tax plan and last November's currency ban ebb, the country's finance minister told CNBC.<p></p>The Indian economy grew at its slowest pace in three years between April and June at 5.7 percent. A Reuters poll conducted in October showed economists predict South Asia's largest economy will grow by 6.7 percent in the fiscal year ending March 2018.<p></p>"I see the Indian economy picking up quite well," Arun Jaitley told CNBC, adding that the negative impact on growth from demonetization and tax reforms appear to have bottomed out.<p></p>"All indications do indicate that we will certainly improve, and whatever is the "Indian normal," other factors remaining the same, we should be able to grow between that 7-8 percent range," he said.<p></p>Worst of demonetization is over<p></p>Last November, India unexpectedly announced all 500 and 1,000 rupee banknotes would be withdrawn from circulation, replaced by new 500 and 2,000 rupee denomination notes. The move caught most people off-guard and led to a massive shortage of cash around the country.<p></p>While Jaitley acknowledged that India's decision to squeeze out a large portion of its high value currency temporarily affected growth, he said the worst of it was "long over."<p></p>He also pointed to the benefits that came about as a result of India's demonetization efforts. Jaitley said it allowed the government to put digitization of the economy — an important aim for Prime Minister Narendra Modi — as a center-stage issue and allow for more cashless transactions.<p></p>The move also opened new funding sources for the economy. "We've been able to increase the tax base as far as the Indian economy is concerned," he said, adding that there have also been an increase in the number of deposits in banks.<p></p>"Today, the banks have more funds to lend even to the [small-and-medium businesses], providing we are able to recapitalize the banks," Jaitley said.<p></p>That said, many economists and analysts have said the real impact of demonetization was felt in India's large informal sector, where most transactions are done in cash.<p></p>When asked how the move affected the informal sector, Jaitley said there wasn't a "lasting impact" since "remonetization took place within a matter of weeks."<p></p>But experts have said that India's quarterly statistics — including its gross domestic product figure — use data on organized sectors as a proxy of the country's unorganized sectors, meaning the numbers may not accurately reflect the impact of demonetization.<p></p>Positives from the tax reform<p></p>The other main factor affecting India's growth outlook was the goods and services tax — India's most ambitious economic reform plan in 70 years. It was rolled out only on July 1, but according to Jaitley, manufacturing slowed down in the months leading up to it because "people were de-stocking."<p></p>The new goods and services tax replaces a thicket of indirect central and state levies that critics argued had blunted economic competitiveness and hobbled efforts to lift more out of poverty. The reform introduced four main tax rate bands on goods and services: 5-, 12-, 18-, and 28 percent irrespective of the location of purchase.<p></p>Jaitley said that, in the first few months since the plan was rolled out, the tax receipts collected had been "fairly okay." Big and medium-sized businesses have adjusted well, he added, but smaller businesses — typically more reliant on cash — will "obviously take some time."<p></p>"Therefore, we are giving them time in terms of compliance burdens," he said. "I do see people will take time in adjusting to the new setup, and therefore, we are moving slowly in implementing some of the eventual steps which are a part of the [goods and services tax] itself."<p></p>He pointed to several positives that came about from the reform. "The decision-making process of the [goods and services tax] has matured itself. The Council is functioning very effectively. You have a common market which has been created. You have all the barriers which have been removed," Jaitley said.<p></p>In order to get states to comply with the reforms, Jaitley said they were promised a 14 percent yearly increase in tax revenue for the first five years.<p></p>"I'm quite sure we'll be able to maintain that," he said.<p></p><em><strong>Below is the transcript of the interview.</strong></em><p></p><strong>Q: High oil prices - is that going to squeeze public finances?</strong><p></p>A: If the oil prices are extraordinarily high, certainly that impacts us adversely. But up to a level at which they have reached now, is something which we can bear the shock. If it rises extraordinarily, it will be another thing.<p></p><strong>Q: How would you define that? At what price points does it come a problem for Indian finances?</strong><p></p>A: I don't think we have a cut off. As it is, when the prices started rising, we had to shed off a little part of our central taxes. Every part of the central taxes that you shed off means lesser revenue for the government, and therefore that has an adverse impact on us. Hopefully if it remains range bound within this range, we can live with it.<p></p><strong>Q: In other words, moves over USD 70, possibly USD 75 a barrel would hurt Indian finances?</strong><p></p>A: Certainly the higher it goes - it's not a great news for us at all. I hope it doesn't rise to that level again.<p></p><strong>Q: Demonetization, have we seen the worst of it, in terms of the impact on the broader Indian economy and can growth recover in 2018?</strong><p></p>A: I think we have seen the best of it. Whatever adversity had to come, I think it's long over. Demonetization in India, in the first instance has met - that we have been able to squeeze in the very first year, a large part of the high value currency, we have been able to put digitization of the economy as a centre stage issue as far as the economy is concerned, which means more digital transactions, less cash-based transactions. We have been able to increase the tax base as far as the Indian economy is concerned. We have seen a very large number of deposits come into the banks and consequently, whether it's the stock market, or mutual funds or insurance policies, we have seen a larger amount of funding available. Today, the banks have more funds to lend even to the SMEs, provided we are able to recapitalize the banks.<p></p>We have also seen a lot of squeezing of the terrorist funds taking place in Jammu and Kashmir and Chhattisgarh. A step like demonetization can temporarily have some impact on growth.<p></p><strong>Q: Especially on the informal economy.</strong><p></p>A: Yes on the informal economy. But that's not a lasting impact because the remonetization took place within a matter of weeks itself and therefore, that is an adversity which you can easily reverse.<p></p><strong>Q: Can we say then that we can see a return to 7 percent plus growth rates for India?</strong><p></p>A: I think it bottomed out with the demonetization, and then the GST coming back-to-back, because even in the short run, as far as the GST is concerned, manufacturing for some months stopped because people were de-stocking and I think that phase is over. So the bottoming out is complete and now we should see a curve for the better.<p></p><strong>Q: What's your outlook for 2018?</strong><p></p>A: I see the Indian economy picking up quite well. All indications do indicate that we will certainly improve and whatever is the "Indian normal", other factors remaining the same, we should be able to grow between that 7-8 percent range.<p></p><strong>Q: If we can talk about GST harmonization, and the move towards a common market, tell me about rollout, implementation, and what that's going to do for tax receipts and tax collection and generation?</strong><p></p>A: I think it is early days for GST. There are a few positives I think which we have scored. The decision making process of the GST has matured itself. The Council is functioning very effectively. You have a common market which has been created. You have all the barriers which have been removed.<p></p><strong>Q: How well has business adjusted?</strong><p></p>A: I think the big businesses have adjusted quite well, the medium businesses have adjusted well. The smaller businesses, obviously will take some time, therefore, we are giving them time in terms of compliance burdens etc. The first few months, the tax receipts have been fairly okay. But I do see people will take time in adjusting to the new setup, and therefore we are moving slowly in implementing some of the eventual steps which are a part of the GST planning itself.<p></p>The harmonization of rates, in fact, has become much faster than what people expected, and therefore our first effort to harmonize the 28 percent rate and bring most of the items down to 18 percent, is a step we have broadly accomplished, and that's a harmonization exercise depending on how the revenue buoyancy takes place, which will probably continue.<p></p><strong>Q: In terms of revenue position for India, what targets do you have?</strong><p></p>A: The central government has its budgetary targets. Therefore we want to keep up with those budgetary targets. As far as the states are concerned, we promised them a 14 percent increase every year under the GST for the first five years, I am quite sure we will be able to maintain that.<p></p><strong>Q:  If we can talk about financial stability concerns in India, have we seen the high-water mark in terms of NPAs or non-performing assets that are held by the state-run lenders?</strong><p></p>A: I think it is a legacy problem which I had inherited, and it is a problem which had continued for a very long time. Both the central bank and the government had attempted various solutions to it. Many of them turned out to be short-lived solutions, or band-aid solutions which really did not resolve the problem. I think now the two major steps that we have taken, one is the Insolvency and Bankruptcy Code (IBC) being put into action - the insolvency proceedings, and a number of cases being referred to it, some more to be referred to it in future, and therefore resolutions being reasonably in sight, I think is a good ray of hope. Coupled with the fact that we decided to recapitalise the public sector banks, I think if the two moves, the two big moves are taken together, I think the vitality of the banks itself will get restored.<p></p><strong>Q: Do you think demand for credit will start coming back as well?</strong><p></p>A: I think as far as the large companies are concerned, they already have been borrowing from the bond market, from international markets and so on. It is the SMEs which were really impacted, and therefore, one of our emphasis after the recapitalisation is going to be for the PSBs to have a special focus as far as the SMEs is concerned.<p></p><strong>Q: So more incentives to try and get them to borrow?</strong><p></p>A: Yes borrow, because they are the ones who are creating the jobs, they are the ones who keep the real economy moving.<p></p><strong>Q: Why do you think demand for credit has been so subdued?</strong><p></p>A: I think demand for credit was subdued because in the post-boom period, a large number of companies after that indiscriminate lending, had expanded themselves beyond a point, and there was no demand. So that unutilised capacity is now being filled up. Once that happens, I think more demand will come up from that sector.<p></p><strong>Q: There have been some concerns raised about India's growth rate. You have made the point that these are related to pre-GST issues and these are one-offs etc. Some, however, feel that India needs a stimulus package, does it?  </strong><p></p>A: I think it would be an overstatement to say that you need some form of a stimulus package. You need an adequate response to the challenges. I think that the whole series of reform steps we have taken, coupled with the recapitalisation, is a response under the circumstances. My own view is that slowly we have bottomed out that 5.7 percent in the last quarter and now I think we should start moving up somewhat. If you see some of the latest data, the PMI has been positive, the IIP has been positive, the core sector growth has been positive, and therefore these are all positive indications coming from the market.<p></p><strong>Q: That being said, where does the priority lie from the finance minister's point, and ministry's point of view, on fiscal consolidation or pro-growth spending?</strong><p></p>A: I think you have to balance between the two. In an economy where public spending is extremely important, the governments must spend, and must spend more, but at the same time you can't afford to be reckless and do away with all kinds of fiscal prudence. My own experience is that markets reward fiscal prudence and therefore we have maintained a reasonable amount of fiscal discipline. Depending on the revenue available in a given year, your glide path can be modulated, but to deviate from it completely, is something which we don't intend doing.<p></p><strong>Q: Do you think you can hit your target for the Budget deficit for current fiscal and the next fiscal?</strong><p></p>A: My effort will be to aim in that direction.<p></p><strong>Q: That is for the current fiscal, and what about the next fiscal year?</strong><p></p>A: The next fiscal is an easy target, in the sense that it is targeted to go from 3.2 percent to 3 percent.<p></p><strong>Q: How worried are you about the risk of a downgrade by the ratings agencies if India doesn't get the fiscal house in order?</strong><p></p>A: I don't think that possibility arises. I think we were by and large, over the last three years shown a considerable amount of fiscal prudence. It has never been as good in history as it has been in the last three years. We will try and maintain the glide path to the extent which is possible.<p></p><strong>Q: The other strategy is to privatise, is to sell stakes in state owned companies, and I want to talk about Air India which is widely seen as the company that is going to really set the tone. Are you finding buyers for the government stakes in Air India?</strong><p></p>A: We are on the verge of appointing a transaction advisor who will then analyse the entire market and see what is the universe of buyers which is available. Once we have a clear idea about the universe of buyers which is potentially available, we will be announcing the terms of the privatisation itself.<p></p><strong>Q: At this point, can you disclose any of the buyers, their identities, any of them who have come forward?</strong><p></p>A: I don't think it will be prudent to do that. There are some people who have made enquiries, who have shown an expression of interest.<p></p><strong>Q: Domestic or foreign?</strong><p></p>A: It could be a combination of both. However, I would rather wait for them to make a specific offer once the field opens for that.<p></p><strong>Q: And if we could circle back to the taxation issue. There was a story of a wealth tax, of a tax being imposed on the rich and the super-rich. Is that still an issue that you are discussing?  </strong><p></p>A: If you remember, wealth tax is a tax which I had abolished two years ago and I don't see the possibility of it coming back. On the contrary, we had imposed some extra income tax on the super-rich which more than covered up for the revenue that we lost on that. We were getting about Rs 900 crore on wealth tax, and we were running a complete department for that purpose. So rather than that, we had a surcharge on the super-rich which gave us more money without the accompanying harassment.<p></p><strong>Q: Is a tax amnesty part of the plan?</strong><p></p>A: We have just had a year and a half ago an income declaration scheme (IDS) scheme. I don't think you can repeatedly have IDS schemes.<p></p><strong>Q: The final question is about monetary policy. RBI policy settings do you believe that they are appropriate?</strong><p></p>A: I have always said that finance minister's normally like the rates to go down. But then, this is something which is in the domain of the central bank and the central bank is a responsible institution which balances the considerations for inflation, growth, they take every factor into consideration and come out with a considered opinion.<p></p><strong>Q: In your considered opinion, do we need lower rates in India given the fundamentals?</strong><p></p>A: I certainly believe yes, but at the same time I would continue to respect the opinion of the central bank.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/A/Arun-Jaitle_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-11-17 08:13:52</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>