<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/future-retail-cfo-sees-double-digit-sales-growthq2fy18_9532101.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Future Retail CFO sees double-digit sales growth in Q2 of FY18]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Future Retail has reported an over two-fold jump in its standalone net profit at Rs 148 crore for the quarter ended June 2017 (Q1FY18) on account of higher income. It posted a net profit of Rs 71 crore during the April-June quarter of FY17.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Himadri Buch</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/retail/futureretail/FR">Future Retail</a>, the retail arm of Kishore Biyani-led Future Group, is expecting double-digit sales growth to continue in July-Sep of this fiscal year as well, said CP Toshniwal, Executive Director, Future Lifestyle Fashions and Chief Financial Officer of Future Retail.<p></p>"Overall growth will be strong. September quarter will continue to be double digit same store sales growth for us," he said.<p></p>He was speaking on the sidelines of Retailers Association of India-CFO Summit in Mumbai.<p></p>Future Retail has reported an over two-fold jump in its standalone net profit at Rs 148 crore for the quarter ended June 2017 (Q1FY18) on account of higher income. It posted a net profit of Rs 71 crore during the April-June quarter of FY17.<p></p>The company's net sales grew 18 percent year-on-year to Rs 4,705 crore led by overall SSSG (same store sales growth) of 11.8 percent, with Big Bazaar posting 15.9 percent SSSG in the first quarter of FY18.<p></p>Toshniwal also said the company will continue to look at double digit store sales growth, adding 15-16 stores in terms of Big Bazaar.<p></p>Supermarket chain Big Bazaar is the second largest format in the company after small store chain EasyDay, which Biyani acquired from the Bharti group in 2016.<p></p>Currently, there are 253 Big Bazaars in 127 cities across 26 states and it has opened stores in three new cities—Guntur (Andhra Pradesh), Gorakhpur (Uttar Pradesh) and Kangra (Himachal Pradesh).<p></p>When asked on transition post GST, he said in the initial few weeks of July the company saw a disruption of supply. However, things are back to normal.<p></p>He believes, cost-savings owing to GST transition will be 100 basis points on an annual basis.<p></p>The company has been facing challenges in mass data and systematic level changes in terms of SAP.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/f/fmcg-big-bazaar-future-group-consumer-durables-720_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-23 16:03:36</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,FR,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>