<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/real-estate/construction-infrastructure-issuesagendanext-gst-council-meet_9884041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Construction, infrastructure issues on agenda in next GST Council meet]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Meeting in Guwahati on November 10 likely to look into issues related to construction, which needs to be “restructured”. Issues related to infrastructure will also be addressed]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><p></p></strong><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The next Goods and Services Tax (GST) Council meet is expected to discuss issues related to real estate, construction and infrastructure, which is scheduled to be held in Guwahati on November 10.<p></p>Sources said that next meeting is likely to look into issues related to construction, which needs to be “restructured”. Issues related to infrastructure will also be addressed.<p></p>“Construction has to be restructured,” said a source, who did not wish to be identified.<p></p>There is a 12 percent GST on sale of under-construction units from July 1 onwards. A stamp duty rate is charged by states over and above the GST for real estate.<p></p>This has subsumed value added tax (VAT) and service tax charged under the previous taxation system. Under GST, while there is an increase of 6.5 percent in terms of the tax payable by flat purchasers, there is also an option of the builder passing the benefit of input tax credit to the buyers.<p></p>India switched to GST regime on July 1, scrapping layers of indirect taxes including sales tax, service tax, octroi and VAT among others.<p></p>Input tax credit for construction activities are not yet clear as it is not available for “works contracts services<strong> </strong>when supplied for construction of immovable property, other than plant and machinery, except where it is an input service for further supply of works contract service and goods or services received by a taxable person for construction of an immovable property on his own account, other than plant and machinery, even when used in course or furtherance of business”.<p></p>Input tax credit is available to both a builder and a taxable person while constructing plant and machinery. However, it is not available to any taxable person who constructs on his own account even if it is for business use.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/I/Infra_construction_LT_Larsen_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-10-17 16:35:19</Entry_Date><Category>Real Estate</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>