<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/reliance-jio-offers-jiogst-starter-kitfree-data_9223921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Reliance Jio offers JioGST Starter Kit with free data]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Reliance Jio on Thursday announced a JioGST Starter Kit worth Rs 1,999. The starter kit offers JioFi device.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Reliance Jio on Thursday announced a new scheme — JioGST Starter Kit worth Rs 1,999. The starter kit offers JioFi device.<p></p>The kit offers 24 GB of 4G data and unlimited voice calls on the JioFi WiFi device.<p></p>The JioGST Starter Kit comes with ‘Jio-GST Solution’ which will assist retailers to maintain records, file GST returns and to comply with the provisions of GST law.<p></p>According to Reliance Jio, the users will be able to avail offers of up to Rs 10,844 for the price of a single device which costs Rs 1,999.<p></p>The company is a part of GST Suvidha Providers (GSP) which was set up to help taxpayers to comply with the provisions of the GST law.<p></p><strong>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>Here are some offers under JioGST Starter Kit on the company’s site:<p></p><strong>Moblie-first compliance solution</strong><p></p>The offer gives you free GSP and ASP services for one year. Computer or any accounting/billing not essential for merchants and automatic list of purchase summary.<p></p><strong>Device and Connectivity</strong><p></p>It offers unlimited voice calling and 24 GB data for a year with JioFi. It also offers doorstep delivery and activation in selected cities.<p></p><strong>Scan and Sell</strong><p></p>It offers mobile-based billing application access for one year. The user will need no printer, there will daily summary invoices for full GST compliance. The app will also give catalogue of thousands of consumer, grocery and electronic products with tax codes.<p></p><strong>Tax professionals</strong><p></p>The users will get access to thousands of JioGST tax practitioners. You can authorise a professional to file your return.<p></p><strong>How to avail the benefits of JioGST Starter Kit</strong><p></p>Order JioGST Starter Kit on Jio.com. Once the device is delivered, visit nearest Reliance Digital/DX Mini/Jio Store with the invoice and JioFi Box for availing Jio SIM.<p></p>Create an account on the JioGST.com when you receive both the device and starter kit. Here you can select GSTIN, and then pair JioFi MSISDN in order to activate JioGST Starter Kit.<p></p><em>Disclosure: Reliance Industries Ltd. is the sole beneficiary of Independent Media Trust which controls Network18 Media &amp; Investments Ltd</em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/r/reliance_jio_data_network_cellular_mobile_internet_720_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-06 17:21:29</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>