<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/55india-unawaregst-survey_9211201.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[55% of India unaware of GST: Survey]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Survey shows 60 percent of the population assumes that GST is either ‘not beneficial’ or ‘has no idea’ about the implications of it.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Ankita Bose<p></p></strong><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Even as the government terms GST adoption a success, more than half of India’s population is unacquainted with the Goods and Services Tax, according to a nationwide survey conducted by Way2Online.<p></p>The survey shows 55 percent of the Indian population having no knowledge of GST.<p></p>The survey, which covers a sample of 3, 60,000 participants across various states, shows that 60 percent of the population assumes that GST is either ‘not beneficial’ or ‘has no idea’ about the implications of it.<p></p>Another 76 percent of the population either believes that GST will lead to surge in commodity prices or are clueless about its effect on the Indian market.<p></p>Although the urban population in India showed a 59 percent awareness about GST, only 20 percent seem to show some faith in the GST regime. A sweeping 80 percent either believe that prices are about to surge or remain clueless about its effects.<p></p>Here's the state-wise awareness rate of GST:<p></p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2318525" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/07/Infographic-1-1.png" alt="Infographic (1)" width="652" height="861" /><p></p>The state-wise break-up of the survey depicts that Telugu-speaking states of Andhra Pradesh and Telangana have the highest awareness of GST, with 64 percent affirming the knowledge of GST. However, 58 percent remain unsure about its effect or feels that its not beneficial.<p></p>Tamil Nadu recorded the lowest awareness with 76 percent having no idea of GST.<p></p>The Hindi-speaking states show a 52 percent awareness, but 57 percent show scepticism regarding its implications.<p></p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2318587" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/07/GST-benefit.png" alt="GST benefit" width="652" height="790" /><p></p>GST has been pitched as a revolutionary tax reform aiming to eliminate intermediary taxes, bringing a single uniform tax structure from July 1.<p></p>A statement issued by Way2Online said, "On the whole, ‘Is India ready for GST?’ is the biggest question of the hour that needs to be addressed."<p></p>Raju Vanapala, CEO and Founder of Way2Online said, “Post the survey, we could easily conclude that there is a lot of uncertainty that smothers GST.”<p></p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi in his midnight speech on Friday termed GST as “good and simple tax” which will keep the interest of the poor as paramount.<p></p>“The conclusion of the survey underlines the severe need to address the questions of a common man, as more than half of India’s population is unaware of the ‘Good &amp; Simple Tax’, which supposedly ‘Pro Poor’,” Vanapala added.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-04 17:44:17</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>