<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/technology/apple-ipad-pro-macbook-proimac-nowindia-at-cheaper-prices-post-gst_9236961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Apple iPad Pro, MacBook Pro and iMac now in India at cheaper prices post GST]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The new 10.5-inch iPad Pro starts at a price of Rs 52,900 for the 64 GB Wi-Fi model, Rs 60,900 for 256 GB, and Rs 76,900 for the 512 GB model]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<b>Moneycontrol News</b><p></p>Fans of Apple have a reason to cheer as the tech major is launching upgraded versions of the 10.5-inch Apple iPad Pro, Apple MacBook Pro and Apple iMac in India today with a price cut following introduction of the Goods and Services Tax (GST).<p></p>The gadgets were unveiled at the Apple Worldwide Developer Conference in San Jose in June 2017.<p></p>Also Read : <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/apple-slashes-iphone-mac-prices-in-india-2316535.html" target="_blank">Apple slashes iPhone, Mac prices in India </a><p></p>Here are the price listings for different variants post GST:<p></p><strong>Apple MacBook Air </strong><p></p><strong>Price : Rs 64,990  ( 13-inch 128 GB) </strong><p></p>The Apple MacBook Air is available at Rs 64,990 on Amazon for the 128 GB variant with Rs 3,089.74 EMI per month. The price for the device was Rs 80,900 earlier.<p></p>The MacBook Air boasts of 13.3-inch screen, latest Mac OS X operating system, 12-hour battery life, a 1.4-kg lightweight body and 8 GB DDR 3 RAM. It is powered by a 1.8 GHz dual-core Intel Core i5 processor and screen resolution of 1440 x 900 pixels.<p></p><strong>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p><strong>Apple MacBook Pro</strong><p></p><strong>Price: Rs 1,58,000 (15-inch with Retina Display)</strong><p></p>The 15.4-inch variant of the MacBook Pro is now available with Apple’s signature Retina Display with a 2880 x 1800 resolution at 220 pixels per inch that supports millions of colours. A 2.2 GHz quad-core Intel Core i7 processor (Turbo Boost upto 3.4 GHz) with 6 MB shared L3 cache, and a unique Force Touch track pad for precise cursor control also comes with the package.<p></p>The 13.3-inch variation of the MacBook Pro (2017) without TouchBar is now priced at Rs 1,04,900 for 128 GB model and at Rs 1,21,100 for the 256 GB, while the 256 GB variant with the TouchBar is priced at Rs 1,47,900.<p></p>The 512 GB version of the 13.3-inch Macbook Pro is priced at Rs 1,64,100.<p></p>The devices sport a 13.3-inch (diagonal) LED Backlight display with IPS technology and 2560 x 1600 native resolution at 227 ppi pixel density and comes packed with a 8 GB RAM.<p></p>The MacBook Pro without the TouchBar is powered by a 2.3 GHz dual-core Intel Core i5 processor, while the variant with TouchBar has a 3.1 GHz dual-core Intel Core i5 chipset.<p></p><strong>Apple iPad Pro </strong><p></p><strong>Price : Rs 52,900 (64 GB Wifi Model) </strong><p></p>Apple has been marketing its iPad Pro as a replacement for all of its PC users. The new 10.5-inch iPad Pro starts at Rs 52,900 for the 64 GB WiFi model.<p></p>Also, the iPad Pro is available at Rs 50,800 for the 64 GB storage model with WiFi, Rs 58,300 for the 256 GB Version and Rs 73,900 for the 512 GB option.<p></p>The WiFi   cellular model of the iPad Pro with 64 GB is priced at Rs 61,400. There is a 256 GB variant at Rs 68,900 and a 512 GB model at Rs 84,500.<p></p><strong>Apple iMac </strong><p></p><strong>Price : Rs 90,200 (without Retina Display)</strong><p></p><strong>             Rs 1,06,400 (with Retina Display</strong>)<p></p>The 21-inch iMac comes with a 2.3 GHz dual-core Intel Core i5 processor. The iMac variant with the Retina Display has a 3.0 GHz quad core Intel Core i5 processor.<p></p>An upper version of 3.4 GHz quad-core Intel Core i5 with Retina Display version is priced at Rs 1,23,700.<p></p>On the other hand, the 27-inch iMac is available at Rs 1,47,400 for the 3.4 GHz quad-core Intel Core i5 variant; at Rs 1,66,000 for the 3.5 GHz quad‑core Intel Core i5 version; and at Rs 1,90,400 for the 3.8 GHz quad‑core Intel Core i5 variant.<p></p>Price of the 12-inch MacBook with a single USB Type-C port has been slashed as well and is now priced at Rs 1,09,900 for the 256 GB variant against earlier price of Rs 1,12,900.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/a/apple-iphone-smart-phone_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-10 14:46:43</Entry_Date><Category>Technology</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>