<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/gst-completely-it-based-system-gstn-biggest-networkworld-sushil-kumar-modi_9695421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST completely IT-based system, GSTN biggest network in world: Sushil Kumar Modi]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Group of Ministers (GoM) set up to look into the technical issues faced by goods and services tax network (GSTN), headed by Bihar Deputy Chief Minister Sushil Kumar Modi held its first meeting in Bengaluru today. In an interview to CNBC-TV18, MS Mani, Tax Partner at Deloitte, Rohan Shah, Tax Expert and also Pratik Jain, Leader-Indirect Taxes of PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) discussed about the same.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Group of Ministers (GoM) set up to look into the technical issues faced by goods and services tax network (GSTN), headed by Bihar Deputy Chief Minister Sushil Kumar Modi held its first meeting in Bengaluru today.<p></p>Hasmukh Adhia, Revenue Secretary, Sushil Kumar Modi, Bihar Deputy CM, Thomas Isaac, Kerala FM, Amar Agarwal, Commercial Taxes Minister of Chhattisgarh, Krishna Byregowda, Agri Minister of Karnataka, Etela Rajendar, Telangana FM, Pravin Rao, Interim CEO of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software/infosys/IT">Infosys</a>, Raghupati Cavale, Head-India Business of Infosys, DN Prahlad, Independent Director of Infosys were present at the meeting.<p></p>GST is completely IT-based system, GSTN is biggest network in the world, Sushil Kumar Modi said.<p></p>Over 22 crore invoices have been filed over last two to two and a half months. All filings and audit for GST are online, he added.<p></p>He appealed to the users to file return early and not wait for last day. There were some technical glitches related to filing to returns in initial few days and we had a detailed discussion over the technical issues with Infosys team, said Modi.<p></p>In an interview to CNBC-TV18, MS Mani, Tax Partner at Deloitte, Rohan Shah, Tax Expert and also Pratik Jain, Leader-Indirect Taxes of PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) discussed about the same.<p></p><em><strong>For entire discussion, watch accompanying videos...</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst-770x433_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-09-16 15:09:26</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,IT,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>