<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/enduy-1-get-1-free-offers-freebies-will-be-taxed-under-gst-regime_9369201.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[End of &#39;Buy 1 Get 1 free&#39; offers? Freebies will be taxed under GST regime]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[This shift in strategy has been dictated by the GST fine print, according to which the companies are liable to pay additional tax on anything they give away for ‘free’]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Popular promotional schemes such as ‘buy one get one free’ will have to be scrapped under the GST regime as the new indirect tax norms suggest anything classified as 'free' will have to forgo input credit.<p></p>Various packaged products and food services companies have been offering such freebies to bolster sales. But, most offers have gradually been withdrawn since GST rolled out on July 1.<p></p>.A top marketing official at Parle Products told the <a href="http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/cons-products/food/forget-about-your-next-free-slice-of-dominos-pizza-companies-will-now-be-taxed-on-freebies/articleshow/59853330.cms" target="_blank">Economic Times</a> that they might drop such offers, and move to more direct discounts. Though it could create disruption, GST demands it, he said.<p></p>For the past eight quarters, the consumer goods market hasn’t been witnessing a good growth, and companies have been relying strongly on such schemes to elevate consumption.<p></p>“Given some of the tax implications under GST, our team is evaluating the optimal path forward and we will likely become more selective when giving products as promotional items,” said Godrej Consumer Products' Managing Director, Vivek Gambhir.<p></p>The companies will now have to look for different strategies such as discounts and product giveaways.<p></p>Premier food services companies such as <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/miscellaneous/jubilantfoodworks/JF04">Jubilant FoodWorks</a> which runs the popular Dominos Pizza chain and Yum Restaurants which runs Pizza Hut – have also taken the buy-one-get-one schemes off their marketing lists. However, they plan to continue their discounts schemes.<p></p>Tax experts said a company supplying anything free has to bear GST on it, and therefore, the policy may extend to the pharmaceutical sector as well.<p></p>“As per the GST Act, every time something is sold free of cost, its ‘transactional value’ must be found out and GST paid on it,” ClearTax Chief Executive Archit Gupta said. This means companies may prefer to avoid pre-defined discounts and price reductions to avoid confusion on GST charges on free products and uncertainty on input credit, he said.<p></p>Further clarity on such issues is required from the government, the tax experts added.<p></p>Officials of the some companies also claim the withdrawal of freebies has nothing to do with GST, and that it is purely to improve profitability.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/P/Pizza_food_FMCG_price_hotel_piece1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-01 11:13:09</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><sc_id>,JF04,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>