<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/popular-basmati-rice-brand-india-gate-is-gst-free-here’s-why_9230601.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Popular basmati rice brand India Gate is GST-free: Here’s why]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[KBRL rivals, including Kohinoor and Daawat have been very critical of the exemption carried out for India Gate, them having to pay the 2.5 percent CGST applicable on branded cereals]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<b>Moneycontrol News</b><p></p>India Gate, one of the country’s leading brands selling basmati rice is exempt from the Good and Services Tax (GST), because the company did not get the brand name registered under the Trade Marks Act 1999.<p></p><strong>What is the Trade Marks Act ? </strong><p></p>The <a href="http://www.ipindia.nic.in/writereaddata/Portal/IPOAct/1_43_1_trade-marks-act.pdf">Trade Marks Act, 1999</a> protects trademarks of various companies under the common law, which in turn is administered by the Controller General of Patents, Designs and Trade Marks, a government agency which reports to the Department of Industrial Policy and Promotion (DIPP).<p></p>“This is to further clarify, declare and certify that ‘India Gate, Indian Farm, Lotus and Unity’ brands are owned by KRBL Ltd but since they are not registered in Class 30 under ‘Trade Marks Act, 1999’ hence ‘NIL’ GST rate is applicable on it,” KRBL Ltd, which sells India Gate packaged rice, said in an internal communication dated July 3 as per a LiveMint <a href="http://www.livemint.com/Industry/1fs5AXOkT6RuGb7ASeUn0I/Indias-largest-selling-rice-brand-is-now-a-zerotax-product.html" target="_blank">report.</a><p></p>Before the GST, branded rice either carried a 5 percent Value-Added Tax (VAT) depending on the state where it was sold.<p></p><strong>GST Explained In 30 Seconds</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_hGu28LswM" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/full-list-of-gst-rates-for-98-categories-of-goods-2283599.html">Also Read : Full list of GST rates for 98 categories of goods</a><p></p>KBRL rivals, including Kohinoor and Daawat have been very critical of the exemption carried out for India Gate, them having to pay the 2.5 percent CGST applicable on branded cereals.<p></p>As per the report, the company had applied multiple times to the Controller General of Patents Design and Trade Marks since 1999 but they were objected, opposed or refused.<p></p>The last brand to hold the trademark for India Gate basmati rice was Vikram Flour Mills Ltd which today sells the wheat flour under the same brand.<p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/features-2/your-company-name-is-your-brand-1531463.html">Why is the Trademark Act important for a company: Find out here</a><p></p>GST is applicable only on those branded cereals that are registered with Register of Trade Marks, while others will remain exempted.<p></p>"GST rate of five per cent will not be applicable to the supply of goods unless the brand name or trade name is actually on the Register of Trade Marks and is in force under the Trade Marks Act, 1999," the Finance Ministry had said in a statement.<p></p>The parent company KBRL Ltd had on June 30 applied for cancellation of name from the Trade Marks Registry. However, the company at the same time stated “not using the trademark KBRL Limited in relation to rice”.<p></p>Mostly, under the Goods and Services Tax Scheme, unpacked goods such as <em>chhena</em> (paneer), unbranded honey, wheat, rice and other cereals, pulses, etc. which are not branded in a container are having nil tax on them.<p></p>However, at the same time, the same goods when put up in a registered container and bearing a brand name attract 2.5 per cent CGST rate.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/w/wheat-rice-stock-warehouse-market-pulses-grains-farmer-farm-output-sacks_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-07 20:48:18</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>