<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/film-producers-decide-not-to-release-tamil-moviesfriday_9809541.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Film producers decide not to release Tamil movies from Friday]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Noting that film producers were facing difficulties after the implementation of the Goods and Services Tax from July 1, the council in a statement said the announcement of levying an additional 10 per cent local body tax has come as a &#39;shock&#39; to the industry. There&#39;s been a 28 per cent GST on films.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Tamil Film Producers Council has decided not to release new Tamil movies from Friday in protest against the levy of 10 per cent local body tax.<p></p>Noting that film producers were facing difficulties after the implementation of the Goods and Services Tax from July 1, the council in a statement said the announcement of levying an additional 10 per cent local body tax has come as a 'shock' to the industry. There's been a 28 per cent GST on films.<p></p>"The council has already expressed its stand on the issue during various meetings with government officials," it said.<p></p>Without regularising the entrance tickets for a long time, charging 10 per cent local body tax would lead to confusion among film producers, it said.<p></p>The council said it decided in a meeting today to request the government to withdraw the local body tax, and also that no new Tamil movie would be released from Friday.<p></p>Theatres across the state had remained shut for a few days following the implementation of the GST in July. They opened following a request by the government and the announcement to form a committee to look into their demands.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/G/GettyImages-540184155_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-10-04 12:10:20</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>