<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/bombay-high-court-employee-cheatedrs-48000the-namegst_9345781.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Bombay High Court employee cheated of Rs 48,000 in the name of GST]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The incident occurred when the woman was tricked by a person into paying the sum for the receipt of a parcel that she believed to be of gold ornaments.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>A Bombay High Court clerk was allegedly duped of Rs 48,000 in the name of Goods and Service Tax (GST). The incident occurred when she was tricked by a person into paying the sum for the receipt of a parcel that she believed to be of gold ornaments.<p></p>As per the police, the victim, who is a 38-year old divorcee, had been befriended by a person named Vivek Patel through a matrimonial website in mid-June. The man had claimed that he was from London and employed in the shipping industry. <em>Hindustan Times</em> quoted an anonymous<a href="http://www.hindustantimes.com/mumbai-news/bombay-high-court-clerk-duped-of-rs48-000-on-pretext-of-gst/story-kje6voyJSgd8sUcUcmk5eO.html"> officer</a> from the Azad Maidan police station stating that “The two became close friends and even started video-calling each other. In the last week of June, Patel said he was sending her some ornaments as a gift.”<p></p>As per the report, she received a call from a person on July 18 claiming to be courier boy and asking her an additional payment of Rs 48,000 as GST and customs duty charges. The victim then made the payment to the account given by the courier boy. It was only after consulting with friends did she realise that she was duped and complained to the police.<p></p>The police suspect that both Patel and the courier boys were the same person and are tracing both the numbers. They have also registered a case under sections 419 (punishment for cheating by personation) and 420 (cheating and dishonestly inducing delivery of property) of the Indian Penal Code along with sections 66 (C) and 66 (D) of the Information Technology Act.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2012/356x200/t/tourism_in_mumbai_300_250_30254151_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-27 18:05:58</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>