<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/govt-announces-mega-bank-recap-infra-push-to-boost-growth-create-jobs_9910221.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt announces mega bank recap, infra push to boost growth, create jobs]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance minister Arun Jaitley said that the government will launch an umbrella road building programme to de-bottleneck the sector.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Shreya Nandi</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The government on Tuesday announced a Rs 2.11 lakh crore recapitalisation plan for state-owned banks and approved mega infrastructure projects worth Rs 6.92 lakh crore as part of a broad plan to create thousands of new jobs, raise income, boost investment and quicken growth in the broader economy.<p></p>Finance minister Arun Jaitley said that the government will launch an umbrella road building programme to de-bottleneck the sector. The program will cover 83,677 km of roads and will involve a capital expenditure of Rs 6.92 lakhs crore over the next 5 years.<p></p>Of this, 34,800 km of roads will be created under the Bharatmala Pariyojana (BMP) with an outlay of Rs 5.35 lakh crore will generate 14.2 crore man-days of jobs, a finance ministry statement said.<p></p>This includes Economic Corridors (9000 km), Inter Corridor and Feeder Route (6000 km), National Corridors Efficiency Improvement (5000 km), Border Roads and International Connectivity (2000 km), Coastal Roads and Port Connectivity (2000 km), Green field Expressways (800 km), National Highway Development (NHDP) works (10,000 km).<p></p>For the BMP programme,  Rs 2.09 lakh crore will be raised as debt from the market, Rs 1.06 lakh crore of private investments would be mobilized through PPP and Rs 2.19 lakh crore is to be provided out of accruals to the Central Road Fund (CRF), toll-operate-maintain transfer (ToT) monetisation proceeds and toll collections of the National Highways Authority of India (NHAI).<p></p>In addition to 34,800 km under Bharatmala,  another 48,877 km of works under other current schemes will be implemented in parallel by the NHAI with an outlay of Rs 1.57 lakh crore. This will be financed by providing Rs 97,000 crore from CRF and Rs 59,000 crore as gross budgetary support (GBS).<p></p>For the first time ever, monetisation of 82 operating highways under a low risk ToT Model has been initiated with a private investment potential of Rs 34,000 crore. The first bundle of nine highway stretches of 680.64 km has been put out to tender by NHAI with potential monetization value of Rs 6,258 crore.<p></p>Jaitley said the government has also decided capitalise public sector banks (PSBs) in a front-loaded manner, with a view to support credit growth and job creation.<p></p>This entails mobilization of capital, with maximum allocation in the current year, to the tune of about Rs 2,11,000 crore over the next two years, budgetary provisions of Rs 18,139 crore, recapitalisation bonds to the tune of Rs 1.35 lakh crore, and raising of capital by banks from the market while diluting government equity (estimated potential Rs 58,000 crore).<p></p>“The government actions are not limited to addressing capitalisation of PSBs. Definite steps will be taken alongside capitalisation to enable them to play a major role in the financial system. PSBs having 70 percent market share in the banking space will be geared for greater growth and to contribute through enhanced credit off-take,” Jaitley said.<p></p>There will also be a strong push on enabling growth of micro, small and medium enterprises (MSMEs) through enhanced access to financing and markets, and a drive to finance MSMEs in 50 clusters.<p></p>While individual ministries will spearhead and provide momentum, banks will undertake speedy processing of loan applications in a hassle-free manner. Fintech companies will be roped in to cut down the appraisal process and generate quality loan applications, the finance ministry said.<p></p>The latest decisions are aimed at helping India claw out of a three-year low growth slump. India’s real or inflation-adjusted gross domestic product grew 5.7 percent in April-June, the slowest in 13 quarters.<p></p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has also sharply revised the economy’s growth forecasts for 2017-18. The central bank now expects the gross value added (GVA) to grow at 6.7 percent in 2017-18 from 7.3 percent projected earlier.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/l/l20170701110502_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-10-24 21:34:32</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>