<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/businesses-under-composition-scheme-to-soon-start-filing-gst-returns_9938461.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Businesses under composition scheme to soon start filing GST returns]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[As per the GST laws, for July-September quarter businesses, with a turnover of up to Rs 75 lakh, opting for composition scheme can file quarterly returns and pay taxes]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Businesses which opted for composition scheme in the July-September quarter will get to file their maiden GST returns soon.<p></p>Around 15 lakh businesses opted for composition scheme, which allows them to pay taxes at a concessional rate and makes compliance easy, till September under the Goods and Services Tax (GST) that rolled out from July 1.<p></p>"We are ready with GSTR-4 which will be used by composition scheme businesses for filing returns. The utility will be available on GSTN portal soon," GST Network CEO Prakash Kumar told PTI.<p></p>Also Read: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/rate-rationalisation-govt-mulls-same-gst-rate-for-similar-product-categories-2420949.html" target="_blank">Rate rationalisation: Govt mulls same GST rate for similar product categories</a><p></p>As per the GST laws, for July-September quarter businesses, with a turnover of up to Rs 75 lakh, opting for composition scheme can file quarterly returns and pay taxes.<p></p><p class="title style-scope ytd-video-primary-info-renderer"><strong>How Anti-Profiteering Works Under GST</strong></p><p></p> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V_AP6svGbtI?rel=0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>The scheme is optional under which manufacturers other than those of ice cream, pan masala and tobacco products have to pay a 2 percent tax on their annual turnover.<p></p>The tax rate is 5 percent for restaurant services and 1 percent for traders.<p></p>There is over 1 crore registered businesses under the GST, which has amalgamated over a dozen taxes to make India a single market for a seamless flow of goods and services.<p></p>The GST Council had earlier this month raised the turnover threshold from Rs 75 lakh to Rs 1 crore for businesses to opt for the scheme.<p></p>Also Read: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/traders-in-gujarat-to-ask-officials-to-file-gst-returns-for-them-in-protest-2421439.html" target="_blank">Traders in Gujarat to ask officials to file GST returns for them in unique protest</a><p></p>Hence, those with a turnover of up to Rs 1 crore can take advantage of composition scheme beginning October 1.<p></p>Also, a group of state finance ministers have been set up to make the scheme more attractive.<p></p>The objective behind the composition scheme is to bring simplicity and reduce the compliance cost for small taxpayers.<p></p>As per the Central GST Act, businesses are eligible to opt for the composition scheme if a person is not engaged in any inter-state outward supplies of goods and not into making any supply of goods through an electronic commerce operator who is required to collect tax at source.<p></p>While a regular taxpayer has to pay taxes on a monthly basis, a composition supplier is required to file only one return and pay taxes on a quarterly basis.<p></p>Also, a composition taxpayer is not required to keep detailed records that a normal taxpayer is supposed to maintain.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst-770x433_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-10-29 13:45:09</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>