<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/what-changed-formarket-while-you-were-sleeping-20-things-you-should-know_9832561.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[What changed for the market while you were sleeping? 20 things you should know]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[A look at top cues from domestic and international cues that could have a bearing on D-Street.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The bulls managed to regain control of D-Street as Nifty closed above its crucial psychological level of 9950 levels and above its key short-term moving average on Friday. It made a strong bullish candle on the daily candlestick charts.<p></p>The Nifty closed at 9,979.7 on Friday. According to Pivot charts, the key support level is placed at 9,927.75, followed by 9,875.8. If the index starts to move higher, key resistance levels to watch out are 10,010.5 and 10,041.3.<p></p>The Nifty Bank closed at 24,190. Important Pivot level, which will act as crucial support for the index, is placed at 24,095.5, followed by 24,001. On the upside, key resistance levels are 24,263.3, followed by 24,336.6.<p></p>Stay tuned to Moneycontrol to find out what happens in currency and equity markets today. We have collated a list of important headlines from across news agencies:<p></p><strong>US market ends mixed, S&amp;P breaks record run</strong><p></p>The S&amp;P 500 eased on Friday, ending a six-day run of record highs as the first monthly decline in US non-farm jobs in seven years. The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell 1.72 points, or 0.01 percent, to end at 22,773.67, the S&amp;P 500 lost 2.74 points, or 0.11 percent, to 2,549.33 and the Nasdaq Composite added 4.82 points, or 0.07 percent, to 6,590.18, Reuters reported.<p></p><strong>Asian Markets inch ahead</strong><p></p>Australian shares inched higher on Monday as the flow of economic news remained generally supportive for global growth, while political uncertainty caused some early ructions in currencies. Nikkei futures added 0.1 percent even though the cash market was shut, Reuters reported.<p></p><strong>SGX Nifty</strong><p></p>The Nifty50 futures on the Singapore Stock Exchange were trading 45 points lower at 9975 indicating a negative opening for the domestic market.<p></p><strong>North Korea diplomacy has failed, 'only one thing will work': US President</strong><p></p>US President Donald Trump has said that diplomatic efforts with North Korea have consistently failed, adding that "only one thing will work." The US has not ruled out the use of force to compel Pyongyang to halt missile and nuclear tests, and Trump has threatened to "totally destroy" the country, AFP reported.<p></p><strong>GST refunds to exporters in 2 months: Revenue Secy</strong><p></p>The government will clear pending GST refunds of exporters by November-end and over the next six months no tax will be levied on exports as the Council has decided to revert to the pre-GST era, Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said.<p></p>Over July-August, an estimated ₹67,000 crore has accumulated as the Integrated GST (IGST), of which only about ₹5,000-10,000 crore will be due as refunds to exporters, he added, as reported by PTI.<p></p><b>Relief for exporters &amp; SMEs as GST Council reduces compliance issues</b><p></p>The Goods and Services tax (GST) council on Friday cut rates on 27 items and 12 services, and approved sweeping changes in rules to soothe frayed nerves of millions of small enterprises and exporters that have been battling with procedural irritants, delayed refunds and technical glitches on returns filing.<p></p>The Finance Minister Arun Jaitley-headed panel pushed for big changes in its 22nd meeting to iron out rough edges of the new tax system that has been hit by multiple pain points since it was rolled out on July 1.<p></p>Top sectors which are likely to benefit most from the GST tweak include SMEs, exporters, gems &amp; jewellery sector, pumps and man made yarn.<p></p><strong>Gold sales likely to revive during Diwali</strong><p></p>Gold sales are likely to revive during the ensuing Diwali festival with the government revoking an order that mandated PAN and Aadhaar cards for purchases above Rs 50,000, an industry body said.<p></p><strong>Govt to launch sovereign gold bond scheme</strong><p></p>The government will launch the next tranche of sovereign gold bond (SGB) scheme, the second in 2017-18, on October 9 to cash in on festive fever. The bonds will be sold through banks, Stock Holding Corporation of India Limited (SHCIL), designated post offices and recognised stock exchanges namely the NSE and BSE, the finance ministry said.<p></p><strong>SEBI sets 5 broad categories for MF Schemes</strong><p></p>SEBI has rolled out Mutual Funds reforms and has set five broad categories for MF Schemes namely equity schemes, debt schemes, hybrid schemes, solution oriented schemes, and other schemes.<p></p><strong>FPIs pour Rs 5k crore in debt markets in 4 trading sessions</strong><p></p>Overseas investors have pumped in nearly Rs 5,000 crore into the country's debt markets in the last four trading sessions, primarily due to increase in the limit on foreign ownership of bonds. According to latest depository data, FPIs invested a net sum of Rs 4,886 crore (USD 747 million) in debt markets during October 3-6, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>Sebi orders forensic audit of Landmarc Leisure Corp </strong><p></p>Sebi has ordered forensic audit of Landmarc Leisure Corporation Ltd after finding prima facie evidence of misuse of books of accounts by the firm. The trading curbs imposed on the firm, which figures among 331 'suspected shell companies' under Sebi's scanner, have also been removed, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>SMEs garner record Rs 656cr via IPOs in Apr-Sep FY18</strong><p></p>As many as 58 small and medium enterprises (SMEs) got listed on capital markets with IPOs worth record Rs 656 crore in April-September 2017 and many are lined up for the coming months. Besides, more than 18 companies have already announced their issue opening dates, merchant banker Pantomath Group Managing Director Mahavir Lunawat said, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>Indian Energy Exchange IPO to open on Monday</strong><p></p>Indian Energy Exchange's initial public offer will open for subscription on October 9, with price band of Rs 1,645-1,650 per share. The issue will close on October 11. The book running lead managers to the offer are Axis Capital, Kotak Mahindra Capital Company and IIFL Holdings.<p></p>The issue is an offer for sale of up to 60,65,009 equity shares by 11 shareholders, including Tata Power and Multiples Private Equity Fund. It is expected to raise Rs 997.7-1,000.7 crore at a price band of Rs 1,645-1,650 per share.<p></p><strong>Petroleum dealers on nationwide strike on Oct 13</strong><p></p>The United Petroleum Front (UPF) on Saturday announced nationwide strike of dealers on 13 October to press for various demands including better margins and inclusion of petroleum products under the goods and services tax (GST) regime, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>GDP to recover in Q2 as fundamentals strong</strong><p></p>Union minister Ravi Shankar Prasad on Saturday said that decline in GDP growth in Q1 is temporary and that the economy will bounce back in the second quarter as the macro fundamentals are strong, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>Sebi bans individual from securities markets for 3 years</strong><p></p>Sebi on Saturday restrained Imtiyazhusain Saiyed Mohamed Saiyed from the securities market for three years for violating various norms. It conducted an investigation into matter of Imtsons Investments and Imtiyazhusain Saiyed for the period from April 2007 to June 2011, after receiving references from several investigating agencies concerning various issues, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>BSE-listed cos' promoters pledge shares worth Rs 2.6 lakh cr</strong><p></p>The value of shares pledged by promoters of BSE-listed firms stood at Rs 2.6 lakh crore at the end of September quarter, an increase of 3.5 per cent from the preceding three months, the bourse data showed. In comparison, the figure stood at Rs 2.49 lakh crore at the end of June quarter, The Business Standard reported.<p></p><strong>Godrej Agrovet IPO draws heavy demand, oversubscribed 95 times</strong><p></p>The initial public offer of Godrej Agrovet was a big hit as the issue oversubscribed 95.34 times on the last day of bidding on Friday. The Initial Public Offering (IPO) to raise around Rs 1,157 crore received bids for 1,71,86,73,920 shares against the total issue size of 1,80,27,464 shares, as per NSE's data till 1930 hrs, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>Govt to lower number of PSBs to 10-15: FinMin advisor</strong><p></p>India will have 10-15 public sector banks with majority stake by the government, down from 21 percent at present, as part of its plan to consolidate banks, Finance Ministry's principal economic advisor Sanjeev Sanyal said on Friday. He said cleaning up of the bad loan problems is the first priority and after that the PSU banks could be consolidated, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>N Chandra plans to prune Tata Group portfolio</strong><p></p>Tata Sons will simplify overlapping business operations, prune its expansive portfolio by consolidating companies which have synergies, create new business clusters such as defence, infrastructure, consumer and retail, financial services and hotels and airlines while supporting the growth of the three largest companies, Tata Consultancy, Tata Steel and Tata Motors.<p></p>Loss making or marginal operations like Tata Teleservices could be shut down while in capex heavy sectors like aviation multiple JV operations are likely to be streamlined for maximum scale, The Economic Times reported.<p></p><strong>RBI to stand pat on rates for rest of this fiscal: Report </strong><p></p>No change in interest rates is likely over the rest of this fiscal, as the Reserve Bank is expected to adopt a 'wait and see' approach due to rising inflation and downside pressure on rupee, says a report. According to BMI Research, headline consumer price inflation (CPI) is likely to head higher over the coming months, largely owing to rising food and housing prices, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>MAS Fin Services IPO oversubscribed on Day 1</strong><p></p>The initial share sale offer of MAS Financial Services was oversubscribed 1.06 times on the first day of the subscription on Friday. The IPO, to raise Rs 460 crore, received bids for 75,31,808 shares against the total issue size of 71,24,910 shares, as per the NSE data.<p></p><strong>Auto, OMCs, metals &amp; private banks may buoy Q2 show </strong><p></p>After a brief lull in the previous quarter, Nifty 50 companies are expected to report double-digit growth in profits with improved profitability in the September quarter, aided largely by a better showing by automobile players, oil marketing companies (OMCs), metal and mining companies and private sector lenders, The Economic Times reported.<p></p><strong>Visible signs of growth in second half: RBI Governor</strong><p></p>Reserve Bank of India (RBI) governor Urjit Patel said there are visible signs of upturn and economic growth is likely to exceed 7 percent in the last two quarters of the year as projected in last week’s monetary policy report. Patel added that RBI will support growth, but not at the cost of inflation, as reported by Livemint.<p></p><strong>Sebi may find it tough to Uday Kotak panel recommendations</strong><p></p>The latest proposals by the stock market regulator’s corporate governance panel could turn out to be a tough sell. The corporate affairs ministry has opposed half of them, and an independent survey found implementing them will require many companies to overhaul their boards, Livemint reported.<p></p><strong>Oil up on expectation of Saudi production restraint</strong><p></p>Oil prices edged up on Monday, halting a 2 percent slide from Friday, on expectations that Saudi Arabia would continue to restrain its output in order to support prices. Brent crude futures, the international benchmark for oil prices, were up 8 cents, or 0.14 percent, at USD 55.70 a barrel, Reuters reported.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/B/BSE_Sensex_Markets_Stock_market_Dalal_street1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-10-09 07:59:33</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>