<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/expect-fy18-gdp-at-68-sajjid-chinoy_9587121.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Expect FY18 GDP at 6.8%: Sajjid Chinoy]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ten months after demonetisation and just 2 months after the launch of the goods and services tax (GST), India&#39;s growth rate has dropped to its lowest level since Narendra Modi took charge as Prime Minister. In an interview to CNBC-TV18, Sajjid Chinoy of JP Morgan, Tanvee Gupta Jain, India Economist at UBS Investment Bank and Manish Wadhawan, MD & Head-Interest Rates at HSBC India shared their readings and outlook on the same.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Ten months after demonetisation and just 2 months after the launch of the goods and services tax (GST), India's growth rate has dropped to its lowest level since Narendra Modi took charge as Prime Minister.<p></p>In an interview to CNBC-TV18, Sajjid Chinoy of JP Morgan, Tanvee Gupta Jain, India Economist at UBS Investment Bank and Manish Wadhawan, MD &amp; Head-Interest Rates at HSBC India shared their readings and outlook on the same.<p></p>Forecast for the full year for gross domestic product (GDP) is 6.8 percent which means gross value added (GVA) will be close to 6.5-6.6 percent, Chinoy said.<p></p>GDP numbers released yesterday are numbers that drove the August rate cut, he further added.<p></p>It was the weaker growth in this quarter that pushed down core inflation, pushed down Reserve Bank of India’s (RBI) inflation forecast, he said.<p></p>According to him, if growth does not pick up in the next few quarters, it should put some downward pressure on core inflation.<p></p>Tanvee Gupta Jain said we have revised our forecast lower. Expect FY18 GDP at 6.6 percent versus earlier 7.2 percent and GVA at 6.5 percent, she said.<p></p>She said they are factoring in one more rate cut from RBI but the timing is uncertain.<p></p>Manish Wadhawan said that consolidation in bond markets likely to continue. It will be a wait and watch for Indian bond markets, he added.<p></p><em><strong>For entire discussion, watch accompanying video...</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/G/GDP_Gross_domestic_price_economy_Growth_inflation1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-09-01 09:59:52</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>