<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/manmohan-singhgujarat-today-to-interacttraders_10005281.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh in Gujarat today; to interact with traders]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[His visit comes a day before Congress vice-president Rahul Gandhi&#39;s likely tour of Surat as the Congress marks the first demonetisation anniversary on November 8 as &#39;black day&#39;.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Former prime minister Manmohan Singh will address small businessmen on GST and other issues and also address the media on Tuesday to boost the Congress's prospects in the Gujarat elections.<p></p>Singh will take part in an interactive session on the current state of economy with businessmen and traders during his visit, the Gujarat Congress said in a release.<p></p>His visit comes a day before Congress vice-president Rahul Gandhi's likely tour of Surat as the Congress marks the first demonetisation anniversary on November 8 as 'black day'.<p></p>The session has been organised at the Sardar Patel Memorial in Shahibaug area in the morning, the party said.<p></p>After the event, the Congress leader will address a press conference at the state party headquarters, it added.<p></p>The former prime minister is visiting Gujarat at a time the state is witnessing a heated campaigning for the assembly polls.<p></p>Rahul Gandhi has already toured the state multiple times in the last few months and addressed a number of rallies.<p></p>The note ban has been a recurring theme of Gandhi's speeches.<p></p>It is expected that the economist-politician would touch upon various aspects related to note-ban as well as the implementation of GST and its impact on the economy during his interaction with the business community.<p></p>Gjarat, the home state of Prime Minister Narendra Modi, goes to polls on December 9 and 14.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/G/GettyImages-628745086_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-11-07 07:50:17</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>