<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/3goodsservices-tax-leviedgold-too-low-economic-survey_9492541.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[3 % goods and services tax levied on gold too low: Economic Survey]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Also, the document called for taxing education and healthcare]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The tax on gold, which currently attracts 3% Goods and Services Tax (GST), should be increased, according to the Chief Economic Advisor Arvind Subramanian.<p></p>The Economic Survey Volume II 2016-17, <a href="http://indiabudget.nic.in/es2016-17/echapter_vol2.pdf" target="_blank">authored </a>by Subramanian states "The tax on gold and jewellery — items that are disproportionately consumed by the very rich — at 3 percent is still low."<p></p>The survey acknowledged that the multi-pronged objectives of GST called for a variety of tax rates. This meant an intentional lowering of the rates of a few essential goods so as to protect the poor from a price rise.<p></p>Although Alcohol, petroleum, energy products, electricity, land and real estate transactions have no GST rates, they are taxed by the Centre and State government outside the GST framework.<p></p>“Inclusion of land and real estate and alcohol in GST will improve transparency and reduce corruption," Subramanian added.<p></p>Also, the document called for taxing education and healthcare. "Keeping health and education completely out is inconsistent with equity because these are services consumed disproportionately by the rich," it said.<p></p>Another observation states "Bringing electricity into the GST framework would improve the competitiveness of the Indian industry because the taxes on power get embedded in manufacturers' costs, and can be claimed back as input tax credit".<p></p>The survey called for the GST Council, the body which takes a final call on all matters GST, to take up these suggestions in the coming months.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/j/jewellery-gold-metals-precious-metal-commodity1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-17 11:54:50</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>