<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/odd-tax-rates-within-gst-human-hair-exempttax-shampoos-attract-28_9209521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Odd tax rates within GST: Human hair exempt from tax; shampoos attract 28%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The all-powerful GST council used the merits of goods and services to divide them into essential, non-essential and Luxury goods, according to which the tax rates for respective goods have been decided.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Shubham Raj</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Under the Goods and Services Tax (GST), over 1,200 goods and 500 services have been divided in the tax bracket of 5, 12, 18 and 28 percent. From July 1, these rates are applicable countrywide except Jammu and Kashmir.<p></p>The all-powerful GST council used the merits of goods and services to divide them into essential, non-essential and Luxury goods, according to which the tax rates for respective goods have been decided. Essential goods attracting zero or five percent, luxury goods at 28 percent and rest in between.<p></p>However, for a few goods, the classification makes it difficult to digest. It is hard to gauge what could have been the thought process behind putting following items in their respective tax slabs.<p></p><strong>Human hair or waste of human hair:</strong> This attracts zero percent tax rate which is reserved for daily used and essential items.<p></p>Human hair or the waste of human hair is used primarily for wigs and testing hair care products. Most of the hair waste in India is exported and it has negligible domestic usage. Ergo, it is hard to understand the rationale behind classifying human hair as essential.<p></p><strong>Watch: Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life After July 1</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p><strong>Sanitary pads:</strong> Despite repeated appeals by various activists and politicians, sanitary napkins are put under non-essential goods and 12 percent tax is levied on them. This is actually higher than what it was earlier: around six percent.<p></p>In contrast, sindoor, bangles and bindis have been classified as ‘essential’ and have been exempt from any taxes.<p></p>According to a 2011 study by AC Nielsen, only 12% of India's 335 million adult women can afford sanitary pads. Therefore, making it even more costly is a discouragement and may hamper female hygiene in the country.<p></p><strong>Stationery:</strong> Most of the stationery items—notebooks, register, paper, boards etc. have been put in the 18 percent tax bracket. Only books are exempts from any taxes.<p></p>Provided the literacy rate in India, the decision may not be a right step for a better future of the country.<p></p><strong>Read: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-impact-what-may-get-costlier-what-may-get-cheaper-2316013.html">GST impact: What may get costlier, what may get cheaper</a></strong><p></p><strong>Toothpaste and soap:</strong> Two of the things used by a majority of the population, every morning, has been put under 18 percent tax slab.<p></p>Given Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s emphasis on cleanliness and hygiene, this decision is surprising.<p></p><strong>Shampoo and detergents:</strong> These two things, perhaps, used in every house in the country has been classified as luxury items and attract 28 percent tax.<p></p>Contrastingly, diamonds, gold and other precious metals which are bought be a minuscule population has been put under a special tax bracket of 0.25 percent and three percent.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/t/tax3_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-04 14:44:46</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>