<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/govt-to-offer-gst-courses-at-garib-nawaz-skill-centres_9233341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt to offer GST courses at &#39;Garib Nawaz&#39; skill centres]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Centre will offer certificate courses in Goods and Services Tax (GST) accounting, programming and other related subjects through its &#39;Garib Nawaz&#39; skill development centres.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Centre will offer certificate courses in Goods and Services Tax (GST) accounting, programming and other related subjects through its 'Garib Nawaz' skill development centres.<p></p>The announcement was made by Union minister Mukhtar Abbas Naqvi after inaugurating the first such centre here. The centres are being set up to offer employment-oriented training to youths of minority communities.<p></p>"The demand for professionals with knowledge of GST accounting/programming will increase significantly in the coming days. The GST courses will be offered with the assistance of experts," an official statement quoting Naqvi said.<p></p><strong>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life After July 1</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>The minister said on completion of the three-month course, the youths will be able to help small and medium size businessmen.<p></p>They, he added, also stand to benefit immensely at individual levels as the course will open vast job opportunities in related areas.<p></p>The Union Minister of State for Minority Affairs said the government plans to launch the centres at 99 more places.<p></p>The centres will provide certificate courses in health services, mobile and laptop repairing, computer hardware and networking, retail management programme, motor driving training, security guard training, courses in housekeeping and others.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/shutterstock_549852313_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-09 10:05:18</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>