<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/discussionseconomy-gst-good-for-democracy-venkaiah-naidu_9825181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Discussions on economy, GST good for democracy: Venkaiah Naidu]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["Discussions are going on about the country, its economy and also GST - its effects, after-effects and side-effects. Let the discussions go on. It is always good for democracy," Naidu said during his speech at the International Conference on Technological Advancements in Railway and Metro Projects.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Vice President Venkaiah Naidu today said discussions on economy and GST should go on and that such debates and consultations are always good for democracy.<p></p>In the long run, GST will be beneficial for all, the vice president asserted.<p></p>"Discussions are going on about the country, its economy and also GST - its effects, after-effects and side-effects. Let the discussions go on. It is always good for democracy," Naidu said during his speech at the International Conference on Technological Advancements in Railway and Metro Projects.<p></p>Speaking on a day when the GST council is meeting in Delhi, the VP said that people must understand that any transformation, any reformation face "some initial hiccups, some teething troubles".<p></p>"But at the end of the day, the PM's mantra of reform, perform and transform has a meaning," he said, adding that GST is India's most revolutionary tax reform ever.<p></p>Quoting news reports, Naidu said that the World Bank and big multinational companies have also endorsed GST and that future generations of Indians will be happy with this tax reform.<p></p>He also said that the political debate on GST should be allowed to go on and the government of the day will take a note of the positive and the critical points and then "take corrective measures".<p></p>"With about 8 lakh crore brand investments opening up FDI in retail infrastructure and the implementation of GST, I am sure the Indian Railways, particularly the long-distance transport, will stand to benefit in the years ahead," he said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/V/Venkaiah_Naidu_Minister_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-10-06 14:43:25</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>