<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/insurance-sector-will-benefitgstthe-long-run-gaurav-seth_9215041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Insurance sector will benefit from GST in the long run: Gaurav Seth]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The GST rate is slightly higher than the existing service tax rate. Therefore, it would result in a small increase in the insurance premium]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The implementation of GST is likely to increase insurance premiums. However. Despite the cost increase, one should buy insurance mainly for financial protection, says Gaurav Seth, CFO, Canara HSBC Oriental Bank of Commerce Life Insurance Company Ltd. In an interview with Navneet Dubey, he talks about GST’s impact on insurance sector. Excerpts:<p></p><strong>How do you view GST and its impact the insurance sector? </strong><p></p>One nation, one tax is a welcome step. However, the new environment will mean the indirect tax compliances would be decentralized and hence there would be a need to file returns as well as manage compliances in every state from the current situation where industry files only a single centralised return and all tax compliances are fulfilled at a single location.<p></p>To explain, from the current 2 returns in a year (half-yearly &amp; annual) every insurer would need to file 37 returns (3 per month plus one annual return) per state. Therefore, if an insurance company operates in 20 states they would need to file 740 returns per year. This would mean substantial changes to the IT system &amp; the overall governance framework. However on the flip side, today there are 17 indirect taxes that are levied on goods and services which would be replaced by a single integrated tax, so from that aspect it eases the procedural formalities as well. So to summarize, in the short term there could be teething issues, however it would ease as we progress during the course of the year.<p></p><strong>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p><strong>How GST will affect the premium calculations of different products?<p></p></strong><p></p>The GST rate is slightly higher than the existing service tax rate. Therefore, it would result in a small increase in the insurance premium. A product-wise impact on life insurance is as below:<p></p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2319009" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/07/insurance-image-1.png" alt="insurance image" width="578" height="223" /><p></p><strong>Will GST benefit the insurance sector?<p></p></strong><p></p>GST has all the ingredients of fuelling growth for our economy. It is expected to push the India GDP growth to over 8% as it will enhance production due to higher demand and also allow the movement of goods and services between the various states. Growth in the economy is a primary driver for the Insurance Industry and hence from that perspective GST will be an enabler. Therefore, in my view a well implemented GST would have hugely positive impact on the insurance sector in the medium to long term.<p></p>It show that in coming future the insurance sector is going towards a positive direction where, though today you and me will get affected by the increase in the premium rates but in the future you may get benefited by getting higher sum insured at the same cost of premium and so on.<p></p>&nbsp;]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/I/Insurance-1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-05 13:06:43</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>