<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/adopt-gstbecome-parthistorysmriti-irani-to-biz-community_9311461.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Adopt GST and become part of history : Smriti Irani to biz community]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Calling the Goods and Services Tax (GST) a "great step towards transparency," Textile and Information and Broadcasting Minister Smriti Irani urged the business community to become a part of this historic tax reform.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Calling the Goods and Services Tax (GST) a "great step towards transparency," Textile and Information and Broadcasting Minister Smriti Irani urged the business community to become a part of this historic tax reform.<p></p>"GST is not only a good and simple tax, but also a great step towards transformation. Let us make history and be a part of it, so that we can tell our future generations that we never evaded tax," she said.<p></p>"Now with GST, as consumers and taxpayers, you are informed that this is the part of the economy you contribute...(The effort is) how to expand manufacturing base, how to expand the base of tax, and build infrastructure so that people do not evade paying tax."<p></p><p></p><strong>How GST Will Change Your Life</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>According to Smriti Irani, GST is supported by all political parties in Parliament which is a rare achievement.<p></p>"The GST Council is one place where all political parties spoke in one voice, and through consensus supported GST, which is something you do not get to see in Parliament."<p></p>She confirmed that the government will ensure traders, who have been protesting against the new tax regime that came into force on July 1, are not harassed.<p></p>Taking a dig at opposition Congress, Irani said those who are criticising GST are the same people who gained when this tax system was not in place. They are now trying to create fear against the new tax regime among traders.<p></p>GST actually subsumes 72 taxes and 17 cesses. Post the new tax regime, trucks no longer have to stop at checkpoints to pay octroi (entry tax), she said.<p></p>On input tax credit, Irani said the provision is to give the money back for paying GST.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/S/Smriti_Irani__356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-22 16:40:17</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>