<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/meeting-customer-expectations-biggest-challenge-gstn-ceo_9749721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Meeting customer expectations biggest challenge: GSTN CEO]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Taxpayers have complained of various glitches including lack of forms, inability to rectify errors, bugs in the software and inaccessibility of the site]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Meeting taxpayers’ expectations and ensuring glitch-free return filing have been GST Network’s (GSTN’s) biggest challenges, its CEO Prakash Kumar said, responding to criticism about the portal’s under preparedness to implement a country-wide goods and services tax (GST).<p></p>“That (meeting taxpayer’s expectations) is what our job is and need to make sure that we come up to that expectation,” Kumar told <em>Moneycontrol</em>.<p></p>Taxpayers have complained of various glitches including lack of forms, inability to rectify errors, bugs in the software and in many cases, the site was not accessible.<p></p>Kumar and his team are now working towards enhancing certain aspects in the system.<p></p>In the last meeting on September 9, the GST Council headed by finance minister Arun Jaitley formed a state finance ministers’ panel to look into the problems traders and taxpayers are facing in using the GSTN portal, the information technology (I-T) backbone of the new tax system.<p></p>Industry bodies and traders have repeatedly sought more time to enable glitch-free filing of returns, minimise erroneous entries and the get accustomed to the GSTN.<p></p>GSTN is a portal-driven IT backbone created to enable real-time taxpayer registration, filing returns, handle invoices, execute inter-state tax settlements, and connect states for two-way data flow.<p></p>Its readiness has come under question, with many states complaining about its under-preparedness.<p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/current-affairs-trends/gst-council-imposes-differential-cess-on-luxury-cars-suvs-and-sedans-returns-filing-deadline-extended-2383501.html" target="_blank"><strong>Also read: GST Council imposes differential cess on luxury cars, SUVs and sedans; returns filing deadline extended</strong></a><p></p>GSTN’s smooth function is essential for a steady rollout of the new tax system and a string of snags have forced the government extended the deadline for filing various tax returns more than once.<p></p>“Improvement is a constant function. Improvement on the portal is done for two things--for user friendliness any bug that slows down the software,” he said.<p></p>For instance, a preview for submission of the input-output summary form GSTR3B wasn’t available, for first few days.<p></p>“People wanted preview before they submit the form. So we provided it on the fifth (day). It was a huge relief for the people (taxpayers),” he said.<p></p>Similarly, businesses have complained that some key forms are not available on the portal. From next week, an entity can choose to opt out from the small tax payers’ plan—composition scheme.<p></p>Composition scheme is an alternate method of taxation, which allows small businesses with annual turnover up to Rs 75 lakhs, to pay tax at a concessional rate, as well as reduce the compliance cost.<p></p>“An opt-out option (from the composition scheme) will be available from next week if an entity decides it wants to become a normal taxpayer,” Kumar explained.<p></p>Another key form pertaining to cancellation of registration will be introduced around October 20.<p></p>Under GST, if a person decides to exit or wrap up the business, then the registration has to be necessarily cancelled.<p></p>“An entire workflow needs to be prepared to ready the cancellation form for someone who has decided to close the business,” Kumar said.<p></p>“There is a complete workflow. The cancellation request will be forwarded to the tax officer. He will then look at the data, raise a query, review forms, purchases, among others. The officer has to draft an order and the order has to be delivered. That’s why it takes time,” he said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/P/Prakash-kumar-GSTN-3_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-09-25 15:25:00</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>