<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/smooth-rollout-to-gst-arun-jaitley_9411021.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Smooth rollout to GST: Arun Jaitley]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["It has been an extremely smooth turnover without any disruption" the Union Finance Minister told reporters here.  He rejected the argument that trade registration under GST was less and said a record number of registrations have taken place.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Union Minister Arun Jaitley today said the rollout of Goods and Services Tax (GST) was 'extremely smooth' in the country.<p></p>"It has been an extremely smooth turnover without any disruption" the Union Finance Minister told reporters here.  He rejected the argument that trade registration under GST was less and said a record number of registrations have taken place.<p></p>On the alleged irregularities connected with MCI clearance to a private medical college involving a BJP functionary in Kerala, Jaitley said the state BJP had taken prompt action against the worker.<p></p>"We are the only political party in the country, which,as part of self-introspection, takes action, he said, adding that in several states, people have been caught for improprieties and parties were strongly trying to defend them.<p></p>"If a party sets a precedent by dismissing a member for irregularities, it is a good action and also a good step in Indian politics", Jaitley said.<p></p>BJPs Kerala unit came under a cloud after an internal party report purportedly said that a functionary allegedly took Rs 5.60 crore bribe to facilitate approval from the Medical Council of India for the college at nearby Varkala.<p></p>After the issue surfaced in the media, the BJP dismissed R S Vinod, convener of BJPs co-operative cell in the state, whose name was mentioned in the purported party report.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-07 07:35:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>