<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/ambit-govts-warblack-money-throwsinteresting-opportunities-for-investors_9361641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Ambit: Govt&#39;s war on black money throws up interesting opportunities for investors]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ambit Capital is now showcasing some of the themes its analysts have been highlighting.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[In recent reports, broking firm Ambit Capital has talked about how the Indian economy is being transformed by some of the measures taken by the central government.<p></p>The firm's market calls have sometimes gone awry -- but having acknowledged its mistakes a few days ago, the brokerage is now showcasing some of the themes its analysts have been highlighting.<p></p>Themes such as the massive transformation that India has been undergoing thanks to the government’s war on black money.<p></p>Even though the benchmark indices have run up significantly, these themes will continue to throw up opportunities for investors, says Pramod Gubbi, Managing Director and Head – Equities Ambit Institutional Equities, in an interview with Malini Bhupta of Moneycontrol.<p></p><strong>Ambit’s research tends to get a lot of attention. In recent times, you have come out with your calls that went wrong. But what about ones that went right and what themes can investors look at now?</strong><p></p>We started highlighting what we did right and what we missed in the year 2011 as the year came to a close. Since then we have done this every year. This year we decided to do it differently by putting out things every week. We started where we went wrong. We decided to take out mistakes on our chin. But our hits are coming in instalments.<p></p>We were among the first to say what this dispensation up to in terms of its long-term agenda. We talked about attack on black money and corruption. By doing that the government automatically attacked two asset classes — real estate and gold. As both these asset classes go out of favour, money has to find a new place to hide. And given where interest rates were headed, money started coming into bank deposits and mutual funds. This got accelerated by demonetisation. Once the money is in the system, it is unlikely to go out again, as motive to hide it is not there. By demonetisation, sheen was taken off gold and real estate. Once the money comes into financial markets, it kicks off a virtuous cycle with more money coming into the market, they go higher and more money comes in. Part of the money is cyclical. A lot of this is structural as well. Assuming the clamp down on black money continues, this theme should be structural. People will put their money into mutual funds.<p></p>This will have ramifications on economy and markets. The economy benefits as cost of capital goes down. You have already seen where interest rates are going and where bond yields are headed. Companies are able to raise money in markets at significantly high valuations shows that cost of capital is 200 basis points lower. Access to capital is now cheaper for many businesses, which was not so a few years ago despite India having a high savings rate. Now projects at the margin can become viable. Other two factors of production — land and labour — also need to come down.<p></p><strong>So you are saying investors can benefit from this theme?</strong><p></p>Flow is one thing and keeps buoyancy in the market. But there are companies that intermediate between the saver and user of capital. These will benefit a lot. You’ve already seen that with mutual funds with assets under management is up to Rs 5 lakh crore and industry has gone up three times. Anybody in the value chain between saver and broker will benefit significantly like brokers, insurance and mutual funds.<p></p>In terms of stock market plays, ICICI Pru and Max Life are two listed entities. Hopefully, we will see more. Motilal Oswal has been in the midst of this theme and we have seen they have benefited first as an asset manager, then as a broker and now as housing finance company. So this financialisation of the economy is a big theme. The mutual fund industry went through five years of outflow and people had given up.<p></p><strong>What is the other theme that investors can look at?</strong><p></p>The second theme is the formalisation of the economy. The attack on black money and tax evasion has brought under the scanner a large component of the unorganised sector. India because of its porous nature had a large part of the economy that was out of the tax net and as a result what was unviable business became viable because there was no tax. Such businesses employed people and contributed to growth of economy, except that the exchequer was not benefited. The attack on cash economy and finally the GST has also ensured that it is difficult to stay out of the tax net. A number of businesses occupying the tax arbitrage zone have no option but to fold up or margin will squeeze. Implications of this are that formal sector will take market-share from this unorganised sector. Hence the market’s earnings will remain buoyant. The formal sector has access to capital. Typically, any consumer facing sector will benefit from this like hospitality, food sector and restaurants. Then you have distributors of building materials or suppliers to real estate like electrical, plywood and pipes. As they get formalised, the formal sector will start gaining share. A lot of builders for instance are existing because they are out of tax net.<p></p><strong>What sectors will benefit from the focus of the government on attacking black money?</strong><p></p>A few of these themes we have been highlighting have done well include: financial intermediaries, retail, building materials, hospitality, shopping complexes and hotels.<p></p><strong>Markets have run up a lot. What is your view on this and is there potential in the market if investors have a long-term horizon?</strong><p></p>Valuations are elevated and factor in sharp recovery in earnings and that to sustain over the long term. There are risks to both assumptions which aren’t factored in adequately. If the investors have long-term capital, then there are opportunities. If you have a horizon of 5-7 years then what valuation you enter at has little bearing on the returns. This is still a high growth market and earnings of good companies is over 15% and if you are compounding at 15-20% then whether it is 30x P/E, you will offset it with compounding. If you have access to capital with that kind of a horizon, there is opportunity in the market.<p></p>If an investor is totally fundamental about the market then it is best to step away from the market for a while. Purely based on fundamentals, you cannot justify anything less than a three year horizon. Partly the risks lurking and there is little support of earnings. And valuations are factoring in super normal earnings. So this is a classic case of risking loss. For those who cannot live with these drawdowns, the last thing you want is to sell stock when they are down.<p></p><strong>What are the risks?</strong><p></p>At the macro level, globally the end of easy money. We still see the central banks participating in global asset classes. They dread unwinding themselves but they are talking of unwinding. But for that we will need all central banks to step away, not just the US Federal Reserve. There is a lot of backlash because of this. While central banks stepping into asset markets may have prevented a meltdown in global asset markets, but this has only benefited a few. The elite top one percent will suffer if this easy money ends.<p></p><strong>Is India unique when it comes equity returns?</strong><p></p>It is simple actually and peculiar is not the word associated with it. Market has yielded 15% over the last three decades. If you are seeing cost of capital is coming down then you are looking at 12-13% returns. If economy will have lower inflation then return of 12% is fairly handsome from an equity point of view. India has a lot more depth than other markets of our size. For the retail investors, there are plenty of companies yet to be discovered and invest in them for a long period of time. Also the entrepreneurial culture with new businesses coming up from nowhere. This makes India more attractive and also that it has delivered best returns over a long period of time. It is a lot easier to beat benchmark in India as there are so many options outside India, which is why ETFs will take some time to come to India.<p></p><strong>Every rally has been driven by a few themes and which are going to drive the rally. Are you seeing some new themes that may enter the benchmark?</strong><p></p>Financialisation means a lot of beneficiaries will be up there. Some of these will be large enough to be in the benchmarks. As long as you have the eyes and ears, banks and financial services will continue to be in the benchmarks. Auto have consistently given returns historically. Autos will be part of the benchmark. Consumption will continue to be a large part of the benchmark — be it staples or discretionary. The need of the hour is for manufacturing to pick up and for that a lot of further reforms to happen. If that happen you will see a lot of light industrials. Infrastructure is need of the hour but unfortunately does not lend itself to stock markets. IT in the same vein may be no, but fintech yes.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/f/fando_market-1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-31 13:05:39</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>