<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/toyota-records-best-ever-july-sales-43-growth_9369981.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Toyota records best-ever July sales, 43% growth]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The company also exported 1723 units of the Etios series this month. Toyota Kirloskar Motor had sold 12404 units in the domestic market and exported 1,344 units of the Etios series in July 2016. The company passed on the benefits of GST to customers on an immediate effect post GST roll out from the beginning of July. GST has been fruitful for the industry by boosting customer demand across segments owing to the price reduction.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Toyota Kirloskar Motor recorded its best ever July sales in July 2017, it sold a total of 17750 units in the domestic market thereby registering over 43% growth as compared to its domestic sales in the corresponding period last year. This is the company’s third highest ever domestic sales achievement in a month.<p></p>The company also exported 1723 units of the Etios series this month. Toyota Kirloskar Motor had sold 12404 units in the domestic market and exported 1,344 units of the Etios series in July 2016. The company passed on the benefits of GST to customers on an immediate effect post GST roll out from the beginning of July. GST has been fruitful for the industry by boosting customer demand across segments owing to the price reduction.<p></p>The Innova and Fortuner have seen a stupendous growth in the month of July 2017 with the highest ever units sold since its launch. Both Innova Crysta and All New Fortuner have been receiving great response post its launch in May 2016 and November 2016 respectively.<p></p>Read More: <a href="http://www.news18.com/news/auto/toyota-records-best-ever-july-sales-43-growth-1479161.html">http://www.news18.com/news/auto/toyota-records-best-ever-july-sales-43-growth-1479161.html</a>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/T/Toyota-logo_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-01 12:05:06</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>