<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/lower-endtax-slabs-could-be-nextgst-councils-rejig-agenda_10043441.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Lower end of tax slabs could be next on GST Council&#39;s rejig agenda]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The government plans to streamline the current rates and have only two to three rates instead of multiple rates.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[After cutting rates on 178 goods to bring them under the 18 percent slab, the GST Council will now shift its focus toward the lower end of the tax slabs, <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/policy/next-step-in-gst-recast-lower-end-of-tax-slabs/articleshow/61620482.cms" target="_blank">reports</a> <em>The Economic Times.</em><p></p>The focus will now be on the 12 percent and 5 percent slabs, a top official told the newspaper. Talks on bringing real estate and petroleum under GST will also be taken up.<p></p>The government plans to streamline the current rates, and have only two to three rates instead of multiple rates.<p></p>Besides rates, the Council is also likely to discuss simplification of rules and procedures as per the industry's feedback.<p></p>On Friday last week, the <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-council-cuts-taxes-on-about-175-items-from-28-only-50-luxury-and-sin-goods-like-tobacco-to-remain-in-highest-slab-2435145.html" target="_blank">Council cut rates</a> on 178 goods leaving only 50 luxury and sin/demerit goods like ACs, automobiles paints, cement, washing machines and tobacco, among others, in the 28 percent slab.<p></p>The tax cuts will have a revenue implication of about Rs 20,000 crore.<p></p>The government has also set up a committee with industry experts to review the new tax regime, which was implemented in July this year.<p></p>A committee headed by the Chief Economic Advisor Arvind Subramanian has suggested revenue-neutral rate of 15-15.5 percent. The committee has also suggested standard rate of 17-18 percent and another 40 percent for sin and luxury items such as tobacco. For essential goods, the rate suggested was 12 percent.<p></p>GST, billed as the country's biggest indirect tax overhaul, has consolidated a dozen of state and central duties into one single levy. All goods and services have been fitted into four broad slab structure — 5, 12, 18 and 28 percent —along with a cess on luxury and demerit goods such as tobacco, pan masala and aerated drinks.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst-770x433_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-11-13 11:07:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>