<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/lifestyle/heresgetting-by-is-not-getting-any-easier-despite-falling-inflation_9208281.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Here&#39;s why getting by is not getting any easier despite falling inflation]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[From eating out to moving getaways, from DTH bills to home rents, from doctor visits to gym sessions have all become costlier, as yesterday’s luxuries become today’s necessities]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Nikita Vashisht<p></p></strong><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Officially, the last few years have been remarkable for low prices, globally and in India as well. Persistently low crude oil prices and a bumper food crop, aided by abundant summer rains, have kept overall inflation rates low.<p></p>This cool-off has been particularly pronounced in the last three years. Between June 2014 and May 2017, monthly retail inflation or the consumer price index (CPI)—a metric to measure changes in shop-end prices—has averaged 4.81 percent.<p></p>Food inflation, a proxy to gauge household kitchen budgets, have also broadly followed the headline inflation rate. It has moderated to (-)1.05 percent in May.<p></p>Waning inflation rates, however, seem to be hiding soaring costs of several everyday services and non-essential products, bleeding household budgets. This has made getting by get harder for millions of average middle class families.<p></p>It could get even costlier, with the goods and services tax (GST), which kicked-in from July 1, placing many commonly used services such as mobile services and AC restaurants at the 18 percent, from the earlier 15 percent service tax rate.<p></p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2317933" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/07/Retail-inflation.jpg" alt="Retail inflation" width="1280" height="749" /><p></p>Data collated by <em>Moneycontrol</em> from industry sources show that from eating out to moving getaways, from DTH bills to home rents, from doctor visits to gym sessions—have all become costlier, as yesterday’s luxuries become today’s necessities.<p></p>“If we analyse our bills, we end up paying more and more every year; major chunk of it goes as taxes,” said Rahul Kukreja, a management student.<p></p>In current prices, Indians’ average earnings, measured by the per capita income has risen from Rs 61, 855 in March 2012 to Rs 103219 in March 2017—a 66 percent jump. Adjusted for inflation, however, per capita income has increased only 33 percent over the last five years—from Rs 61,855 to Rs 82,269. This growth in income is far slower than the prices of several widely used services such as a gym subscription, DTH charges, spa sessions, movie tickets and doctor visits. The same amount of money now buys less goods and services, as spending has outpaced income growth.<p></p>DTH costs, for instance,  has risen 400 percent from an average of about Rs 50 a month in 2012 to Rs 250 currently. Doctors’ OPD fees have jumped 267 percent from about 150 to Rs 500 now, while salon costs have risen about 133 percent from Rs 300 in 2012 to Rs 700 now.<p></p>Monthly gym subscription fees have increased at relatively lower 30 percent—from Rs 5000 a month five years ago to Rs 6500 currently. At about Rs 196 movie tickets, on an average, are 26 percent more expensive now than about Rs 156 five years ago.<p></p>The cost of a three-course meal in an upscale restaurant has nearly doubled from about Rs 500 (without taxes per person) to about Rs 900 now.<p></p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2317953" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/07/Services.jpg" alt="Services" width="1094" height="686" /><p></p>“Cost of living has always increased,” said Madhavi Arora, economist, Kotak Securities Ltd. “The increase has only slowed down”.<p></p>It is not just services that are pinching. Travel bills are far higher now compared to five years ago, despite record low crude global oil prices in the last 12 to 18 months. A litre of diesel now costs Rs 56 in Delhi, up 35.5 percent from Rs 41.29 in 2012.<p></p>“Travelling by car is not as convenient as it is perceived to be… the increased prices have significantly push up the maintenance cost,” said Mukul Sharma, a home-décor businessmen.<p></p>India’s inflation rates have remained well within the RBI’s tolerable threshold limit of 6 percent. It was 2.18 percent in May—a level that some analysts see as symptomatic of poor demand and weak economic activity.<p></p>Besides, non-food, non-fuel inflation, or what economists refer to as “core” inflation, remains sticky at close at about 4.5 percent levels.<p></p>“Core inflation is sticky (presently),” said Arora, adding that only the food inflation has fallen while services remain high.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/i/inflation_1280_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-04 12:10:09</Entry_Date><Category>Lifestyle</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>