<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/gst-to-be-partsyllabusup-higher-education-institutes_9224721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST to be part of syllabus in UP higher education institutes]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The taxation system under GST will soon be part of the commerce and management curriculum in Uttar Pradesh&#39;s higher education institutes, a minister said on Thursday.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The taxation system under GST will soon be part of the commerce and management curriculum in Uttar Pradesh's higher education institutes, a minister said on Thursday.<p></p>The Goods and Services Tax (GST) -- India's biggest tax reform since independence -- came into force on July 1, unifying more than a dozen central and state levies.<p></p>Deputy Chief Minister Dinesh Sharma said, "GST is a major step in the direction of economic reforms and besides apprising the common people about the new tax regime, there is also a need to include it in the syllabus."<p></p>"It will be included in the management and commerce curriculum," he said.<p></p><strong>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>"We have requested vice-chancellors of all universities to hold seminars in their institutes in cooperation with the commercial tax department and invite chartered accountants, intellectuals, teachers, traders, and students," the minister said.<p></p>Sharma, who also holds the secondary and higher education portfolio, said problems being faced by teachers will be resolved soon as they can carry on with their duties only with a free mind.<p></p>Noting that teachers of junior classes were being deployed in a census and other such works, he said they will be removed from such duties and will be deployed fully for their prime task of imparting education.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/G/GST_Goods_and_Services_Teax1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-06 20:46:17</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>