<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/hindustan-sanitaryware-targets-rs-6000-cr-revenuefive-years_9358881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Hindustan Sanitaryware targets Rs 6,000 cr revenue in five years]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["With the projects that we already have in the pipeline plus we are putting up two new plants, with those plants getting commissioned, I think we should be closer to Rs 5,500 to 6,000 crore in revenue in five years&#39; time," HSIL Vice Chairman and MD Sandip told PTI here.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Sanitaryware manufacturer HSIL is eyeing over two-fold growth to be Rs 6,000 crore company in the next five years, a top company official has said.<p></p>"With the projects that we already have in the pipeline plus we are putting up two new plants, with those plants getting commissioned, I think we should be closer to Rs 5,500 to 6,000 crore in revenue in five years' time," HSIL Vice Chairman and MD Sandip told PTI here.<p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/ceramics-granite/hsil/HSI02">Hindustan Sanitaryware and Industry</a> (HSIL), which sells products under the Hindware brand, had registered a revenue of Rs 2,200 crore last fiscal, and Somany said the company aim to register 15-20 per cent growth each year for the next five years.<p></p>This fiscal year, it aims to grow at 18 per cent.<p></p>The company is setting up a security closure plant and a CPVC pipes plant in Telangana, which will be a backward integration to its building materials business.<p></p>Somany said the company will be able to to sell Rs 700- 800 crore worth of pipes in the near future.<p></p>The bathroom solutions firm, which gets more than 50 per cent of its revenue from premium products, recently entered super-premium category with the brand Alchymi and expects luxury and the super-premium segments to grow faster than the normal market.<p></p>The general market is growing at 10-12 per cent and luxury is growing at 20 per cent.<p></p>HSIL has a market share of 38 per cent in the Rs 4,000 crore sanitaryware industry and with foray into the super- premium category, it expects it to be 40 per cent in the next two years.<p></p>The company plans to add 200 stores by next year to its large format store Hindware Galleria that are owned by dealers and distributors, taking the total number to 400.<p></p>The smaller towns contribute around 40 per cent of the company's sales, and Somany said they are growing at a faster rate and in the next three years could account for half their sales.<p></p>At present, retail segment accounts for 70 per cent of HSIL's sales, while institutional sales account for the rest.<p></p>On the new tax regime of goods and services tax (GST), he said things are settling down and expect a significant improvement for the business from August end.<p></p>The company, which has 12 per cent market share in the Rs 3,000 crore organised faucet market, has reduced prices in the category post GST, extending the benefit to customers.<p></p>The company sells its products in Africa, Middle East, South America and some countries in Europe and exports account for Rs 100 crore of the turnover.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/R/Rupee_finance3_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-30 13:57:15</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,HSI,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>