<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/ca-signatures-carry-more-power-thansignaturethe-prime-ministerthis-country-pm_9192161.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[CA signatures carry more power than the signature of the Prime Minister of this country: PM]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[India has finally turned a new page with the launch of GST.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>And that's a wrap ! Modi leaves to uproarious applause.Do stay for tuned for more news and updates.</strong><p></p><ul class="listBlog"><p></p>	<li><p></p><div class="bDtl"><p></p><div class="clearfix"><p></p>My heartiest congratulations to you Chartered Accountants on your founding day.<p></p></div><p></p></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>20:00</strong> (IST) Don’t let this opportunity to run away from integrating the whole nation.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:58</strong> (IST) Modi's challenge: On the 75 th year of the founding ICAI, will you change the big four to the big eight companies of Chartered Accountant firms of the world?</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:54</strong> (IST) The name of a CA  must be equated with Compliance and Accuracy, says PM.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:53</strong> (IST) Chartered Accountants have a great role to play in the insolvency code.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:52</strong> (IST) I invite everyone to carry on with their profession with dignity.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:51</strong> (IST) PM says that man only committs crimes only when he has someone saving him</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:48</strong> (IST) I invite you to set your ways straight this July. Understand the greatness of your profession and carry it forward.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:46</strong> (IST) PM: I appeal to you, your signature carries the trust of crores of Indian, never let break, never let it get a scratch even.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:44</strong> (IST) CA signatures carry more power than the signature of the Prime Minister of this country.</p><p></p><p class="time"></p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:43</strong> (IST) Chartered Accountants are the economic ambassadors between the people and businesses.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li></ul><p></p><ul><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:42</strong> (IST) The role of CAs have become more important after the rollout of the goods and services tax.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:41</strong> (IST) Today our nation stands at an important stage in history. 2017 will the year where one naiton,one tax and one market will be fulfilled.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:37</strong> (IST) How is it possible that only 25 Chartered Accountants are prosecuted? Are only these many people committing crimes?</p><p></p></li></ul><p></p><ul class="listBlog"><p></p>	<li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:35</strong> (IST) Only 35 lakh people file their returns with an income above 10 lakhs, do you believe this?</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:34</strong> (IST) In a country of 2 crore engineers and management people, and 2 crore 13 lakh people traveled abroad.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:31</strong> (IST) I urge you to spot these thieves between us, who have looted us with the black money.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:26</strong> (IST) We have noted around 38,000 shell companies that hide and move around black money, they will be given strict punishment.</p><p></p></li></ul><p></p><ul class="listBlog"><p></p><ul class="listBlog"><p></p>	<li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:26</strong> (IST)We have noted around 38,000 shell companies that hide and move around black money, they will be given strict punishment.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:25</strong> (IST) Just 48 hours back, more than 1 Lakh companies have been shut with the single stroke of a pen.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:25</strong> (IST) Just 48 hours back, more than 1 Lakh companies have been shut with the single stroke of a pen.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:23</strong> (IST) We have lined up the figures after November 8 through data mining : 3 Lakh registered companies are under the scanner.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:19</strong> (IST) On one hand, I am carrying out Swach Bharat Abhiyaan, on the other, I am cleaning up the economy.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:18</strong> (IST) In two years down the line, when Swiss start releasing real time data, then it will be a tough time for these people.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:17</strong> (IST) 30 years ago, in 1987, Swiss banks started disclosing the amounts countries put up. According to the latest reports, the amounts deposited came down by 45 percent.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:16</strong> (IST) If people keep stealing from a country, the country will not sustain.</p><p></p></li></ul><p></p>	<li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:13</strong> (IST) Our elders say: Even after a fire, we can rebuild, but if anyone keeps stealing, the family stops working.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:10</strong> (IST) Your worth is equivalent to the great Rishimunis for handling wealth in the right ways. How to go about using wealth in the right way is the responsibility of you Chartered Accountants.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:08</strong> (IST) I have the honor of inducting this dynamic course, which will improve the financial education in our country.</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:07</strong> (IST) You, as CAs are an important pillar for our economy. The world looks up to the CAs of India for their diligence.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>19:06</strong> (IST) You have been given a divine right to decide the right from the wrong in this country</p><p></p></li></ul><p></p><ul class="listBlog"><p></p>	<li><strong>19:03</strong> (IST) Today marks the beginning of GST, the Good and Simple Tax in this country.</li><li><p></p><div class="bDtl"><p></p><div class="clearfix"><strong>19:01</strong> (IST)My greatest salutations to you all for braving the rain and making it to the event on this historic day.</div><p></p><div class="clearfix"></div><p></p></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>18:58</strong> (IST)<strong>PM Modi begins speech.</strong></p><p></p></li><li><p></p><div class="bDtl"> <strong>18:58</strong> (IST)The CA profession is behind you. Your presence will motivate us for a long time to come.</div><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>18:56</strong> (IST) <strong>CA Nilesh.A.Vikamsey gives introductory speech, praises Modi for the most awaited, </strong><strong>long awaited</strong><strong> reform</strong></p><p></p></li><li><strong>He's </strong><strong>Here !</strong><strong> PM Narendra Modi enters </strong><strong>stage</strong><strong> with "Kadam Badhaeyga" song in </strong><strong>background</strong><strong>. Modi recived to cheers.</strong></li></ul><p></p><ul class="listBlog"><p></p>	<li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>18:45</strong> (IST)  The Prime Minister is on his way in a few minutes, thank you Chartered Accountants</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>18:44</strong> (IST) we will keep moving the direct and indirect taxes towards digitization, will help assessees and the general public.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>18:42</strong> (IST) All those who say that whether single or double rate of tax is not possible yet.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>18:40</strong> (IST) <strong>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley is back, no sign of PM.</strong></p><p></p></li></ul><p></p><ul class="listBlog"><p></p>	<li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>17:41</strong> (IST) A majority of support and solutions around GST came from Chartered Accounts, for that I am very grateful</p><p></p></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>17:39</strong> (IST)<strong> Let's see what Hasmukh Adia has to say 12 hours into GST</strong></p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>17:38</strong> (IST) Government which blinks, are never able to reform.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>17:38</strong> (IST) I specifically thank the ICAI and Chartered Accountants for carrying out the campaign while keeping public opinion positive.</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>17:36</strong> (IST) We are not dealing with the tribals, meant for top one percent of the country.For those businesses with a turnover of crores, will the software present itself as a hurdle ?</p><p></p><div class="bDtl"></div></li><li><p></p><p class="time"><strong>17:35</strong> (IST) <strong>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley speaks at ICAI event </strong></p><p></p></li></ul><p></p><strong>1.45</strong>  That's all for the night. Thanks for staying tuned to the live coverage.<p></p><strong>01.15 Sushil Modi on GST Launch</strong><p></p># Central Government has assured that each state will see 14% revenue growth<p></p># Must thank PM Modi &amp; FM Jaitley for this historic moment<p></p># The efforts made by the BJP towards GST overshadows Congress’ effort<p></p><strong>01.12 </strong>BJP president Amit Shah speaking about GST:<p></p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p></p><p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash">#WATCH</a>: BJP president Amit Shah speaking about <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GST?src=hash">#GST</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/gstrollout?src=hash">#gstrollout</a> <a href="https://t.co/wi2YeR8HFX">pic.twitter.com/wi2YeR8HFX</a></p><p></p>— ANI (@ANI_news) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI_news/status/880871623850467328">June 30, 2017</a></blockquote><p></p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script><p></p><strong>00.24</strong> SBI chief Arundhati Bhattacharya on GST<p></p># SBI’s Tech Platform, Internal Process Have Been Integrated With GoI Portal<p></p># Have already seen more than 1,000 visits, over 100 transactions on SBI’s IT backend<p></p># GST An Enormous Reform That Is Not Only Financial, But Social. Hope This Will Be A Really Seminal Reform For Country<p></p># There Is a Lot Of Capacity In The GST Tech System, Don’t Think There Will Be An Overload<p></p># There Will Be Some Hiccups, But Nothing We Cannot Take In Our Stride<p></p><strong>00.05</strong> <strong>Dawn of a new India - At the stroke of the midnight GST is rolled out with a bang!</strong><p></p>[caption id="attachment_2316175" align="aligncenter" width="424"]<img class=" wp-image-2316175" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/06/3-5-378x246.jpg" alt="Lucknow: A group traders burst fire-crackers to welcome GST in Lucknow on Friday. PTI Photo by Nand Kumar (PTI6_30_2017_000245B)" width="424" height="276" /> Lucknow: A group traders burst fire-crackers to welcome GST in Lucknow on Friday (PTI Photo by Nand Kumar).[/caption]<p></p><strong>00.03</strong> <strong>History has been created! PM Narendra Modi, President Pranab Mukherjee launches GST through the press of a button.</strong><p></p><strong>00.03</strong> President Pranab Mukherjee addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># GST will make our exports more competitive and also provide level playing field to domestic industry<p></p># GST will make tax incidence will be transparent<p></p># GST will be administered through a modern IT system<p></p># GST is a disruptive change no doubt<p></p># There is bound to be some teething problems<p></p># Deep appreciation for all those who made this possible<p></p><strong>23.59</strong> President Pranab Mukherjee addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># In these meetings and with CMs that most of them had a constructive approach and underlying commitment of GST<p></p># Confidence stood justified when then Parliament passed the Constitution Amendment Bill in 2016<p></p># It is remarkable the in the 18 GST council meetings decisions have been taken through a consensus<p></p># GST is the result of broad consensus between the centre and states<p></p># It is a tribute the maturity and wisdom of India's democracy<p></p><img class=" wp-image-2316171 aligncenter" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/06/2-2-378x179.jpg" alt="2" width="526" height="249" /><p></p><strong>23.56</strong> President Pranab Mukherjee addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># In a few minutes we will witness the launch of GST<p></p># This is a culmination of  14 year old journey when the Kelkar Task force mooted GST<p></p># Proposal for GST was first mooted in the budget of 2006<p></p># Design of GST assigned to the Empowered Committee of state FMs<p></p># Introduction of GST is a momentous event<p></p># Moment of personal satisfaction as I had presented the constitution amendment bill in 2011<p></p># Have a vivid recollection of meetings with the Empowered Committee<p></p><strong>23.53</strong> PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># GST is actually Good and Simple Tax<p></p># Good because it frees up layers of taxes, simple because it helps return filing easier<p></p># Thankful to President Pranab Mukherjee for guiding us<p></p># I invite President to deliver his speech<p></p><strong>23.50</strong> PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># GST will remove imbalance in the country<p></p># The more we spread economy horizontally - the country can go higher up vertically<p></p># GST is like Indian railways, run by the states and the Centre<p></p># GST's influence will be remembered by the future generations for its immense benefits<p></p># GST is a tax system of New India, Digital India and way of doing business<p></p># GST is not just tax reform, it is also an economic reform and a social reform<p></p><strong>23.48</strong> PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># Don't fall prey to rumours, adjusting with GST is as simple as a change in the power of prescription glasses<p></p># India has emerged as a preferred business destination internationally and GST will make exports competitive<p></p># Backward states are blessed with abundant natural resources<p></p># GST will provide the best opportunity for eastern states to progress<p></p><strong>23.45</strong> PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># Tax terrorism and inspector raj are not new things<p></p># GST, because of technological trails will free India from 'Inspector Raj'<p></p># GST has exempted traders with turnover of less than Rs 20 lakh and imposed low rates for traders with turnover of less than Rs 75 lakh<p></p># In simple terms GST will prove to be the most beneficial for the poor<p></p># The games of 'kuccha bills'and 'pucca bills' will be eliminated<p></p># It is true that not everybody is tech friendly<p></p># But every household with 10th and 12th standard students can guide on GST<p></p><strong>23.41</strong> PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># Lines of lorries had to queue up for hours in state borders and it is critical to ferry perishable goods. We are freeing ourselves today from such irregularities and barriers.<p></p># GST is simple, progressive. It will help curb black money and respects honesty<p></p># GST will bring in a new governance culture<p></p><strong>23.40</strong> PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># Chanakya said, Whatever is very distant or difficult to get, hardwork and perseverance can make it achievable<p></p># If Vallabhbhai Patel had not integrated all provinces into a single union, GST would not have been possible<p></p># From Ganganagar to Itanagar, from Leh to Lakhshwadweep, our dream of ONE NATION, ONE TAX will be fulfilled<p></p># One wonders what Albert Einstein would have said if he had seen the multiplicity of taxes in India, who had said that income tax was most different to understand<p></p># Earlier, the same good was priced differently in Delhi, Gurugram and Noida. Today, we have freed ourselves from such multiplicity of taxes.<p></p><strong>23.35</strong> PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># Today, there could not have been a more pious place to launch GST<p></p># GST, like the debates of the Constituent Assembly, has gone through a series of debates participated by the best brains of the country<p></p># When the Constitution was adopted, it gave the country's citizens fundamental rights<p></p># Likewise GST, is an example of cooperative federalism shows the collective strength of team India<p></p># Today midnight, all of us together will determine the nation's next course<p></p># Regardless of party and governments, GST council shows that upliftment of the poor remains paramount<p></p><img class=" wp-image-2316165 aligncenter" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/06/1-6-378x179.jpg" alt="1" width="456" height="216" /><p></p><strong>23.33</strong> GST council met for the 18th time today. The Holy Gita also has 18 chapters, says PM Modi.<p></p><strong>23.32</strong> PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># The Constituent Assembly met for the first time on December 9, 1946<p></p># The path we have chosen is not a decision of a single party, this is not a decision of single government<p></p># This is the result of collective effort of all of us<p></p># We have gathered together at the Central Hall and this is an extremely pious place<p></p># The government adopted the Consitution on November 26, 1949 in this very place<p></p># From a few moments from now, the country will move towards a new system<p></p><strong>23.29</strong> PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p># In the building of a nation, some moments come when reach a new turn to scale new heights<p></p># Today midnight, all of us together will determine the nation's next course<p></p># From a few moments from now, the country will move towards a new system<p></p># 125 crore people are witness to this change<p></p># GST's benefit is not limited just to the economic system<p></p><strong>23.23 </strong>PM Narendra Modi addresses Parliament on GST Launch<p></p><strong>23.17</strong>  Here's more from Jaitley on GST<p></p># GST is an important achievement for the whole country. In 2006, UPA announced its intent to launch GST by 2010.<p></p># Hon'ble President Pranab Mukherjee as FM introduced the constitution amendment bill in 2011<p></p># Parliamentary Standing committee under former FM Yashwant Sinha recommended setting up a GST Council<p></p># Successive governments decided to appoint leader from an opposition party as the chairman of Empowered Committee of state FMs<p></p><strong>23.12</strong> Consensus based decision making in the GST council underscores that India can collectively think and act with maturity for a collective purpose: FM Jaitley<p></p><strong>23.10</strong> It will be an India where the centre and state will work together for common goal of shared prosperity: FM Arun Jaitley<p></p><strong>23.08:</strong> GST is a journey that will awake India to limiltess possibilities: FM Jaitley<p></p><strong>23.06: </strong>We are in the process of making history with the launch of GST: FM<p></p><strong>23.05</strong> President, Vice President, PM Modi, former PM Deve Gowda, Lok Sabha Speaker present on dais for launch event<p></p><strong>23:00</strong> President Pranab Mukherjee arrives at the Parliament for the GST launch event.<p></p><strong>22:58</strong> PM Narendra Modi and Lok Sabha speaker Sumitra Mahajan arrive at the Parliament for the GST launch event.<p></p><strong>22:50: GST Launch - Next On Agenda</strong><p></p>President Pranab Mukherjee and PM Narendra Modi to arrive in Parliament at 11 pm.<p></p>PM Narendra to deliver a speech after FM Jaitley's speech at GST launch event.<p></p>President Pranab Mukherjee to symbolically launch GST at the stroke of midnight and deliver a short speech.<p></p>Two short films on the subject of GST will be screened during the launch event.<p></p>Lok Sabha speaker Sumitra Mahajan arrives in Parliament for GST launch event<p></p><strong>22:45</strong> President Pranab Mukherjee and Prime Minister Narendra Modi to arrive in Parliament at 11 pm<p></p><strong>22:43</strong> FM Arun Jaitley arrives at Parliament, to give a brief introductory speech on GST launch at 11 pm.<p></p><strong>22:31 Parliament of India illuminated ahead of GST Launch</strong><p></p><img class="alignnone wp-image-2316149" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/06/1-Parliament-344x258.jpg" alt="1 Parliament" width="485" height="364" /><p></p><strong>22:27</strong> <strong>Kerala Finance Minister TM Thomas Isaac views on GST Launch:</strong> GST is an important reform, but midnight celebration a political propaganda. Can’t join GST celebrations when people are being lynched. GST is not as monumental as gaining independence. In 2011, GST was scuttled because the BJP opposed it.<p></p><strong>22:20</strong><p></p>[caption id="attachment_2316131" align="aligncenter" width="393"]<img class="wp-image-2316131" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/06/PTI6_30_2017_000199B-1-403x435.jpg" alt="New Delhi: GST 17-Year Roller Coaster ride to Final Rollout. (PTI Graphics)" width="393" height="424" /> New Delhi: GST 17-Year Roller Coaster ride to Final Rollout (PTI Graphics).[/caption]<p></p><strong>22:15</strong> GST Launch: Former Tata Sons chairman Ratan Tata, actor Amitabh Bachchan (also a brand ambassador for GST), melody queen Lata Mangeshkar, former Delhi Metro Rail Corporation Managing Director E Sreedharan have been invited for the event.<p></p><strong>22:13</strong> Don't fret! All insurance policies will not attract 18% tax under GST. Read <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/dont-fret-all-insurance-policies-will-not-attract-18-tax-under-gst-2315445.html">here</a>.<p></p><strong>22:02 </strong>'Half-baked' GST launch a 'self-promotional spectacle': Rahul Gandhi. Read <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/politics/half-baked-gst-launch-a-self-promotional-spectacle-congress-vice-president-rahul-gandhi-2315847.html">here</a>.<p></p><strong>21:56</strong> Finance Minister Arun Jaitley: In the last council meet before launch, consensus was to ensure fertilizer price does not go up.<p></p><strong>21:45</strong> GST rollout tonight: Read everything you want to know about India’s biggest tax reform, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/goods-and-services-tax-all-that-you-wanted-to-know-2315465.html">here</a>.<p></p><strong>21:42</strong> Meanwhile, Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath's minister wonders what the GST full form is! Read <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/the-full-form-of-gst-is-yogis-minister-wonders-2315425.html">here</a>.<p></p><strong>21:41</strong> GST rollout: Malls clueless on the impact but billing system in place. Read <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-rollout-malls-clueless-on-the-impact-but-billing-system-in-place-2315567.html">here</a>.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><strong>21:39 GST Explained In 30 Seconds. Watch the short video below!</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_hGu28LswM" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p><strong>21:38</strong> P Chidambaram: Unpreparedness of business community a big stumbling block to GST rollout. GST law is still imperfect.<p></p><strong>21:37</strong> GST impact: What may get costlier, what may get cheaper. <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-impact-what-may-get-costlier-what-may-get-cheaper-2316013.html">Here's the list</a>.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><strong>21:36</strong> Just In: Next meeting of the GST Council is on first Saturday of August.<p></p><strong>21:35</strong> GST expected to add more jobs in a whole host of sectors. Read more <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-expected-to-add-more-jobs-in-a-whole-host-of-sectors-2315633.html">here</a>.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><strong>21:33</strong> GST Council revises tax rates on fertilisers, exclusive tractor parts. Read <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-council-revises-tax-rates-on-fertilisers-exclusive-tractor-parts-2316007.html">here</a>.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><strong>21:31</strong> Small pharma stores not ready with GST-compliant billing systems, olding stocks. <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/small-pharma-stores-not-ready-with-gst-compliant-billing-systems-holding-stocks-2315827.html">Here</a> is all you need to know about it.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><strong>21:29</strong> Traders cautious in Azadpur mandi, markets in Old Delhi shut in protest against GST. <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/traders-cautious-in-azadpur-mandi-markets-in-old-delhi-shut-in-protest-against-gst-2315795.html">Here's the report</a>.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><strong>21:27 </strong>GST: Connaught Place traders worried, clueless ahead of rollout. ad <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-connaught-place-traders-worried-clueless-ahead-of-rollout-2315857.html">here</a>.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><strong>21:24</strong> Buying cars and two-wheelers will be a much cheaper affair from tomorrow as Goods and Services Tax (GST) will ring in a lower tax than all the taxes applied before. <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/gst-impact-full-list-of-cars-bikes-that-will-become-cheaper-from-tomorrow-2315333.html">Read more here</a>.<p></p><strong>21:23</strong> With the Goods and Services Tax (GST) rolling out tonight, many businesspersons are still unaware that they have to register their business to the new tax regime. <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/are-you-a-businessman-who-hasnt-registered-for-gst-yet-heres-what-you-need-to-do-2315293.html">Here's more</a>.<p></p><strong>20:58</strong> Stay tuned with Moneycontrol.com for all the latest updates on India's biggest economic and tax reform<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><strong>20:57</strong> President Pranab Mukherjee, Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Vice President Hamid Ansari, Lok Sabha Speaker Sumitra Mahajan, two former Prime Ministers—Manmohan Singh and the HD Deve Gowda—have been invited for the launch event, reminiscent of August 15, 1947 marked by India’s first Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru’s famous “Tryst with Destiny” midnight speech in Parliament.<p></p>&nbsp;<p></p><strong>20:57</strong> July 1, the midnight event in Parliament’s Central Hall to launch the Goods and Services Tax (GST) will be an hour and fifteen-minute affair, with a gong sounded at the stroke of 12 am to mark the switch over.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/G/GST-e1489979952404_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-01 17:07:07</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>