<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/gstn-launches-offline-utility-for-gstr-2_9964401.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GSTN launches offline utility for GSTR-2]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The tool will allow taxpayers to export data of GSTR-2 to an MS-Excel spreadsheet. This will be helpful in comparing this data with purchase register to take actions like accept, reject and modify, GSTN said in a statement.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[GST Network, which developed the technology backbone for new indirect tax regime, said it launched an offline tool for filing purchase returns GSTR-2 on Wednesday.<p></p>The tool will allow taxpayers to export data of GSTR-2 to an MS-Excel spreadsheet. This will be helpful in comparing this data with purchase register to take actions like accept, reject and modify, GSTN said in a statement.<p></p>"We keep introducing new features and tools for the convenience of the taxpayers. This new version of the offline tool for GSTR-2 is better than the previous one as it allows taxpayers to compare data with the purchase data," GSTN CEO Prakash Kumar said.<p></p>So far, nearly 21 lakh businesses have filed GSTR-2 for July. The last date for filing is November 30.<p></p>Nearly 47 lakh businesses had filed GSTR-1 or sales returns, which has to be correspondingly matched with GSTR-2 or purchase returns.<p></p>Besides, the portal has also activated form GST CMP-02 which allows taxpayers to opt for composition scheme.<p></p>The GST Council last month hiked the threshold for businesses to opt for composition scheme to Rs 1 crore, from Rs 75 lakh earlier. The window for opting for composition scheme will remain open until March 31.<p></p>Also, GSTN has activated the form for intimation of details of stock on the date of opting for composition levy form GST CMP-03 is now available on the portal. However, this applies only for persons registered under the existing law migrating on the appointed day.<p></p>Form GST ITC-04 is also available on the GST portal. This will enable taxpayers to file a quarterly statement that has to be furnished by taxpayers having details of goods or capital goods sent to job worker and received back.<p></p>Besides, taxpayers who are registered under the existing laws and has been migrated can cancel his registration if not liable for registration under GST.<p></p>In case a taxpayer has a grievance pertaining to discrepancy relating to payment, he can use Form GST PMT-07 which is available on the common portal.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst-770x433_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-11-01 17:26:13</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>