<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/indias-consumption-story-intact-rural-india-may-spur-demand-rama-bijapurkar_9215401.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[India&#39;s consumption story intact; rural India may spur demand: Rama Bijapurkar]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The consumption story for India looks intact, consumers are feeling good, said Consumer Economy Expert, Rama Bijapurkar.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Consumption is a big theme for the India story but some of the big questions related to that are will goods and services tax (GST) consume volume growth? Will monsoons aid consumption? Will rural India consume more? To gauge how all these factors will impact consumption –positive or negative, CNBC-TV18 spoke to Consumer Economy Expert, Rama Bijapurkar.<p></p>According to her, the consumption story for India looks intact, consumers are feeling good. The consumption markets that are made of real people are okay, she said.<p></p>Rural India every ten years or so, surprises with a spurt of consumption when all factors get aligned together, she said adding that monsoons also seem to be in line this year.<p></p>Historically, elections have also always aided consumption, so the elections slated to come in the near future will boost consumption growth, said Bijapurkar. Plus announcements of loan waivers will also help, she added.<p></p>With regards to the impact on consumption due to demoentisation, she said the segments that were running on black money will take some time to recover. However, regular consumers seemed to have just postponed their purchases. The desire to consume in India remains strong, so consumption will return and seems to have come back already, she said.<p></p>However, with regards to GST, she said the jury is still out on what is going to be passed on to the consumers and what is not, so still a bit unclear.<p></p>She said for one to gauge real consumption, one must delink consumption demand from toplines of companies that stock markets track, because they are not always a reflection of correct consumer demand.<p></p>According to her, rural India could be the flavor for the next few months at least with regards to consumption demand.<p></p><strong><em>For the entire discussion, watch video</em></strong>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/I/India-internet_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-05 13:30:37</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>