<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-edge/nifty@10k-what-should-investors-do-book-profits-or-add-fresh-positions_9325421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Nifty@10K: What should investors do - book profits or add fresh positions?]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[There is a strong resistance around 10,100 levels which will act as stiff resistance for the market and to avoid getting caught on the wrong side of the trade, investors should book profits at current levels.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Kshitij Anand</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The Nifty scaled a historic landmark level of 10,000 for the first time in history on Tuesday, but any further rally should be taken with a pinch of salt. Traders which are already sitting on profitable positions should consider booking profits at current levels.<p></p>The Nifty rose 22 percent so far in the year 2017 without any meaningful correction. But, it is time for traders to book out of leveraged positions if any. The possibility of 4-5 percent kind of correction from current levels cannot be ruled out.<p></p>There is a strong resistance around 10,100 levels which will act as stiff resistance for the market and to avoid getting caught on the wrong side of the trade, investors should book profits at current levels.<p></p>Investors should avoid adding any fresh positions at current levels and consider adding fresh long after some decline. Investors can re-enter markets around 9400-9500 which has a better risk-to-reward ratio.<p></p>Long term investors have nothing to fear about Nifty50 reaching record highs as the trend is still on the upside. However, in the short term, there could be some consolidation, but that will not change the course of this market, suggest experts.<p></p>“Probably for the first time in 2017, the market is reaching a point wherein technically and fundamentally markets are looking little overbought. There should be some caution at current levels,” Gautam Shah, CMT Associate Director, Chief Technical Analyst- JM Financial Services Ltd told CNBC-TV18.<p></p>Technical charts suggest that the large upcycle which started close to 8,000 on the Nifty gets completed around current levels. I think there is a wall of resistance around 10,000-10,100 mark.<p></p>“It makes a lot of sense for investors or traders who are sitting on profits to book out of trading/leverage positions. I think we have not seen any meaningful correction in the past 6 months and the first meaningful correction of Nifty might well start from current levels,” said Shah.<p></p>Shah further added that he won’t be surprised if we see a 4-5 percent kind of drop in the next couple of months. Hence, somewhere around 9,400-9,500 mark, there is a value from a risk-to-reward perspective. This is one level which investors can work with for fresh entry.<p></p>The journey in the year 2017 from 9,000 to 10,000, took just four months, but the index first hit 9,000 way back in March 2015, following a RBI rate cut. We have seen a great comeback by equities as an asset class, gaining 47 percent in the last 17 months.<p></p>A Large part of the rally is on the back of strong macro fundamentals, expectations of a turnaround in earnings, stable rupee as well as pro-growth reforms initiated by the Modi-led government. Political stability is another key factor which has made Indian markets stand out among the peer group.<p></p>Investors should not forget that despite a slowdown in growth India will still be outperforming China in terms of GDP growth rate. The International Monetary Fund (IMF) kept its outlook for India GDP growth rate unchanged at 7.2 percent in 2017-18 and 7.7 percent in 2018-19, according to the latest update of the fund’s World Economic Outlook released Monday.<p></p>Overseas investors have poured in more than USD 5 billion in the Indian market so far in the month of July taking the total inflow to over USD 25 billion since January.<p></p>“As we move forward, I see a good reason to expect this uptrend to continue. Continued preference towards India, buoyed by growth, demography, stable macros and a government with intent will attract foreign capital and a high earnings yield v/s fixed income will draw in domestic money into equities,” Amar Ambani - Head of Research - IIFL Wealth Management told Moneycontrol.<p></p>“After initial disruption caused by the newly implemented GST, we expect corporate earnings to revive significantly in FY19,” he said.<p></p>Ambani further added that the near term challenge will be to manage geopolitical stand-offs and a longer term concern would be to improve jobs within our country given the huge manpower.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/b/businessman-2241421_1280-e1500562700264_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-25 13:56:23</Entry_Date><Category>Market Edge</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>