<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/motown-comes-to-gripgst-flip-flops-even-as-cigarette-players-have-seen-it-all_9432581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Motown comes to grip with GST flip-flops even as cigarette players have seen it all]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[With the government tweaking its GST rates, an unsettled auto and cigarette industry are left to deal with the consequences.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Shishir Asthana<p></p></strong><strong>Moneycontrol Research</strong><p></p>During the run-up to the implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST), government officials touted it as a reform that would simplify taxation. To be fair, GST was meant to subsume a number of taxes and make life easier for the people at large. But trust the bureaucrats running the government to make a simple thing such as the GST into a taxing affair. All pun intended.<p></p>In a move that has caught the auto industry by surprise and, in some cases, shock, the government has recommended an amendment to increase the cess on all passenger vehicles above four meters and with an engine capacity of 1,500 cc and above. Such vehicles were attracting a GST of 28 percent and a 15 percent cess. The cess amount has been increased from 15 percent to 25 percent taking the total tax up from 43 percent to 53 percent.<p></p>The only silver lining here is that the increased tax will take the time to implement. The Centre will have to amend the schedule to Section 8 of the GST Act, 2017, for this increase to take effect.<p></p>The auto industry is going through the same cycle of euphoria-to-anxiety that was witnessed by the cigarette industry a few days ago. When GST was first implemented it was found that tax incidence on the cigarette was lower than pre-GST days. However, the government soon realised its mistake and soon corrected the anomaly.<p></p>However, the increase was significantly higher under the new tax regime as compared to the pre-GST scenario.<p></p>The auto industry has also undergone similar swings at the launch of GST. The higher end cars were taxed at the peak GST rate of 28 percent with a cess of 15 percent. This was a positive development for high-end cars, some of whom were attracting taxes of up to 55 percent in the pre-GST era.<p></p>Recognising the sharp drop in high-end vehicles the government took corrective action by revising the cess higher, as it did in the case of cigarettes.<p></p>But auto players, who were upbeat post GST implementation and expected lower taxes to continue, are naturally crying foul.<p></p>Rahil Ansari, Head of Audi India, has been quoted as saying: “This move, unfortunately, is against the spirit of liberal market dynamics. This proposed increase in cess will most definitely adversely impact sales and we will be forced to re-evaluate our business plans.”<p></p>Roland Folger, Managing Director and Chief Executive of Mercedes-Benz, also spoke on similar lines saying: “This will also affect our plans of expansion under the Make in India initiative. The constant shift in policy makes our long-term planning for the market highly risky, and we think this would only have an adverse impact on the country's financial ratings."<p></p>Though the management of luxury car makers is right in complaining about the shifting goal post which affects long-term planning, it is unlikely that the government will accede to their logic.<p></p>Firstly because the decision to increase cess was taken after it was found that the taxes on these cars were lower when GST rates were first announced than under the indirect taxation system prevalent earlier.<p></p>And, secondly because, luxury cars annual sales of around 30,000 units account for only 1 percent of the passenger vehicle market. It’s too small a market to politically affect the government.<p></p>From the government's point of view, they had said that it would take a few months before the system is streamlined. Some stakeholders will benefit in the changing dynamics while some may be affected.<p></p>Luxury car makers are crying over the rate change that has taken place in the last one month and not for the rates that were prevalent in the pre-GST era. The first few months post-GST were expected to be fluid in terms of getting the act in place. Firming up future growth plans during such fluid times is a high-risk decision.<p></p>Nonetheless, the government has to face the flak of unnecessarily complicating GST in its haste to meet its aggressive deadline. It does not take too much of an effort to align pre-GST rate with what the rate should be at the time of launch, especially in the case of cigarettes and luxury cars as they were enjoying peak rates and easily noticeable.<p></p>To make matter worst the state governments present another set of problems. Tamil Nadu and Maharashtra have imposed their own taxes on cinema tickets and vehicles. We are heading back to the same scenario of multiple taxes which was prevalent in pre-GST days.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/G/Gross_domestic_price_economy_Growth_inflation_Growth_GST-e1497189541353_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-08 18:14:35</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>