<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/daily-home-use-products-like-dosa-battercustard-powderkitchen-lighter-may-seegst-cut_9423381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Daily home-use products like dosa batter,custard powder,kitchen lighter may see a GST cut]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[A number of daily use products ranging from idli/dosa batter to kitchen gas lighter may cost less as the GST Council is considering lowering rates on these items.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[A number of daily use products ranging from idli/dosa batter to kitchen gas lighter may cost less as the GST Council is considering lowering rates on these items.<p></p>Tax rates on over two dozen products are being sought to be lowered by the GST Council after anomalies in their fixations were pointed out, official sources said.<p></p>To deal with businesses that are deregistering their brands, post GST to avoid taxes, the fitment committee has proposed to the GST Council to consider 15 May 2017 as the cut off date for considering as a registered brand for the purpose of levy of GST, irrespective of whether or not the brand is subsequently deregistered.<p></p>A final decision in this regard would be taken by the GST Council, headed by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley and comprising representatives of all states, at its next meeting on September 9 in Hyderabad.<p></p>Unbranded food items are exempted from GST, whereas branded and packaged food items attract 5 percent rate. Hence, many businesses are deregistering their brands to avoid the levy.<p></p>Hence, many businesses are deregistering their brands to avoid the levy. Sources said that the GST Fitment Committee approved new rate structure of over two dozen items and forwarded the proposal to the apex decision-making body.<p></p>Sources, however, could not state the items on which the tax rates have been lowered. They said GST on dried tamarind has been proposed to be lowered to 5 percent from 12 percent currently and so will be the case in roasted gram.<p></p>Custard power would attract 18 percent GST as against 28 percent currently while idli/dosa batter would be charged with 12 percent tax against 18 percent currently. Oil cakes would be charged with a uniform 5 per cent GST irrespective of end use as against present practice of nil rate on oil cake for animal feed.<p></p>GST on dhoop batti, dhoop and other similar items has been proposed at 5 percent, down from 12 percent at present. This brings dhoop batti at par with agarbattis which attract a 5 percent tax rate. Plastic raincoats, rubber bands, rice rubber rolls for paddy de-husking, computer monitors and kitchen gas lighters would see GST being lowered from 28 percent to 18 percent.<p></p>GST on corduroy fabrics is to be lowered to 5 percent from 12 percent currently and the same is to be done for saree fall. Tax on textile caps is to be lowered to 12 percent from 18 percent and that on idols made of clay to 5 percent from 28 percent currently.<p></p>Brooms and brushes would be tax-free as against 5 percent GST levied currently while rosaries and prayer beads would be charged with 5 percent tax as compared to 18 percent now.<p></p>Hawan samagri would be charged with 5 percent GST as compared to nil now.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/shutterstock_549852313_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-07 19:15:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>