<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/gold/what-changed-formarket-while-you-were-sleeping-20-things-you-should-know_10042161.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[What changed for the market while you were sleeping? 20 things you should know]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[A look at top cues from domestic and international cues that could have a bearing on D-Street.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The Nifty, which opened with a slight gap on the downside on Friday, managed to recoup most of the losses as bull pushed the index back above 10300 towards the close of the trade.<p></p>The Nifty closed at 10,321.8 on Friday. According to Pivot charts, the key support level is placed at 10,268.93, followed by 10,216.07. If the index starts to move higher, key resistance levels to watch out are 10,359.83 and 10,397.87.<p></p>Nifty Bank closed at 25,498.9 on Friday. Important Pivot level, which will act as crucial support for the index, is placed at 25,291.2, followed by 25,083.5. On the upside, key resistance level is 25,652.6 followed by 25,806.3.<p></p>Stay tuned to Moneycontrol to find out what happens in currency and equity markets today. We have collated a list of important headlines from across news agencies:<p></p><strong>Wall Street ends lower as Trump tax cuts weigh</strong><p></p>Wall Street ended marginally lower on Friday, with losses in Intel and Apple as investors worried about the future of promised corporate tax cuts following dueling plans unveiled by Republican lawmakers.<p></p>The Dow fell 0.17 percent to end at 23,422.21, while the S&amp;P 500 slipped 0.09 percent to 2,582.3. The Nasdaq Composite edged up 0.01 percent to 6,750.94, Reuters reported.<p></p><strong>Asian markets trade lower, Nikkei falls 0.9%</strong><p></p>The Nikkei 225 fell 0.87 percent in early trade, with trading houses and financials mostly lower. The Kospi edged down 0.24 percent as gains in automakers and cosmetics stocks were offset by losses in manufacturing names. the S&amp;P/ASX 200 slipped 0.18 percent, CNBC reported.<p></p><strong>SGX Nifty</strong><p></p>The Nifty50 futures on the Singapore Stock Exchange were trading 5 points higher at 10347 indicating a flat to positive opening for the domestic market.<p></p><strong>GST Council cuts taxes on about 175 items from 28%</strong><p></p>The Goods and Services Tax (GST) Council on Friday decided to slash rates on more than 175 items, reducing taxes on these from the existing 28 percent in one of the biggest tax reductions since the new system kicked-in from July 1.<p></p><strong>India's factory output slows to 3.8% in Sept</strong><p></p>India’s industrial output slowed to 3.8 percent in September from the month ago when factory output grew at 4.3 percent. Manufacturing sector, which accounts for more than three-fourths of the entire index, grew 3.4 percent in September, compared with 3.1 percent growth in August, and 0.9 percent in September 2016, government data showed.<p></p><strong>Trump begged for a war during Asia trip: North Korea</strong><p></p>North Korea said on Saturday that US President Donald Trump’s first trip to Asia showed he was a “destroyer” and he had begged for war on the Korean peninsula.<p></p>“Trump, during his visit, laid bare his true nature as destroyer of world peace and stability and begged for a nuclear war on the Korean peninsula,” the foreign ministry spokesman said in a statement carried by the state news agency, Reuters reported.<p></p><strong>RBI remains net buyer of greenback in Sept</strong><p></p>The Reserve Bank continued to remain the net purchaser of the US currency after it bought USD 1.259 billion in September from the spot market. The central bank bought USD 3.788 billion, while it sold USD 2.529 billion in the spot market, according to the latest RBI data.<p></p><strong>PM Modi in Manila, to attend ASEAN-India, East Asia summits </strong><p></p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi arrived in Manila on a three-day visit to attend the ASEAN-India and East Asia summits where he is likely to reassert India's push for crafting a global approach to deal with growing challenge of terrorism and radicalisation besides pitching for steps to boost regional trade.<p></p>Apart from participating in the ASEAN-India and East Asia Summits, in the three-day visit, Modi would also take part in special celebrations of the 50th anniversary of ASEAN, Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP) Leaders' Meeting and ASEAN Business and Investment Summit, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>Stockbrokers ask govt to reduce STT</strong><p></p>The Association of National Exchanges Members of India (ANMI) has urged the finance ministry to reduce STT and abolish dividend tax for growth of the capital markets.<p></p>The national body of stockbrokers said the Securities Transaction Tax (STT) has impacted revenue generation and escalated the cost of transaction for clients.<p></p><strong>Govt, SEBI aim at zero tolerance towards corporate governance non-compliance</strong><p></p>The government is working with SEBI to ensure there is zero tolerance towards unethical behaviour and non-compliance. "Adoption of the highest standards of corporate governance is imperative for us to reach the global position that we aspire for," corporate affairs secretary Injeti Srinivas told a CII summit.<p></p><strong>DIPP approves FDI proposal for single-brand retail sector</strong><p></p>The Department of Industrial Policy and Promotion (DIPP) on Saturday said it has cleared a proposal of Christian Louboutin FZCO in the single-brand retail sector, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>FPI inflow in equities at $1.5 billion in Nov so far</strong><p></p>Foreign investors have pumped in a staggering USD 1.5 billion in the Indian equity markets this month so far, propelled by the government's Rs 2.11 lakh crore bank recapitalisation plan.<p></p>According to depository data, foreign portfolio investors (FPIs) infused a net sum of Rs 9,710 crore (USD 1.5 billion) in equities during November 1-10.<p></p><strong>Govt fixes Sovereign Gold Bond rate at Rs 2,961/gram</strong><p></p>The price of the new series of Sovereign Gold Bonds (SGBs), opening on Monday, has been fixed at Rs 2,961 per gram, the government said on Friday.<p></p>The government, in consultation with the Reserve Bank, has decided to offer a discount of Rs 50 per gram to investors applying online and making payments digitally.<p></p><strong>Bitcoin slides by over $1,000 in less than 48 hours</strong><p></p>Bitcoin dropped below USD 7,000 on Friday to trade more than $1,000 down from an all-time high hit on Wednesday, as some traders dumped it for a clone called Bitcoin Cash, sending its value up around a third, Reuters reported.<p></p><strong>Rs 1 lakh fine on those violating construction ban: NGT </strong><p></p>The National Green Tribunal on Friday directed the Delhi government and all public authorities to strictly implement its order banning construction activity in the wake of the alarming pollution levels in the capital.<p></p><strong>Govt to table Bill in Parliament to allow NRIs to vote</strong><p></p>A bill to amend the electoral law to allow Non-Resident Indians (NRIs) to vote through postal or e-ballots would be introduced in the upcoming winter session of parliament, the Centre informed the Supreme Court.<p></p>The poll panel had said the move to allow NRIs to use proxy voting on the lines of defence personnel and e-ballot facility would require changes either in the RP Act or in the rules made under the Act, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>Chitrakoot bypoll: Cong retains seat, defeats BJP by over 14K votes</strong><p></p>The Congress on Sunday retained the Chitrakoot Assembly constituency in Madhya Pradesh with its candidate winning the seat in a bypoll with an improved margin of over 14,000 votes.<p></p><strong>P-notes investment drops to 8-year low</strong><p></p>Investments in the Indian capital market through participatory notes (P-notes) plunged to an over eight-year low of Rs 1.23 lakh crore at September-end in view of stringent norms put in place by regulator Sebi.<p></p><strong>PSBs suggest tweaks in lending structure to boost efficiency</strong><p></p>A weekend meeting of public sector bankers called by the department of financial services (DFS) deliberated over a differentiated lending structure to make state-run lenders more efficient, said four bankers who attended the workshop. “Large banks will do corporate banking and smaller banks will do retail. Smaller banks will focus on their niche strengths and geographies,” said one of the four bankers, Livemint reported.<p></p><strong>New India Assurance Rs 10K cr IPO to list on bourses</strong><p></p>New India Assurance Company will be making its stock market debut on Monday, November 13, and most likely at a discount or to a slight premium. The Rs 9,600-crore IPO was oversubscribed 1.19 times during November 1-3.<p></p>The portion set aside for qualified institutional buyers (QIBs) was oversubscribed 2.34 times, non-institutional investors 12 percent and retail investors 11 percent, according to data available with the NSE.<p></p><strong>DIIs’ invests record amount in Indian equities</strong><p></p>Amid steep valuations and disappointing earnings, domestic institutional investors (DIIs) ploughed a record amount of money into stocks in 2017 so far, more than double what they invested in all of last year.<p></p>According to data from BSE, local insurers, pension funds and mutual funds were net buyers of Indian shares worth Rs74,728.35 crore till 10 November 2017, against Rs35,526.37 crore in all of 2016, Livemint reported.<p></p><strong>Stamp duty, property tax may stay out of GST</strong><p></p>Real estate may not fully come under the goods and services tax (GST) because the stamp duty and property tax can stay out of its ambit, suggests a presentation prepared for the GST Council. While work contracts for under-construction houses are under the GST, the stamp duty and land are out of it, Business Standard reported.<p></p><strong>Over 450 companies to report for Sept quarter numbers</strong><p></p>Over 450 companies are likely to report their September quarter numbers on BSE including NTPC, Adani Enterprises, Adani Ports, General Insurance Corporation, Idea Cellular, Reliance Nippon Life Asset Management, etc among others.<p></p><strong>F&amp;O cues: Maximum Put OI at 10,200, Call OI at 10,500</strong><p></p>On the options front, maximum Put OI is shifting at 10200 followed by 10000 strikes while maximum Call OI is at 10500 followed by 10400 strikes. Significant Put writing was seen at 10300 and 10100 while Call writing was seen at 10300, 10450 and 10500 strikes.<p></p>India VIX moved up by 1.54 percent at 13.47. A rise in VIX suggests that volatile swings are likely to continue in the market and VIX has to cool down to get the market stability.<p></p><strong>Rupee hits 1-month low, dives 22 paise </strong><p></p>The rupee on Friday took a steep plunge of 22 paise to end at a fresh one-month low of 65.16 against the US dollar due to frantic demand for the American unit from importers and corporates, PTI reported.<p></p><strong>NSE bans 10 companies from trading</strong><p></p>The derivative contracts of DHFL, HDIL, Indiabulls Real Estate, India Cements, Infibeam, Jet Airways, Jain Irrigation Systems, JSW Energy, Just Dial and Reliance Communications have crossed 95 percent of the market-wide position limit and are currently in the ban period.<p></p><strong>Gold lingers near 3-wk high amid US tax concerns</strong><p></p>Gold eased on Friday on a firmer dollar but uncertainty over US tax reforms helped prices stay close to a three-week high touched in the previous session. Bullion was on track for its first weekly gain in about a month, Reuters reported.<p></p><strong>Oil prices slide after US drillers add rigs</strong><p></p>Crude was down slightly on Friday as expectations that OPEC and other producers will extend their production cut agreement were offset by US drillers adding the most oil rigs in a week since June. Brent futures fell 41 cents, or 0.6 percent, to USD 63.52 a barrel, Reuters reported.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/B/BSE_Sensex_Markets_Stock_market_Dalal_street1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-11-13 07:53:35</Entry_Date><Category>Gold</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>