<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/indias-economy-will-pickmuch-sooner-than-most-think-says-adi-godrej_9822801.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[India&#39;s economy will pick up much sooner than most think, says Adi Godrej]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[India&#39;s economy failed to meet expectations for the April-June quarter as gross domestic product growth slowed to 5.7 percent — the country&#39;s lowest pace since early 2014.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[India's economic growth rate has seen a dismal run, but a turnaround could be in store much sooner than most expect, according to one of the country's richest business moguls.<p></p>"I expect that GDP growth rate will catch up in the July-September quarter, and it will be very good in the second half of the year," said Adi Godrej, the chairman of consumer goods conglomerate Godrej Group and reported possessor of a $2.8 billion net-worth.<p></p>India's economy failed to meet expectations for the April-June quarter as gross domestic product growth slowed to 5.7 percent — the country's lowest pace since early 2014.<p></p>However, the slump is likely a one-off result of the new goods and services tax (GST) regime, launched July, the chairman said.<p></p>"Because many of the GST rates on manufactured products were lower than the earlier cumulative tax rates, there was destocking as well as lower manufacturing," Godrej.<p></p>"People did not wish to clear goods prior to GST [implementation] and end up paying a higher tax than they would have to [post-reform]. So most of the clearing took place after July 1."<p></p>Some are less optimistic about the country's economic outlook, however. India's bad loans problem, ripple effects from its GST reform and last year's ban on high-value bank notes, could hinder growth for a longer period, analysts have warned.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/B/Budget2016_economy_growth_GDP-e1490023173284_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-10-06 10:44:30</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>