<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/recommendations/hul-q2-tractionnatural-portfoliorural-recovery-to-be-closely-monitored_9925621.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[HUL Q2: Traction in natural portfolio & rural recovery to be closely monitored]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[HUL posted a good recovery in volume and had a relatively smooth transition through GST. While its focus on the natural portfolio is worth noting, competitive intensity cannot be wished away.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Anubhav Sahu<p></p></strong><strong>Moneycontrol Research</strong><p></p>It has been a smooth transition to GST for <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personal-care/hindustanunilever/HU">Hindustan Unilever</a> (HUL) as it posted a volume growth of 4 percent. Volume pick-up was broadly uniform with both urban and rural areas benefitting from a lower base and restocking. While we acknowledge the improved operating performance, the key factors to monitor would be the traction in natural portfolio, premiumisation trend and the pick-up in rural growth. Investors need to be watchful about raw material cost inflation and the competitive intensity.<p></p><strong>Quarterly update: Comparable sales growth of 10 percent YoY </strong><p></p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2420787" src="http://static-news.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/10/Capture-24.png" alt="Capture" width="448" height="240" /><p></p>HUL posted a like-for-like sales growth of 10 percent, taking GST accounting impact into consideration, with a volume and pricing mix of 4 percent and 6 percent respectively. Comparable EBITDA margin improvement of 180 bps YoY was driven by lower cost of goods that was partly offset by higher advertising spend and employee costs.<p></p>While the surge in raw material costs was lower than the topline growth, in the near term, inputs costs are expected to edge higher.<p></p>As far as GST transition is concerned, company took price cuts of about 3‐4 percent which had partially offset gains on the input taxes received.<p></p><strong>CSD (Canteen Stores Department) channel uptick</strong><p></p>Unlike some of the other FMCG players, HUL reported fast recovery in the CSD channel (~7 percent of HUL’s sales) wherein sales to the channel is now 85 percent of the normal level. While a part of the uptick could be related to restocking from the diminished levels in the last quarter, the company has guided for near normalcy in the near future.<p></p>Wholesale channel remains a laggard but sale through modern retail channel has picked up.<p></p><strong>Gradual improvement in rural areas</strong><p></p>Volume pick-up was similar in both urban and rural areas. Further, HUL expected a steady improvement in rural demand with near normal monsoon, government’s spending on infrastructure and support from MSP (minimum support prices) for the crops in place.<p></p><strong>Premiumisation trend continues; focus on naturals </strong><p></p>With premium portfolio roughly contributing 25 percent of sales, HUL’s management appeared confident on the premiumisation trend. The company mentioned double-digit growth in brands like Surf and Rin. In personal care, Indulekha hair oil witnessed strong growth.<p></p>The foods segment reported 11 percent YoY with strong support from Kisan and new variants in Knorr.<p></p>HUL’s recent focus is on the naturals range led by its Lever Ayush campaign, which is positioned for the intensely competitive ayurvedic/naturals category.<p></p><strong>Oral care remains a let-down</strong><p></p>While HUL is pursuing a new Lever Ayush push for the oral care, overall oral care growth remains subdued, impacted by intense competition and market share loss to Patanjali and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personal-care/daburindia/DI">Dabur</a>.<p></p><strong>Elevated valuations</strong><p></p>Overall, HUL posted a good recovery in volume and had a relatively smooth transition through GST. While its focus on the natural portfolio is worth noting, competitive intensity cannot be wished away. Key trends to watch out in near term are premiumisation, competitive intensity led by Patanjali and pick-up in rural growth. The stock trades at an expensive valuation of 45x 2019e earnings that leaves little room for near-term upside.<p></p><a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/anubhavsays?ref_src=twsrc^tfw" data-show-count="false">Follow @anubhavsays</a><p></p>For more research articles, visit our <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/equity-research/">Moneycontrol Research Page</a>.<script src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/R/RTR4LYNK_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-10-26 17:02:45</Entry_Date><Category>Recommendations</Category><sc_id>,HL,DI,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>