<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/as-gst-releases-it-curtains-at-tamil-nadu-theatres_9204581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[As GST releases, it curtains at Tamil Nadu theatres]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The GST which mainly aimed to eliminate the tax-on-tax structure has proved to be a flip for the Tamil film industry, with additional tax burden on the Film Chamber of Commerce.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Cinema-goers, film-makers and film distributors in Tamil Nadu are distressed due to the theatre shut down which began Monday as part of an indefinite strike by the Tamil Nadu Film Chamber of Commerce in the aftermath of GST.<p></p>After the nationwide implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) from July 1, Tamil Nadu Theatre Owners and Distributors Association (TNTODA) remained confused about the exact amount of tax that would be levied on ticket prices.<p></p>The new tax regime, the biggest economic reform since Independence, levies a 18 percent tax on tickets up to Rs 100 while tickets priced more than Rs 100 fall under the 28 percent bracket. Additionally, there's around 30 percent entertainment tax which is levied by local municipal bodies, according to an ordinance issued by the state government as part of Tamil Nadu Local Bodies Entertainment Tax Act 2017.<p></p>The GST framework doesn't account for local body taxes, which makes such levies payable above the GST rates. Theatre owners in the state thus are burdened with about 58 percent due to multiple taxes.<p></p>Calling for an indefinite strike, TNTODA President Abiram Ramanathan declared on Saturday that all theatres would remain shut from Monday. Online ticket bookings for the weekend were also suspended in the state.<p></p>Moreover, earlier tax exemptions that movies with Tamil titles enjoyed in the state have also ceased to exist under the new GST regime.<p></p>The indefinite theatre shutdown has proved to be dismal for the films that released this Friday, while casting a shadow over the success of upcoming releases.<p></p>Director R Kannan's movie <em>Ivan Thanthiran</em> which hit the theatres on June 30, for now, is the collateral damage in the statewide stir.<p></p>Kannan <a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/tamil/tamil-nadu-film-theatres-shut-down-indefinitely-against-new-gst-regime-shankar-vishal-express-concern-4732969/">said</a> that he had borrowed money for his directorial project and would be running losses. The distributor of the film, Dhananjayan Govind tweeted, requesting the public to refrain from downloading the movie online.<p></p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p></p><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Until the situation is resolved, we appeal to people of TN not to watch <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/IvanThanthiran?src=hash">#IvanThanthiran</a> in Online/Pirated DVDs. Pl. encourage good cinema</p><p></p></blockquote><p></p>The GST, which mainly aimed to eliminate the tax-on-tax structure now has the Tamil Nadu film industry on its knees.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/R/Rajinikanth_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-03 21:04:30</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>