<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world-news/asus-slashes-smartphone-prices-byto-rs-3000_9207321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Asus slashes smartphone prices by up to Rs 3,000]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Following the roll out of GST from July 1, Apple has reduced the prices of its products in India to pass on the benefits to customers.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[After Apple, it is now Taiwanese firm Asus that has slashed prices of its Zenfone range of smartphones by up to Rs 3,000.<p></p>Following the roll out of GST from July 1, Apple has reduced the prices of its products in India to pass on the benefits to customers.<p></p>The price of Zenfone 3 (5.5) has been reduced by Rs 3,000 to Rs 16,999. Similarly, Zenfone 3 Max 5.5 will be available for Rs 14,999 instead of Rs 15,999 earlier.<p></p>"Both Zenfone 3 and Zenfone 3 Max series have received an overwhelming response in India, and we are happy to offer a new exciting price for both the models," Asus Region Head South Asia and Country Manager India Peter Chang said in a statement.<p></p>The company did not clarify if the Goods and Services Tax (GST) roll out had prompted Asus to slash prices.<p></p>Under GST, mobile handsets are being taxed at 12 per cent as compared to an earlier range of 8-18 per cent depending on the states.<p></p>Interestingly, the government has also introduced a 10 per cent basic customs duty on mobile phones and certain parts, in a bid to promote domestic manufacturing.<p></p>Asus manufactures its Zenfone 3 Max in India, while the Zenfone 3 in imported.<p></p>The price reduction could help the company expand its foothold in the intensely competitive smartphone market.<p></p>India is one of the fastest growing mobile phone markets globally. While feature phones sales have been growing at a slow pace, that of smartphones have grown at a faster speed on the back of rising consumption and falling data prices.<p></p>While players like Samsung, Micromax and Lava have had a significant hold of the market, Chinese players like Lenovo, vivo and Oppo are aggressively eating into their market share.<p></p>The competition among these players is fierce, especially in the affordable (Rs 12,000 and below) and mid-range (Rs 12,000-20,000) handsets.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/0/0PTI5_24_2017_000069B-e1499144442316_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-03 16:56:17</Entry_Date><Category>World News</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>