<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/real-estate/new-launchesreal-estate-sector-drop-41-lowest7-years-report_9215721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[New launches in real estate sector drop 41%, lowest in 7 years: Report]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Sales volumes also went down by 11 percent year-on-year, recording the lowest first-half sales in the past five years, says a Knight Frank India report.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>The residential real estate market had barely come out of the woods post demonetisation when the need for RERA compliance put breaks on a large section of new launches that crashed by almost 41 percent, the lowest in seven years. Sales volumes also went down by 11 percent year-on-year, recording the lowest first-half sales in the past five years, says a Knight Frank India half-yearly report titled India Real Estate released today.<p></p>While unsold inventory dropped to the lowest as well at 5,96,044 units, this was more a function of shrinking market size. NCR still shows an availability of 4 years of inventory. And there has been a surge in “ready for possession” inventory in these top 8 cities, reflecting slow demand for even for ready apartments, where there is no execution risk.<p></p>The report presents a comprehensive analysis of the residential (across eight cities) and office (across six cities) market performance for the period January-June 2017 (H1 2017).<p></p>Office transactions also fell by 10 percent to 18.1 million sq ft in the first half of 2017. The 5 percent decline in supply saw 17.9 million sq.ft added to the office space inventory. At 12 percent, vacancy levels were at the lowest since 2012 when it was 21 percent. Except Mumbai and NCR, vacancy levels were low in other cities. Vacancy levels at prime CBDs in Mumbai and NCR were in single digits, the report said.<p></p>The average rental values across six cities grew at 7 percent year-on-year during the first half of 2017. While Mumbai saw flat year-on-year rental growth, Hyderabad and Bengaluru experienced the strongest rental growth at 14 percent and 8 percent year-on-year, respectively.<p></p>IT/ITeS sector witnesses a fall in share to 39 percent in H1 of 2017 from 43 percent in the same period a year ago. Co-working space operators show traction with around 0.5 million sq ft taken up across Bengaluru, Pune and NCR.<p></p>Speaking on the occasion, Shishir Baijal, Chairman &amp; Managing Director, Knight Frank India, said, “Some of the most path-breaking reforms in independent India came to force in quick succession over a span of a few months.<p></p>Described by many as the battery of reforms against the black economy in an unorganised sector, brave policy decisions such as demonetisation, the Real Estate (Regulations and Development) Act, 2016, the Benami Transactions (Prohibition) Amendment Act, 2016 and the recently rolled out Goods and Services Tax Act (GST) have time and again pushed the already sluggish residential market to the brink.<p></p>But we believe that these were corrective measures long due to transform real estate into a robust, transparent and thriving industry. The short-term hiccups grappling the sector would eventually fade away and bear rich dividends in the future.”<p></p>“The commercial real estate sector has been the most dependable segment of the overall market. However, some recent geopolitical disruptions in the advanced economies had a bearing on office transactions even as the country continues to grapple with shrinking commercial real estate. But the investment environment is changing and we expect a radical difference in the office landscape on the back of institutional funds foraying into the sector," he said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/I/Infrastructure_infra_building_construction_smartcity_Real_estate_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-05 14:01:42</Entry_Date><Category>Real Estate</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>