<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/planningtrip-abroad-be-prepared-to-pay-more-as-gst-could-make-it-expensive_9243881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Planning a trip abroad? Be prepared to pay more as GST could make it expensive]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Earlier too, while tax was applicable it was offset by input tax credit. With the absence of that, the increase in taxes are being directly passed on to customers. But some agencies are offering discounts.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Goods and Services Tax (GST) regime may lead to a rise in the costs for international tour packages especially since input tax credit will not be available for travel-related services. However, some players like Thomas Cook India are offering discounts to customers for a limited period.<p></p>Viren Batra, Founder, Nirvana Excursions, said that earlier input tax credit was available for travel which has now been done away with under GST. Due to this, he added that there will be a 7-10 percent jump in the overall cost of the travel packages. “This will have to be directly borne by the customers and we have seen some of them postponing their travel plans,” he said.<p></p>The travel industry has already made a representation to the government to seek clarity on applicability of GST for international travel. This could be taken up in the GST Council meeting in August.<p></p><strong>Must watch: Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>Debasis Nandy, Chief Financial Officer &amp; President, Finance and Accounts, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/miscellaneous/thomascookindia/TCI">Thomas Cook India Group</a> said that given the current consumer sentiment and with the intent to catalyse demand, they have launched a campaign where we absorb the 5 percent charge on select tour packages, both international and domestic, for a limited time period.<p></p>Smaller travel companies have seen a reduction in demand from leisure travelers who have sought discounts or more information on the new rates of taxation.<p></p>While there has been a slight increase in tax on international air tickets from 1.5 percent to 1.8 percent and also levy via a model management fee, Nandy said that from a corporate travel perspective, given that the amount can be offset, they do not envisage a downside.<p></p>However, he added that it is the sheer complexity in the execution/compliance that we see significant challenges: filing required at multiple levels and hence involving a substantial increase in effort-time.<p></p>Clarity is also being sought on whether GST will be applicable in foreign land. Batra said that since GST is a destination-based tax, it is not clear whether it is applicable for their services provided abroad.<p></p>If the GST Council provides an exemption for these services, travel packages will see a reduction in prices. Earlier too, while tax was applicable it was offset by input tax credit. With the absence of that, the increase in taxes are being directly passed on to customers.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/t/travel_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-11 15:16:29</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,TCI,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>