<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/pharma-weekly-wrap-pharma-stocks-had-tough-week-due-to-gstpricing-pressuresus_9466321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Pharma weekly wrap: Pharma stocks had tough week due to GST and pricing pressures in US]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The news highlights in the sector include first quarter results of Sun Pharma, Aurobindo Pharma, Cipla, Cadila Healthcare among others. The US pricing pressure looks more structural than a temporary event.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Viswanath Pilla</strong><p></p><strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>For pharmaceutical stocks, this past week was one of the worst - many have sunk on weak Q1 results due to destocking of channel on account of GST rollout and US pricing pressures. The weak global cues also didn't help the matters.<p></p>The news highlights in the sector include first quarter results of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/sunpharmaceuticalindustries/SPI">Sun Pharma</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/aurobindopharma/AP">Aurobindo Pharma</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/cipla/C">Cipla</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/cadilahealthcare/CHC">Cadila Healthcare</a> among others. The US pricing pressure looks more structural than a temporary event.<p></p><strong>How did Pharma Index Perform?</strong><p></p>The BSE Healthcare index declined 8.13 percent in the past week, while the benchmark Sensex dropped 4.04 percent.<p></p>None of the big pharma stocks have seen gains this past week.<p></p>Sun Pharma (-11.13 percent), <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/cadilahealthcare/CHC">Cadila Healthcare</a> (-11.35 percent), <a href="http://livecms.moneycontrol.com/business/earnings-business/cadila-healthcare-profits-drop-65-to-rs-138-4-crore-in-q1fy18-2357141.html">Glenmark</a> (-10.99 percent) and Dr Reddy's (-10.37 percent) have lost one-tenth of their market value. <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/natcopharma/NP07">Natco Pharma</a> (-26.05 percent) was worst hit shedding almost a quarter of its value.<p></p>The rest of the pack saw huge dips of their share prices.<p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/lupin/L">Lupin</a> (-5.3 percent), Cipla (-4.79 percent), Aurobindo Pharma (-3.98 percent), Divis (-8.36 percent), Torrent Pharma (-4.81 percent) and Biocon (4.61 percent).<p></p><strong>Here's What Kept the Sector Buzzing:</strong><p></p>Sun Pharma, India's largest drug maker reported Rs crore 425 loss in Q1 impacted by steep pricing pressure, GST and one-time write-off.The company said thing could see improvement in second half. The company also said it had completed remedial measures and is awaiting US re-inspection of its critical Halol facility.<p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings-business/sun-pharma-posts-q1-loss-at-rs-425-cr-on-settlement-provision-us-biz-drags-revenue-25-2357681.html">http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings-business/sun-pharma-posts-q1-loss-at-rs-425-cr-on-settlement-provision-us-biz-drags-revenue-25-2357681.html</a><p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/companies/sun-pharma-says-it-sought-re-inspection-of-its-halol-facility-awaiting-us-fda-response-2358227.html">http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/companies/sun-pharma-says-it-sought-re-inspection-of-its-halol-facility-awaiting-us-fda-response-2358227.html</a><p></p>Aurobindo Pharma, India's third largest drug maker posted a 11.4 percent decline in net profit to Rs 518.5 crore for the first quarter ended June FY18 with flat US generics sales and drop in revenues of API and anti-retrovirals impacting the bottomline, despite surge in Europe business.The company reported a net profit of Rs 585 crore in the corresponding quarter of the previous year. The revenues declined 2.3 percent to Rs 3678.75 crore for the quarter ended June.<p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings-business/aurobindo-pharma-q1-net-profit-drops-11-4-to-rs-518-cr-2355263.html">http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings-business/aurobindo-pharma-q1-net-profit-drops-11-4-to-rs-518-cr-2355263.html</a><p></p>Cipla was one of very few companies that was able to wither the storm. The company posted 21 percent rise in net profit to Rs 409 crores on a year-on-year basis for the first quarter ended June 30 reigning in expenses and enhancing operational efficiency.<p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings-business/cipla-profit-rises-21-to-rs-409-cr-in-q1-on-cost-controls-operational-efficiency-2357463.html">http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings-business/cipla-profit-rises-21-to-rs-409-cr-in-q1-on-cost-controls-operational-efficiency-2357463.html</a><p></p>Dr.Reddy's regulatory woes surfaced again this week with German regulator revoking the GMP certificate of company's Bachupally Unit-2 formulation plant.<p></p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/companies/german-regulator-revokes-gmp-certificate-of-dr-reddys-bachupally-plant-for-non-compliance-2356341.html">http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/companies/german-regulator-revokes-gmp-certificate-of-dr-reddys-bachupally-plant-for-non-compliance-2356341.html</a>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/m/medicine-pharma-1280-720_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-12 14:00:59</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,SPI, AP, C, CHC, CHC, GP08, NP01, LL, LC03,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>