<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/indias-plan-for-higher-rate-luxury-car-tax-to-hit-sales-mercedes-benz_9423741.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[India&#39;s plan for higher rate luxury car tax to hit sales: Mercedes-Benz]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Mercedes-Benz on Monday said India&#39;s proposal to increases taxes on luxury cars and sport-utility vehicles (SUVs) could impact the carmaker&#39;s expansion plans in the country and hurt sales.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Mercedes-Benz on Monday said India's proposal to increases taxes on luxury cars and sport-utility vehicles (SUVs) could impact the carmaker's expansion plans in the country and hurt sales.<p></p>Mercedes-Benz, owned by Daimler AG, is one of the biggest luxury car sellers in India, and a senior company executive said that the constant shift in policy in the country was making long-term planning for India "highly risky".<p></p>"This decision once again reiterates the need for a long-term roadmap for the luxury car industry, which has been at the receiving end of arbitrary policies," Roland Folger, managing director at Mercedes-Benz India said in a statement.<p></p>"We believe this will be a strong deterrent to the growth of luxury cars," Folger said, adding the government should have waited for at least six months before revisiting the rates.<p></p>On July 1, India rolled out the goods and services tax (GST)replacing a multitude of provincial and national levies in the biggest tax reform in 70 years.<p></p>Under GST, most vehicles are taxed at 18 percent with an additional levy of 15 percent on some types of cars.<p></p>At a meeting held on August 5 a council set up to implement the new tax regime decided to raise the additional levy to 25 percent. The council will decide later when the higher rate will be applicable.<p></p>Other luxury carmakers in India include BMW, Audi, Volvo and Jaguar Land Rover, owned by <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-lcvs-hcvs/tatamotors/TM03">Tata Motors</a>. Automakers such as Toyota Motor, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-cars-jeeps/mahindramahindra/MM">Mahindra &amp; Mahindra</a> and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-cars-jeeps/marutisuzukiindia/MS24">Maruti Suzuki</a> sell SUVs in the country.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/R/RTX30A55-720_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-08-07 20:04:04</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,TEL, MM, MU01,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>