<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/gst-cranks-upheatcompliancereturns-cas-hike-fees_9199881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[GST cranks up the heat on compliance and returns, CAs hike fees]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The pressure will be up and going from now on for the three lakh tax and sales accounts and the 1.5 lakh Chartered Accountants in India.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>Chartered accountants and tax consultants have bumped up their consultant fees after the increased pressure in compliance, tax returns and maintaining books under the new Goods and Services Tax (GST) regime.<p></p>“Due to increased compliance and filings in the new tax regime, chartered accountants, and tax consultants have already hiked their fee by 15 percent. The entire cost of compliance will now fall on the traders,” said Viren Shah, president, Federation of Retail Traders Welfare Association, to <a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/business/economy/eye-on-gst-cas-tax-consultancies-hike-fee-by-up-to-30-per-cent-4732553/"><em>the Indian Express</em>.</a><p></p>The federation represents two lakh shop owners in Maharashtra, or 96 per cent of traders across Maharashtra.<p></p>“The retainership fee has gone up by 30-50 percent,” said a Mumbai-based tax consultant, who wished against being named.<p></p>The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India (ICAI) expects an increase of Rs 15,000 crore from consulting fees.<p></p>The heat will be felt by the three lakh sales-tax accounting practitioners, that help the small and micro businesses, as well as the 1.5 lakh Chartered Accountants in India.<p></p>“With the introduction of GST, the complexities will definitely go up. As of now, Service Tax assessees are required to file two half-yearly returns and some VAT assessees are required to file quarterly returns. But in GST, all of them will have to file three returns each every month, leading to substantial increase in volume," Amit Maheshwari, partner at Ashok Maheshwary &amp; Associates LLP, told IE. "Besides, other issues like the widening of the scope of reverse charge transactions, the introduction of TDS, TCS, etc., will add to these complexities.”<p></p>“With 36 returns to file in a year, each accountant by that measure will be interacting at least 720 times with each client in a year.” said Sunil Gabhawalla, a chartered accountant, who is a representative of Bombay Chartered Accountants’ Society, told <em>BloombergQuint</em>.<p></p>Tax consultants were issuing an impact analysis report in the months before the GST launch. This was meant to show how their business would be affected by the GST.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/g/gst_cgst_igst_utgst_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-03 11:30:21</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>