<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/a-weekgst-teething-troublefacepalm-moments-for-consumers-traders_9230321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[A week of GST: Teething trouble and facepalm moments for consumers, traders]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The "common man" is still confused and traders lives are getting increasingly complicated.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol News</strong><p></p>It's been a week since the Goods and Services Tax (GST) was rolled out, but the "common man" is not any wiser. There also seems to be a fair amount of confusion prevailing among small traders and kirana store owners, who are still sorting their goods into GST slabs under which they fall.<p></p>Consumers at several stores are being presented with bills claiming <a href="http://www.hindustantimes.com/business-news/gst-day-6-confusion-continues-among-sellers-and-buyers/story-vyqIwbxLjJlwFKHBaPRIwL.html" target="_blank">random GST rates</a>. The consumers are also unaware how their credit card bills are going to look like. However, they hope that the confusion will settle down soon.<p></p><strong><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/gst-rates-are-here-how-it-will-affect-your-restaurant-bills-2285339.html" target="_blank">Also read: GST rates are here! How it will affect your restaurant bills</a></strong><p></p>For traders, however, things are a little more complicated. Two things that traders are not aware of are — one, the pricing scheme for the stock they bought before GST; two, they are unaware of the eligibility criteria to register for GST.<p></p><strong>Another Tryst With Destiny! How GST Will Change Your Life After July 1</strong><p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_tBdRd7hPg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>Until a few days back, traders were worried that they will make losses post-GST because they thought that the inventory bought before July 1 would now carry different prices. On July 4, the government announced that <a href="http://www.news18.com/news/india/reflect-price-revision-post-gst-via-mrp-stickers-till-sep-30-govt-1451859.html" target="_blank">a three-month time waiver, till September 30, will be given to traders.</a> This will help businesspersons recover losses and smoothly incorporate GST.<p></p>However, several traders are unaware of the registration process. Every businessperson is liable to pay tax and with the new tax regime, every taxable person has to re-register or register under GST.<p></p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cwih3JA30xw?ecver=1" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><p></p>Most traders are unaware of the eligibility criteria. According to a <a href="http://www.financialexpress.com/economy/gst-explained-what-is-gst-hasmukh-adhia-takes-1st-master-class-says-traders-with-turnover-under-rs-20-lakh-will-have-to-register-for-interstate-business/752584/" target="_blank">Financial Express</a> report, Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia said in his first of six GST Masterclass sessions — an initiative he undertook to clear every one's doubts on GST — that even a businessperson who has a turnover below Rs 20 lakh and is involved in an inter-state business has to register with GST, contradicting his earlier claim.<p></p><strong><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/are-you-a-businessman-who-hasnt-registered-for-gst-yet-heres-what-you-need-to-do-2315293.html" target="_blank">Also read: Are you a businessman who hasn't registered for GST yet? Here's what you need to do</a></strong><p></p>"Those with a turnover below Rs 20 lakh need not file any return. Their life will not change at all after July 1," Revenue Secretary Hasmukh Adhia told the <em><a href="http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/policy/guide-to-filing-gst-returns-revenue-secretary-hasmukh-adhia-makes-it-easy-for-you/articleshow/59337150.cms" target="_blank">Economic Times</a></em> earlier.<p></p>If the government keeps adding specifications later, traders may fear being held against the law for evading taxes.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2017/356x200/s/sadppl1_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2017-07-07 19:19:33</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>