<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/fieo-asks-fiscal-benefits-for-msme-exportersbudget_5620581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[FIEO asks fiscal benefits for MSME exporters in Budget]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["MSME exporters may be provided additional exports benefits. It would help in promoting exports," Federation of Indian Export Organisations (FIEO) said in a statement.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Apex exporters body FIEO suggested the government to extend fiscal benefits to micro, small and medium enterprises (MSMEs) to boost exports from the sector.</p>
<p>MSME sector contributes about 45 percent to the country's total exports.</p>
<p>"MSME exporters may be provided additional exports benefits. It would help in promoting exports," Federation of Indian Export Organisations (FIEO) said in a statement.</p>
<p>In view of current downfall in exports, encouragement to MSME sector by way of fiscal incentives on their year-on-year export growth would motivate them for aggressive export marketing, which in turn could help in restoring export momentum, it added.</p>
<p>It also said that the biggest challenge affecting MSME exports is on the marketing front as most of the units lack financial resources to meet the cost.</p>
<p>"Government needs to chip in with liberal funding. The total marketing support extended by (the Commerce Ministry) is insufficient to meet the demand of MSME for export marketing.</p>
<p>"Government may create an Export Development Fund (EDF) in order to support them on this front. The corpus of the fund should be 0.5 percent to 1 percent of export value so that sizable money is available to promote MSME exports," it said.</p>
<p>Exports dipped for 14th month in a row in January, down 13.6 percent to USD 21 billion due to fall in shipments of petroleum and engineering goods, although trade deficit showed improvement.</p>
<p>Imports shrank 11 percent to USD 28.71 billion last month, resulting in a trade deficit of USD 7.63 billion, lowest in eleven months.</p>
<p>In February last year, the deficit was USD 6.85 billion.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget_expectations_356_2208_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 07:38:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>