<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/continue-to-see-pressuredomestic-aluminium-prices-crisil_5634701.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Continue to see pressure on domestic aluminium prices: CRISIL]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[No MIP/similar measures have been announced to help the aluminium industry. Hence, we expect domestic aluminium prices to continue their southward sojourn and decline further by 3-5% next fiscal.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><em>Below is a report on state of the metals industry by CRISIL Research</em></strong><br /><br /><strong>Slammed by falling prices</strong><br /><br />Metal prices plummeted in 2015 due to global slowdown and massive overcapacity, especially in China. Tailing these global trends, domestic steel and aluminium prices are estimated to decline by 16-19% and 15-17% respectively, in the current fiscal. Consequently, the operating margins of the steel and aluminium sectors are expected to tumble by 500-700 basis points (bps) and 1,000-1,200 bps, respectively. <br /><br />In the wake of deteriorating profitability and rising imports, the government imposed a minimum import price (MIP) on 173 steel products on February 5, 2016, for six months. This levy comes as a breather for the ailing industry, as it is expected to curb imports and also marginally improve pricing flexibility of producers in the short term. <br /><br />We expect operating profitability of steel industry to improve slightly in the next fiscal especially if MIP is extended beyond six months. However, debt coverage ratios are unlikely to improve significantly. <br /><br />No MIP/similar measures have been announced to help the aluminium industry. Hence, we expect domestic aluminium prices to continue their southward sojourn and decline further by 3-5% next fiscal. Moreover, with use of high-cost captive coal, the profitability of domestic aluminium players will deteriorate and some may even incur cash losse]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/c/CRISILLOGO_2_356_1907_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 20:59:55</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>