<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/give-infrastructure-status-to-industry-broadcasters_4902261.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Give infrastructure status to industry: Broadcasters]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Leading broadcasters today sought "Infrastructure Status" for the broadcasting industry, including direct-to-home (DTH) and cable sectors in a pre-Budget consultation with Finance Minister Arun Jaitley.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Leading broadcasters today sought "Infrastructure Status" for the broadcasting industry, including direct-to-home (DTH) and cable sectors in a pre-Budget consultation with Finance Minister Arun Jaitley. In a statement, the Indian Broadcasting Foundation (IBF), which has the country's leading television channels as its members, said that at a pre-Budget consultation meeting, chaired by Jaitley, its representatives stressed that the expected investment in set-top boxes (STBs) and optical fibre network alone would be to the tune of Rs 25,000 to 30,000 crore. "In the present era of convergence, distinction between Telecom, IT and Broadcasting sectors is getting blurred.</p>
<p>Telecom is already treated as an infrastructure service. Broadcasters and distribution platforms will be aided with better and affordable financing options in the present capital-intensive growth phase if broadcasting sector is accorded infrastructure status," IBF Secretary General Girish Srivastava said at the high level meeting. Srivastava also said that such a move would provide a level playing field to the broadcasting sector with telecom and ISP industry.</p>
<p>The IBF also urged the Government to reduce customs duty on STBs to 5 per cent from the present 10 per cent. "The Finance Act, 2013 had increased customs duty on STBs to 10 per cent from earlier 5 per cent. In order to push digitisation, customs duty on STBs should be reduced to the earlier level of 5 per cent if not entirely removed," Srivastava said.</p>
<p>On the direct tax front, IBF urged the Finance Ministry, to allow carry forward of losses in case of amalgamation or merger. All industrial undertakings in manufacturing, software, electricity and telecom sectors are allowed to carry forward their losses in case of merger or amalgamation and media industry should be granted a similar status, IBF representatives said in the meeting chaired by Jaitley, who also holds the Information and Broadcasting portfolio. Another proposal presented by IBF related to tax withholding on transponder charges, the statement said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/m/media_TV_356x200_3105_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-06 20:21:55</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>