<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/power-generation-to-grow-at-5current-fiscal-crisil_5631921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Power generation to grow at 5% in current fiscal: CRISIL]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[CRISIL Research expects capacity additions to slow to 60 GW over 2015-20 compared with 93 GW over the previous five years led by central and state PSU’s. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><em>Below is snapview of the state of capital goods industry by CRISIL Research</em></strong><br /><br />Conventional capacity addition to decline, renewables and T&amp;D to do well<br /><br />▪ Power generation is expected to grow at a moderate 5% in the current fiscal owing to unseasonal rains and poor offtake by state discoms. <br /><br />▪ Despite modest growth in generation, plant load factors (PLFs) of coal-based power plants are estimated to decline to around 61% this fiscal due to strong capacity additions of approximately 20 GW each in 2013-14 and 2014-15 and weak offtake from discoms. Around 22.5 GW of capacity today does not have long-term purchase agreements.<br /><br />▪ The government has taken steps to address issues related to poor financial helath of discoms with the launch of the Ujwal Discom Assurance Yojana scheme. If the scheme is implemented successfully, we expect the gap between the average cost of supply and the average revenue realised to decline significantly over the next five years.<br /><br />▪ Given that these issues will be resolved only over the long term, CRISIL Research expects capacity additions to slow to 60 GW over 2015-20 compared with 93 GW over the previous five years led by central and state PSU&rsquo;s. Also, PLFs for coal-based plants are expected to be low, around 65%, till 2018-19.<br /><br />▪ On the other hand, capacity additions in the renewable space (wind and solar) are expected to increase significantly to 20 GW over the next three years compared with ~9 GW over the past three years, driven by strong government support, falling capital costs, and improvement in the execution ecosystem.<br /><br />▪ Investments in T&amp;D (transmission and distribution) are also expected to grow strongly owing to the government&rsquo;s thrust on improving transmission infrastructure and reducing AT&amp;C (aggregate technical and commercial) losses.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/c/CRISILLOGO_2_356_1907_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 18:17:45</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>