<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/cnbc-tv18-comments/coming-a-mega-healthcare-plan-this-budget_4953661.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Coming: A mega healthcare plan this Budget?]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[CNBC-TV18’s Nayantara Rai, quoting sources, says that the Budget 2016 will see a ‘mega’ healthcare scheme with an initial investment of Rs 6,000 crore.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[After a lackluster healthcare budget in 2015, the government is planning to revamp its budget for 2016 and the focus is expected to be on senior citizens, sources say. <br /><br />CNBC-TV18&rsquo;s Nayantara Rai, quoting sources, says that the Budget 2016 will see a &lsquo;mega&rsquo; healthcare scheme with an initial investment of Rs 6,000 crore. The budget will be laid down the Finance Minister Arun Jaitley and Minister of State for Finance, Jayant Sinha. <br /><br />Sources say that the government is planning to rely on unclaimed employee provident fund (EPF) and public provident fund (PPF) deposits to launch the scheme.&nbsp;<br /><br />Jaitley, in September 2015, at an event had said that the idea of using unclaimed funds was there in last Finance Bill, but could not be worked out. The government is hoping to implement it in the upcoming Union Budget in February. <br /><br />The new scheme is expected to focus on providing sunsidised services to senior citizens, marginal farmers as well as below poverty line (BPL) families, sources say. The scheme could also make healthcare services free for super senior citizens (over 80 years of age).<br /><br />Sources add that the government also plans to club existing schemes into a single entity. The scheme could be combined with government&rsquo;s other schemes like Pradhan Mantri Jan Dhan Yojana. <br /><br /><strong><em>Watch video for more.</em></strong>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/h/Healthcare_driver_shutterstock_356x200_0628_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-11 13:06:14</Entry_Date><Category>CNBC-TV18 Comments</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>