<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/no-expectationsrailway-budget-says-nitish-kumar_5615181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[No expectations from Railway Budget, says Nitish Kumar]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["I do not have any expectations from railway budget. Though the nation has always big expectations from railway budget...Railway minster is my friend and wish him best," Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar said while talking to reporters after the cabinet meeting.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Stating he had 'no expectations' from Railway budget, Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar today opposed the Centre's decision asking state governments to invest in railway projects.</p>
<p>"I do not have any expectations from railway budget.&nbsp;Though the nation has always big expectations from railway budget...Railway minster is my friend and wish him best," Kumar said while talking to reporters after the cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>The Central government should work for development and expansion of railways across the country, he said.</p>
<p>"State governments have been asked to make investments in the railway projects of the concerned state. In how many areas and sectors, the state government will invest. The development and expansion of railways are the responsibility of the Central government," Kumar said.</p>
<p>RJD leader Lalu Prasad had yesterday criticised the BJP government at the Centre for pushing railways to "serious crisis".</p>
<p>Stating that Railway ministry should not allocate 'token' funds, Kumar said that people have huge expectations from railways whose various projects are pending in the state.</p>
<p>There are many projects which have crossed their deadlines too, he added.</p>
<p>Centre is talking about private investments in railways which are in bad shape, Chief minister said and added that it was the Centre's responsibility to develop railways in a manner that its benefits should be passed on to all people.</p>
<p>Railways play a bigger role in unifying the country, he added.</p>
<p>Nitish's grand secular alliance partner and RJD leader Prasad, who had served as Railway minister in the UPA I government, had shot off a letter to Prime Minister Narendra Modi about the "recent flawed policy moves of Railways." <br /><br />"The decision to recklessly increase financial leverage manifold by signing MoUs for borrowing of 40 Billion US dollar from institutions like LIC and JICA, that too for un-remunerative and cash guzzling projects like Bullet train is likely to prove suicidal," Prasad had said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Indian_Railways_rail__rail_overcrowded_engine_freight_coal_356x200_1252_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-23 19:12:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>