<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/buzzing-stocks/budget-2016-ongc-sinks-1020-ad-valorem-cess-no-custom-duty-lifts-hpcl_5705341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: ONGC sinks 10% on 20% ad valorem cess, no custom duty lifts HPCL]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Oil marketing companies gained due to non-imposition of custom duty on crude oil imports. HPCL rallied over 4 percent followed by BPCL and IOC with marginal gains.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong></p>
<p>Shares of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/oildrillingandexploration/oilnaturalgascorporation/ONG">Oil and Natural Gas Corporation</a> (ONGC) was the biggest loser on Sensex, losing 10 percent to Rs 194.10 at close on Monday after the government made changes in a cess levied on domestically produced crude oil.</p>
<p>While presenting Union Budget 2016, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said the government reduced cess on domestically produced crude oil from Rs 4500 per metric tonne to 20 percent ad valorem.<br /><br />JP Morgan says 20 percent ad valorem results in only around USD 2 a barrel reduction in cess.</p>
<p>According to the brokerage, current environment remains negative. Even after today&rsquo;s 10 percent&nbsp;share price fall, the stock does not fully capture the current stressed environment, JP Morgan feels.</p>
<p>Another reason that pushed stock lower was non-imposition of custom duty on crude oil.</p>
<p>As international oil prices slumped to 12-year lows, the domestic industry was widely anticipating re-imposition of 5-percent customs duty on crude oil imports.</p>
<p>In June 2011, when rates zoomed to over USD 140 per barrel, the customs duty on crude oil imports had been cut to zero from 5 percent.</p>
<p>However, oil marketing companies gained due to non-imposition of custom duty on crude oil imports. HPCL rallied over 4 percent followed by BPCL and IOC with marginal gains.<br /><br /><em>Posted by Sunil Shankar Matkar</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/c/CRUDE_OIL_16-9_356x200_3255_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 19:15:01</Entry_Date><Category>Buzzing Stocks</Category><sc_id>,ONG,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>