<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/over-64000-new-companies-registeredfy-2014-15_5662621.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Over 64,000 new companies registered in FY 2014-15]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The total number of new companies registered in India during the financial year 2014-15 stood at 64,395, while 66 companies listed themselves in stock exchange during the period under review, Minister of Corporate Affairs Arun Jaitley said in a written reply to Lok Sabha.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>More than 64,000 new companies were registered in the country during 2014-15 with majority of them from Delhi and Maharashtra, Parliament was informed today.</p>
<p>The total number of new companies registered in India during the financial year 2014-15 stood at 64,395, while 66 companies listed themselves in stock exchange during the period under review, Minister of Corporate Affairs Arun Jaitley said in a written reply to Lok Sabha.</p>
<p>Delhi has topped the list of states and Union Territories as it saw registration of 11,076 companies under the Companies Act during 2014-15, followed by Maharashtra in the second place with 11,020 firms and Uttar Pradesh at the third place with 5,989 such registrations, the minister informed.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Karnataka saw registration of 5,025 new companies, Tamil Nadu (4,867), West Bengal (4,155) and Telengana (3,761) companies, he added.</p>
<p>The minister while replying to a written Lok Sabha further said that total authorised capital of public companies registered during the year 2014-15 stood at Rs 8,826.80 crore, while the total authorised capital of private limited companies registered during the same period stood at Rs 22,953.93 crore.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/c/company_act_4840_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 14:38:11</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>