<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/railway-budget-2016-17-3-ways-bysuresh-prabhu-aims-to-regain-freight-mkt-share_5642821.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Railway Budget 2016-17: 3 ways by which Suresh Prabhu aims to regain freight mkt share]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Railways plans to start time-tabled freight container, parcel and special commodity trains on a pilot basis. The container sector would be opened to all traffic barring coal, specified mineral ores and part-loads during the non-peak season]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu on Thursday outlined a three-pronged approach to help&nbsp;Railways&nbsp;regain its market share in freight haulage. From a high of close to 80 percent in 1951, Railways' share of freight has fallen below 20 percent.<br />A combination of congested rail networks and a steady rise in freight rates to offset the losses in passenger revenues&nbsp;is to blame for this trend.<br /><br />This is what Suresh Prabhu proposes to do:<br /><br /><strong>Expanding the freight basket of Indian Railways</strong>: To start time-tabled freight container, parcel and&nbsp;special commodity trains on a pilot basis. The container sector would be opened to all traffic&nbsp;barring coal, specified mineral ores and part-loads during the non-peak season. All existing&nbsp;terminals/sheds would be granted access to container traffic, where considered feasible.<br /><br /><strong>Rationalising the tariff structure: </strong>Undertake review of tariff policy to evolve a competitive&nbsp;rate structure vis a vis other modes, permit multi-point loading/unloading and apply&nbsp;differentiated tariffs to increase utilization of alternate routes, explore possibility of signing long term tariff contracts with key freight customers using pre-determined price&nbsp;escalation principles.<br /><br /><strong>Building terminal capacity:</strong>&nbsp;To develop Rail side logistics parks and warehousing<br />in public private partnership (PPP) mode, 10 goods sheds will be developed by TRANSLOC, the Transport Logistics&nbsp;Company of India, in 2016-17.&nbsp;Encourage development of cold storage facilities on vacant land near freight terminals. Local<br />farmers and fisherman would be given preferential usage of the facility.<br /><br />In additions, the Railways plans to nuture&nbsp;customers by appointing key Customer Managers to liaison with major&nbsp;freight stakeholders. Each Zonal Railway will develop customer commitment charter&nbsp;indicating service level commitments of IR, will explore the feasibility of opening up leasing&nbsp;of general purpose wagons.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Indian_Railways_rail__rail_overcrowded_engine_freight_coal_356x200_1252_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 13:46:49</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>