<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/experts-satisfiedsuresh-prabhu’s-railway-budget_5653561.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Experts satisfied with Suresh Prabhu’s Railway Budget]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Railway Minister kept passenger fares and freight rates unchanged but proposed to set up a tariff regulator in a bid to keep fares dynamic.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Railway Minister, Suresh Prabhu today presented the Railway Budget 2016-17. <br /><br />Long on intent but short on delivery, the Railway Minister stepped-up on reforms but missed on his own FY16 estimates - total receipts fell short by Rs 16,000 crore and fund-raising is over Rs 20,000 crore below the last Budget's projection.<br /><br />Railway Minister kept passenger fares and freight rates unchanged but proposed to set up a tariff regulator in a bid to keep fares dynamic. Also announces 2 new coach factories, 3 new type of high-speed trains and 2 mobile apps for grievances and ticket-booking.<br /><br />The Budget reflected aspirations of all with core objective of improving individual experience. Prabhu said Railways needed an overhaul in work culture and a new approach - there was a need to reorganise, rejuvenate and restructure. <br /><br />The minister in Budget 2016-17 has increased plan outlay to Rs 1.21 lakh crore from around Rs 1 lakh crore in the previous Budget.<br /><br />Nalin Jain, President &amp; CEO, GE Transportation, Bharat Salhotra, MD, <br />Alstom Transport India, Rajeev Jyoti, Chief Executive - Railway Business <br />Larsen &amp; Toubro, Abhaya Agarwal, Partner &amp; PPP Leader, EY in an interview to CNBC-TV18 decoded the Railway Budget.<br /><br />The experts were satisfied with the Budget. Jain said the minister showed his commitment to earlier targets and was trying to involve the states with regards to get the funding. The states too are aggressively trying to come forward, he said.<br /><br /><strong><em>For the entire discussion, watch video</em></strong>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/r/railbudget3_0935_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 21:33:28</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>