<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/fiscal-consolidation_4791961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Fiscal Consolidation]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley has reiterated his target of reining in fiscal deficit at 3.9 percent of GDP this year and 3.5 percent in the next year]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>India's fiscal books are in a much better shape than what they were a year ago even as the economic recovery has been patchy so far. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley has reiterated his target of reining in fiscal deficit at 3.9 percent of GDP this year and 3.5 percent in the next year. However, Chief Economic Advisor (CEA) Arvind Subramanian in the mid-year review of the economy has made a strong case for deviating from the fiscal roadmap.<br /><br />Though tighter government spending may help meet the fiscal deficit target, Subramanian feels the only way of propping the economy forward is through public investment, considering private consumption is recovering but not at a robust pace, and private investment and global growth are still rather anaemic.<br /><br />The CEA's comments also assume significance in light of the added expenditure that the government will have to incur on account of implementation of 7th Pay Commission and OROP, which may result in an additional outgo of Rs 1.02 lakh crore a year. Jaitley as well as the minister of state for finance Jayant Sinha have repeatedly said that despite the added expense, the government will stick to its fiscal deficit target.<br /><br />In that context, it is also worth mentioning that the mid-year review saw India's GDP forecast being lowered to 7-7.5 percent for the current year against the earlier forecast of 8.1-8.5 percent.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/f/fiscal_fiscal_deficit_deficit_1312_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-08 14:39:25</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>