<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-has-clear-thrust-for-rural-economy-ritesh-jain_5701801.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 has clear thrust for rural economy: Ritesh Jain]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The 2016-17 Union Budget has a clear thrust for the rural economy while taxing urban and the top of the pyramid consumption, says Ritesh Jain, CIO of Tata Asset Management.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ritesh Jain, CIO, Tata Asset Management</strong><br /><br />&ldquo;A Budget for the real economy&hellip;</p>
<p>"The 2016-17 Union Budget has a clear thrust for the rural economy while taxing urban and the top of the pyramid consumption. It carries the highest ever allocation to MNREGA &ndash; remember, MNREGA expenditure had been coming down in the last 3 years adding to the rural stress. Allocation to the agriculture and allied sector has been increased but the subsidy route has been avoided (efficient spending) while thrust is on job creation. The good thing is that the government is sticking to its initial disposition of clampdown on black money, subsidy rationalisation and push for job creation."<br /><br />"Various estimates have put the black economy at par with and even higher than the real economy. The thrust on bringing back black money into productive use in the real economy can rejuvenate the economy and put us back in growth trajectory. This budget has a clear emphasis on making taxes more efficient, reduce opaqueness in tax dispute handling .While the budget is structurally positive in medium term, no room to spend and a tight fiscal stance could act as a dampener for capital markets. As has been in the past, execution remains the key.&rdquo;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Sensex_Budget2016_nifty_bse_nse_stockmarkets_jaitley_FM_up_356x200_2752_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 17:48:50</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>