<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/arun-jaitley-unveils-pro-poor-budget-pledges-reforms_5692441.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Arun Jaitley unveils pro-poor Budget, pledges reforms]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Presenting his third Budget, Jaitley described Asia's third-largest economy as a bright spot in a gloomy global landscape but said the government wanted to ensure that the benefits of growth are more widely shared among India's 1.3 billion people.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley unveiled a Budget for the poor on Monday, announcing new rural aid and health programmes in a strategy shift that could boost his ruling Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) in coming state elections.</p>
<p>Presenting his third Budget, Jaitley described Asia's third-largest economy as a bright spot in a gloomy global landscape but said the government wanted to ensure that the benefits of growth are more widely shared among India's 1.3 billion people.</p>
<p>In his opening remarks, Jaitley pledged to "spend prudently and wisely for the people, especially for the poor and downtrodden."</p>
<p>The spending package marks a radical shift from Prime Minister Narendra Modi's initial focus on investing in infrastructure in a bid to kick-start private-sector investment that remains weak.</p>
<p>Jaitley described his three priorities as: strengthening India's firewalls by ensuring macroeconomic stability and prudent fiscal management; driving growth through domestic demand; and reforms to boost economic opportunity.</p>
<p>Key areas of policy focus would be farming, social reforms, infrastructure and recapitalising India's banking system, Jaitley said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Arun_Jaitley_budget_FM_budget_356x200_4209_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 11:38:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>