<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-financial-prudence-isnamegame-says-deepak-parekh_5693761.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Financial prudence is the name of game, says Deepak Parekh]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[While there is disappointment over lowered amount for recapitalization for public sector banks (PSBs) at Rs 25,000 crore, Deepak Parekh, Chairman of HDFC says that there no reason to be disappointed. 
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[While there is disappointment over lowered amount for recapitalization for public sector banks (PSBs) at Rs 25,000 crore, Deepak Parekh, Chairman of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-housing/housingdevelopmentfinancecorporation/HDF">HDFC</a> says that there no reason to be disappointed. <br /><br />&ldquo;Financial prudence is the name of the game,&rdquo; he says adding that FM is right in providing within the limits. Parekh says that the Finance Minister, in his speech, also stated that any lag in recapitalization will be provided for. <br /><br />In the non-performing loans issues, the assurance of renegotiation of old public private partnership (PPP) projects beings slight relieve for banks, he adds.<br /><br />The emphasis has been on three crucial areas - rural economy, farmers and job creation, health and education. <br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Udayan:</strong> What did you make of it because the market is disappointed, there are couple of positives but many negatives, what do you stand out as the key reasons why the market slipped off so much today? <br /><br /><strong>Parekh:</strong> I think the Finance Minister has done the right thing as Uday Kotak has pointed out and financial prudence is the name of the game. You cannot spend more money than you have and you have to be within limits. He has stuck to his 3.5 percent commitment of previous year despite headwinds against us, despite global headwinds, despite domestic headwinds. <br /><br />If you see the Budget, this Rs 25,000 crore, I am not disappointed at it because he also made a point after that, that if the banks need more money, we will find more money. So, I am not disappointed with the Rs 25,000 crore. I am not sure why the market is so disappointed. <br /><br />People who earn more have to pay more taxes. We are not the highest paying tax payer in the highest paying nation in the world and if you earn more than Rs 10 lakh, I think it is just fair to pay 10 percent of that as additional income and you have to make up revenues. Don&rsquo;t forget, the Budget has emphasised the areas which the Finance Minister spent almost 70 percent of his time is the agriculture and pharmaceutical welfare, the rural economy and job creation, skill development, health, education. &nbsp;<br /><br />He is trying to give more money to the farming community. He said from food security we have to give them income security. The more income the farmers get, the more spending will happen and we want to see this. The last year and half, two years because of bad monsoon, we have seen that the demand from the rural sector has been extremely subdued. So, I am not disappointed with it, in fact I am reasonably happy with it. &nbsp;<br /><br />It is probably the worst time globally and he said that there are huge challenges but let us look at it as an opportunity, let us see what we can do. Unfortunately, all emerging markets (EMs) are bracketed into one homogeneous asset class and we are getting the brunt of it because although we are the fastest growing nation, we are still being an emerging market are suffering due to the global mentality of the foreign investors and the foreign investing community.<br /><br />I think the market will realise a little later, after reading the text. There are number of annexure&rsquo;s one has to see because he has referred to a&nbsp; number of annexure&rsquo;s and to give you&nbsp; a proper interpretation I think you must give us a day or so to read the annexure&rsquo;s. <br /><br /><strong>Udayan: The disappointment seems to be around banking and I know you have made some interesting comments on that off late. How did you read the government&rsquo;s approach to fixing this banking problem? There was Rs 25,000 crore recapitalisation, allusion to a Bankruptcy Bill but there did not seem to be a cogent or credible plan to resolve this problem. Are you satisfied? </strong><br /><br /><strong>Parekh:</strong> I am reasonably satisfied. One of the thrusts of the Finance Mininster&rsquo;s speech was also ease of doing business. If you see the number of times he spoke about dispute resolution, the Finance Minister had the courage to say that old public private partnerships (PPPs) can be renegotiated because large number of infrastructure projects which the banks are hurting because of renegotiation is not happening; no one is willing to bell the cat. <br /><br />Renegotiation can happen with transparency of old PPP projects and most of the funding that is blocked of the banks, are on those old PPP projects which have stalled, which have half complete, which have last mile approvals needed. So, ease of doing business on Income Tax also, many things have been given for MSME and other sectors where you pay, you are waived interest and waived penalty - you just pay the tax and you get away with it. So, clearing up, simplification and rationalisation. <br /><br />Now, on the banking side, he again stressed the importance of asset reconstruction company (ARC). We will have to read the annexure that what the government is planning to do on the asset reconstruction company because there was a lot of talk about strengthening the ARC mechanism and what the government and Reserve Bank of India (RBI) are wanting to do on strengthening the ARC. So, to reasonable extent he has taken care of it and I don&rsquo;t think we should look at it too negatively.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch video for more</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/d/deepakparekh_356_2750_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 13:09:50</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,HDF,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>