<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/fii-view/overweightindia-see-12-15-upside-nomuras-kurtz_5657041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Overweight on India, see 12-15% upside: Nomura's Kurtz]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Michael Kurtz, Chief Asia Equity Strategist of Nomura says, while this will be a 'run-of-the-mill' Budget, corporate tax cut will be a positive. 
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Nomura is overweight on India for the calendar year 2016 and believes underperformance of Indian&nbsp;market&nbsp;will soon conclude, says Michael Kurtz, Chief Asia Equity Strategist of Nomura.<br /> <br />Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Kurtz says, while this will be a 'run-of-the-mill' Budget, the likely corporate tax rate cut will&nbsp;be a positive. He sees further upside of&nbsp;12-15 percent in Indian equities.<br /><br />Calling India's growth story as&nbsp;the strongest in Asia, he says, a growth of 15 percent in earnings over the next 12 months may be possible.<br /><br />Kurtz likes <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/axisbank/AB16">Axis Bank</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-carsjeeps/marutisuzukiindia/MS24">Maruti Suzuki</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/infrastructure-general/larsentoubro/LT">L&amp;T</a>&nbsp;and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/infrastructure-general/nationalbuildingsconstructioncorporation/NBC01">NBCC</a> and says the firm has exposure to <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/power-generationdistribution/suzlonenergy/SE17">Suzlon</a>.<br /><br /><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Michael Kurtz's interview with Latha Venkatesh and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong><br /><br /><strong>Sonia: The Indian market had fallen 8 percent this month and has underperformed the rest of the globe. Are you getting a sense that this underperformance from India could continue and if yes, why would that be?</strong><br /><br />A: To directly answer your question, we do not think the underperformance is going to continue. We think that a lot of the soggy performance in India has been a function of what we can now see from the result season being a sort of a kitchen sinking of a lot of the bad loan recognition by the Indian banks and at the same time we think it basically clears the way for much better performance now both in terms of the aggregate earnings outlook and specifically in terms of investors now being able to take a fresh look at the banks with much more of the bad news now already in the price and arguably at this point, much more upside risk than downside.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: What is the foreign institutional investor (FII) community expecting from the Budget? Will that be seen as incrementally a reason why you would buy or not buy?</strong><br /><br />A: I think we have to be realistic in terms of the outlook for this Budget. It is clearly going to be more of a run-of-the-mill incremental exercise than a radical exercise. There are going to be some positives here. For example, some additional commitment to road infrastructure development, there is probably going to be some additional public sector bank reform announced, the start-up India initiative and so on.<br /><br />Clearly, a cut in the corporate tax rate if we get that, we think probably the 29 percent from the current 30 percent would all be positive and yet, really, it doesn&rsquo;t look like this Budget is going to offer such revolutionary positives that it is going to be a major catalyst for upside rather probably more like a bullet dodged than anything else.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: I heard you mention that there is more upside to the Indian markets than downside, what gives you that confidence and what could the upside look like for India in the near-term?</strong><br /><br />A: I think the principle driver of upside is the fact that India's gross domestic product (GDP) growth rates and particularly nominal GDP, which is the platform for corporate revenues is now the strongest, most robust GDP growth story in the Asia-Pacific region. India notwithstanding -- as I mentioned -- a rather bumpy quarterly result season, still enjoys about the most robust earnings growth outlook in the entire region.<br /><br />While, at the same time, the recent underperformance in the market has brought the earnings multiples back down to levels that are fairly neutral. In other words, we don&rsquo;t expect much more multiple compression possibly indeed a bit of multiple expansion and when you add that in the context of 15 percent earnings growth, over the next 12 months that implies significant outperformance by Indian equities.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: So is your base case that the markets have fully discounted the disappointments of the earnings season that the Nifty sub-7,000 is an attractive buy?</strong><br /><br />A: Yes, we would say both of those things and indeed we are overweight India as we look at over the rest of this calendar year on the view that the superior growth story in India is indeed going to deliver stocks substantially higher. We are thinking in terms of 12 to 15 percent upside over the course of the next 12 months.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: One more question on the Budget. I heard you mention that this could be a run-of-the-mill Budget, but we are getting some exclusive details on the fact that the government may choose to stick to its 3.5 percent fiscal deficit target and compromise a bit on the expenditure. So, they may reduce the Seventh Pay Commission allocation as well by a tad bit in order to meet the fiscal deficit target number. How would a foreign investor react to that?</strong><br /><br />A: The interesting thing is that the fiscal consolidation in the past few years has brought with it some things that were arguably not so positive for the equity asset class in particular; expenditure cuts, for example, not allowing pass through of windfall oil gains, reduced central government support to various schemes that may ultimately feed into rural spending. So, while this may be positive from the standpoint of fiscal consolidation &ndash; and I am sure the bond markets are more impressed and more satisfied -- from a growth specific perspective, it is arguably not as positive for equities.<br /><br />What we would like to see on the equity side of things is for the growth outlook in India to remain well supported. We all understand, of course, that fiscal consolidation is absolutely an important target over the medium term. But, what the equity markets right now are much more focused on is the growth outlook and not necessarily particularly worked up over 3.5 percent versus 3.7 percent of GDP budget shortfalls. That is relatively inconsequential for the equity asset class.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: If that is the case, then when the 3.5 percent fiscal deficit is indeed announced, and not so much of pump-priming is announced, will that be a reason to sell then, on Monday, when the Budget is announced?</strong><br /><br />A: I think, it would very much depend on exactly where that 0.2 percentage point difference is coming from. If it is lower taxes, that is arguably a pro-growth consideration that equities might like. If it comes in the form of less expenditure on basic infrastructure, then clearly, that would be somewhat more equity negative. So, we need to simply see the actual composition of the expected revenues and the expected expenditures and see how they balance out.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: What would you buy since you say that now the shares are attractive?</strong><br /><br />A: As a matter of fact, we have a variety of different Indian companies on our recommended stock list in the region right now. Everything from private sector banks like Axis Bank to industrial sector names, like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/transportlogistics/containercorporationindia/CCI">Container Corporation of India</a> (CCRI) for example and we still want to maintain exposure to interest rate sensitives consumer cyclical type names, Maruti Suzuki for example, is also on our recommended stock list.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: Any other names that you are looking at from the capital expenditure (capex) or from the infrastructure space -- the likes of Larsen and Toubro of the world because you were expecting to see some sort of boost to infrastructure spending as well?</strong><br /><br />A: For example, also in the industrial space, we have Suzlon Energy. We do want to maintain some exposure to alternative energy type plays in India. The list goes on for quite a bit. But, in the industrial space, we also look at L&amp;T, as you mentioned and National Buildings Construction Corporation (NBCC) is another name that we like in that space.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/asian_markets_markets_bse_nse_stock_356x200_3926_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 08:55:11</Entry_Date><Category>FII View</Category><sc_id>,UTI10,MU01,LT,NBC,SE17,CCI,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>