<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/budget-2016-no-movecapital-gains-service-tax-biggest-+ve-says-arora_5693561.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: No move on capital gains, service tax biggest +ve, says Arora]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Samir Arora, Founder & Fund Manager at Helios Capital says the two biggest positives in the Budget presented were - no increase in the services tax, which was speculated to rise by 2 percent, and no change in capital gains tax. 
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Samir Arora, Founder &amp; Fund Manager at Helios Capital, commenting on the Budget, says that the two biggest positives in the Budget presented were -&nbsp;no increase in the services tax, which was speculated to rise by 2 percent, and no change in capital gains tax. <br /><br />However, the biggest disappointment is the recapitalization of Rs 25,000 crore for public sector banks. Arora says that it is like &ldquo;trying to say (we) don&rsquo;t believe in the issue.&rdquo; <br /><br />The government is anti-gold and anti-cigarette and any reaction on those fronts is surprising.<br />
<p><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Samir Arora&rsquo;s interview with CNBC-TV18's Udayan Mukherjee &amp; Sonia Shenoy.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Udayan: From a market reaction point of view what do you think has caused the biggest disappointment this afternoon?</strong></p>
<p>Arora: I think you missed the big positives. One, there is no increase in service tax. You have completely forgotten that. Second, long-term capital gain (LTCG). So, today's negative reaction although for specific stocks clearly is justified but it is just because of number of individual tax and this and that, there are too many for me to even quickly grasp. But the big picture is that you avoided service tax which we had more or less accepted at two percent increase and also the LTCG there were fears.</p>
<p>Now in terms of tax increases; it was expected in some sense and it is more of an administrative issue rather than bringing the stock market down. But the biggest negative is I agree totally with you, when the number of the Budget are so large what is the shyness in saying and surprising the market by saying that we will give Rs 35,000 or Rs 40,000 crore to public sector undertaking (PSU) banks Rs 25,000 crore looks as if a number which was just trying to make it as if you don't really believe in the problem. So, the biggest disappointment was that but overall my feeling is and we will know at the end of the day that you had all the taxes the fact that you did not increase service tax would maybe take care of all the other taxes. Except that obviously those that have gone to certain specific sectors.</p>
<p><strong>Sonia: Do you think the disappointment in terms of taxes has already been priced in to the market or do you expect some more to go because right now the Nifty is down about 100 points odd?</strong></p>
<p>Arora: The thing is today obviously this disappointment in respect of state owned banks and just the fact that the number of taxes, so, today we may not be able to quickly assess but we know and I have known for long and I have been surprised that the public does not know that or the market that this government is anti-gold and it is anti-cigarettes. They want to be surprised again and again. The point is that government is against these two sectors. Why people don't grasp it I don't understand. We are short one of the two sectors. We should have been short both but it is very clear policy of that government to have been against this. Now whether it is 10 or 15.</p>
<p>So, I don't know right now but if you added all the numbers of the tax increases and compare it with the service tax increase that could have happened and the fact that you have gone away from having that LTCG issue I hope, because he didn't say it in the Budget. End of the day today's fall maybe still justified a little bit because of the big disappointment on recap of state owned banks. It could easily have been much more and it would not have mattered Rs 10,000 crore. You could have pulled out from here and there, maybe could have build one less road, but you know what the current problem is. There is no point in not dealing with the current problem and trying to do something less.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_India_GDP_Growth_inflation_rise_Inflation_Service_Tax_356x200_4840_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 12:57:14</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>