<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/q3-gdp-at-73-full-year-forecast-revised-upward-to-76_5363921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Q3 GDP at 7.3%, full-year forecast revised upward to 7.6%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The full year GDP forecast has been revised to 7.6 percent from 7.2 percent estimated earlier. The gross value added (GVA) for FY16 is seen at 7.3 percent, compared to 7.1 percent in the previous year.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The third quarter (Q3) FY16 gross domestic product (GDP) has come in at 7.3 percent, compared to 7.4 percent in the second quarter and 6.6 percent in Q3 last year.</p>
<p>The full year GDP forecast has been revised to 7.6 percent from 7.2 percent.<em><strong><br /></strong></em></p>
<p>The Q1FY16 growth has been revised to 7.6 percent from 7.0 percent, while Q2FY16 has been revised to 7.7 percent from 7.4 percent.</p>
<p>The gross value added is seen at 7.3 percent, compared to 7.1 percent in the previous year.</p>
<p>At current prices, the economy grew at 9.2 percent in Q3, while in Q2 it was 6.4 percent due to higher deflation and 8.7 percent in Q1.<br /><br />The manufacturing&nbsp;sector&nbsp;is expected to grow at 9.5 percent in FY16 as compared to growth of 5.5 percent in FY15.<br /><br />Trade, hotels and transport &amp; communication and services related to broadcasting is expected to grow at 9.5 percent compared to 9.8 percent previous year.<br /><br />Financial, insurance, real estate and professional services sector is expected to grow at 10.3 percent compared to 10.6 percent in the previous year.</p>
<p>The growth in the agriculture, forestry and fishing, mining and quarrying, electricity, gas, water supply and other utility services, construction and public administration, defence and other services&nbsp; is estimated to be 1.1 percent, 6.9 percent, 5.9 percent, 3.7 percent and 6.9 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Pronab Sen, former principal advisor of Planning Commission says, there is re-distribution happening in the Indian economy. While there have been positive surprises in the quarter's growth numbers, Q4 GDP may be back to 7.3 percent.</p>
<p>Backing Sen, Sajjid Chinoy, chief India economist and executive director at JP Morgan says, boost from oil prices this quarter may not be a benefit going forward and there is loss of momentum in growth compared to the first half of FY16.</p>
<p>Anubhuti Sahay of Standard Chartered Bank points out that while the industrial numbers are a surprise, actual improvement is minimal. She believes government's strategy of public spending rather than private has not been successful.</p>
<p>Gaurav Kapur of Royal Bank of Scotland expects the whole-year economic growth at 7.4 percent.</p>
<p><em><strong>&nbsp;</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/e/Economy_improved_shutterstock_356x200_5530_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-08 17:43:40</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>