<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/railway-budget-2016-17-projects-to-be-undertaken-by-railwaysfy-2016-17_5642421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Railway Budget 2016-17: Projects to be undertaken by railways in FY 2016-17]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[While announcing new trains in dense routes to improving the basic amenities for the passengers, Prabhu said the Budget reflects the aspirations of the aam-aadmi.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Union Railways Minister Suresh Prabhu on Thursday presented Railways Budget 2016-17 in Parliament and highlighted the vision of the Narendra Modi government.</p>
<p>While announcing new trains in dense routes to improving the basic amenities for the passengers, Prabhu said the Budget reflects the aspirations of the aam-aadmi.</p>
<p><strong>Here is the list of projects to be undertaken by Railways:</strong></p>
<p>- Delhi to get relief from rising pollution through development of ring railway system.</p>
<p>- A high speed passenger corridor from Ahmedabad to Mumbai is being undertaken with help from Japan government.</p>
<p>- We will partner with Tamil Nadu government for developing suburban network in Chennai through innovative financing methods.</p>
<p>- Mumbai needs a robust transport system. Working towards an early award of tender for two elevated suburban corridors between Churchgate/Virar; CSTM and Panvel.</p>
<p>- Collies to be called Sahayaks.</p>
<p>- A sub-quota of 33 percent will be introduced for women in each of the categories.</p>
<p>- New uniforms to be provided to porters in Railway stations.</p>
<p>- Specialised teams mandated to screen rail operation in specific ares to detect inefficiencies.</p>
<p>- GPS services inside coaches, increased number of information boards.</p>
<p>- Looking to save around Rs 3000 crore by rationalising power management.</p>
<p>- New policy of multi-purpose stalls at station to provide milk and medicines.</p>
<p>- Centralised data management for land holding is being developed by Indian Railways. E-booking on concession passes for journalists to be introduced.</p>
<p>- Local cuisine of choice will be made available to passengers.</p>
<p>- We plan to introduce cancellation of ticket facility</p>
<p>- IRCTC will begin to manage catering service in phased manner.</p>
<p>- Work on Katra-Banihal section of Udhampur-Srinagar-Baramulla rail link progressing satisfactorily and 35 kms of tunneling completed</p>
<p>- E-ticket facility for foreign debit and credit cards to be available:</p>
<p>- Utkrisht- Double Decker AC Yatri express on busiest routes.</p>
<p>- Barcoded tickets to be introduced at major stations.</p>
<p>- Overnight double-decker "Uday" expresses to be introduced on busiest routes</p>
<p>- For the reserved passengers, three new trains - Humsafar, Tejas and Uday- to be rolled out.</p>
<p>- Antoyaya Express (a long-distance, fully unreserved superfast service) and 2-4 Deen Dayalu Coaches (unreserved) to be introduced.</p>
<p>- Railway University is being set up at Vadodara.</p>
<p>- Increased quota of lower berths, in coming financial year. We are increasing senior citizen quota/coach by 50 percent.</p>
<p>- All major stations to be brought under CCTV surveillance in a phased manner.</p>
<p>- High end technology to significantly improve safety record by 2020.</p>
<p>- New train between Varanasi and Delhi, Mahamana Express, with modern refurbished coaches.</p>
<p>- Enhanced capacity of e-ticketing system from 2,000 tickets per minute to 7,200 per minute.</p>
<p>- 100 stations to have WiFi facility 2016-17 and 400 stations 2017-18.</p>
<p>- 17,000 bio-toilets and additional toilets in 475 stations before close of this financial year.</p>
<p>- Railways to shift to completely paperless contract system in 2016-17.</p>
<p>- Ensuring online booking of retiring room.</p>
<p>- Will set up 2 locomotive factories at the cost of Rs 40,000 crore.</p>
<p>- 44 new projects valued Rs 92,714 crore to be implemented this year.</p>
<p>- Will commission 9 km/Day of broad gauge lines in FY 2017-18 and 13km/day in FY 2018-19</p>
<p>- Indian Railways to surpass ambitious target of commissioning 2,500 kms of broad gauge lines, almost 30 percent higher than 2015-16</p>
<p>- 1600 kms of electrification 2016-17 and 2,000 km in 2017-18 are proposed</p>
<p>- Rs 8.5 lakh crore to be spent over 5 years for modernisation of railway infrastructure.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Suresh_Prabhu_2016_railways_rail_minister_356x200_2848_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 13:11:05</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>