<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/oppn-slams-budget-says-it-presents-half-baked-truth_5864501.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Oppn slams Budget, says it presents 'half-baked truth']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Participating in a debate on the Budget 2016-17, Tariq Anwar (NCP) targeted Prime Minister Narendra Modi for giving full marks to it, saying he was acting as an examinee as well as examiner himself.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Opposition today slammed the General Budget in Lok Sabha, saying it presents a "rosy picture" and "half-baked truth", and mocked at the 'achhe din' slogan of the government, quipping that "good days" had come only for RSS which has "graduated from shorts to full pants".</p>
<p>Participating in a debate on the Budget 2016-17, Tariq Anwar (NCP) targeted Prime Minister Narendra Modi for giving full marks to it, saying he was acting as an examinee as well as examiner himself.</p>
<p>The Budget has presented a "rosy picture", but this is "half-baked truth" when it comes to allocation of money to farmers and agricultural sector, he said.</p>
<p>"Prior to the Budget, the Prime Minister said it is his test. After the Budget he gave himself full marks. This was the only Budget where the examinee and the examiner were same," Anwar said.</p>
<p>With regard to the 'acche din' slogan of the government, he said, "It is only the RSS that is seeing 'acche din'. They have graduated from shorts to full pants during the tenure of this government," he said.</p>
<p>Santok Singh Chaudhary (Cong) said the Budget was "anti-middle" class.</p>
<p>Jai Prakash Narain Yadav (RJD) described the Budget as "directionless" and hollow.</p>
<p>Mocking at the government's 'acche din' slogan, he said 'good days' had come only for the BJP and the ruling party will see "bad days" after 2019 Lok Sabha polls.</p>
<p>Yadav said the Prime Minister, on assumption of power, had promised to bring down inflation but the situation today is that prices of essential commodities are "sky-rocketing".</p>
<p>He also criticised the government's ambitious 'Smart Cities' programme and said the country needs 'Smart rural areas'.</p>
<p>Ganesh Singh (BJP) ridiculed the opposition for constantly criticising the Prime Minister even when he is "working for 18 hours a day just to make the country a super power".</p>
<p>Listing the achievements of the government, he highlighted Modi's invitation to all SAARC leaders for his swearing-in and his participation in Pakistan Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif's family function in Lahore as efforts to develop India's ties with the neighbouring nations.</p>
<p>Poonam Mahajan (BJP) said the Budget was extremely progressive and pro-poor as it has addressed all sections of the society.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/u/Union_Budget_2016_2_356X200_4020_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-14 15:14:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>