<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/quantum-jumpbudget-allocation-for-northeastjitendra-singh_5751141.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA['Quantum jump' in Budget allocation for Northeast:Jitendra Singh]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[There has been a "quantum jump" in allocation for the Northeast in the Union budget 2016-17 and it will help all-round development of the region, Union Minister for Development of North Eastern Region (DoNER) Jitendra Singh said on Thursday.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>There has been a "quantum jump" in allocation for the Northeast in the Union budget 2016-17 and it will help all-round development of the region, Union Minister for Development of North Eastern Region (DoNER) Jitendra Singh said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Singh said the announcement of Organic Value Chain Development Scheme, with an allocation of Rs 115 crore, will prove to be a "game-changer" for the entire region.</p>
<p>"Not only will it help boost the enormous unexplored potentials of organic entrepreneurship in the region but will also convert the entire region into a favourite destination for new start-ups from across the country to come to the Northeast," he said in a statement.</p>
<p>The minister said emphasis of the government has been on promotion of organic farming and Northeast has become an important destination for that with Sikkim being declared as the first organic state of India by Prime Minister Narendra Modi recently.</p>
<p>Singh said the budgetary allocation for the Ministry of DoNER has been increased from Rs 2,334.50 crore last year to Rs 2,400 crore this year.</p>
<p>Provisions have been made for connectivity in Northeastern region, skill development and organic value chain development among others, he said.</p>
<p>The minister said a budget of Rs 33,097.02 crore has been allocated for the Northeast across 56 ministries, which is 14 per cent higher than the budget estimate of Rs 29,087.93 crore for the previous year.</p>
<p>Under Non-Lapsable Central Pool Reserve (NLCPR), budget estimate has been increased from Rs 90 crore to Rs 200 crore in 2016-17.</p>
<p>The budget allocation for North Eastern Council schemes has been increased from Rs 700 crore to Rs 795 crore this year, he said.</p>
<p>The minister also said Rs 150 crore has been provided for the newly launched NE Road Sector Development Scheme which will be helpful in the development of inter-state roads.</p>
<p>In addition, he said, Asian Development Bank (ADB) will spare funds for construction and maintenance of roads in the region.</p>
<p>"The budget allocation for Northeast this year is not only substantial but also very imaginative and hoped that the state governments will respond in similar vein by offering cooperation through timely submission of DPRs (Detailed Project Reports), utilisation certificates and states sharing of 10 per cent of funds etc," he said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/u/Union_Budget_2016_3_356X200_4040_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-03 19:54:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>