<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/railway-budget-2016-17-partneringgoogle-for-wi-fi-at-400-stations2-years_5643141.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Railway Budget 2016-17: Partnering with Google for Wi-Fi at 400 stations in 2 years]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Suresh Prabhu announced that an application of Track Management System (TMS) was already launched, under which activities of track inspection, monitoring and maintenance have been switched over to an IT platform, and automatic alerts in the form of SMS and e-mails are being generated.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Union Railways Minister Suresh Prabhu while presenting Railway Budget 2016-17 in Parliament on Thursday said that the process has begun to introduce Wi-Fi services at stations especially for youth and business travellers.</p>
<p>He proposed to commission Wi-Fi services at 100 stations in 2016 and at 400 more stations in the next 2 years, announcing that Indian Railways is partnering with Google in the endeavour.</p>
<p>Suresh Prabhu announced that an application of Track Management System (TMS) was already launched, under which activities of track inspection, monitoring and maintenance have been switched over to an IT platform, and automatic alerts in the form of SMS and e-mails are being generated.</p>
<p>Inventory Management module of TMS has resulted in inventory reduction by 27,000 MT resulting in saving of Rs 64 crore and scrap identification of 22,000 MT equivalent to Rs 53 crore, said the minister.</p>
<p>During 2016-17, the system is expected to be implemented on entire Indian Railways. Indian Railways has developed an application for maintaining centralized land data, and records of all land holdings over Indian Railways have been digitised.</p>
<p>Facilities such as ticketing, grievance redressal, etc. will be integrated into two mobile apps; one dealing with all ticketing issues and the other for receipt and redressal of complaints and suggestions related to all our services.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/g/Google_356x200_3046_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 14:15:52</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>