<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-boosting-infra-agri-right-step-for-economy-say-corporates_5706221.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Boosting infra, agri right step for economy, say corporates]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The government has, though, tried to expand the tax space, gone in for simplification in tax laws, emphasized on tax dispute resolution and come out with ways to benefit the lower income groups, says Rajiv Memani, Chairman of India Region, EY.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>In Budget 2016, stress has been more on the incentives side and hence tax rate reduction hasn't come through, says&nbsp;Rajiv Memani, Chairman of India Region, EY. The government has, however, attempted to rationalise&nbsp;the system by&nbsp;trying&nbsp;to expand the tax space, simplify&nbsp;tax laws, emphasise&nbsp;on tax dispute resolutions and come&nbsp;out with ways to benefit the lower income groups, Memani tells CNBC-TV18.<br /> <br /> Meanwhile, Vipin Sondhi, MD &amp; CEO of JCB India, says there has been a big thrust on improving the rural economy &mdash; including agriculture and irrigation. This is critical as after agriculture, infra sector is the biggest job creator, Sondhi adds.&nbsp;<br /> <br /> Backing Sondhi, Vinayak Chatterjee, Chairman of Feedback Infra, says big push to roads and&nbsp;railways should spur growth. The government has, on expected lines, considered private sector's demands regarding public private partnership (PPP) guidelines.<br /> <br /> Calling this a balanced Budget, Sumant Sinha, Chairman &amp; CEO of ReNew Power Ventures, says the government has worked towards boosting demand via 100 percent electrification target. Sticking to fiscal deficit target and introducing Clean Environment cess is&nbsp;a critical step for economic growth, Sinha adds.&nbsp;<br /> <br /> <strong><em>Watch video for more</em></strong></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_economy_growth_GDP_356x200_2811_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 19:36:19</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>