<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/nifty-falling-below-6650-6700-unlikelynear-term-nirmal-jain_5719181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Nifty falling below 6650-6700 unlikely in near term: Nirmal Jain]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The allocation for the rural sector in the Budget has nearly doubled and this in turn will lead to consumption-led growth, which in turn will have a cascading effect, says Nirmal Jain of IIFL]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>It may be a good time to enter the equity market with a 2-3 year view, says Nirmal Jain of IIFL. But at the same time, investors should have a bottom-up stock picking approach, he says. Buy some of the IT companies, private banks now if you are building a portfolio, he tells investors.</p>
<p>Jain does not see more than 5-7 percent downside from current levels. He believes Nifty is unlikely to fall below 6650-6700 in the near-term.</p>
<p>As far as Monday's Budget goes, he says a lot of procedural hurdles in income tax have been cleared by the government this time around. "The government has come back to focus on the rural sector &mdash; roads, irrigation, among others. The allocation for the rural sector has nearly doubled and this in turn will lead to consumption-led growth, which will have a cascading effect," he adds.</p>
<p><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Nirmal Jain&rsquo;s interview with Anuj Singhal and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong> </em></p>
<p><strong>Anuj: Still scratching our heads. What has lead to this 750 point gain on the Sensex. The day after normally is reserved for better reaction on the Budget. What is your own analysis? What do you attribute this big gain to?</strong> </p>
<p>A: One of the key positives and the pleasant surprise of the Budget has been that, they kept to the path of fiscal consolidation and discipline. And they kept to fiscal deficit 3.9 percent and 3.5 percent next year. And what is more important here is that this number, the fiscal math is credible and basically, these are realistic assumptions about tax revenue and tax expenditure, so it is not that they have just tried to make the number look good, but the underlying, in fact I would say there is some cushion in tax revenue. They have just taken 12 percent income tax growth, but they have not taken any tax on this amnesty scheme or Voluntary Disclosure of Income Scheme (VDIS) that they have. So, that can actually make up if there is any overrun in expenditures side. </p>
<p>On the whole, it looks up, so that has been one big macro which will lead to a cut in interest rate by RBI and further southward journey of interest rates which has been one big problem with the revival of private sector investment cycle. Everybody says that what difference interest will make at 0.5-1 percent. It is more about sentiment. So, the private sector investment on any capital expenditure (Capex) is taken based on expectations about future and not actually what has happened in the past. So, that way entrepreneur will be more enthused as the interest rate gets into single digit. That is one. </p>
<p>Other than that, now this government has come back to focus on rural and including NREGA as well as a lot of other investments which is more, capital expenditure is more productivity oriented such as irrigation or on rural roads as well as there are a lot of other initiatives about rural India. In fact, the allocation for rural sector has almost been doubled, sort of unprecedented, and that actually will take care of demand side, because if we look at GDP, there is a demand side and there is an investment side. So, the consumption led growth. So, we had seen that earlier when rural folks had more money in their hands, the demand for sectors like FMCG, two wheelers or consumer durables and that basically has a cascading impact and the domino impact basically makes the whole economic cycle accelerate. So, that is one part of it. </p>
<p>Other than that, there is a significant increase in allocation for rail and road sector. Now only thing that we need to watch out of course rate cut has to happen as soon as possible. More or less, there is consensus that RBI was waiting for fiscal discipline and a fiscal consolidation, so that has happened. Inflation is broadly under control, if you look at wholesale price index (WPI), it is sort of deflationary or sort of static. So, in this kind of a scenario, a rate cut should start, that is one. And other than that, corporate earnings which have been disappointing, maybe it will take a quarter or a couple of quarters to revive. </p>
<p>So, market is looking at a big macro view. Having said that, I would caution that just in a day or two, the Budget is absorbed and market will again look for cues from global environment, global financial markets as well as sentiment for emerging markets. That will be the short-term tendency, but if you look at medium to long-term, then India stands out. I mean even prior to the Budget as well as with the Budget, India is actually a bright spot in terms of economies, the fastest growing economy and a very good destination for foreign capital as an investment. And government has made a sincere attempt to remove quite a few of other bottlenecks like say there was a text anomaly or a doubt about pass through on the Real Estate Investment Trust (REIT) structure, a number of procedural hassles in income tax and the DTS status for AIF, so there are hundreds of such small provisions which are basically trying to resolve the problems. Many of them have been resolved, some of them will still remain. But on the whole, the approach is positive and that is what market is recognising today. </p>
<p><strong>Sonia: I just want to pick up on that point you mentioned about the fact that you would still be a bit cautious in the near-term because of global cues, etc. So, what would this caution extend to? I mean is there a bottom in place for this market at Rs 6,800-7,000 or do you think that question is still open for debate?</strong> </p>
<p>A: Again, what kind of unknown catastrophe happens in the global environment, that we really cannot predict today. Under normal circumstances, I would think that I find it difficult that market will have a bottom which is 5 percent or 7 percent at the most on the downside. Unless something completely unforeseen which you and I really cannot visualise today happens, leaving that aside, market is unlikely to go, if you talk about Nifty, then maybe 6,700-6,650 and you can work out parallel levels for Sensex. So, on the downside, maybe 5 percent or 7 percent at the most, I do not see a bigger downside than that. Even in a corrective phase, if the global cues suddenly become negative. </p>
<p><strong>Anuj: The two stocks which have really led this rally, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/cigarettes/itc/ITC">ITC</a> and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/icicibank/ICI02">ICICI Bank</a>, do you get a feeling that both of them were too oversold and are now good buys?</strong> </p>
<p>A: I think so, because ITC was hammered on the Budget day also and I think the excise duty increase on cigarette was more or less given and the demand in inelastic brands are strong and ITC also is diversified, so it is a good FMCG company and obviously, long-term investors saw the opportunity. So, both these stocks were oversold, ICICI Bank, again a private sector, one of the leading private sector banks, valuations from a peak have gone almost down by 35-40 percent. So, obviously it became a favourite stock when people were looking for liquid stocks to build up long positions after the Budget, that is how these two stocks have been favoured. </p>
<p><strong>Sonia: You also made his point about the rural push that the government has done which is quite credible and in that, even in today&rsquo;s trade we are seeing some of these companies like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-carsjeeps/mahindramahindra/MM">Mahindra and Mahindra (M&amp;M)</a> post good numbers. M&amp;M&rsquo;s tractor sales for the month of February has grown almost 20 percent year-on-year. Is this a time to shift to rural focused stocks, the tractor makers, some of the consumption oriented names?</strong> </p>
<p>A: I think so. Tractor makers yes, but they also depend on monsoon, and by law of natural averages, monsoon should be good this year. And, that is what would be, because they had two bad years, so tractor is good and also consumption, discretionary, consumption led stocks should also do well. But, overall, there is nothing negative for other sectors as well. So, if you are building a portfolio, you look at IT sector also, you can look at private banks also, you can look at infrastructure because a lot of outlay for road sectors, railways, so broadly, even other sectors will benefit. So, one should do a bottom-up stock picking. </p>
<p><strong>Sonia: For the last six months a lot of experts were telling us that holding cash is the best thing to do. It is better to keep your arsenal and when the market gives you an opportunity then get in, not right now. Is cash preservation not the strategy any more, is the strategy to go out there and deploy some money into the market now?</strong> </p>
<p>A: I would think so, but if you want to deploy money in equity market then you should have a perspective of three years. In very short term there can be sudden shocks or jitters from global market. So, it is not a good idea to leverage and invest in this market. Now that the interest rate should be heading southward, so it is not a bad idea to invest in debt funds or fixed income products or even government securities. So, I would say that if one is holding on to cash then you should get it deployed in mix of equity and debt. If you have an appetite to hold the stock for two to three years then yes, equity makes a good investment choice. </p>
<p><strong>Anuj: If I can read your body language right, you are still not constructive on this market from here on for a big rally. You still believe that it was a bit of a short covering pop and back to the mercy of global cues and there is still a risk of this markets again falling back to previous lows?</strong> </p>
<p>A: No, there are two things, if you are a trader or you are an investor. If you are an investor for say, 2-3 years then I am pretty certain that this market will give you above average return or a better return than what your alternate asset classes can give you. But if you are a day to day trader looking at 15 day to 3 months scenario I am not an expert on that but I won't feel comfortable for that. So, that is how it should be viewed.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/n/Nirmal-Jain-093-356_3317_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 15:13:38</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,ITC,ICI02,MM,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>