<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/great-budget-2016-for-affordable-housing-rajesh-prajapati_5701961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Great Budget 2016 for affordable housing: Rajesh Prajapati]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[100 percent tax deduction to entities constructing 30 sq metre houses in 4 metros n 60 sq mtrs in other areas is a major booster to the affordable housing sector, says Rajesh Prajapati, MD, Prajapati Constructions.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Rajesh Prajapati, MD, Prajapati Constructions:</strong><br /><br />The hon Finance Minister has offered sops to the affordable housing front, Mr Prajapati said and pointed out that there was a definite direction laid out in this budget towards implementing the ambitious Housing For All by 2022.<br /><br />100% tax deduction to entities constructing 30 sq mtr houses in 4 metros n 60 sq mtrs in other areas is a major booster to the affordable housing sector. Also it is probably the first time that affordable housing has been defined in terms of size n not value of flat. It seems that the Housing Industry is finally being deservedly recognized as one of the major contributor to the GDP of the nation. <br /><br />The exemption of service tax on construction of houses up to 60 sq mtr is a welcome step. This will provide relief to a section of home buyers opting for 1RK / 1BHK / small 2BHK flats. Similarly, the additional deduction of Rs 50,000 on interest payment for first home buyers on house value of upto Rs 50 lakhs is a welcome step. However it will have limited impact as it leaves out a large section of home buyers in Metro cities. <br /><br />It would have been better if the Government would have extended this additional tax exemption for homes valued at Rs 1&nbsp;crore for tax deductions in Metro cities. <br /><br />He expressed the hope that the commercial / office and retail market will benefit from REIT as tax exemption from DDT to SPVs as well as Funds will give a boost to these funds and facilitate easy flow of much needed funds.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/h/housing_budgethousing_3021_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 18:01:02</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>