<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-empowerment-over-subsidiesgood-thing-says-manish-chokani_5693981.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Empowerment over subsidies, a good thing, says Manish Chokani]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Chokani also commended the borrowing figure, which has decreased from the previous year. This he thinks would be taken positively by the bond markets. He also discussed the fiscal deficit number, which according to him is real and credible.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Speaking to CNBC TV18, Manish Chokani, Director, Enam Holdings says the empowerment of people with the schemes introduced is much better than providing them with subsidies. He is of the opinion that the budget does not have any surprises and wasn't flashy. <br /><br />Chokani also commended the borrowing figure, which has decreased from the previous year. This he thinks would be taken positively by the bond markets. He also discussed the fiscal deficit number, which according to him is real and credible.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is Manish Chokani's view on Budget 2016.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Sonia:&nbsp; How would you react to the adherence of the fiscal deficit target and also both net gross borrowing figure lower than what the street had feared, what would your reaction be?</strong><br /><br />A: I think that is the most important thing that comes out because we are living in a world which hates uncertainty and that 0.5 percent move in currency in China or tremor somewhere else in the world sets off shockwaves that go across the world. So, from that perspective the headline that India adheres to the&nbsp; path of fiscal prudence and that it sticks to the path that it wants to make business easier in India, I think that is really the headline takeaway that the world was looking for. I am glad that, that has been delivered. The fact that the fiscal deficit number is real and credible and not based on some outlandish forecast of I can collect extra revenues by higher taxes and so on and so forth hasn&rsquo;t been made.<br /><br />Also the fact that the borrowing figure is in fact lower than last year will be taken very positively by bond markets, then currency markets and eventually equity markets will get it as well.<br /><br />So, on balance&nbsp; I would think workman like Budget as was expected of the Finance Minister who is not known to be sort of flashy and swing for the fences. So, no real surprises.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: The market has been in a downtrend since the start of the year. Do you think that downtrend courtesy weak global cues will continue?</strong><br /><br />A: That is the most likely scenario. We have spoken earlier as well that the Budget is exciting on the day it comes. I don't think this is a mood changer Budget in that sense either positively or negatively. Like most governments like to reiterate that lot of the good work happens outside the Budget. I just want to make 5 or 6 points on that very quickly. If you think of this government having brought back rule based policy making that is a good thing. The fact that they have gone federal&nbsp; and introduced the Niti Aayog and introduced the 42 percent devolution to states is a good thing.<br /><br />The fact that we have gone for empowerment of people instead of sending subsidies their way and are using the Jan Dhan Yojna and the direct benefit transfer more and more is a good thing. The fact that we have got the expenditure management commission under Bimal Jalan is a good thing and we have seen better quality of expenditure.<br /><br />The fact that we have got this whole financial sector bank board reform programme under way is a good thing. So, there are good things happening in our country. A lot of good things were mentioned in the Budget and also were well known about what is happening on roads, power, railways, defence and so on. So, that is all which is going on. I understand that in a sombre global environment sometimes these things are forgotten. Specifically from the Budget I think what people were looking were has he found a way to widen the tax base and for that the biggest game changing reform I am surprised no one has mentioned a word of today is, goods and services tax (GST) and where that hangs and whether it will get through, I think that was the most substantive thing that could have positively turned sentiment. However you won't know what happens and whether Rajya Sabha passes it&nbsp; and in what timeframe.<br /><br />The second thing that people looked for was how does he get his resources&nbsp; up and the magic word of strategic sale cleverly tucked away through the Niti Aayog. Also on the banking front while the Rs 25000 crore headline number is disappointing, the fact that they said we will now think about consolidation of banks and are willing to go willing to go below 51 percent I think will be taken by investors as a big positive. Also it has opened up the gates for the private sector to clean up because literally 70 percent of the banking sector is in the ropes and is allowing someone to come out and compete better in the free market. So, that is a good thing.<br /><br />What was disappointed was the simplification of the tax code, it still read like a old sort of socialist left wing Budget where there were plethora of schemes. If you come into this scheme you get that, if you come into that scheme you get that. I am hoping if I read the fine print - of course Easwar committee he said he will accept majority of the recommendations, the Shome committee recommendations have come through. So, there is work going on. It just doesn't&nbsp; come out, manifest on Budget day. I suspect lot of us having read the finance bill will be in a better position by tomorrow. To say that India is really sticking to the path which it had promised&nbsp; and I am glad he has actually mentioned the 9 things which are the priorities for this government and really it bares the fingerprints of the Prime Minister.<br /><br />]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Arun_Jaitley_budget_FM_budget_fm_356x200_4150_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 13:32:30</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>