<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/macro-eco-survey-2016-recognise-recapitalise-resolve-reform-says-cea-to-banks_5665441.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Macro Eco Survey 2016: Recognise, recapitalise, resolve, reform, says CEA to banks]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The 2015-16 Macro-Economic Survey tabled in the Parliament on Friday, stated the need for consolidation, strategic divestment and the 4 R’s namely recognition, recapitalisation, resolution and reform to resolve the stressed assets issues plaguing the Indian public sector banking system.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The 2015-16 Macro-Economic Survey tabled in the Parliament on Friday, stated the need for consolidation, strategic divestment and the 4 R&rsquo;s namely recognition, recapitalisation, resolution and reform to resolve the stressed assets issues plaguing the Indian public sector banking system.</p>
<p>Highlighting that the trouble exists on twin balancesheets, one being corporate India and the other the banks that have lent to them, the survey pointed out that between FY10 and the first half of FY16, there has been total capital infusion of nearly Rs. 1.02 lakh crore in some banks put together.</p>
<p>What do these 4 R&rsquo;s essentially mean?</p>
<p><strong>Recognition</strong> &ndash; probe banks to recognise loans that are never going to be repaid and tag them as bad.</p>
<p><strong>Recapitalise</strong> &ndash; ensure banks get capital to the extent of bad loans that are moved out as bad loans</p>
<p><strong>Resolution</strong> &ndash; loans that are not going to be paid should be sold out. So, if a particular company owes Rs 20000 crore and its financials indicate no possible recovery then its best to sell off all available assets and recover to the extent possible.</p>
<p><strong>Reform</strong> &ndash; changing the mindset that restructuring and refinancing are not the eternal solutions and that they cannot get away with this. &nbsp;</p>
<p>To reduce pressure on banks, the Reserve Bank had earlier listed out strategic debt restructuring (SDR) and the 5:25 routes, which meant a group of banks could take over the loans of an ailing company and convert it into equity, holding over 51 percent stake, or extend the amortisation period (gradually deduct value of non-performing loans from profits), while periodically providing additional loans.<br /><br />This meant that the asset could still be classified as standard and not as non-performing.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The only setback with SDR was that the banks were required to find a new promoter for the ailing company, within a period of 18 months and divest the entire 51 percent at one go.</p>
<p>However, on Thursday, the RBI tweaked these norms stating that banks can now get asset classification benefits by divesting 26 percent. Also, the new promoter could, in no way, be connected to the original promoter.</p>
<p>Further, banks can also use joint lender forum (JLF) to revoke/cancel SDR in cases of failure of restructuring as a Corrective Action Plan (CAP).</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/b/banks_shutterstock_356x200_3505_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 17:01:50</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>