<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-social-media-abuzzwits-wisdom_5708681.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Social media abuzz with wits, wisdom]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[
The social media was flooded with comments, cartoons and jokes on the annual event. One of the posts reads that after this Budget kids will aspire to be farmers rather than going for any other profession.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>As Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today presented the Union Budget, social media sites were abuzz with millions of interesting posts from netizens.</p>
<p>Hashtags like #Budget2016, #VikasKiBudget and #UunionBudget trended throughout the day on Facebook and Twitter.</p>
<p>Cricket Commentator Harsha Bhogle tweeted, "Yes, lots of impressive words in the #Budget. Hope it isn't like my fitness plan! All intent and no execution!!" Biocon MD Kiran Mazumdar-Shaw posted, "Leap year Budget jumped but did not leap high enough! Inclusive economic growth main thrust so no surprises." Bollywood star Alia Bhatt said, "Sooo.. Leo called for action on climate change in his speech. And @arunjaitley made a case for animal welfare in his Budget speech!" Apart from celebs and business leaders, common men were also seen sharing their views on the Budget. <br /><br />The social media was flooded with comments, cartoons and jokes on the annual event. One of the posts reads that after this Budget kids will aspire to be farmers rather than going for any other profession.</p>
<p>One Prashant Navadgi posted, "FM #ArunJaitley Let us know if you find affordable hosing below 50 Lakhs in Mumbai! #UnionBudget2016 #Budget2016 #Budget." Citing Arun Jaitley's pre-poll promise of raising income tax ceiling to Rs 5 lakh another Manoj Kumar Sahu said, "#AskYourFM Kya hua tera vada, woh kasam woh irada?" Terming the Budget as farmer friendly, Sidhant Shubham of Hyderabad posted on Facebook, "...it was the current need of our country." According to tweetreach, a website that provides analytics about social media websites, the word Budget had a total impression of more than 26.63 lakh as of 19:45 hrs on Twitter.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/t/twitter_356_2811_356_2723_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 21:16:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>