<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-fiscal-deficit-target-likely-to-be-37-for-fy17-says-dbs_5621381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Fiscal deficit target likely to be 3.7% for FY17, says DBS]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[According to the global financial services major, the fiscal slippage in the next financial year would be largely due to the need to accommodate higher spending commitments, especially a bigger public sector wage/pension bill and rising banks' recapitalisation needs.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The pace of fiscal tightening is likely to slow down next fiscal, with the government's deficit target expected to be higher at 3.7 percent of GDP, says a DBS report.</p>
<p>The target for 2016-17, as per the earlier roadmap, was 3.5 percent and is likely to be pushed back.</p>
<p>According to the global financial services major, the fiscal slippage in the next financial year would be largely due to the need to accommodate higher spending commitments, especially a bigger public sector wage/pension bill and rising banks' recapitalisation needs.</p>
<p>"On the fiscal math, signs are that the FY15/16 fiscal deficit target will not be breached," DBS said in a research note, adding that the "pace of fiscal tightening is likely to slow in FY16/17, with the deficit target to be adjusted higher at 3.7 percent of GDP".</p>
<p>It said worries over bank capitalisation were revived after key public-sector banks reported a sharp jump in non performing loans and higher provisions in the December 2015 quarter.</p>
<p>The report further noted that the budget session of the Parliament, which commenced yesterday, would be crucial for investor sentiment.</p>
<p>"Any signs of a washout session will prove detrimental, in midst of foreign portfolio outflows which are down cumulative USD 2 billion so far this year, a fifth last year's total flows," the report noted.</p>
<p>Passage of key bills, including the crucial Goods and Services Tax, bankruptcy code and the real estate bill are likely to be back in focus.</p>
<p>"Indications are that these bills might yet again meet strong opposition resistance, ahead of which all-party deliberations have been on-going," the DBS research note said.</p>
<p>Markets meanwhile, would keep a close eye on the progress of the reform agenda, also before five key state elections due around April-May, it added.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Rupee_up_down_fiscal_deficit_356x200_3409_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 08:44:02</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>