<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/seeing-excess-capacity-can-livehigher-deficit-bofa-ml_5442521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Seeing excess capacity; can live with higher deficit: BofA-ML]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In an interview with CNBC-TV18, Kaku Nakhate discussed her expectations for the Union Budget said that the markets are going through a cycle where demand is there but it will take time for capacities to catch up.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The global economy is slowing down and uncertainty is likely to prevail for a while, says Kaku Nakhate, Country Head of BofA ML.</p>
<p>In an interview with CNBC-TV18, she discussed her expectations for the Union Budget said that the markets are going through a cycle where demand is there but it will take time for capacities to catch up.</p>
<p>Speaking on the steel sector she said that the minimum import price (MIP) has given companies time to re-think their strategies to bring cost efficiencies.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Kaku Nakhate&rsquo;s interview with CNBC-TV18's Ritu Singh.</strong></em><br /> <br /><strong> Q: What are your views on the current market situation?</strong><br /><br />A: Global economy is slowing down and over a year the growth rate almost like a percent is quite a large slowdown globally. Now, what it means is there are excesses elsewhere. So, you are in a time where you also have reduced your growth rate and the capacities had been built up for much higher growth rate of 9.5-10 percent. So, you are going through a cycle wherein the demand is there but it will take time to catch up on the capacities which are already existing.<br /> <br /> The other thing is also global assets are getting priced cheaply in certain sectors. So, the question now in front of any wise businessman also would be do I need to start building afresh or do I acquire. So, those discussions are also in play in many of the respects.<br /> <br /> <strong>Q: How do you see the minimum import price (MIP) that is on imported steel products, do you see that really helping the sector in the short term or do you think debt servicing for them still remains a tough challenge?</strong><br /> <br /> A: I would say floor price definitely gives them a breather in many respects and it is not just us. US also has put some embargoes.<br /> <br /> It is more like a breather I would say and I am sure even the steel companies have spent the last 12 months or more than 12 months bringing in the cost efficiencies they can. Also, your input cost which were sometimes because of higher coal auctions that would need to get corrected and the sourcing has to be done for us to be world effective even in the pricing.<br /> <br /> <strong>Q: The Union Budget is around the corner and there has been a lot of debate in the fiscal divide whether you should spend more to spur growth or curtail fiscal deficit to maintain the government's credibility, which side of the argument are you on?</strong><br /> <br /> A: I am on the point of view that we can live with a slightly higher fiscal deficit. Where the question is how much more one can afford because that has an implication on your currency which has held up reasonably well versus the dollar.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/b/bse_nse_stock_exchange_markets_356x200_0149_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-12 15:37:43</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>