<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-expect-1-2-cutcorporate-tax-says-bmrs-bobby-parikh_5624341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Expect 1-2% cut in corporate tax, says BMR's Bobby Parikh]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[To balance the books from the cut, the government will have to withdraw some incentives and benefits. But Parikh isn't sure which exemtions will be removed.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Bobby Parikh, BMR Advisors, expects a one to two percent reduction in corporate tax in the coming budget. The government had promised to bring down the corporate tax from 30 to 25 percent in four years. Having brought no change in the corporate tax rate in last year's budget, Parikh feels that this year would bring a small cut in the tax.&nbsp; <br /><br />To balance the books from the cut, the government will have to withdraw some incentives and benefits. But Parikh isn't sure which exemptions will be removed.<br /><br />Talking about the current tax laws, Parikh said that the tax laws are not very complicated, but rather it is the administration of these tax laws that are convoluted and urgently need reform. But he doesn't see any changes in the near future.<br /><br />When asked whether there is any way put an end to the retro tax, Parikh says that the only opportunity to easily abandon the retroactive tax was in this government's first budget in 2014. He admits that there is hardly any chance now to put it behind.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Bobby Parikh's interview with Latha Venkatesh, Anuj Singhal &amp; Guest Editor Nirmal Jain on CNBC-TV18.<br /><br /></strong></em> <strong>Nirmal: With our Indian tax laws are very complex and procedures are also very complex and cumbersome and our fraternity of chartered accountants make a living out of it, they must be happy that things haven&rsquo;t changed much in last two years. What do you say?</strong><br /><br />A: In my mind, more than the complication and the tax laws, it is the administration of the tax laws, which is where the real reform has to happen and so yes, it is a difficult system and it is something in which, at least at this point in time, change is not apparent.<br /> <br /> <strong>Nirmal: How do you think retro tax issues can be put behind in a fair way which is fair to the nation also and fair to tax payers also? What would be your suggestion on that?</strong><br /> <br /> A: I think that the opportunity to deal with this should have been in the first Budget of the government, of the current government because there were cases that were already live on the basis of a retroactive amendment of the income tax law, which was made in 2012. They could have said that we don&rsquo;t believe in these retroactive amendments and we want to abandon this and we want to drop whatever is there and whatever is the change in law that was made, we will apply it prospectively.<br /> <br /> So that opportunity is gone and the formulations that they came up with was to say that okay, whatever is live it will go through the court system or whatever is the process that is required by law to get it to a resolution, but we will be very careful about creating any new cases which apply this law retroactively. So that there is nothing that we add to the kitty than what is already there. If there is anything to be added, they have left it vague but they said that there will be a committee which will review before anything happens and things like that.<br /><br />So now the thing is that, every time that we talk about Vodafone and whatever is happening with Vodafone now that is not something that the government ever said that they are not going to pursue or that it will not go through some process because that is the position that they have taken. So that is what it is.<br /><br />As far as new stuff is concerned, there is not a whole lot which is added and anyway now if things don&rsquo;t get added and they sort of make some kind of a commitment that they are not going to add new things then retroactivity will become academic with the passage of time itself because then the law will apply to transactions, which are prospective rather than anything which is retroactive.<br /><br /><strong>Nirmal: Let us come to what we expect from the Budget. Do you expect any cut in corporate tax rate and removal of exemptions along with that and the second question is where market is fearing that long-term capital gains (LTCG) may be diluted in one-year time period required for exemption maybe increased to three years. What is your view on this, in terms do you expect these things to happen and whether they are desirable or avoidable at this point in time?</strong><br /><br />A: On the corporate tax rate, I feel like there should be some reduction and there was a four-year passage that he was going to set out, one year is already gone, he didn&rsquo;t do anything so now he has got three years to bring it down from 30 to the targeted 25.<br /><br />So, I would imagine that they will want to do that in a graded manner and not do it one short or something like that. So I would reasonably accept that we would see a percentage or two percentage cut so that intention is then starting to manifest into action and then there is a path which is then set out for how it will get to 25.<br /><br />To balance the book, he has to start removing some of the incentives for which the CBDT had published a small white paper indicating what directionally they were thinking of doing. So, I would expect that again some of that gets more -- to the extent that it has to be written into law, it starts getting written into law and beyond that, things are more clearly articulated in a speech in terms of what the intent is in terms of how they will move from 30 to 25 and what they will do with the incentives and the benefits and how they will be withdrawn because all we have so far is a white paper but it was more a discussion paper rather than a firm view of the government in terms of how they are going to navigate.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: What are the likely exemptions that will go?</strong><br /><br />A: I think that at least CBDT white paper seems to suggest that all the action will happen in the year-ending March 2017. So we are in 2016-2017. So I don&rsquo;t know what of the elements they are looking to withdraw or they might withdraw during 2016-2017 itself but otherwise at least what the paper seem to suggest was that they were putting people on notice that is how we would like to do it. So plan for that as best as you can.<br /><br />The LTCG -- I don&rsquo;t know, it is difficult to say whether it is going to happen or not happen, only the government will know but I would think that it would be unhelpful to have such a construct given everything that we are experiencing. I don&rsquo;t know that hurting investor sentiment or hurting their profitability is something which is appropriate.<br /><br />This sort of goes against -- another alternate line of discussion or rumours or speculations, which were doing the rounds not so much in the recent past but earlier was that all capital gains will be replaced only by STT and there will be no capital gains tax at all. So now, that was one sort of extreme in a way and this is going the other direction. For short-term for unlisted shares they had already made it three years last year. So I think to make that same for listed shares is not something that is desirable.<br /><br /><strong>Nirmal: Is tax department getting little more aggressive offlate in issuing notices?&nbsp; What is your experience with your clients?</strong><br /><br />A: I think that towards the end of the year, some of these things happen because they have to try and make the numbers and so at least anecdotally, I hear that there are all kinds of action which scattered across the country, things are happening. So I don&rsquo;t know that, that is anything which is particularly unique to what we are experiencing this year.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/c/CorporateTax_356x200_1204_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 12:53:42</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>