<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/non-tax-based-budget-recommendations-by-fisme-to-fm_5117741.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Non-tax based budget recommendations by FISME to FM]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Increasingly, MSMEs’ inability to access non-fund based finance is rendering them uncompetitive against both large and foreign suppliers even for projects in India.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Operationalizing Kamath Committee recommendation for sale-purchase of MSME bills</strong></p>
<p>To provide succor to fund starved MSMEs, setting up of an online platform for discounting of their supply bills as suggested by Kamath Committee may beexpedited. To make it purposeful, it is necessary that the invoices are uploadedmandatorily and status of deemed acceptance is granted to them to convert theminto negotiable financial instruments. This will not only provide much neededliquidity to MSMEs but will also usher in financial discipline in corporate andPSUs which is equally important for the country&rsquo;s financial system.</p>
<ul>
<li>Suggestion:</li>
</ul>
<p>Expediting the online platform and providing legislative backing to upload theinvoices mandatory on buyers and grant status of deemed acceptance enablingthem convert these into negotiable financial instruments.</p>
<p><strong>Public spending : Ensuring accounting standards among recipient entities</strong></p>
<p>As mentioned earlier public procurement comprises almost 1/3 of India&rsquo;s GDP.By having a direct control through buying on almost a third of goods and serviceproduced in the country, Governments exercise enormous influence on thebehaviour of economic actors of all hues. Utilities &ndash;water, electricity Boards etc,are among the largest buyers. Though these utilities are expected to run oncommercial terms, their accounting systems and their inventory managementsystems are obsolete which allow a lot of unscrupulous practices to take place.</p>
<p>While on the one hand, it results into enormous financial leakages, on the otherhand such a devious system encourages inefficient firms and crowd-out efficientones. This, many experts warn, in the long term lead to hollowing out ofmanufacturing in India as efficient firms may go out of business leaving theinefficient ones who also would not be able to withstand global competition.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suggestion:</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Central funds/ assistance ought not to go the utilities/ agencies engaged inproviding services commercially but not having:</p>
<ol>
<li>double entry accounting system</li>
<li>100% computerization of Inventory with IT based management systems.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;<strong>Investment multiplier: Offsets for MSMEs in all Public funded infrastructureprojects above a threshold</strong></p>
<p>The Government is making massive public investment- over few lac crores, ininfrastructure- Roads, Ports, Airports, Railways, Power, Smart Cities etc. Theimpact of the investment could be further multiplied if suitable offset clause couldbe introduced to ensure that a pie of this investment flows to MSMEs- the biggestemployment generator.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suggestion</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>It would give a great fillip to creation of employment if an Offset clause isintroduced in all centrally funded projects beyond a threshold say of Rs. 500crore that say 20% of procurement would be done from MSMEs.</p>
<p><strong>Filling gap in Project Financing: Reviving State Financial Corporation torealize Make in India</strong></p>
<p>The State Financial Corporations are rightly credited for the creation of first waveof MSME entrepreneurship in the country through 60s and 70s. These institutionsspecialized in Project Financing having built capabilities in appraising projects&rsquo;viability both technically, commercially and financially. The institutions sufferedbecause of host of reasons and have become defunct over the years. However,no alternative mechanism appeared in their place. Banks were expected to fillthis gap but they failed miserably as they have neither competency at branchlevel nor the risk assessing capability needed for financing projects especially inMSME sector. It is because of this reason that in spite of all possible policymeasures and coaxing from the Government and the RBI, the lending theMSME sector as percentage of total lending has been consistently coming down.</p>
<p>It has increasingly become arduous for a first generation entrepreneur to set-up amanufacturing unit with bank&rsquo;s assistance. That is why only a few manufacturingunits are coming in the MSMEs sector.</p>
<p>Having realized the criticality of reviving State Electricity Boards to set the Powersector right, the Government has come about on recapitalizing them through aslew of innovating measures. Similarly, instead of brushing aside the suggestionimmediately, there is a need to look at the SFCs with a fresh perspective. Theycan be one of the most important pillars in realizing the Make in India missionand may help set-up millions of MSMEs in manufacturing. Their presence inalmost all major towns, having the backing of the State governments- critical tomake units successful in the States, and a refinancing mechanism throughSIDBI, makes them attractive FIs.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suggestion</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>A high level committee needs to be set-up to look at reviving the SFCs and alsoexploring possibility of initiating similar institutions in PPP or Private mode.</p>
<p><strong>Non-Fund Based Finance: Constricting MSMEs&rsquo; participation in tenderingbusiness</strong></p>
<p>MSMEs need both fund based (loans, working capital etc) and non-fund basedfinancial instruments (bid-bonds, bank guarantees, Letter of Credit etc).</p>
<p>Increasingly, MSMEs&rsquo; inability to access non-fund based finance is renderingthem uncompetitive against both large and foreign suppliers even for projects inIndia. Banks treat fund based and non-fund based financial products alike andclub them together to calculate eligibility for extent of credit limits and alsoquantum of collateral required. (Distinction needs to be made among variousnon-fund based products such as earnest money- which hardly carries a risk andperformance guarantee which may have a risk element).</p>
<p>As in a highly competitive bidding process, one has to bid for more and moreprojects to increase one&rsquo;s chances, MSMEs cannot even bid because their limitsget exhausted soon in bid-bonds, bank-grantees and performance guarantees.</p>
<p>There is a need to expand MSMEs&rsquo; access to non-fund based finance. Itsimportance is further increased in view of the Public Procurement Policy whichmandates 20% procurement by Central agencies from MSEs. Inability to accessadequate and competitively priced non-fund based finance is becoming a newentry barrier for MSMEs in market access.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suggestion:</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Firstly, there is a need to distinguish between fund-based and non-fund basedlimits and a special dispensation needs to be allowed for MSMEs (PSU banksbegin this straight away).</p>
<p>Secondly, entry of Insurance companies may be allowed to provide non-fundbased guarantees to create competition in the market which would bring downpricing of these products. (Earlier Insurance companies were allowed to offerBGs but the policy was discontinued later. The matter may be quickly examinedas to why was it discontinued. With the insurance sector having matured nowwith a functional regulator, the same issue could be looked at with a fresh pair ofeyes.)</p>
<p><strong><em>Courtesy FISME</em></strong></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/a/arunjaitley_5143_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-22 10:58:25</Entry_Date><Category>SME</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>