<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/dicci-says-proposed-scst-hub-to-play-matchmaker-for-them_5699101.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Dicci says proposed SC/ST Hub to play matchmaker for them]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Milind Kamble further said the proposed hub will play the role of "match-maker" between the government agencies who place orders and the suppliers, so that the former cannot complain about not having access to enterprises floated by the Backward Classes people.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The National Scheduled Castes and Scheduled Tribes Hub announced in the Budget completes the Backward Class entrepreneurs' ecosystem and will play the role of a "match-maker" between the government and businessmen, the Dalit India Chamber of Commerce and Industry (Dicci) has said.</p>
<p>"In the past, we have had a venture capital funds, a credit enhancement mechanism and changes in procurement policies. The National Scheduled Castes and Scheduled Tribes Hub announced today completes the ecosystem for Dalit entrepreneurs and now the challenge is before the businessmen to make most of this opportunity," Dicci founder and chairman Milind Kamble told PTI.</p>
<p>"We are celebrating the 125th birth anniversary of BR Ambedkar. This must become the year of economic empowerment for SC/ST entrepreneurs," Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said, announcing the hub in his Budget speech.</p>
<p>Milind Kamble further said the proposed hub will play the role of "match-maker" between the government agencies who place orders and the suppliers, so that the former cannot complain about not having access to enterprises floated by the Backward Classes people.</p>
<p>He explained that in 2012, the government had announced amendments in its procurement policies, under which 4 percent of the overall orders by the government and public sector undertakings were to be sourced from SC and ST entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>However, only 0.5 percent of the orders are placed with the target group and the government arms frequently complain of not being able to spot Backward Class entrepreneurs, which the hub shall address, Kamble added.</p>
<p>A mention of the promise to serve 1.25 lakh Backward Class entrepreneurs by making bank credit accessible in the Budget is also a big positive.</p>
<p>Kamble said investments of over Rs 150 crore have been committed or proposed in 76 companies by a IFCI-managed venture capital fund for enterprises promoted by the Dalits.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget12_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 16:16:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>