<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-india-centre-to-provide-rs-1-lakh-per-family-health-cover_5696801.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 India: Centre to provide Rs 1 lakh per family health cover]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In the back drop of emergence of around 2.2 lakh patients of End Stage Renal Disease in India every year and resulting in additional demand for 3.4 crore dialysis sessions, the government will also initiate a National Dialysis Services Programme to provide dialysis services in all district hospitals.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Centre will launch a new health protection scheme under which a cover up to Rs one lakh per family will be provided bedsides opening around 3,000 medical stores across the country to provide quality medicines at affordable prices.</p>
<p>In the back drop of emergence of around 2.2 lakh patients of End Stage Renal Disease in India every year and resulting in additional demand for 3.4 crore dialysis sessions, the government will also initiate a National Dialysis Services Programme to provide dialysis services in all district hospitals.</p>
<p>"A serious illness of family member(s) causes severe stress on the financial condition of poor and economically weak families, shaking the foundation of their economic security.</p>
<p>"In order to help such families, the government will launch a new health protection scheme which will provide health cover up to rupees one lakh per family," Union Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said while unveiling the Budget 2016-17 in Parliament today.</p>
<p>He said that for senior citizens, who are 60 years of age and above, an additional top-up package up to Rs 30,000 will be provided.</p>
<p>Observing that making quality medicines available at affordable prices has been a "key challenge", Jaitley said the government will "reinvigorate" the supply of generic drugs by opening 3,000 stores under Prime Minister Jan Aushadhi Yojna.</p>
<p>"Making quality medicines available at affordable prices has been a key challenge. We will reinvigorate the supply of generic drugs. 3,000 stores under Prime Minister's Jan Aushadhi Yojana will be opened during 2016-17," he said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/d/drugs_pharma_healthcare_budget2016_2016_356x200_4909_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 15:02:11</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>