<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/railways-signs-mouandhra-kerala-for-project-execution_5176361.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Railways signs MoU with Andhra, Kerala for project execution]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The JV companies will have 51 percent stake of the respective state governments and 49 percent stake of the railways. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>For infrastructure development, the railways today signed MoUs with Kerala and Andhra Pradesh governments for formation of joint venture companies to ensure faster implementation of rail projects in the respective states.<br /><br /> The JV companies will have 51 percent stake of the respective state governments and 49 percent stake of the railways. <br /><br />"It is always necessary to have partnership with state governments and we have declared it in our Rail Budget," said Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu at the MoU signing ceremony here.</p>
<p>In view of the growing demands for railway lines in various states and huge requirement of funds to execute them, JV companies will be now responsible for identifying projects, land acquisition and possible financing in addition to government funding and also monitoring. <br /><br />Describing the JV arrangement with states as "cooperative federalism", Prabhu said, "We will have this with 17 states. We have decided to work together. It is a unique idea to enter into JVs with state governments for project implementation." <br /><br />As per the plan, project specific SPV (special purpose vehicle) will be formed to execute a project under the JV arrangement. Earlier, Odisha and Maharashtra had signed similar agreements with the railways to execute projects in their respective states.<br /><br /> Referring to the railways mega plan of developing 400 stations, Prabhu said this will generate financial resources for the public transporter and this will benefit the country.</p>
<p>Many states governments, including in Andhra Pradesh and Kerala, are keen to develop a few stations in their states, he said. Making a comparision with road sector, Prabhu said, "Large investments have gone into the roads, far exceeding that in the railways.<br /><br /> More traffic has gone to roads at the expense of the railways." Prabhu also advocated multi-modal transportation system in which road sector and the railways must work together to help passengers.</p>
<p>"Unless we work together the multi-modal transportation system cannot go further. We have written to 17 states about this," he said. <br /><br />Railway Board Member (Staff) Pradeep Kumar said formation of JV companies with the states will go a long way in faster commissioning of critical rail infrastructure projects as it will facilitate various clearances and land acquisition.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/e/engine_indian_railways_trains_railway_budget_2015__356x200_0957_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-27 18:10:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>