<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/read-textfm-arun-jaitleys-budget-2016-speechlok-sabha_5694461.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Read: Text of FM Arun Jaitley's Budget 2016 speech in Lok Sabha]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Read Arun Jaitley's full Budget speech in Lok Sabha]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today presented 2016-17 Union Budget in Lok Sabha. Read Jaitley's full speech in attached PDF document.<br /><br />
<p>Madam Speaker,</p>
<p>I rise to present the Budget for the year 2016 -17.<br /><br />I am presenting this Budget when the global economy is in serious crisis. Global growth has slowed down from 3.4% in 2014 to 3.1% in 2015. Financial markets have been battered and global trade has contracted. Amidst all these global headwinds, the Indian economy has held its ground firmly. Thanks to our inherent strengths and the policies of this Government, a lot of confidence and hope continues to be built around India.<br /><br />The International Monetary Fund has hailed India as a &lsquo;bright spot&rsquo; amidst a slowing global economy. The World Economic Forum has said that India&rsquo;s growth is &lsquo;extraordinarily high&rsquo;. We accomplished this despite very unfavourable conditions and despite the fact that we inherited an economy of low growth, high inflation and zero investor confidence in Government&rsquo;s capability to govern. We converted these difficulties and challenges into opportunities.<br /><br />Let us look at our achievements compared to the last three years of the previous Government when growth had decelerated to 6.3%. The growth of GDP has now accelerated to 7.6%. This was possible notwithstanding the contraction of global exports by 4.4% compared to 7.7% growth in world exports during the last three years of the previous Government. CPI inflation was at 9.4% during the last three years of the previous Government. Under our Government, CPI inflation has come down to 5.4%, providing big relief to the public. This was accomplished despite two consecutive years of monsoon shortfall of 13%, compared to normal rainfall in the last three years of the previous Government.<br /><br />Our external situation is robust. The Current Account deficit has declined from 18.4 billion US dollars in the first half of last year to 14.4 billion this year. It is projected to be 1.4% of GDP at the end of this year. Our foreign exchange reserves are at the highest ever level of about 350 billion US dollars.<br /><br />Our initiatives in the last 21 months have not only placed the economy on A faster growth trajectory but have bridged the trust deficit, created by the previous Government. We had to work in an unsupportive global environment, adverse weather conditions and an obstructive political atmosphere.<br /><br />We believe in the principle that money with the Government belongs to the people and we have the sacred responsibility to spend it prudently and wisely for the welfare of our people, especially the poor and the downtrodden. We have increased our Plan expenditure at the RE stage in 2015-16 in contrast to the usual practice of reducing it. We achieved this despite adopting the Fourteenth Finance Commission recommendations which increased devoluti on to the States by 55%.<br /><br />We must now look ahead. The risks of further global slowdown and turbulence are mounting. This complicates the task of economic management for India. It has three serious implications for us. First, we must strengthen our firewalls against these risks by ensuring macro-economic stability and prudent fiscal management. Second, since foreign Markets are weak, we must rely on domestic demand and Indian markets to ensure that India&rsquo;s growth does not slow down. And third, we must continue with the pace of economic reforms and policy initiatives to change the lives of our people for the better.<br /><br />We see these challenges as opportunities. The financial years 2015-16 and 2016-17 have been and will be extremely challenging for Government expenditure. The 14<sup>th</sup> Finance Commission has reduced the Central share of taxes to 58% from the 68%. In the financial year 2015-16, we managed to improve upon the budgeted expenditure due to revenue buoyancy, notwithstanding the steep reduction in The Central share of taxes. The next financial year 2016-17 will cast an additional burden on account of the recommendations of the 7<sup>th</sup> Central Pay Commission and the implementation of Defence OROP. The Government, therefore, has to prioritise its expenditure. We wish to enhance expenditure in the farm and rural sector, the social sector, the infrastructure sector and provide for 31 where there is misreporting of facts. Remission of penalty is also proposed in certain circumstances where taxes are paid and appeal is not filed.<br /><br />Another issue which has led to considerable number of disputes is quantification of disallowance of expenditure relatable to exempt income in terms of Section 14A of the Income Tax Act. I propose to rationalize the formula in Rule 8D governing such quantification. The said Rule is being amended to provide that disallowance will be limited to 1% of the average monthly value of investments yielding exempt income, but not exceeding the actual expenditure claimed.</p>
<br />Another issue which has led to considerable number of disputes is quantification of disallowance of expenditure relatable to exempt income in terms of Section 14A of the Income Tax Act. I propose to rationalize the formula in Rule 8D governing such quantification. The said Rule is being amended to provide that disallowance will be limited to 1% of the average monthly value of investments yielding exempt income, but not exceeding the actual expenditure claimed.<br /><br />As another tax payer friendly measure, I propose to provide a time limit of one year for disposing petitions of the tax payers seeking waiver of interest and penalty.<br /><br />The Income- tax Department is also issuing instruction making it mandatory for the assessing officer to grant stay of demand once the assesse pays 15% of the disputed demand, while the appeal is pending before Commissioner of Income- tax (Appeals). In case of deviation, assessing officer has to get orders of his superiors. The tax payer also has an option to go to superior officer in case he does not agree with conditions of stay order passed by the subordinate officer<br /><br />In order to remove backlog of cases we are creating 11 new benches of Customs, Excise and Service Tax Appellate Tribunal (CESTAT).<br /><br />The monetary limit for deciding an appeal by a single member Bench of ITAT is proposed to be enhanced from Rs 15 lakhs to Rs 50 lakhs.<br /><br />I also propose to amend the CENVAT Credit Rules, 2004, so as to improve credit flow, reduce the compliance burden and associated litigation, particularly those relating to apportionment of credit between exempted and non exempted final products/ services. The amendments in these rules will also enable manufacturers with multiple manufacturing units to maintain a common warehouse for inputs and distribute inputs w ith credits to the individual manufacturing units. Simplification and rationalization of taxation.<br /><br />The Government has already accepted many recommendations of Tax Administration Reform Committee and I propose to accept a number of recommendations of Justice Easwar Committee in this Budget.<br /><br />To reduce multiplicity of taxes, associated cascading and to reduce cost of collection, I propose to abolish 13 cesses, levied by various Ministries in which revenue collection is less than Rs 50 crore in a year<br /><br />To improve the cash flow position of small tax payers who get their funds blocked due to current TDS provision, I propose to rationalize TDS provisions for Income Tax as per Annexure.
<p>Non-residents without PAN are currently subjected to a higher rate of TDS. It is proposed to amend the relevant provision to provide that on furnishing of alternative documents, the higher rate will not apply.</p>
<p>The facility for revision of return, hitherto available to a service tax assessee only, is being extended to Central Excise assessees also.</p>
<p>I propose to provide additional options to banking companies and financial institutions, including non- banking financial companies, for reversal of input tax credits with respect to non-taxable services provided by them by way of extending deposits, loans and advances.</p>
<p>Our Government has taken a number of steps to reduce the cargo release time and the transaction costs of EXIM trade. I propose to amend the Customs Act to provide for deferred payment of customs duties for importers and exporters with proven track record.</p>
<p>In 2014-15 Budget, I had announced the intent to implement Indian Customs Single Window Project. We have made significant progress in this and it would be implemented at major ports and airports starting from beginning of next financial year.</p>
<p>The customs Baggage Rules for international passengers are being simplified so as to increase the free baggage allowance. The filing of baggage declaration will be required only for those passengers who carry dutiable goods. Use of Technology for creating accountability</p>
<p>Technology is a boon for mankind. We plan to use technology in taxation Department in a big way to make life simpler for a law abiding citizen, and also for data mining to track tax evaders.</p>
<p>A pilot was run in 2015-16 for e-assessment to obviate the requirement for tax payers to visit the Income - tax offices. I propose to expand the scope of e-assessments to all assessees in 7 mega cities in the coming years.</p>
<p>The cases selected for scrutiny will be scrutinized in e-environment whereby unless the assessee himself wants to be heard, or for special reasons to be recorded, the assessing officer wants to hear the party, there will be no face to face contact of IT Department with assessee.</p>
<p>Income- tax Department (ITD) will fully expand the pilot initiative of &lsquo;e-Sahyog&rsquo; with a view to reduce compliance cost, especially for small 33 taxpayers. The objective of the &lsquo;e-Sahyog&rsquo; pilot project is to provide an online mechanism to resolve mismatches in Income-tax returns without requiring taxpayers to attend the Income - tax office.</p>
<p>I propose that in matters pertaining to Income- tax Act, Government will pay interest at the rate of 9% p.a against normal rate of 6% p.a in case there is delay in giving effect to Appellate order beyond ninety days. The officers who delay it, will be accountable for this loss to Government.</p>
<p>I also propose to change the procedure to provide for a shift from physical control to record based control for customs bonded w arehouses, supported by sophisticated IT systems.</p>
<p>Madam Speaker, my direct tax proposals would result in revenue loss of Rs&nbsp; 1,060 crore and my indirect proposals are expected to yield Rs 20,670 crores. Thus the net impact of all tax proposals would be revenue gain of Rs 19,610 crores.</p>
<p><strong>CONCLUSION</strong></p>
<p>Madam Speaker,</p>
<p>This Budget is being presented amidst global and domestic headwinds. There are several challenges. We see them as opportunities. I have outlined the agenda of our Government to &lsquo;Transform India&rsquo; for the benefit of the farmers, the poor and the vulnerable.</p>
<p>Madam Speaker, it is said that &ldquo;Champions are made from something</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/n/Narendra_Modi_Arun_jaitley_budget2016_FM_356x200_3920_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 13:54:48</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>