<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/see-20-earnings-growthfy17-idfc-securities_5715441.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[See 20% earnings growth in FY17: IDFC Securities]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Anish Damania, CEO & Head - Institutional Equities at IDFC Securities says boost to urban income via the 7th Pay Commission and OROP will be a positive for sales growth.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Union Budget 2016 has majorly focused on income trends of people, says Anish Damania, CEO &amp; Head - Institutional Equities at IDFC Securities. <br /><br />Boost to urban income via the 7th Pay Commission and OROP will be a positive for sales growth, he says. Damania expects corporate earnings to be near 20 percent in FY17. <br /><br />Damania further sees a sales growth of 9 percent and 15 percent growth in FY17. <br /><br />He is bullish on sectors like consumer discretionary, staple, infra sector, oil &amp; gas and automobile. Oil &amp; gas sector is expected to benefit from no imposition on customs duty, he says. <br /> <br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Anish Damania's interview with Reema Tendulkar &amp; Anuj Singhal on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Reema: Do you think the Budget has done enough for our market to reverse its recent underperformance and how do you forecast the market now?</strong><br /><br />A: We have never looked at the Budget from the point of view of reversing a trend which shows up over the past few months and that has not been the case on most occasions. It has caused the blip plus or minus following the Budget sometime but the overall trend remains similar. <br /><br />What we will change at trend is an expectation that earnings should start growing and this Budget for the first time is looking at incomes. So while it has given boost to urban incomes in the form of the Seventh Pay Commission and One Rank One Pension (OROP). <br /><br />It has also given boost to rural incomes for the first time over the last two years by giving more allocations to the rural development programmes and agricultural and relied activities. So, what I see is that this Budget has focused on the income trends of people and rural which was lagging so far in terms of income growth is now getting that boost from this Budget. <br /><br />So I believe that the expectation of sales growth now coming through over the next 9-12 months, I am more positive in that direction, so while we have an earnings growth target of about 20 percent odd for FY17 with a sales growth target of about 9 percent. I think that could be achieved now.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: You did say that Budgets don't change the market direction. In that sense would you say that even this rally would be sold into or do you think the equity market, anyway, could be at the cusp of turnaround and maybe Budget was just incidental?</strong><br /><br />A: That is where I am coming from. If the allocation towards emerging markets (EMs) continue to reduce and global factors continue to keep playing out for the next six months maybe the trend will not reverse itself. However, given the fact that the trend is a slave of the earnings growth which have been disappointing so far and have caused continue downgrades over the last six months as well. <br /><br />However, what I feel is that if the downgrades turn into great cycle then we will reverse. So Budget would have acted as a catalyst for doing that and that is something which will reverse the trend, is what I am trying to point out. <br /><br /><strong>Reema: Do you think infrastructure cess, which has been imposed on passenger vehicles, will slowdown the auto sector growth and therefore that is a sector we should perhaps avoid for the time being?</strong><br /><br />A: The way I look at it is that there have been considerable savings from raw material cost declines and that is something which I feel will help absorb this increases which we have seen. <br /><br />Since it is a pass-through and I am assuming that urban incomes are continuing to grow and rural incomes are now continuing to grow. I think it could be an easy pass on for most of the auto companies as well without hurting the demand trajectory too much at this point of time.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Which are the areas of market where you are constructive right now. Which are the kinds of stocks that you would want to buy now?</strong><br /><br />A: Since this has given an income boost and consumption boost, so most of the discretionary consumption stories look good to me now. The staple stories also look good to me because they have not performed. <br /><br />However, what also looks good to me is some of the infrastructure stories because this Budget has - while restricting the capital expenditure growth to only 4 percent, they have targeted specific areas like roads and railways. So in case of roads the entire construction sector and the road sector is expected to do well. We are also bullish on oil and gas space, the upstream companies. <br /><br />There we feel that since the Budget is status quo and has not hiked any import duties and stocks had come off quite a lot on the back of expectation and given the fact that earnings growth continues to remain very strong in the oil and gas companies, oil and gas companies are the ones which are likely to benefit and autos and agricultural stocks also could benefit from growth in urban and rural demand stories.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_economy_growth_GDP_356x200_2811_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 12:08:22</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>