<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/rail-budget-2016-the-rail-ministers-efforts-to-reform-ircommendable_5659221.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Rail Budget 2016: 'The Rail Minister's efforts to reform IR are commendable']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Nalin Jain, President and CEO, South Asia, GE Transportation and Aviation, feels the Railway Minister has moved forward on the roadmap announced last year and finds the Rail Budget 2016 to be quite progressive]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<div>Expectations were pretty high from Union Minister of Railways Suresh Prabhu on the Rail Budget. Largely, the Rail Budget 2016 has been appreciated and well-received. While, the general public heaved a sigh of relief because of no hikes in rail fares and augmentation of services. The private sector was appreciative of the budget, for its impetus to infrastructure and investment. <strong>Nalin Jain</strong>, President and CEO, South Asia, GE Transportation and Aviation, feels that the current Rail Budget is a step in the right direction, especially in regards to the way the Rail Minister has laid emphasis on building infrastructure and working with the private sector. He shares his thoughts and reasons in an exclusive interaction with <strong>Shashwat DC</strong>, Features Editor, moneycontrol. Excerpts:&nbsp;</div>
<div>
<div><strong>There have been a comprehensive announcement on revamping the freight business of the railways, what according to you are the key takeaways?<br /><br /></strong>Talking about the freight business, I think the most pertinent point that the Minister made in the Rail Budget was related to increasing the revenues by exploring new business models while rationalising the tariff structure. He seems to be specifically looking to increase operational efficiencies of the rolling stock thus reducing the costs to an extent that it should absorb the financial stress that the sector is currently experiencing.<br /><br />The plan to achieve an operating ratio of 92% in the coming fiscal is a clear indication that the Railway Ministry is seriously looking forward to additional revenue mobilisation by expanding the freight basket and attracting private participation through the PPP route.<br /><br />The Minister has tried to establish a fine balance between the long-term and mid-term infrastructure projects. Announcing three new DFCs is an encouraging proposition from a standpoint of boosting business activity going ahead. DFCs, once fully operational, will also benefit the passengers by allowing more trains to run between stations on different routes apart from adding speed to the overall freight traffic. The announcement to increase the speed of freight trains to 50 km/hr will certainly going to make a huge impact in getting IR&rsquo;s share back from the road transport.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div><strong>Your views on the announcement of 3 new DFC projects, keeping in mind the long delay on the already announced ones?<br /><br /></strong></div>
<div>The Rail Minister&rsquo;s efforts to reform the Indian Railways (IR), which has suffered under-investment in the last two decades, are commendable. The transformative steps announced and implemented by the Railway Ministry will certainly give an impetus to the overall growth of the sector.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>The 2020 vision of the minister clearly defines the special package to improve the freight ecosystem in India thus getting fresh revenue streams for IR. Looking holistically we can say that the INR 8.5 lac crore of overall investment announced last year include a significant chunk of the DFCs that will be developed in due course of time. The three new DFCs will help IR to get more revenues in the long term and align well with the &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo; strategy.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div><strong>The budget talks about technological upgradation of the Rail Infrastructure, from the load-bearing to increase in speeds, how well have they been addressed?</strong></div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>Certainly technology will have a significant role-play in upgrading the Rail Infrastructure and the Railway Minister has clearly defined the areas where digital innovations will be harnessed to improve the services. Whether it&rsquo;s related to passenger services like ticketing or managing of assets and network optimisation, it presents a large opportunity for the industry. This will become an exciting space in the coming year as India Railways plans to work upon several such initiatives.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div><strong>Are you happy with the infrastructure announcements made (like tapping LIC for funds)? Are they good enough to take us to the next level?</strong></div>
<div><br />The Minister talked about initiating about 139 projects that were announced last year. This gives us the confidence that the projects are being planned and are reaching the execution stage at a faster pace than expected. To revamp the vast <br />network of Indian Railways we need huge investment opportunities and a concerted effort by the industry stakeholders.<br /><br />For instance, as reiterated by the Minister, the state-of-the- art locomotive <br />manufacturing facilities in Bihar will usher a new wave of modernization by generating employment and socio-economic development opportunities in the region. These projects will set a new benchmark for technology efficiency and maintenance. We certainly need more of such decision making to augment the overall infrastructural set-up of IR in the near term.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div><strong>There was lot of expectation from the Minister that this will be a reformist budget; do you think it is so?<br /><br /></strong></div>
<div>The Railway Minister has moved forward on the roadmap announced last year to rejuvenate Indian Railways (IR). Of the outlay of INR 8.5 lac crore overall investment announced last year, INR 1.21 lac crore investment has been announced for the coming year. In the coming years, as part of the Rail Ministry&rsquo;s phase-wise approach we will certainly see the impact of the stringent policy decisions that have been taken in the past.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div><strong>If you had to pick out 3 highlights of the 2016 Rail budget, what would they be?<br /><br /></strong></div>
<div>The Rail Budget has crafted out multiple measures to instill the confidence in the industry that IR continues to be the best mode of transport when it comes to speed and efficiency. In my opinion, special emphasis on improving the efficiency of the freight system without increasing the pricing and generating new revenue streams will automatically better the finances of Railways.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>Secondly, to ensure faster decision making and implementation of the policies the Minister discussed about restructuring of the board and creation of cross directorates.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>And lastly, investing into technological upgradation of the railway fleet and the network to meet the global standards will certainly help IR to move forward and provide a better experience to its customers.</div>
</div>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/n/nalin_4711_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 11:45:40</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>