<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/railways-to-tap-autofmcg-sectorsbig-way_5546321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Railways to tap auto and FMCG sectors in big way]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Currently, railways mainly carries commodities such as coal, iron ore, steel, cement, minerals, fertilisers and food grains.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Facing a decline in loadings demand, railways is mulling various options including entering into untapped areas like auto and FMCG to increase freight revenue.</p>
<p>"The need of the hour is to enter new areas to expand the freight operation in a significant way," said a senior Railway Ministry official, adding, "The aim is to enter into untapped areas." Some of the proposals, including tapping automobile and FMCG sectors in a big way, are likely to come up in Rail Budget 2016-17.</p>
<p>Currently, railways mainly carries commodities such as coal, iron ore, steel, cement, minerals, fertilisers and food grains.</p>
<p>However, there are no demands for steel, cement and coal due the various reasons. Food grains loadings were also affected due to change in the policy.</p>
<p>"So we have to look for new areas potential sectors like tapping the automobile and FMCG sectors in a big way. In fact we have listed about 46 commodities where we can explore doing business," he said.</p>
<p>He said door-to-door transportation of goods using road railers is being actively considered. Road railers are capable of movement on road and rail.</p>
<p>Railways' trial run for the road railers is over and the road railers service will be introduced on the Delhi-Chennai route.</p>
<p>Reaching out to industry in the run up to Rail Budget, railways has undertaken series of talks with stakeholders seeking their suggestions to arrest the declining freight operation.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/l/luggage_maal_gaadi_trains_railway_budget_2015__356x200_1448_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-18 16:38:04</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>