<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/macro-economic-survey-2016-not-just-jobs-good-jobs-needed-to-reap-demographic-dividend_5661321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Macro Economic Survey 2016: Not just jobs, 'good jobs' needed to reap demographic dividend]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The challenge of creating the good jobs of India could be seen as a challenge of creating more formal sector jobs which also guarantee workers protection, the Survey said.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />To reap the demographic dividend and meet the growing aspiration of labor force entrants, India needs to create not just jobs, but "good jobs" that are safe and pay well, and encourage firms and workers to improve skills and productivity.<br /><br />According to the Survey, medium sized formal sector manufacturing firms have reported labour regulations to be a significant barrier to growth and specifically "dismissal norm under the Industrial Disputes Act&rdquo; and "the cumbersome nature of compliance with labour regulations in general".<br /><br />Of the 10.5 million new jobs creative between 1989 and 2010, only 3.7 million or about 35 percent, were in the formal sector, the Survey said. <br /><br />The challenge of creating the good jobs of India could be seen as a challenge of creating more formal sector jobs which also guarantee workers protection, the Survey said.<br /><br />Contract workers has increased from 12 per cent of all registered manufacturing workers in 1999 to over 25 per cent in 2010 as companies sought to increase productivity without the risk of labour unrest, the Survey said.<br /><br />The Survey has proposed that policy makers should consider whether lower earners should be offered the same choice---of whether to contribute part of their salaries to the employee provident fund---which the rich have. <br /><br />This would both introduce competition in the market for savings, which may improve Employee Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) service standards, and allow the poor-some of whom may be liquidity constrained- to optimize as per their own personal requirements, the Survey said.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/s/sme-jobs-356_3051_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 13:09:46</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>