<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-secys-confidentbank-consolidation-achieving-divestment-tgt_5704661.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Secys confident of bank consolidation, achieving divestment tgt]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Union Budget 2016 presented today had two areas that analysts had a bone to pick with: the continuation of the bank recapitalization target at Rs 25,000 crore and the lofty aim of divesting government stakes Rs 56,000 crore.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Union Budget 2016 presented today had two areas that analysts had a bone to pick with: the continuation of the bank recapitalization target at Rs 25,000 crore and the lofty aim of divesting government stakes Rs 56,000 crore.<br /><br />In an exclusive CNBC-TV18 interview, Shereen Bhan put up the market's doubts to the officials who matter: Financial Services Secretary Anjuly Chib Duggal and Disinvestment Secretary Neeraj Gupta.<br /><br />Duggal maintained the Finance Minister's line that the government will up the recapitalization figure if need be.<br /><br />To a question whether the government could push for more consolidation in the banking space, she said she expects consolidation to happen by itself as the sector&nbsp;was undergoing a change -- with the advent on new banks and banking models.<br /><br />While Gupta said he was confident of achieving the government's target of divestment, including about Rs 20,000 crore of strategic stake sales. <br /><br />"The NITI Aayog has come out with a framework. The targets are fixed. We have scope. Only 44 of 235 central public sector enterprises (CPSEs) are listed.<br /><br /><strong><strong><em>Below is the verbatim transcript of the interview..</em><br /></strong></strong>
<p><strong>Q: Because the big hope in the market was that the bank recap outlay will be much higher than Rs 25,000 crore. The expectation was Rs 30,000-35,000 crore. The Finance Minister has articulated and caveated several times over that we will give additional funds as and when the need arises. It also hinges I am told by the minister of state for finance on the government's plan as far as consolidation of public sector banks (PSBs) is concerned. This is not the first time we have tried to go down that road on consolidation of PSBs again fought with many challenges. So, what can be the realistic expectation now as far as the judicial outlay for recap is concerned?</strong></p>
<p>Chib: That is question with answer and I agree with you. It is out there in public domain, it is as required, one. B, about consolidation you said what is different this time. It is the banking space which is different. We do have licenses out for 21 payment and small finance banks. We have two new universal bank. We have a commitment from Reserve Bank of India (RBI) for licenses on tap. If the banking space is going to change so much there is going to be a certain amount of a shake down and realignment within that space. So, that is what is different this time.</p>
<p><strong>Q: So, how soon do we move towards this process of consolidation. I know the banks bureau has only been recently set up. In fact it is barely a day and half old. Mr Rai is going to be chairing that. But what can we expect now in terms of the next milestone in this journey?</strong></p>
<p>Chib: It would be precipitate on my part to set a specific milestone because really any consolidation or merger - when I say a consolidation or a merger I mean specific consolidation or merger - has to arise out of a need, an assessment etc. So, as those assessments get made we should be moving ahead but I would at this point of time not like to make any commitment about a very specific timeline.</p>
<p><strong>Q: The previous target was almost Rs 70,000 crore. It has finally been scaled down to Rs 25,000 crore in FY16. You now perhaps have a little more realistic target of Rs 56,000 crore. Mr Watal just told me every time I come here and you ask me whether you will meet your targets or not I come back and smile because I always do. The disinvestment secretary so far haven't had much luck on that front. I am hoping that you will break that jinx. But really as far as disinvestment is concerned 20,000 for strategic sales and the balance 36,000 is what you are going to push significantly. You believe that this is a realistic target?</strong></p>
<p>Gupta: First of all strategic sale the intent of the government was very clear from the last Budget speech itself. And now the whole mechanism and the process of strategic sale is also in the public domain. We have issued all the operative instructions today. That simply reaffirms the government's commitment to take the process forward and now the whole of the process is on and I am sure that will happen and you will see some success stories which will be definitely taking into consideration the target which is given there.</p>
<p>Coming to minority stake sale, I agree that market had been volatile, there had been problems but we had been having two Offer for Sale (OFS) recently and they both have been well received. The space which is available to me is big enough to attempt this target. For example only 44 of the 235 CPSCs are listed CPSCs and they are commanding a market cap of almost 12 percent. Not only that in top 200 companies 21 are CPSCs. So, we have ample space available if I go in terms of market capitalisation against which I have to operate the disinvestment process. So, the targets are fixed, they should never look very easy but that department will be having best effort to reach these targets.</p>
<p><strong>Q: The NITI Aayog is now going to identify the CPSCs and then discuss the quantum so on and so forth. Has any work been done already as far as drawing up a possible list of contenders is concerned?</strong></p>
<p>Gupta: There had been two disinvestment commissions earlier. Their reports are in public domain. There had been various other commissions and committees which have recommended on this topic. Department of Investment and Public Asset Management will definitely be assisting NITI Aayog in whole of the exercise and we will be bringing before them all the positive recommendation which are there in the public domain and which can be considered before making an opinion. So, I am sure there is lot of work already in place and NITI Aayog has to really come out with clarity and very prudent advice for us.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/banking_Rupee_note_budget_2016_356x200_4651_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 18:52:47</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>