<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-it-sectors-expectationsfm-arun-jaitley_5365221.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: IT sector's expectations from FM Arun Jaitley]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Since the last Budget, the Government has undertaken various steps on the tax and regulatory front in its endeavour to make the Indian tax regime predictable and non-adversarial.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Ravi Mahajan</strong><br /><br />The Indian IT sector will significantly benefit from the initiatives announced by the Government of India such as Make in India and Digital India, along with the more recent landmark one &ndash; Start up India.<br /><br />Since the last budget, the Government has undertaken various steps on the tax and regulatory front in its endeavour to make the Indian tax regime predictable and non-adversarial.<br /><br />The APA program has received a positive response from the IT industry and the Government has concluded several APAs in the past 12 months. Steps are also being taken to build technology backbone for the introduction of GST.<br /><br />Having said so, there are certain areas from the perspective of the IT sector which require attention.<br /><br />The IT sector expects a clear roadmap for proposed rationalisation of the corporate tax rates and clarity on availability of profit-linked/ investment linked incentives for investments which have already been committed. Further, there is also a need to rationalise MAT rate where tax incentives are proposed to be phased out.<br /><br />The industry expects that its recommendations be considered while finalising the guidelines on POEM.<br /><br />The IT sector deputes a significant number of employees to overseas countries to provide onsite services to clients which in turn result in foreign exchange inflows for the country.<br /><br />Very often employees deputed to overseas countries face difficulties in getting credit of taxes withheld abroad on account of difference in tax years, proof of tax deposited, etc. The foreign tax credit process can be streamlined.<br /><br />From a service tax standpoint, a key area of concern is the delay in assessment and processing of service tax refunds.<br /><br />In the context of eventual implementation of GST, the industry expects that the refunds process should be automatized and standardized. This would go a long way in making the refund process predictable, less cumbersome and lead to unclogging of working capital.<br /><br />The Government must also give effect to the &ldquo;Start up India&rdquo; action plan which should provide growth impetus to technology innovation in India. &nbsp;<br /><br /><em>(The author is Tax Partner at EY India. Views expressed are personal)</em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/budget_20161_356X200_2836_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-08 18:24:20</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>