<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-despite-pressures-how-govt-can-cut-deficit-to-35-next-year_5506861.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Despite pressures, how govt can cut deficit to 3.5% next year]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[A Citi Research report says that the government can achieve FY17 fiscal target without compromising on public expenditure.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Sidhartha Shukla</strong><br /><em>money<strong>control.com</strong></em><br /><br />Over the past many years, India has followed a path of gradual fiscal consolidation in line with its stated principles of sticking to fiscal prudence.<br /><br />Given the weakness in the economy&nbsp;and with spending expected to rise in the next fiscal, observers have wondered whether Finance Minister Arun Jaitley can achieve&nbsp;the government's previously-stated&nbsp;target of achieving a fiscal deficit of 3.5 percent in&nbsp;FY17.<br /><br />This, they say, cannot be achieved without&nbsp;the government resorting to savage cuts to expenditure -- something that would harm growth.<br /><br />However, a&nbsp;Citi Research&nbsp;report says that the government can achieve&nbsp;FY17 fiscal target without compromising on public expenditure.<br /><br /><strong>Arithmetic behind meeting FY17 Fiscal Targets (%GDP):</strong><br /><br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2016/a/ArithmeticbehindmeetingFY17FiscalTargetsGDP.JPG" alt="" width="574" height="295" align="left" />As the chart above shows, cost of&nbsp;schemes such as &lsquo;one rank, one pension&rsquo; (OROP) and the 7th Pay Commission, which will likely be rolled out in FY17, stands at 0.55 percent of GDP. <br /><br />As a result, the government will need to compress the fiscal deficit elsewhere by 0.95 percent of GDP to achieve its target of 3.5 percent of GDP (compared to 3.9 percent in FY16).<br />&nbsp;<br />Citi estimates that this 95 basis points adjustment can come largely from the revenue side and reduction from expenditure may not be required.<br /><br />To be more precise, as represented in the chart above, this compression could be achieved through the following manner:<br /><br />-A rise in excise duty collection on petroleum products, approximately 0.2 percent of GDP.<br /><br />-Hikes in service tax, contributing around 0.2 percent of GDP.<br /><br />-Divestment stake sales of approximately 0.2 percent of GDP.<br /><br />-Relatively subdued pace of expenditure growth against revenues can contribute around 0.15 percent of GDP.<br /><br />Last, but not the least, telecom spectrum auction remains a wildcard for the government which could surprise positively. <br /><br /><a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/shukla_05sid" data-show-count="false">Follow @shukla_05sid</a>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/b/black_money_5713_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-16 16:48:34</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>