<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2016-growthaifs-to-aidsuccessmakeindia-initiative_5665361.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Growth of AIFs to aid the success of Make in India initiative]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Neither the tax reforms nor the regulatory reforms come without riders. For instance the tax pass through for AIFs is coupled with a 10% tax withholding obligation on income payable to investors.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Saumil Shah</strong> </em><br /> <br />Make in India initiative has been launched with an aim to boost industrial growth and make the country a global manufacturing hub. The Private Equity (&lsquo;PE&rsquo;) industry provides long term and high-risk capital for a wide variety of enterprises including but not limited to startups, growth stage and distress enterprises. Given that investments are critical to augment growth in the industrial sector, growth of the PE industry will directly contribute to the success of the Make in India initiative. <br /><br />SEBI registered Alternative Investment Funds (&lsquo;AIF&rsquo;) have so far raised capital commitments of more than INR 30,000 crores of which INR 14,000 crores Data updated upto December 31, 2015, as compiled by <a href="http://www.sebi.gov.in/cms/sebi_data/attachdocs/1455105174705.html" target="_blank">SEBI</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;have already been invested. To provide further impetus, the Indian Government has in the last one year taken several positive tax and regulatory reforms towards simplification and certainty on long outstanding concerns. <br /><br />One of the most important tax reforms introduced vide Finance Act, 2015 was to grant tax pass-through status for Category I and Category II AIFs whereby any income from investments by AIF is exempt in the hands of the AIF and is taxable in the hands of the investors as if they had made the investments directly. The above has provided for long awaited clarity to AIFs given that prior to this amendment, AIFs were subject to trust taxation provisions and the same posed several tax uncertainties. <br /><br />Further, very recently, RBI has permitted Indian AIFs to accept upto 100% foreign funds under automatic route. RBI has gone one step further to permit such AIFs with &lsquo;India owned and controlled&rsquo; sponsor and manager to invest without any downstream conditionalities, thereby opening up funding avenues in quasi equity and debt instruments and removing pricing restrictions from a FEMA standpoint. This allows domestic fund managers to raise and manage a much larger pool of funds for AIFs and invest across various sectors in various instruments without any exchange control restrictions. <br /><br />However, neither the tax reforms nor the regulatory reforms come without riders. For instance the tax pass through for AIFs is coupled with a 10% tax withholding obligation on income payable to investors. The way the tax laws are worded presently, the tax withholding obligation extends in respect of exempt income streams like dividend and capital gains earned by investors coming from a tax exempt jurisdiction also. Further, there is no clarity on whether the tax withholding has to be made on gross income of the AIF or on income after netting off expenses incurred by the AIF. Also, given that AIFs are set up with the objective of making investments, the income of AIF should be characterized as investment income and not business income. However, the tax laws presently provide that the tax pass through to AIFs will be available only in respect of income other than business income. Further, tax pass through is not available in respect of losses of AIFs. <br /> <br />Similarly, RBI&rsquo;s amendment to permit foreign investments in AIF also restricts an LLP from acting as a Manager and /or Sponsor entity. Also, while RBI has permitted AIFs to receive money from Foreign Portfolio Investments (&lsquo;FPI&rsquo;), SEBI is yet to amend the FPI regulations permitting FPIs to invest in AIFs.<br /><br />Therefore, even though a lot has been done, some finer aspects still need to be ironed out to boost investor sentiments. SEBI constituted Narayan Murthy led &lsquo;Alternative Investment Policy Advisory Committee' vide its report has also made several recommendations to promote AIFs. Some key tax recommendations include clarity on tax withholding by AIFs, exemption to AIF and portfolio companies from applicability of deemed income provisions Under sections 56(2)(viia) and 56(2)(viib) of the Income-tax Act, 1961, permitting deduction of management fee from income earned by AIF, AIFs to be permissible investments for charitable and religious trusts. <br /><br />Similarly, several regulatory reforms recommended in the report such as permitting investments by pension funds in AIFs and increasing investment limits for insurance companies, banks, etc. will go a long way in unlocking a huge pool of funds. Other recommended changes are expansion of definition of VCF and Category I AIF to include growth stage investee companies, Registrar of Companies to permit LLP to carry on investing activities, i.e. register as AIF, permission for investment by NRIs in AIFs from NRO accounts, etc. Some other reforms in respect of overseas investments by AIFs like extension of limits to higher of 25% of the corpus of an AIF (as currently provided by SEBI) or 50% of the offshore component of the corpus of AIF, permitting such investments under automatic route (presently SEBI approval is required) and liberalization of SEBI&rsquo;s requirement of &lsquo;Indian connection&rsquo; would attract Pan-Asia focused funds to be pooled in India as against countries like Singapore.<br />A flourishing AIF industry will directly impact the &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo; initiative and therefore these asks will be closely watched out for in Budget 2016. <br /><br /><em><strong>Author is partner, tax at KPMG in India</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>(Views expressed are personal.)</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_India_GDP_Growth_inflation_rise_down_economy_Indian_rupee_money_356x200_1741_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 10:18:05</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>