<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-a-signal-for-tax-regime-stability-for-corporate-india_5697301.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: 'A signal for tax regime stability for corporate India']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Reacting to the Arun Jaitley’s Budget speech, Dinesh Kanabar, CEO of Dhruva Advisors said the FM's decision to get some state-run companies to issue bonus debentures instead of dividends was a positive as it would reduce the strain on their cash positions.
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Reacting to the Arun Jaitley&rsquo;s Budget speech, Dinesh Kanabar, CEO of Dhruva Advisors said the&nbsp;FM's decision to get some&nbsp;state-run companies to issue&nbsp;bonus debentures instead of dividends was a positive&nbsp;as it would reduce the strain on their cash positions.<br /><br />Overall, he said the&nbsp;Budget signalled stability in&nbsp;the&nbsp;tax regime, he told CNBC-TV18.<br /><br />In the same interview, Pranav Sayta of EY said, &ldquo;This is a clear decisive shift towards reducing exemptions, tax holidays, incentives and moving towards a low corporate tax rate.&rdquo;<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Dinesh Kanabar&rsquo;s interview<br /></strong><br /></em><strong>Sonia: Do you want to make a point?</strong><br /> <br /> <strong>Kanabar:</strong> Actually he said something very different which I don't think very many people caught on. He spoke about the word bonus debentures and let me just elaborate because there is just one public sector undertaking (PSU) which has done that and done that successfully last year which was <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/power-generationdistribution/ntpc/NTP">NTPC</a>.<br /> <br /> The point really is, take Coal India Limited, sitting on maybe reserves of about Rs 40,000 crore. If you pay it out then you are unable to reach your goal of creating a higher production. If they give bonus debentures as Ashok said there will be dividend distribution tax but they will issue only a paper to the government which paper could be redeemed 8th, 9th or 10 year.<br /> <br /> So, you issue bonus debentures, the money continues to remain with the PSU, the government can discount that paper, because it will be traded almost at par because it will have a coupon which is consistent with the market. So, the government collects the money, the PSU retains the money, it goes for development. NTPC did it last year, others should be doing very soon.<br /> <br /> So, this is not the right time to sell the shares because stock markets are low but the reserves on which PSUs are sitting can be extracted without the cash going out of the system. That is what he meant and that is what we are likely to see.<br /><br /> <strong>Latha: If you can wrap up what this means to corporate India in terms of taxes?</strong><br /> <br /> <strong>Kanabar:</strong> In terms of corporate India this is a signal for stability of a tax regime. We are still deciphering the fine print but first of all there is this regime of uncertainty, regime of discretionary powers going away. Take for example an issue on penalty. You today had a discretion given for tax officer to levy a penalty of between 100 to 300 percent with no guidelines on when 100 could be there and when it would be 300 percent and globally it was accepted that it was probably the most penal regime in the world. What he has now proposed is a penal regime of just 50-200 percent and again provisions to when could 50 be laid and when could 200 be laid. Hopefully as we see the fine print there might be a degree of certainty there.<br /> <br /> He also mentioned about acceptance of number of simplification measures from what the Easwar Committee has proposed. for example one of the proposals says that if there is a tax demand and you pay 15 percent of the demand the balance would be state and you can again go and say even 15 percent is too high. Something which is very welcome, something which everybody was looking forward to. The Easwar Committee had recommended 7.5 percent, he has come back with 15 percent but a step in the right direction.<br /> <br /> Number of other proposals will provide certainty but most important really is the fact that this is the first time we are seeing in a single Budget a Voluntary Disclosure of Income Scheme (VDIS) of sorts, a Kar Vivad of sorts, an attempt to bite the bullet on retrospective amendment, attempt to provide a new penalty regime, too many changes on tax front will be interesting to see how this will go ahead.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Any other tax points you want to make?</strong><br /> <br /> <strong>Satya:</strong> I would feel that this is a clear decisive shift towards reducing exemptions, tax holidays, incentives and moving towards a low corporate tax rate. We are biting the bullet on corporate tax rates coming down to globally competitive rates probably 25 percent. He is also looking for the patent regime so he is talking of R&amp;D regime and a patent company being subject to only 10 percent tax on royalty. For that, we have to look at the fineprint but that could be again major initiative. He is talking of expanding for the purpose of employment generation, a lot of non-manufacturing companies also opening up to the weighted deduction for employment cost. So it is giving a fillip to make in India, he is also talking of the start-ups being getting the incentive.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_India_GDP_Growth_inflation_rise_Inflation_Service_Tax_356x200_4840_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 15:24:37</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,NTP,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>