<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/arun-jaitley-to-skip-g20-meetshanghai-beginning-february-26_5591541.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Arun Jaitley to skip G20 meet in Shanghai beginning February 26]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Additional Secretary from Finance Ministry Dinesh Sharma would be attending the meeting as most of the officials, including Economic Affairs Secretary Shaktikanta Das, would be busy with the Budget.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>With the Budget session of Parliament beginning tomorrow, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley is most likely to skip the G20 meeting of Finance Ministers and central bank governors on February 26-27 in Shanghai.</p>
<p>Additional Secretary from Finance Ministry Dinesh Sharma would be attending the meeting as most of the officials, including Economic Affairs Secretary Shaktikanta Das, would be busy with the Budget.</p>
<p>Reserve Bank Governor Raghuram Rajan will participate in the deliberations.</p>
<p>Jaitley, according to sources, will not be travelling to China as he would be tied up with 2016-17 Budget. The second full fledged Budget of the NDA government will be unveiled in Parliament on February 29.</p>
<p>China is currently holding the chair of the G20, which is a grouping of 20 developed and developing nations. The G20 Summit, in which Prime Ministers and heads of states of these countries will participate, will be held at Hangzhou on September 4-5.</p>
<p>The G20 meetings assume significance as it comes they come in the backdrop of troubled global economy and volatility in stock and currency markets.</p>
<p>International Monetary Fund (IMF) in its latest World Economic Outlook has lowered global growth projections to 3.4 percent for 2016, from earlier estimated 3.6 percent.</p>
<p>India, however, stands out as a bright spot among major economies as it is expected to clock a growth rate of 7.6 percent in 2015-16 as per CSO's estimates.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_FM_Arun_Jaitley_356x200_3634_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 14:58:02</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>