<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/stocksnews/despite-todays-rally-itc-still-has-room-to-run-icici-direct_5713781.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Despite today's rally, ITC still has room to run: ICICI Direct]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In an interview with CNBC-TV18, Sanjay Manyal of ICICI Direct termed yesterday's excise duty hike on cigarettes as the "mildest in the last 3 years" and said a price hike of 5-6 percent price hike on cigarettes would be enable ITC to cover the additional cost.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The proposed excise duty hike on tobacco products in the Budget may&nbsp;hit cigarette companies in the coming days, which are already suffering from declining volumes over the last few years.</p>
<p>But shares of ITC rallied 8 percent today&nbsp;amid a perception that&nbsp;the hike was&nbsp;not as bad as was expected.</p>
<p>In an interview with CNBC-TV18, Sanjay Manyal of ICICI Direct termed yesterday's&nbsp;hike as&nbsp;the "mildest in the last 3 years" and said&nbsp;a price hike of 5-6 percent on cigarettes would be able to&nbsp;cover the&nbsp;additional cost.<br /><br />He predicts sales volume to decline by 3 percent in FY17.</p>
<p>ICICI Direct has&nbsp;a buy rating on the stock, with a price target of&nbsp;Rs 387 per share.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Sanjay Manyal&rsquo;s interview with Latha Venkatesh and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /> <br /> <strong>Sonia: I think it is a big relief rally that we are seeing on ITC because the excise duty hike at 10 percent was not as bad as feared but what is the sense you are getting about the trajectory of the stock hereon considering that the valuations are also looking quite good at about 22 times forward earnings, do you think that a case could be built for a big upside for ITC?</strong><br /> <br /> A: Yes, we believe that the excise hike which happened yesterday, approximately 10 percent, was much milder than compared to the previous three years. We have seen in 2014, a 72 percent kind of excise hike below 65mm category. So, considering all those steep hikes, yesterday&rsquo;s 10 percent hike was pretty much mild. <br /> <br /> We believe approximately 5-6 percent kind of price hikes would be required for cigarette companies to pass on the entire burden of this excise hike which can be easily done over the period of next one or two quarters. So, what we believe is it will rather rest the steep volume decline which we have seen in last two years for ITC and considering the valuations, approximately 20 times forward earnings, we are positive on ITC. We have a target of Rs 387 on the stock. <br /> <br /> <strong>Latha: What about this game plan of the government that they are being soft on tobacco and soft on ITC so that the price corrects upwards and then they can sell the Specified Undertaking of Unit Trust of India (SUUTI) stake?</strong> <br /> <br /> A: I can&rsquo;t say about the SUUTI stake but one thing is also sure that the continuous increase of last four years has seen a lot of volume decline for cigarette companies and in turn it would affect government revenue also because it will affect the overall value collection from the excise duty from cigarettes. So, in a turn it will be a 10 percent kind of hike and not more and suits well for government as well. <br /> <br /> <strong>Sonia: You did say that the company will easily pass on a 5-6 percent price hike, so what are you penciling in terms of volumes, I am sure the volumes will still decline but the decline won&rsquo;t be as bad. For FY17 what is the volume expectation?</strong> <br /> <br /> A: We are expecting approximately 3 percent kind of a volume decline for FY17 and FY18. Though volume decline was approximately 9-10 percent in previous years so we believe that the steep volume decline will be arrested and it will be a sort of relief from that angle. Considering the steep decline has happened in previous years, it is a low base also for companies. So probably this 3 percent is the worst case scenario for cigarette companies and it could be better if things are better. <br /> <br /> <strong>Sonia: I just wanted to ask you about the game between ITC and Hindustan Unilever (<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personalcare/hindustanunilever/HU">HUL</a>) now. As we know, HUL has become one of the most expensive stocks in the FMCG space and ITC is the cheapest so would you recommend ITC over HUL at least for the medium-term?</strong><br /> <br /> A: We are positive on both the stocks for different reasons. Considering again, Budget expenditure if you see, yesterday a lot has been done from the rural side also. There is increase in the expenditure in NREGA, there is increase in the expenditure in other welfare schemes which will directly benefit the other FMCG stocks considering 35 percent of the revenues are coming from the rural India. So, we are positive on both, ITC as well as HUL. <br /> <br /> <strong>Latha: I just wanted to know how much of non-cigarette revenues you are penciling in, in your earnings per share (EPS) growth and in your Rs 387 price?</strong> <br /> <br /> A: Maximum of valuation still is from the cigarette business because still FMCG business is not contributing to the bottomline though revenues approximately are contributing Rs 10,000 crore. So maximum of the value in our target price would be from the cigarette business. <br /><br /><em>(Copy edited by Sidhartha Shukla, interview transcribed by Priyanka Deshpande)</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/i/ITC_budget2016_cigratte_356x200_5809_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 10:55:58</Entry_Date><Category>Stocks in News</Category><sc_id>,ITC,HL,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>