<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-ready-to-discuss-all-issues-including-jnu-row-pm-modi_5508861.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt ready to discuss all issues, including JNU row: PM Modi]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Following the meeting, Union Minister Venkaiah Naidu told mediapersons that all the parties agreed that Parliament must be allowed to function during the Budget Session.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>In a bid to reach out to the opposition, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Tuesday met leaders of major political parties to discuss issues ahead of Budget Session of Parliament.</p>
<p>Following the meeting, Union Minister Venkaiah Naidu told mediapersons that all the parties agreed that Parliament must be allowed to function during the Budget Session.</p>
<p>He further said that the Prime Minister had communicated that government was willing to discuss all issues, including the JNU row, in the House.<br /><br />This comes even as the ongoing JNU row has given fresh ammunition to the opposition to target the government.</p>
<p>Members of the opposition parties sought the Prime Minister's intervention into the JNU row, pointing at multiple views on the issue within the government.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Congress, JDU and Left have demanded proof from Union Home Minister Rajnath Singh for claims of Hafiz Saeed backing the JNU protests.</p>
<p>The government is worried that Key bills like GST will be stuck amid opposition's protests.</p>
<p>The current protests may also impact Assembly elections scheduled in various states in 2016.</p>
<p>With issues like Pathankot attacks and Arunachal Pradesh President's rule set to rock the session, the Prime Minister is expected seek cooperation to ensure smooth functioning of Parliament.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/m/Modi_PM_all_party_meet_venkaiah_naidu_356x200_0953_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-16 15:04:25</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>