<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-interview/budget-2016-mkt-still-at-3-4-premium-to-long-term-average-says-subramaniam_5695301.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Mkt still at 3-4% premium to long-term average, says Subramaniam]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[From the market point of view, he says corporate earnings still haven’t improved and the valuations too continue to remain at 3-4% premium to long-term average, says Vetri Subramaniam of Religare Invesco Mutual Fund.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Vetri Subramaniam,Chief Investment Officer, Religare Invesco Mutual Fund, says the two clear positives from the Budget was the government sticking to fiscal deficit target and not tinkering with the long-term capital gain tax. Both these should leave people happy.<br />
<p>From the market point of view, he says corporate earnings still haven&rsquo;t improved and the Nifty company profits are down 8-9 percent and the valuations too continue to remain at 3-4% premium to long-term average &ndash; all this is putting pressure on the markets.</p>
<p>Therefore, it is important that one remains patient in this market. Moreover, a long-term investor it could still be a reasonable time to enter, says Subramaniam.</p>
<p>From the sector perspective, he is still positive on autos.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Vetri Subramaniam's interview with Latha Venkatesh and Anuj Singhal on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Latha: Do you think that this Budget deserves more than five out of ten simply because this delivered on fiscal prudence?</strong><br /><br />A: Without trying to put actual number in terms of rating the Budget, I think the two clear positives that we can see one is that we were looking for a commitment to the fiscal target, which is clearly there and I think the other factor which perhaps has the equity market a little bit happy was that in the run up to this Budget, the biggest concern was any change in the long-term capital gains taxation regime and the fact that it has been left unchanged has left most people quite happy.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Did you get a sense that the kind of underperformance that Indian market has seen all through this month, part of which was on these fears of these taxes in Budget, that should correct itself, even if we have a fall in global markets, can we see some kind of rally in our market?</strong><br /><br />A: The challenge remains that Indian earnings remain extremely weak. The quarter that went by for December, Nifty companies' profits were down almost about 8-9 percent. So we are still in a very difficult environment as far as earnings growth is concerned for Indian companies and at this point of time, valuations continue to remain at a 3-4 percent premium to the long-term average. So from that point of view, I still think the Indian market is battling headwinds and those headwinds are primarily related to the fact that our earnings outcome remains very weak right now.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch video for more...</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Sensex_Budget2016_nifty_bse_nse_stockmarkets_jaitley_FM_finance_Down_stock_markets_356x200_4912_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 14:59:45</Entry_Date><Category>MF-Interview</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>