<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/panagariya-opposes-tinkeringfiscal-deficit-targets-_5068601.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Panagariya opposes 'tinkering' with fiscal deficit targets ]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[As part of that strategy, the deficit target for the year to March 31 was set at 3.9 percent of GDP, and for 2016/17 to 3.5 percent.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>India should not loosen its fiscal deficit targets in the forthcoming Budget, Prime Minister Narendra Modi's top economic adviser Arvind Panagariya told Reuters, saying a windfall from cheap oil would help the government keep its spending promises.</p>
<p>"I personally don't think we should be tinkering with the deficit as a percentage of GDP," Arvind Panagariya, who runs the government's Policy Commission, said in an interview.</p>
<p>In last year's Budget, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley stretched the timeline for bringing the federal budget deficit down to 3 percent of gross domestic product to three years.</p>
<p>As part of that strategy, the deficit target for the year to March 31 was set at 3.9 percent of GDP, and for 2016/17 to 3.5 percent.</p>
<p>Panagariya's views diverge from those of Arvind Subramanian, Jaitley's economic adviser. In a mid-year economic review last month, Subramanian favoured a review of the 2016/17 target to reflect hikes in public pay and weak private sector investment.</p>
<p>"Luckily, on the positive side, oil prices have come to the rescue, and - very wisely - a large part of this has been captured in the increased revenues for the government," Panagariya said.</p>
<p>"So I think that, without actually going back on the expenditure commitments, it seems to me still feasible to meet the fiscal target as it's been set."</p>
<p>Oil prices slumped on Monday below &#36;28 per barrel, the lowest since 2003, due to worries about over-supply at a time of weakening global demand.</p>
<p>Jaitley faces a challenge to achieve the deficit target in the current financial year because nominal GDP growth - which drives tax revenues - has slowed to around 6 percent from earlier estimates of 11-12 percent.</p>
<p>He is due to present his budget by the end of February.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/p/panagariya_1_356_0109_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-19 14:52:42</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>