<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/what-yes-bank-md-rana-kapoor-expects-fromfmbudget-2016_5405021.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[What YES Bank MD Rana Kapoor expects from the FM in Budget 2016]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Rana Kapoor, MD & CEO of YES Bank expects that in Budget 2016 the finance minister Arun Jaitley will increase disposable incomes by relaxing personal income tax slabs to Rs 5 lakh from Rs 2.5 lakh as a one-time correction and thereafter as per inflation-linked indexation every three years.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Following&nbsp;are the 10&nbsp;key proposals&nbsp;by Rana Kapoor, MD and CEO, YES Bank</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Enhance savings:&nbsp;</strong>Adopt structural GEAR (Growth, Efficiency, Attractiveness, Reach) approach, recommended by YES Institute, as elaborated below, to augment the savings rate in the economy:</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Enhance economic growth&nbsp;to increase per capita income: Increase disposable incomes by relaxing personal income tax slabs (to Rs 5 lakh versus Rs&nbsp;2.5 lakh one-time correction&nbsp;and thereafter inflation-linked indexation every three years)</li>
<li>Focus on EFFICIENCY in financial transactions:&nbsp;Use of plastic currency and e-transactions (via internet/mobile) to improve ease of transactions and enhance saving propensity</li>
<li>Make financial savings attractive:&nbsp;Financial savings must be promoted by improving tax incentives (enhancing 80C limits to INR 3,00,000 from current level of INR 1,50,000), increasing their inflation adjusted post tax returns (reduce lock in period eligible for tax rebate to 1 year from 5 years &amp; enhancing threshold for mandatory tax deduction at source (TDS) on interest income to Rs&nbsp;50,000 a year from Rs&nbsp;10,000 currently) and also by introducing innovative products and diversification (level tax treatment for national pension system (NPS) and employee provident fund (EPF)</li>
<li>Expand financial reach:&nbsp;Converting India Post into Postal Bank of India, a full-fledged payments and savings&nbsp;bank, to leverage its rural penetration and reach.</li>
</ul>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Investment revival:&nbsp;</strong>It is mission critical to ensure significant investment pick up in 2016, by prioritizing project clearances and providing targeted measures to revive farm and infrastructure sectors.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Initial public offer (IPO) Indian railways star eCommerce entity IRCTC which will be valued at least USD 5-6 billion today, to free up funds for significant government spending.</li>
<li>Revitalize PSU bankson priority basis by providing capital and sustainable short-medium term solutions to asset quality by addressing underlying issues.</li>
<li>Large cash-rich public sector enterprises should be allowed to buy out projects via transparent auctioning</li>
<li>Explore land pooling model for PPP &amp; SEZ projects</li>
<li>Incentivize takeout financingfor infrastructure projects and float<strong>&nbsp;</strong>smart city municipal bonds.</li>
<li>Grant infrastructure status to hotels with capital investment of Rs&nbsp;25 crore&nbsp;(presently very high at Rs&nbsp;200 Crores), also for education institutions and hospitals for boosting these sectors as well as for smart city acceleration</li>
</ul>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Specific measures to revive farm sector:&nbsp;</strong>The Farm and allied sectors have borne the brunt of consequent droughts and there is an urgent need for short-medium term measures:</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>There must be significant enhancement to existing schemes such as&nbsp;<em>Pradhan Mantri Krishi Sinchai Yojana, Rashtriya Krishi Vikas Yojana &amp; Pradhan Mantri Gram Sadak Yojana</em>&nbsp;to boost the overall rural economy.</li>
<li>The micro-irrigation sector should be given infrastructure lending</li>
<li>Payments made by banks to all service providers working for financial inclusion initiatives (under PMJDY and/or other FI services) should be exempt from service tax liability irrespective of location and/or area of operation of the service provider and customer served.</li>
</ul>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Export promotion:&nbsp;</strong>Extend the Gujarat international finance tec-city (GIFT city) concept to Mumbai&nbsp;and possibly Noida.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Encourage states to form export promotion centers with focussed product&nbsp;appellation</li>
<li>Exempt special economic zone (SEZs) from application of minimum alternate tax (MAT) and dividend distribution tax (DDT), pending for very long</li>
</ul>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong>IBU tax treatment:&nbsp;</strong>Exempt IBU from withholding tax; grant clarity over exemption from TDS for any income booked in IBUs in the wake of 5-year tax holiday granted, extend the 5-year tax holiday to 10 years</li>
<li><strong>Affordable housing (AH) requires thrust for growth:&nbsp;</strong>Given the government&rsquo;s aim to provide housing to all citizens by year 2022, following efforts are required to eliminate the estimated deficit of Rs 11 crore housing units:</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Grant infrastructure status to the housing sector, especially affordable housing&nbsp;to open additional funding avenues, in addition to direct tax benefits and easy finance availability</li>
<li>Place AH under PSL classification, not to be bunched up with real estate for overall credit cap bulk limits</li>
<li>Create a zoning process:Demarcate land for AH development, designate areas where housing-friendly zone rules apply with higher FAR/FSI, relax density norms/TDR for effective use of land</li>
</ul>
<ol start="7">
<li><strong>Road sector: removing impediments</strong></li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Reduce time for 100 percent exit after COD for road developers from 2 years to 1 year, in order to facilitate unlocking of value of road projects by developers, without imposing any condition or reinvestment requirement</li>
<li>Lay out a clear policy for premium re-schedulement:At present, while national highway authority of India (NHAI) has already decided on deferment of premium for projects which are under stress, the selection of such projects is discretionary and therefore warrants a standardized approach for expedient clearances</li>
<li>Adopt a different mechanism to acquire land for road projects: Set up a separate wing within NHAIto work on land acquisition in consultation with states<strong>.&nbsp;</strong>NHAI should award projects only when substantial land parcels have been acquired.</li>
</ul>
<ol start="8">
<li><strong>Specific measures to boost Start Up India:&nbsp;</strong>To complement the government's emphasis on entrepreneurship, there is a need to reduce direct and indirect taxes on all Start Ups to improve their cashflows. Additionally, there is a need to formalize and streamline the processing of crowd-funding to boost Indian Start Ups.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>The govenrment should also establish an innovation district in Lower Parel-Mahalakshmiarea in Mumbai to nurture and boost design and innovation; and&nbsp;India&rsquo;s equivalent of Silicon Valley in Mumbai/mumbai metropolitan region,&nbsp;Pune&nbsp;and&nbsp;Nasik&nbsp;triangular belt</li>
</ul>
<ol start="9">
<li><strong>Sops for renewable and green energy sector:</strong>To actualize India&rsquo;s ambition of mainstreaming solar and wind energy, there is an urgent need for tax sops for the sector to go up. Further, there must be a thrust on rooftop solar projects via tax incentives and raw material subsidies.</li>
<li><strong>Serviced from India:&nbsp;</strong>Adopt a two-pronged strategy to leverage India&rsquo;s strength in services by a) reducing tax distortions, b) allowing extensive foreign investment and optimizing India the services hub of the world</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Remove customs duty for all equipment and spare parts for hospitals to promote medical tourism and considersales tax exemption on&nbsp;maintenance, repair &amp; overhaul operations for airlines to avoid cascading tax impact. (MRO operations in India are&nbsp;~50 percent more expensive than Dubai or Singapore.)</li>
<li>Develop Mumbai as an international financial centre with expediency.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2013/356x200/y/yes_bank_16-9_356x200_2715_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-10 16:51:53</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>