<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-badal-terms-budget-pro-farmer-balanced_5701001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Badal terms Budget 'pro-farmer', 'balanced']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Calling it an "unprecedented" decision, Badal said the allocation for observing the tenth Sikh Guru's birthday celebrations was a matter of great pride and a "supreme gift" for Sikhs across the globe.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Punjab Chief Minister Parkash Singh Badal today hailed the Union Budget 2016-17 as "pro-farmer, growth oriented, balanced and realistic" and thanked Finance Minister Arun Jaitley for allocating Rs 100 crore for the 350th birth anniversary celebrations of Guru Gobind Singh.</p>
<p>Calling it an "unprecedented" decision, Badal said the allocation for observing the tenth Sikh Guru's birthday celebrations was a matter of great pride and a "supreme gift" for Sikhs across the globe.</p>
<p>He welcomed the government's allocation of nearly Rs 36,000 crore for the farm sector and the raising of agri-credit target to Rs 9 lakh crore for the next fiscal, saying the measures would go a long way in ensuring well-being of the agricultural community.</p>
<p>He said it was a matter of great satisfaction and pride that the NDA government almost doubled the budgetary provisions for Agriculture sector in fiscal 2016-17 over the current financial year.</p>
<p>Badal also expressed happiness over the decision to encourage farmers to take up allied farming activities to supplement their income.</p>
<p>He hailed the decision of creating a dedicated long-term irrigation fund in NABARD with an initial corpus of Rs 20,000 crore to build irrigation facilities and initiation of a programme for sustainable management of ground water resources at an estimated cost of Rs 6,000 crore.</p>
<p>The Chief Minister also welcomed a health insurance scheme which protects one-third of India's population against hospitalisation expenditure and decision to provide BPL families with a cooking gas connection, supported by a government subsidy.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Arun_Jaitley_budget_FM_budget_Finance_356x200_4344_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 17:18:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>