<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-does-wellflooring-downside-risks-citi_5705221.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 does well on flooring downside risks: CITI]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[he budget does well on flooring downside risks: the Fisc & macro stay controlled, in an uncertain growth/global environment, says CITI.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Consolidation over Consumption, and Cautiou</strong>s - It&rsquo;s a budget that seeks fiscal consolidation (3.5 percent, ahead of market, impressive), does risk some segments of consumption, and focuses on process rather than pushing the boundaries &ndash; is cautious in its approach. This will keep India positioned and in play for upsides - but the budget is unlikely to fire the market or the mood.<br /><br /><strong>The Big Picture: Consolidation</strong> &mdash; The budget takes a decisive call on fiscal consolidation: a) Stays on track with a 3.5 percent target (3.9 percent FY16, reasonable assumption &ndash; ex telecom); b) Bank capitalisation &ndash; Sticks with Rs 250b (commitment for more if needed) &ndash; will likely disappoint; and c) Agri, rural &amp; roads spends &ndash; an economic &amp; political focus, with some growth gains. The rating agencies &amp; RBI should like this.<br /><br /><strong>Tinkering with Taxes, and Consumption</strong> &mdash; The budget does tax in places: a) Consumption: Auto&rsquo;s (cess), Jewellery (excise duty), Tobacco (+10 percent) High Networth&rsquo;s (dividends): will hurt these sectors, b) Corporates: No reduction in corporate tax rate (1 percent indicated last year), dividend distribution while some exemptions have been removed (Pharma), and c) Some relief: Tax risks that do not play out (LT cap gains unchanged, 0.5 percent service tax instead of 2 percent). The consolidation gains risk some consumption pains.<br /><br /><strong>Process Simplification &amp; Institutionalization</strong> &mdash; This budget also seeks to focus on process &ndash; of tax resolutions (simplification, including voluntary disclosures), taxation (standardizing pension benefits, double taxation issues &ndash; REIT&rsquo;s, ARC&rsquo;s), and institutionalization (Bankruptcy norms &ndash; corporate/financial, Aadhar , PPP&rsquo;s and DRT&rsquo;s, bank consolidation ). These are all much needed &amp; welcome changes for the Indian economy: their gains though will be longer term, than immediate. <br /><br /><strong>Limits Downside Risks, But Also Upside Ones</strong> &mdash; The budget does well on flooring downside risks: the Fisc &amp; macro stay controlled, in an uncertain growth/global environment. That said, it lacks growth impulses, is unlikely to (initself) spur economic or market momentum, and the equity market will need a more bottom up earnings / growth uptick, to respond to what should be a stable top down India. Maintain positive view on India, with a 27,200 Dec 16 Sensex target.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/c/citi_356_3431_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 19:45:24</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>