<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-looking-at-shome-panel-report-to-simplify-tax-system-fm_5149201.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt looking at Shome panel report to simplify tax system: FM]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["The Shome Committee report has given several recommendations which we are at a very advanced stage of looking into. It has suggested certain reforms in tax administration," he said addressing the Platinum Jubilee celebrations of Income Tax Appellate Tribunal here. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of the Budget 2016-17, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today said the government is looking into the recommendations of Parthasarathi Shome committee for simplifying tax administration.<br /><br /> "The Shome Committee report has given several recommendations which we are at a very advanced stage of looking into. It has suggested certain reforms in tax administration," he said addressing the Platinum Jubilee celebrations of Income Tax Appellate Tribunal here.</p>
<p>Jaitley said a committee has also been set up under Justice R V Easwar to simplify the the Income Tax Act. "Laws must be simple, so even if you have a large number of assessees and you have a large number of population, if your laws are simple, then the possibility of excessive litigation itself does not arise," Jaitley added.<br /><br /> Referring to his last Budget proposal of reducing corporate tax from 30 percent to 25 percent over 4 years along with removal of tax exemptions, Jaitley said it would make the tax system cleaner and simpler and will ensure that "oppressive taxmen does not hover over us".</p>
<p>The Tax Administration Reform Commission (TARC), headed by Shome, had in its report pitched for a separate budget allocation to ensure time bound tax refund and a passbook scheme for TDS (Tax Deduction at Source).<br /><br /> It had suggested that retrospective amendments to tax laws should be avoided as a principle and Income Tax Return forms should also include wealth tax details.<br /><br /> Recommending far-reaching reforms in tax administration, the panel had suggested abolition of the post of Revenue Secretary, merger of CBDT and CBEC and broadening the use of Permanent Account Number (PAN).</p>
<p>The TARC submitted report to Jaitley in June 2014. The Easwar Committee, in its draft report released last week, had recommended an across-the-board raising of threshold limits for TDS and halving of the withholding tax in most cases. It also suggested a 12 percent or 18 percent interest on delayed refunds.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/j/jaitley_startup_356_2116_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-25 15:59:15</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>