<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-govt-to-gain-marginallymakeindia-says-cbec_5705281.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Govt to gain marginally from Make in India, says CBEC]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Najib Shah Chairman, Central Board of Excise & Customs (CBEC) says, the government will also gain marginally by the way of Make in India programme.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The government this year has reduced 13 taxes but will levy three new taxes&mdash;Clean Environment cess, Infrastructure cess and Krishi Kalyan cess, says Najib Shah Chairman, Central Board of Excise &amp; Customs (CBEC). <br /><br />In addition, the government will also have&nbsp;marginal gains sectorally by the way of Make in India programme, Shah tells CNBC-TV18.<br /><br />The strategy in the Budget this time is that the smaller tax payers, having higher effective tax rate of 30 percent&mdash;the highest bracket&mdash;have immediately been given a relief by bringing it down to 29 percent, says Rani Singh Nair Member, Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT). <br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of the interview.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: As far as the roadmap is concerned for the cut in corporate tax rate and there is clear disappointment that the corporate tax rate has not been cut in fact barely by 1 percent but that too for companies with turnover of Rs 5 crore. I understand that the exchequer would have been hit with a charge of about Rs 15000 crore if you had decided to bring down corporate tax rates by 1 percent but that was the stated objective of the government, that was the stated promise that the Finance Minister made, why the decision not to move?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Nair:</strong> When the Finance Minister made this statement he said he would reduce the rate of tax from 30 percent to 25 and would also have withdrawal of exemptions and deductions which are available to tax payers. Now if you look we put out the phase out of deductions in the public domain and we got a lot of feedback where they said that to abruptly take away the deductions would interfere with the business plans. We took a conscious decision that we would allow people who are already invested into the economy, who have made their business plans looking at the deductions that would be available that they should continue with it. <br /><br /><strong>Q: When is it realistic then to expect the corporate tax rate to come down to see that annual cut? One was expecting an annual cut of 1 percent but when can we realistically then expect to see the corporate tax rate coming down?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Nair:</strong> Finance Minister has made a commitment that he will reduce it to 25 percent.<br /><br /><strong>Q: I would imagine it wouldn&rsquo;t happen one shot?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Nair:</strong> It will not happen in one shot. If you see the strategy in the Budget the smaller tax payers who had a higher effective rate of tax they were paying at 29-30 percent, they have the highest bracket, we have immediately given them a relief by bringing it down to 29 percent. To all new companies which are incorporated from tomorrow we are straight away giving them a rate of 25 percent if they do not go for the deduction regime. So, we are moving forward and as and when there is more fiscal space we would look at it how to reduce the corporate tax rate further.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch video for&nbsp;more</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_India_GDP_Growth_inflation_rise_Inflation_Service_Tax_356x200_4840_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 19:14:40</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>