<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2016-17-farming-sector-to-get-rs-35984-cr-unified-agri-market-mooted_5691421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2016-17: Farming sector to get Rs 35,984 cr; unified agri market mooted]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[This development comes to provide farmers with income security and a unified agriculture market scheme to enhance farmer access to markets.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Raveena Singh</strong><br /><em>money<strong>control.com</strong> </em><br /><br />In an bid to double farmers' income in next 5 years, the government has allocated Rs 35,984 crore to the farming sector. This development comes to provide farmers with income security and a unified agriculture market scheme to enhance farmer access to markets.<br /><br />The government, in FY17, has an all-time high target of Rs 9 lakh crore for agri credit and has proposed Rs 5,500 crore for Crop Insurance Scheme.<br /><br />Also, under the Rural Sadak Yojana, net allocation of Rs 19,000 crore has been made for the year. The government will also implement Online Procurement System under Food Corporation of India. Not just this, there will be unified agricultural marketing ePlatform to connect better with the wholesale agriculture markets.&nbsp;<br /><br />Additionally, 4 new schemes&mdash;'Pashudhan Sanjivani', 'Nakul Swasthya Patra', 'E-Pashudhan Haat' and National Genomic Centre for indigenous breeds&mdash; have been introduced to enhance dairy farming in india at Rs 850 crore. The government is further&nbsp;looking to promote organic farming through 'Parmparagat Krishi Vikas Yojana' and 'Organic Value Chain Development in North East Region'. <br /><br />Furthermore, the finance ministry has provisioned Rs 15,000 core for interest subvention for agriculture loans and creation of new infrastructures for irrigation as a value addition to farm-market connectivity. Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced allocation of Rs 17,000 crore to Accelerated Irrigation Programme Benefit (AIPB) for FY17.<br /><br />With an initial corpus of about Rs 20,000 crore, a dedicated Long Term Irrigation Fund will be created in National Bank for Agriculture and Rural Development (NABARD).<br /><br />The farming community had been most expectantly watching Budget 2016 given the massive losses from a double whammy of deficient rainfall and unseasonal rains. The steep drop in farm income had been a drag on overall economic growth, with two-wheeler companies and consumer goods companies feeling it the most.<br /><br />Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced allocation of Rs 17,000 crore to Accelerated Irrigation Programme Benefit (AIPB) for FY17. Another programme for sustainable management of ground water resources will be given an estimated cost of Rs 6,000 crore and will be implemented through multilateral funding.&nbsp;<br /><br />Under the Soil Health Card scheme, 14 crore farm holdings will be covered by March 2017 and 2,000 model retail outlets of Fertilizer companies will be provided with soil and seed testing facilities during the next three years.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget_farmers_agriculture_bullock_2016_rural_fertiliser_growth_356x200_1821_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 12:00:26</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>