<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/fii-view/to-focusspeedreforms-sales-taxindia-allianz-global_5640901.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[To focus on speed of reforms, sales tax in India: Allianz Global]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Lucy Macdonald, CIO of Allianz Global Investors feels there is an inflationary bias within India but it has been under much better control recently.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Lucy Macdonald, CIO of Allianz Global Investors says many global and regional investors have lost some enthusiasm due to the slow speed of reforms in India causing fund outflows. But, it is healthy that the unrealistic and over optimistic expectations seen over the end of last year have lowered, she adds.</p>
<p>She believes that while taxation&nbsp;is interesting&nbsp;for global investors, it will not be the most important thing in the medium term. Instead, the focus would be on path of reforms and sales tax, she says.</p>
<p>According to her, fiscal deficit figures are not alarming yet but it would be better if stronger controls can be maintained on the fiscal and monetary situation.</p>
<p>On Reserve Bank of India&rsquo;s inflation target, she feels there is an inflationary bias within India but it has been under much better control recently.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Lucy Macdonald's interview with Latha Venkatesh on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: How important will the upcoming Budget be for the market and what are the key things a global investor will be watching out for in the Budget?</strong><br /><br />A: I think many of the global investors and regional investors have lost some of their enthusiasm for the speed of reform in India and that has caused some outflows from the country. I think some of those outflows have gone towards Indonesia this year hence the outperformance of that country.<br /><br />So, there is a lot of real focus on how that reform goes, how the sales tax moves through the Upper House in particular, there is a lot of focus on that. But at the same time, it is quite healthy that the expectations have come down a bit because the expectations were probably a little bit unrealistic and too optimistic towards the end of last year about India. So, I think it is quite healthy that the valuations will come down to a more normalised level.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Most important policy statement from the Indian government is the Budget and that is just a few days away. What are you expecting from the Budget?</strong><br /><br />A: At the moment, our expectations are not particularly specific. It is much more looking and saying the path of reform as we go through the next year and in particular waiting to see how that sales tax gets through the Upper House.<br /><br /><strong>Q: There are murmurs that the short-term capital gains tax will be expanded to not just one year but three-years. In other words, equity investments could get taxed a bit more than they are currently, will that be a major negative for you?</strong><br /><br />A: Taxation is, on the margin, important to us so yes, it is on the margin but I think we are much more interested in those big issues of freeing up infrastructure, making foreign investment easier into the country and allowing easier flow of goods and services around the country. Those are the real major things; on the margin what is happening to taxation is interesting but it is not the most important thing in the medium-term.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Would the fiscal deficit be a very important number that you would watch out for? The government ought have reached 3.5 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) as the fiscal deficit target last year they pushed it to this year. If it is not achieved in the 2016 Budget, would it be disappointment that 3.5 percent number?</strong><br /><br />A: No, it is not a particularly distressing number when you look at it in global terms and when you look at some other deficits. We are surrounded by in Europe or even in the US, fiscal deficit of that side is not alarming, but at the same time you do like to see the control.<br /><br />One thing that we have been very encouraged by is that investor has been seeing stronger control of the fiscal situation and also monetary control within India. So, we do want to make sure that, that is maintained and that credibility is maintained as an overseas investor.<br /><br /><strong>Q: When you say the monetary control is maintained you would want the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to pursue its inflation targeting, is that what you are expecting?</strong><br /><br />A: Yes, because there is an inflationary bias within India, which has been under much better control recently. So, you want to make sure that is maintained. Speaking from the UK, which also has an inflationary bias, we need strong monetary management.<br /><br /><strong>Q: To come back with the earnings issue, we have been waiting for earnings to reach double digits for practically the past two years every time we push it by about a quarter or two down. How disappointment was the recent earnings season?</strong><br /><br />A: It has been disappointing. However, when you look at in a global context, there has been disappointments widespread and India is only marginally worst than average. So, you have seen disappointment throughout the earnings season in the US, not huge but on the margin there has been misses at the revenue level and you have seen that in India too that revenue has been slight disappointing. However, the corporate sector has been very strong globally at keeping its margins quite strong and that has also been the case in India. So you have seen the EBITDA missing less than revenue.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/l/lucymcdonald_5213_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 14:36:00</Entry_Date><Category>FII View</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>