<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/macro-eco-survey-cheers-market-nifty-eyes-7050-banks-rise_5661361.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Macro Eco Survey cheers market, Nifty eyes 7050; banks rise]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[SBI, Coal India, Axis Bank, L&T and NTPC are top gainers while Bajaj Auto, Hero MotoCorp, Bharti Airtel and Lupin and Gail are top losers in the Sensex.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneyconytrol Bureau<br /><br />1:55 pm Market check: </strong>The Sensex is up 232.16 points or 1 percent&nbsp;at 23208.16, and the Nifty up 70.95 points or 1 percent&nbsp;at 7041.55. About 1018 shares have advanced, 1282 shares declined, and 156 shares are unchanged.&nbsp;SBI is up 4 percent. <br /><br /><strong>1:45 pm Exclusive:</strong> The government has maintained a conservative growth target of 7-7.75 percent for FY17 in light of the instability in global economies, says Arvind Panagariya, VC of NITI Aayog. However, there is no reason to be pessimistic that the 8 percent target listed out post FY17 is unachievable, he adds.</p>
<p>Panagariya was expressing his opinion on the Macro-Economic Survey tabled in the Parliament on Friday, in an interview to CNBC-TV18.</p>
<p>He says sticking to the fiscal consolidation target will be taken positively, adding he has always pitched for a rate cut and if the fiscal deficit target is achieved then the Reserve Bank will get more room to cut rates. He feels the process should begin with at least 50 basis points cut.</p>
<p><strong>1:35 pm Bonds:&nbsp;</strong>Indian bonds rallied after the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) announced a USD 1.75 billion bond purchase and said it would not allow debt issued by state governments as part of a bailout scheme for power companies to hit markets.</p>
<p>The benchmark 10-year bond yield was down 5 basis points at 7.81 percent, after falling as much as 10 basis points earlier.</p>
<p>The RBI said late on Thursday it would purchase bonds up to 120 billion rupees (USD 1.75 billion) through open market operations on March 3.</p>
<p>In addition, the central bank said on Friday state governments would issue debt under the so-called UDAY scheme to banks under a private placement, thus keeping the bonds outside of markets.</p>
<p><strong>1:30 pm View: </strong>Keki Mistry- Vice Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, HDFC says, he expects some changes in the income tax norms in the upcoming Budget but is unsure whether tax rates will be re-jigged or the tax slabs will be changed. Mistry believes it is important to increase the tax exemptions on home loans and even a marginal increase will pep up the home-buyers sentiments. Considering the increase in house prices has been significantly higher than increase in exemptions, even a little raise of about Rs 50,000 will go a long way in improving sentiment, he says. On the possibility of the Reserve Bank cutting interest rates if government sticks to fiscal deficit target, Mistry says, interest rates are high, as is the trend for this time of the year, and he expects rates to decline gradually in the near term.<br /><br /><strong>1:20 pm Macro Economic Survey: </strong>Government has taken steps such as safeguard duty, anti-dumping duty and minimum import price to check surging steel imports, but further protection will impact downstream industries, the Economic Survey said. On account of an almost "stagnant" steel demand globally, particularly in China, major producers are pushing products into the Indian market, which is leading to a surge in steel imports, said the 2015-16 report card of the economy tabled by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in Parliament today. The domestic steel industry, with higher borrowing and raw material costs and lower productivity, is at a comparative disadvantage.<strong> <br /></strong></p>
<p>To check this, government initiated several measures to curb surging imports and make domestic production sustainable, it added. "Any further safeguards will impact downstream industries as steel is used as an input in different industries like basic metal and non-metal products, machineries, transport, construction and consumer goods," the Survey said. It is estimated that for a 10 per cent increase in steel prices due to a hike in anti-dumping or import duties, the cost of production of basic metal and non-metal products will increase by 5.4 per cent, it added.</p>
<p><strong>1:15 pm Macro Economic Survey: </strong>The Economic Survey has said that power tariffs for the Indian industry is "unusually high", considering the quality aspect.<br /><br />Since electricity supply and its quality impacts industrial output, the Survey has proposed that consumers with electricity load above 1 MW be allowed to procure electricity directly from electricity markets.<br /><br />The Open Access (OA) policy introduced under the Electricity Act 2003, was aimed at helping discover a single market price for power around the country.<br /><strong><br />1:10 pm Macro Economic Survey: </strong>DBS Bank says, "The economic survey has adopted a cautious tone on the economic assumptions, near and medium-term. By extension, realism in nominal growth projections bodes well for credibility on Budgetary assumptions (primarily deficit, tax buoyancy etc).</p>
<p>"A benign inflation estimate is, however, puzzling ahead of pay commission changes and is perhaps an indication that the housing allowance increase might be staggered/postponed.</p>
<p>"Re-think of the fiscal framework is likely, which suggests the 3 percent target for FY18 is likely to be pushed out. However subsequent comments on need for "credibility and optimally" on FY17 deficit raises the possibility that the -3.5 percent red line might be adhered to on Monday.<br /><br /><strong>Don't miss: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-must-stick-to-35-fiscal-deficit-target-fy17-cad-1-15_5661041.html">Govt must stick to 3.5% fiscal deficit target; FY17 CAD 1-1.5%</a><br /><br /></strong>The market seems to be cheering up Macro Economic Survey. The Sensex is up 160.54 points or 0.7 percent at 23136.54, and the Nifty up 51.10 points or 0.7 percent at 7021.70. About 901 shares have advanced, 1333 shares declined, and 147 shares are unchanged.</p>
<p>SBI, Coal India, Axis Bank, L&amp;T and NTPC are top gainers while Bajaj Auto, Hero MotoCorp, Bharti Airtel and Lupin and Gail are top losers in the Sensex.</p>
<p>Indian stocks are relatively resilient despite volatility in the worldwide financial markets and the country can become a leading investment destination going ahead, the Economic Survey said today.</p>
<p>"The (Indian) market has rebounded time and time again, and it is hoped that as the global financial markets settle down, India can become the leading investment destination owing to its robust macroeconomic fundamentals," as per the 2015-16 report card of the state of the economy tabled by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in Parliament today.</p>
<p>"Despite volatility in global financial markets, the Indian equity market has been relatively resilient during this period compared to the other major emerging market economies," it added.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Stock_bse_nse_markets_sensex_dalal_street_graph_356x200_4055_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 13:00:04</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>