<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-fm-announces-all-time-high-agricultural-creditrs-9-lk-crore_5678581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: FM announces all-time high agricultural credit of Rs 9 lk crore]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[During the last Budget, the government had outlined target of Rs 8.5 lakh crore of agricultural credit.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Shweta Mungre</strong><br /><em>money<strong>control.com<br /></strong></em></p>
<p>While presenting the Budget for 2016-17 on Monday, the Finance Minister Arun Jaitley announced an all-time high&nbsp;agricultural credit of Rs 9.0 lakh crore. <br /><br />He also announced a&nbsp;provision of Rs 15000 crore towards interest subvention to&nbsp;reduce burden of loan repayment.&nbsp;<br /><br />During the last Budget, the government had outlined target of Rs 8.5 lakh crore of agricultural credit.</p>
<p>In a pre-Budget note, Standard Chartered had outlined the need for&nbsp;model legislation for digital registration of tenancy agreements between landowners and farmers. This would help in&nbsp;formally classifying farmers and landowners as cultivators and improve their access to institutional credit.</p>
<p>Various initiatives have also been put in place to aid farmers, like crop loans up to Rs 3 lakh at 7 percent interest, the effective rate of which was cut to 4 percent during 2015-16 as an incentive for prompt repayment. These measures were aimed at helping farmers tide over short-term contingencies and price shocks which may affect their seasonal operations.</p>
<p>The small and marginal farmers with Kisan Credit Cards (KCCs) also have the benefit of interest subvention scheme extended for a further period of up to six months (post-harvest) against Negotiable Warehouse Receipts (NWRs), at the same rate as available to crop loan, to discourage distress sale of crops by small farmers.</p>
<p>However, it is interesting to note that although the ratio of agricultural credit to agricultural GDP has nearly quadrupled in percentage terms within a decade up to 2013, the share of long-term agriculture credit has declined significantly dropped.</p>
<p>The Macro-Economic Survey tabled in the Parliament on Friday had pointed out the immediate need to arrest and reverse this decline.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget_farmers_agriculture_2016_356x200_1946_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 11:29:58</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>