<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/macro-economic-survey-2016-gdp-growth-to-remain-flat-next-year-fisctarget_5660321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Macro Economic Survey 2016: GDP growth to remain flat next year; fisc on target]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The government today tabled the Economic Survey 2016-17 in Parliament today.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>1.00 pm: </strong>With that, we bring the live coverage for the Economic Survey to a close.<strong><br /><br />12.56 pm: </strong>The NITI Aayog Vice Chairman is&nbsp;discussing&nbsp;a myriad of issues, from&nbsp;the&nbsp;growth outlook and fiscal deficit to bank NPAs and whether the RBI should cut interest rates.<br /><br />The full interview would be up on Moneycontrol soon. Watch out for it.<strong><br /><br />12.53 pm:&nbsp;</strong>The Economic Survey has shied away from making an 8 percent growth forecast for FY17, saying that it seems "realisable over the medium term".<br /><br />What explains the subdued&nbsp;expectations? "The outlook for the global economy is more clouded than it was last year [when the Economic Survey was tabled in 2015, which forecast 8 percent growth], explains Panagariya.<strong><br /><br />12.50 pm:&nbsp;</strong>CNBC-TV18&nbsp;is now talking to Arvind Panagariya, Vice Chairman, NITI Aayog.<strong><br /><br />12.45 pm: </strong>"The&nbsp;informal sector has created jobs and is keeping unemployment low," says the Finance Ministry.<br /><br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2016/c/CcH4L-BUAAAam8e.jpg" alt="" width="544" height="544" align="left" /><strong><br /><br />12.40 pm: </strong>A word from the Economic Survey&nbsp;on public sector banks, which are precariously positioned at this moment, thanks to the NPA crisis: "Recognition, recapitalization, resolution, and&nbsp;reform needed to resolve twin balance sheet challenge of PSBs and&nbsp;corporate firms."<strong><br /><br />12.35 pm:</strong>&nbsp;While&nbsp;the government will likely meet the fiscal deficit, its own spending space will be constrained&nbsp;--&nbsp;especially given that rural India needs a lot of help&nbsp;--&nbsp;so the market can rule out a broadbased stimulus package in the Budget, says HSBC Chief India Economist Pranjul Bhandari.<br /><br />Bhandari, however, says that she expects one more rate cut to come in soon and&nbsp;adds that the falling bond yields themselves&nbsp;work as a stimulus&nbsp;for corporate India by way of lower borrowing cost.<br /><br /><strong>12.33 pm:&nbsp;</strong>"The current account deficit has declined and foreign exchange reserves have risen to USD 351.5 billion in early February 2016," the Finance Ministry tweets.<br /><br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2016/c/CcHw87bVAAI_dBT.jpg" alt="" width="596" height="596" align="left" /><strong><br /><br />12.30 pm: </strong>Stocks appear to have taken the news of the fiscal deficit target positively. The Bank Nifty has suddenly shot up and is up 1.4 percent.<strong><br /><br />12.28 pm: </strong>"It will be good if the government sticks to its fiscal consolidation&nbsp;path, not just for the next year but also for the medium term," Barclays Chief India Economist Siddhartha Sanyal tells CNBC-TV18. "Tinkering around with medium term targets so frequently will&nbsp;bring down the government's credibility in the eyes of foreign investors."<strong><br /><br />12.26 pm: </strong>The government meeting its fiscal target would be good news for the bond market, where yields have remained stubbornly high of late, and will&nbsp;give the RBI to further cut rates.<br /><br />Is a rate cut looming right after the Budget?<strong><br /><br />12.23 pm: </strong>The Survey's argument in favour of meeting the fiscal deficit should set to rest speculation over whether the government&nbsp;will&nbsp;miss its&nbsp;target.<br /><br />Remember, it was&nbsp;the CEA who set the cat among the pigeons&nbsp;by hinting&nbsp;that the government&nbsp;should spend more to counter the economic slowdown, implying it can afford to&nbsp;miss its target.<strong><br /><br />12.22 pm: The good news. "Credibility and optimality requires the government should meet 3.5 percent fiscal deficit target in FY17," the Survey says.<br /><br />12.20 pm: </strong>"The&nbsp;survey expects continued good performance by industrial, corporate and&nbsp;infrastructure sectors due to recent reforms,"&nbsp;the Finance Ministry tweets.<br /><br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2016/c/CcHx4U9VAAAdQBP.jpg" alt="" width="597" height="597" align="left" /><strong><br /><br />12.16 pm: </strong>The Economic Survey also talks about inflation, saying that the increase in wages from the rollout of the 7th Pay Commission will have little impact on prices.<strong><br /><br />12.14 pm: </strong>Below is the government's GDP growth forecast:<strong><br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2016/c/CcHu6hOUsAAoWFs.jpg" alt="" width="595" height="595" align="left" /></strong><br /><br /><strong><br /><br />12.10 pm: </strong>The Survey is a 300-400 page document,&nbsp;authored by the Chief Economic Advisor, currently Arvind Subramanian.&nbsp;It is the government's summary of the current economic situation, the outlook going forward, and is also considered by some as the&nbsp;CEA's wish-list for economic reforms needed going forward.<strong><br /><br />12.07 pm: </strong>The Survey says the government will&nbsp;likely meet its FY16 fiscal deficit target of 3.9 percent.&nbsp;For the next year,&nbsp;there's no number yet (the official target is 3.5 percent).&nbsp;It only says that the government will face a tight fiscal situation.<strong><br /><br />12.04 pm: </strong>The&nbsp;Economic Survey forecasts growth to come in at&nbsp;7-7.75 percent this year.<br /><br />"Amidst a gloomy international economic landscape, India stands as a haven of stability," the Finance Ministry tweets. <br /><br />No news yet&nbsp;on the growth forecast of FY17.<strong><br /><br />12.00 pm:</strong> Welcome to the live coverage of the Economic Survey 2015-16 that the government has tabled in Parliament today.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/b/Budget2015_parliament_ecomony_survey_356x200_3817_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 12:01:20</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>