<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/cnbc-tv18-comments/cii-ficci-assocham-table-recommendations-for-budget-2016 _4904341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[CII, FICCI, Assocham table recommendations for Budget 2016 ]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The recommendations made by industry chambers CII, FICCI and Assocham along with export lobby FIEO take into account the possibility of a weaker demand and offer possible solutions to get the growth momentum going. 
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley's third budget under the Modi government will be his most challenging. His own finance adviser has tapered down the growth rate and with the pace of investment yet to show any traction, Jaitley has his work cut out for him. <br /><br />No surprise then that the recommendations made by industry chambers CII, FICCI and Assocham along with export lobby FIEO take into account the possibility of a weaker demand and offer possible solutions to get the growth momentum going. <br /><br />CII budget recommendations include <br /><br />- Higher allocations to PM Gram Sadak Yojana, PM Krishi Sinchai Yojana<br />- Enhance investments in railways, irrigation &amp; power<br /><br />FICCI's Recommendations<br /><br />- Recalibrate the fiscal deficit roadmap to promote public investment<br /><br />Industry body Assocham has called for boosting infrastructure investment through support from IIFCL to rebuild capacity of private infrastructure companies. The recommendations include replacement of costly bank guarantees by bid bonds and doing away with the surcharge on corporate tax and service tax. <br /><br />Essentially, the industry bodies have asked that the onus of getting the investment mojo back rest with the government. But for the finance minister, the big challenge will be sticking to its fiscal target for FY16 and powering up the growth cycle. <br /><br /><strong><em>Watch video for more.</em></strong>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/j/Jaitley_ArunJaitley_Budget_356X200_200X200_ss1_3630_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-06 21:51:32</Entry_Date><Category>CNBC-TV18 Comments</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>