<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2016-proposals-to-boost-real-estate-sector_5707781.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Proposals to boost real estate sector]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Acting in the need of the hour and realising that a robust real estate sector can help push India’s growth further, the government introduced a slew of measures aimed at reviving the sector and bringing a cheer to the industry players.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Gaurav Karnik</strong></em><br /><br />In India, the real estate sector contributes approximately 7.5% of the GDP of the country directly and through allied activity. This sector witnessed tepid growth in the last few years and thus anticipated positive proposals to boost growth in the country.<br /><br />Acting in the need of the hour and realising that a robust real estate sector can help push India&rsquo;s growth further, the government introduced a slew of measures aimed at reviving the sector and bringing a cheer to the industry players.<br /><br /><strong>Key changes proposed in the sector by Union budget 2016 are as under:</strong><br /><br />- Exemption from levy of dividend distribution tax on amount of dividends paid by a special purpose vehicle to a Real Estate Investment Trust (&lsquo;REIT&rsquo;); the proposed amendment would make REIT an effective vehicle for promoters to monetize their assets and raise funds from investors; the proposed amendment had been the key ask of the sector since introduction of REIT and has been duly met in this year&rsquo;s budget; <br /><br />- 100% deduction on profits earned by an assessee engaged in developing and building affordable housing project, subject to certain conditions. The proposed deduction should enable investments in the affordable housing sector and meet the objective of providing shelter to the masses at affordable; the said incentive would also enable the government to achieve its objective of &lsquo;housing for all by 2022&rsquo;;<br /><br />- Section 50C of the Act provides for mechanism for determining value of land or building or both for determining the capital gains on their transfer, a controversy existed where the date of agreement and date of registration of such land or building or both were not same; <br /><br />In line with the existing provisions of section 43CA of the Act i.e. when an immovable property is sold as stock in trade, it has been proposed to provide that stamp duty value on the date of agreement may be taken for the purpose of computing the full value of consideration; this would put an end to the controversy which existed for determining the date where there is a gap between the date of agreement and execution of sale deed;<br /><br />- Increase in time period for acquisition or construction to 5 years (from existing time limit of 3 years) from the end of the financial year in which such capital was borrowed for providing deduction in respect of interest on borrowed capital. Such increase would provide relief to the taxpayers where the period of acquisition or construction exceeded 3 years;<br /><br />- Simplification of provisions in respect of unrealised rent and arrears of rent; a single section (section 25A) has been proposed to be inserted to provide that amount of rent received in arrears or amount of unrealised rent received subsequently shall be chargeable to tax in the financial year in which such rent is received or realised; further, it has also been provided that 30% of such amount shall be allowed as standard deduction;<br /><br />Union budget 2016 entailed major expectations from varied sectors across country which have been addressed notably by FM Mr. Arun Jaitley. The above amendments brought in by the FM should enable providing a double digit growth to the country and should provide a much needed impetus and boost to the real estate sector in India. <br /><br /><em><strong>Author is Partner and Real Estate and Infrastructure Leader, EY</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/r/real_estate_invest_356x200_5642_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 20:46:54</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>