<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/fii-view/correction-brutalnota-bear-market-ridham-desai_5521601.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Correction 'brutal', but not in a bear market: Ridham Desai]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[As far as corporate earnings go, India is growing faster on a relative basis, though earnings recovery that the market has been looking for since the last year is yet to come through, says Ridham Desai, head of India equity research and India equity strategist, Morgan Stanley]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Recent market moves can be called a 'brutal correction' and it is in a more deep correction phase rather than a bear market, says Ridham Desai, head of India equity research and India equity strategist, Morgan Stanley.</p>
<p>As far as corporate earnings go, India is growing faster on a relative basis, though the earnings recovery that the market has been looking for since the last year is yet to come through, he says.</p>
<p>Desai ofcourse agrees that the sentiment is looking rotten. However, he adds that whatever India is facing on the markets' front is more global and not India-specific. "India is like a quality stock in a torrid global market," he told CNBC-TV18<em>.<br /><br /></em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Ridham Desai&rsquo;s interview with Latha Venkatesh &amp; Anuj Singhal on CNBC-TV18.</strong><br /><br /><strong>Anuj: You are the eternal optimist except for the last bear market that you call, right? However, what is happening right now? Is this a bear market or is this just one of those brutal corrections which you feel that it is the worst but actually is a great buying opportunity?&nbsp;</strong> &nbsp;<br /><br />A: I feel like it is that, which is that it is the brutal correction. Reminds me of the summer of 2004 if you recall there was an election result and the market sank, it had been preceded by a big emerging market sell-off. We lost over 25 percent from the top in that fall. It took quite a few months for the market to bottom out. That proved to be a great buying opportunity in the context of that bull market. <br /><br />We got a shallow correction again in the summer of 2006. It wasn&rsquo;t as brutal as 2004 but it was still a big correction. So, it reminds me of that, I mean how bear market is defined is up for debate but we have had successive lower tops and bottoms since March 2015. The market has actually not gone pass that and so we have spent almost a year now below that level. Globally it does seem like we are in a bear market and for India to stand out is quite exceptional.<br /><br />So, far now it is still a brutal correction but every bodies patience&rsquo;s will be tested; it is being tested. If I look at various things in the market place for example just a very simple thing. The number of stocks that are trading above 200 day moving average (DMA) in the BSE 200 that number is now close to zero. When did that last happened? October 2008, so if you look at it the sentiment is very bad. <br /><br />We have a proprietary sentiment indicator where we put in a lot of things like the breadth, volatility, put options data that number is now back to where it was in September 2013. It is not very much above where it was at the crisis low of 2008. So, sentiment looks very rotten. <br /><br />Usually it is a contra indicator which is you buy the market but that doesn&rsquo;t mean that we are in a V-shape recovery. So, it could take a while for the market to trough out and rise. I still think that we are probably in a deep correction rather than in a bear market.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>Latha: We are not even talking about V-shape recoveries suffice if you gave us enough evidence or enough reasons to believe that we won&rsquo;t fall too much from current levels?</strong><br /><br />A: I can&rsquo;t, because this is a global thing it is not an India related thing. India is still outperforming and the recent weakness that we are seeing in India is like what happens in the depth of a bear market when quality gives out. So, India is like that quality stock in a global environment which is very torrid and it is giving up. It is giving up and it like, the US and India are actually making new lows. <br /><br />If you look at various emerging markets, the ones that have got bad, economic fundamentals, they have stopped making new lows now &ndash; Brazil, Russia they have stopped making new lows , whereas India and US have made new lows. US has probably stopped for now. India is still trying to find a bottom. We have not made a new low because we made a low last week. However, we may test that and then come back. So, it is like that quality stock that gives up in the very end.<br /><br />&nbsp;<br /><strong>Latha: That was the point we were discussing. Are we the HDFC and the Infosys and the basket which you sell last? What prevents me from taking that positive hue that we are the HDFC&rsquo;s? We didn&rsquo;t have particularly a good result season and then you always knew that their nonperforming loans (NPL) is not what they were indicating. However, the market got an even bigger shock that it was prepared for so do you still want to call us the <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-housing/housingdevelopmentfinancecorporation/HDF">HDFC</a> and the <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software/infosys/IT">Infosys</a> or do you think we have underperformed genuinely on earnings front?&nbsp;</strong> &nbsp;<br /><br />A: So, let us get the numbers out, since the low of September 2013 when we had two leadership changes. We had a new Prime Ministerial candidate and then subsequent Prime Minister and we had a change in the leadership of the Reserve Bank of India (RBI). India has outperformed emerging markets by 60 percentage points. It is a whopping amount of performance. <br /><br />We have not had such type of performance ever. Since the top which we made on January 1st on a relative basis, the relative top was made on January 1st, the absolute top was made in March 2015 we are down about 7-8 percent. So, it is plain vanilla correction on a relative basis. <br /><br />If you look at the relative chart it is looking like a raging bull market, which is why I wrote an essay last week which was titled &ldquo;India&rsquo;s third bull market how weird does that sound&rdquo; and we were making new lows on the Nifty. So, that is as far as statistic is concerned. Now you made a point on earnings, so you can point out to me if there is any place on the planet where there are earnings. There aren&rsquo;t. Again on a relative basis India is growing faster. <br /><br />Even corporate earnings, India is growing faster than the rest of the world. One thing which was striking about the earning season in Europe and US because that is where the earnings season runs concurrently with India is that the ones who missed were really hammered and the rest got a very little lift to share price. <br /><br />Now doesn&rsquo;t that sound very familiar? Precisely what happened in India if you missed earnings you got slaughtered and for the rest the market was okay. I will give you a small bid and in fact that bid also vanished with the passage of time. So, that is like a bear market that is how bear markets behave. They don&rsquo;t want reward anything that is happening good. <br /><br />The point on absolute earnings is absolutely valid and we made a call last year that earnings will turn and we are still waiting for that to happen. So, what worked in our favour and I can point out the reasons why that has not happen but the fact is that it has not worked out in our favour. We still think that the earnings cycle should trough and we should see better earnings growth but there are caveats to that and largely coming from global factors. <br /><br /><strong>Anuj: You are hedging your bets. I am not seen you do that. You are saying that this is still a bull market correction but you are saying that data is pointing out that it could be a bear market. Stick your neck out, what is this?</strong><br /><br />A: It is a unique situation compared to 2003 and 2008. 2003 and 2008 was a global synchronous bull market everything went up. Some stuff outperformed, some underperformed but everything went up in absolute terms. The reason why I am sounding like I am hedging is because you are a assessing this on an absolute basis. If you make that assessment on an absolute basis, we had discussed this even at the end of last year, it is a year of low returns.<br /><br />Now low has turned into negative and therefore the rest of the year should be better. However, it is still a year of low returns and in that context India will probably still outperform. However, to expect a 30-40 percent gain on the Index will not be valid. <br /><br />I am not hedging myself I am just saying that it is different from what we saw in 2003 and 2008. The world is actually far more challenged and India will likely deliver better performance. However, returns have always to be seen in a relative context. You cannot get absolute return on any asset class. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: You started off by saying that globally, you are hedging your bets here because the world is looking so terrible. What is the Morgan Stanley view? Are the global markets going to see a lot more by way of selling? Is a recession around the corner and has that yet to get priced in?</strong><br /><br />A: A lot of the markets around the world came very close to our bear case last week, so did the Indian markets. We were within 1,000 points on the Sensex on a bear case, so the market has seemingly found some support. Again as I said India has not tested last week lows even though we seem to be but maybe we will test that low and then move ahead. On valuation basis things have turned a bit more attractive. <br /><br /><strong>Anuj: You made an interesting point that the domestic mutual funds stake is at a 13 year high. The optimist would say that okay that is great because the retail investors are getting back into the market but the pessimist view is the did they get into the market at the high point and would the cycle repeat and they will end up losing money. Is that a risk?</strong><br /><br />A: We are in a secular uptrend for equity ownership in India. As such domestic households in India own too little equity. We think that will change over the next 5-10 years. That doesn&rsquo;t mean over a 12-24 month period you won&rsquo;t get those periods of pause. Flows were tested in January and we still came out with positive numbers. February again they are getting tested and maybe we don&rsquo;t come out so good but I think this is going to be a pause in what, my view is a likely secure trend towards more and more households buying equities.<br /><br />Fundamentally, the reasons are population is young, is less risk averse. The scars of the scandals of the 90&rsquo;s are behind us. That generation has passed. The new generation doesn&rsquo;t even know about them. Equities are offering better returns. Even in the context of what has happened in the market recently equities are doing better than most of their asset classes. I think equities have a good case for a long-term domestic flow.<br /><br />The way I look at it personally is that equities are not meant to be bought for daily or monthly or six monthly or even annual returns. They have to be bought for really long returns. The only challenge we have is that we should not be anchored to this 16-17 CAGR that the Sensex has generated over the last 30 years. The likelihood is that the next 20-30 years may not be that high nominal number. You will understand this, with your economist background is that inflation in India is lot lower now compared to what it may have been in the last 30 year. So, nominal asset return will also adjust accordingly. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: What will you look for in the Budget? You are the Budget guest editor give us the three numbers you will watch or the three things you will watch?</strong><br /><br />A: The three things, first is continuing the path of fiscal consolidation, it is very important. What the government embarked on two years ago is paying us reach dividends in terms of stemming inflation expectations. I don&rsquo;t see any reason to move away from that path. Ultimately that will result in better growth that is one.<br /><br />Second is, there has to be a continuing focus on infrastructure spending. We all know that the number as we discussed earlier is not a very large one but then there is a follow through effect that takes place in other sectors. So, the government wants to do that as well. <br /><br />From a stock market perspective I don&rsquo;t think there is any real merit in announcing tax breaks. I don&rsquo;t think investors invest because they are going to pay less tax. Investors invest because they are going to make more profits and to that extent boosting the growth in the economy is far more crucial than giving tax breaks. So, I hope that the Finance Minister doesn&rsquo;t use up his limited resources in doing that. <br /><br />Finally, a little bit for the rural economy, that is a low hanging fruit for the government and may be they can do a little bit there to revive the rural economy.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<br /><br /><em><br /></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/r/Ridham-Desai_16_9_5837_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-17 11:38:19</Entry_Date><Category>FII View</Category><sc_id>,IT,HDF,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>