<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/the-mgnrega-decade-hits-missesroad-ahead_5271321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[The MGNREGA decade: Hits, misses & road ahead]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[As NREGA completes 10 years, a longer lifespan than most rural development schemes, Nikhil Dey, Co-Convenor, National Campaign for People's Right to Information (NCPRI) answers some of the key questions related to it.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Today is the 10th anniversary of the launch of the Mahatma Gandhi National Rural Employment Gurantee Act (MGNREGA). This legislation was path-breaking in its scale, architecture and thrust.</p>
<p>Its demand-based legal framework promised an open-ended Budget for implementation, unlike all other allocation-driven social sector schemes.</p>
<p>As it completes 10 years, a longer lifespan than most rural development schemes, it is an opportune moment to answer three key questions: first, has the MGNREGA worked? Second, what is happening with it today? and third, do we still need the act?</p>
<p>Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Nikhil Dey, Co-Convenor, National Campaign for People's Right to Information (NCPRI), says the scheme has been seminal in changing the face of rural India and all parties are in agreement that this affects the entire nation.</p>
<p>This scheme is dependent on an&nbsp;open-ended Budget and the need&nbsp;of the hour is allotment Rs 62,000 crore keeping&nbsp;inflation into account, Dey adds.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Nikhil Dey&rsquo;s interview with Shereen Bhan on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: I am holding up full page advertisements that have been put up by the government outlining the highlights of what this government has done with the NREGS. It is ironic because this government had held up the NREGS as a symbol of the UPA&rsquo;s failure to address problems in the rural sector, but that is politics, so politics aside, this should be good news that the government is now trying to take ownership of the NREGS.</strong><br /><br />A: It is certainly very good news that finally, this battle. When the NREGS was passed, it was passed absolutely unanimously on both houses of Parliament. And we have in between, been stuck in this strange binary of Congress and BJP, other parties, whereas it is time that the NREGS, because of how seminal, the kind of programme is and has been to changing the face of rural India, that it be seen as a national programme, something that everyone needs to contribute to, something that people need to stop having the kinds of arguments that were reflected in Mr Narendra Modi&rsquo;s statement about it being held up as a monument of failure. And people start working to really properly put it into place, and then think of improvements and see where things are not working and where they are to strengthen those that are working and to change those that are not.<br /><br />So, today marks a day after a long time when one can say that all parties are in agreement that NREGS has made a fundamental difference. All parties are in agreement that it is something that affects all people and now, the full page ads that the government is taking out, good idea, certainly to be welcomed, but we need to evaluate the government on how it is in real terms making a difference. One very big question is that this is a programme that is dependent on open budget. Today, there is huge demand and that is what the government is celebrating, the demand across the country and a turnaround from a terrible situation a year ago. That demand is not being met actually by the government. The demand for funds. <br /><br />14 states have a negative balance today. Mr Arun Jaitley, in his Budget, promised Rs 5,000 crore. Actually he should have promised whatever maybe demanded. But even that Rs 5,000 crore has not been provided. Only Rs 2,000 crore out of that Rs 5,000 crore has been released and therefore, there is a crisis even as the celebration is taking place. So, if the government were to at least say that okay, today if Mr Jaitley had said, I am releasing the Rs 5,000 crore, whatever more that may be needed in the remaining two months, we will give and now, let us get down to brass tacks to making sure that all the other things that need to work, work. That would have been great.<br /><br /><strong>Q: This government does have fiscal constraints like the previous government, but just to quote from the achievements that this government has highlighted, it says the highest expenditure on the NREGS has been recorded by the government in 2015-2016 so far compared to the last five years. And you are saying even that is not enough and the full quantum of what was promised or allocated in the Budget has not been passed on. This matter is now also in the Supreme Court, courtesy a public interest litigation (PIL) that has been filed by Aruna Roy on the government not being able to take forward the notification that was passed in February, 2014 claiming that the wages that were actually being given out are well below the minimum wages that have been fixed by state governments. Since we are talking about the road ahead now, what ought to be done at this stage?</strong><br /><br />A: There are two things. The first question itself that the claim of the government that this is the highest in five years, that is true but 2009-2010, the expenditure was Rs 39,400 crore. If you were to just index that to inflation, the NREGS budget today, in real terms, should be around Rs 61,000-62,000 crore. In place of that, we are still not at Rs 39,000 crore. We have allocated Rs 34,000 crore and another Rs 2,000 crore was released. So, the first most important thing that is there in that repetition as well, is that there must be absolutely meeting of the demand of NREGS. So, open ended budget must be made and if we were to only keep to 2009 levels, then we would be at a much higher level. The second issue you brought up about wages is again very important. The NREGA is not paying, the government is not paying the minimum wage in many parts of the country. <br /><br />And, the Minister of Rural Development in Parliament actually made a statement saying that minimum wages would be paid as per the recommendations of the Mahendra Dev Committee, a committee that was set up by the government. Whereas, that has not been implemented either. So, February 2 would have been a good time. It is a real irony, you cannot have a government running a programme and not paying minimum wages and there are 8-9 states where that is not being done. So, again, this would have been a very good opportunity for the government to say we will do, we will follow the law of the land, not just in NREGA, but also in minimum wages. <br /><br />The third issue in that PIL was actually timely payment of wages and timely payment of wages is again dependant. If you have 14 states without balance, then they are either going to go ahead and not employ anyone and the whole scheme will collapse, or they will employ them and pay wages much later when next year&rsquo;s Budget comes. So, next year&rsquo;s Budget is also crucial. Mr Jaitley came today, he celebrated NREGA, but he needs to make sure that he makes a statement next year firstly, giving enough money and secondly, saying that we will provide whatever may be needed. That is a key necessary condition for NREGA.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/m/mnrega_356x200_1804_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-02 21:15:55</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>