<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2016-fm-arun-jaitley-gives-small-tax-benefits-to-small-tax-payers_5668541.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: FM Arun Jaitley gives SMALL tax benefits to Small Tax Payers]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Section 87A benefit is hiked to Rs 5000 and a home loan interest benefit stand increased along with HRA limit.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />While announcing the Union Budget 2016, Finance minister Arun Jaitley mentioned relief to small tax payers as the first category of his tax proposals. He started with raising the ceiling of tax rebate under section 87A from Rs 2000 to Rs 5000. There are two crore tax payers in this category who will get a relief of Rs 3000 in their tax liability.<br /><br />Union Budget 2013-2014 had introduced a new Section 87A which allows a tax credit of special rebate of Rs 2000 to individuals whose net taxable income is below Rs 5 lakh. The rebate is limited to the extent of your tax liability or Rs 2000 whichever is less, for the current financial year. This means if you have a tax liability of Rs 1500, you will get a tax credit of Rs 1500 only. For FY 2016-2017 the same is hiked to Rs 5000.<br /><br />Finance Minister also increased the limit of deduction for rent paid under section 80GG from Rs 24000 to Rs 60000 per annum. This applies to those who do not own a house and also do not get a house rent allowance from the employer.<br /><br />Another positive announcement came on the National Pension Scheme(NPS). FM proposed to make withdrawal up to 40&nbsp;percent&nbsp;of the corpus at the time of retirement tax exempt in the case of NPS. Annuities paid by NPS are taxable in the hands of the annuitants. Tax treatment of the withdrawal is subject to tax as per extant regime. This new rule makes NPS more attractive now. <br /><br />&ldquo;Pension schemes offer financial protection to senior citizens. I believe that the tax treatment should be uniform for defined benefit and defined contribution pension plans,&rdquo; said Finance Minister Arun Jaitly, in his budget speech.<br /><br />In case of superannuation fund and recognized provident funds including EPF, the same norm of 40% of corpus to be tax free will apply for the corpus created after 1st April 2016. Also the annuity funds which go to the legal heir after the death of pensioner will not be taxable. <br /><br />The budget announcements do not offer much to individual tax payers, as compared to what was expected. Barring the increase of Rs 50000 in home loan interest payment, for houses priced below Rs 50 lakh for self occupied property, there is not much for taxpayers in Union Budget 2016.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/u/Union_Budget_2016_2_356X200_4020_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 13:50:29</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>