<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-refuelling-india’s-energy-growth_5308201.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Refuelling India’s energy growth]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The NDA Government appears to be very keen on setting this story right which is evident from the efforts being made by the oil ministry towards stakeholder participation in policy formulation. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Raju Kumar<br /></strong><strong><br /></strong>The fact that India&rsquo;s growth story will not be complete without ensuring energy security cannot arguably be disputed. However, as any other success story, it is very important to have a robust plan with a highly committed execution agenda backed by an investor-friendly policy framework.</p>
<p>The NDA Government appears to be very keen on setting this story right which is evident from the efforts being made by the oil ministry towards stakeholder participation in policy formulation. <br /><br />Conventional oil and gas has seen some policy movement in the form of increased gas pricing freedom and the intention to shift to revenue sharing from cost recovery model. This can be considered as a good step towards enabling a less regulated regime. <br /><br />However, a lot still needs to be done before the next new exploration licensing policy (NELP) auctions. Unviable cost of production in light of lower crude / gas prices, lack of pipeline connectivity and other infrastructure are the biggest challenges before the sector.</p>
<p>Policies like unified licensing are required to boost production. Economically unviable fields are expected to be brought into production post approval of the marginal fields policy &ndash; by granting a single license for exploring conventional and nonconventional hydrocarbons.</p>
<p>Additionally, given the lack of exploration in deep-water and ultra deep-water prospects, it is important that the government consider providing differential impetus to these areas. <br /><br />It is expected that the Government should offer fiscal incentives to promote technological advancements in these areas, obtain clearances from other government departments before offering these blocks and allow a longer term tax&nbsp;holiday which is&nbsp;equal to infrastructure projects (including providing clarity on availability of tax holiday on production of gas).</p>
<p>Apart from the above, it is equally important to renew focus on unconventional sources like shale gas and coal-bed methane (CBM). The draft shale gas policy for PSUs is yet to be finalised, given the tests being carried out on some blocks. <br /><br />Global experience also suggests that countries are giving tax incentives notably research and development (R&amp;D) credits and additional investment allowance for development and production from shale plays, which must be replicated in India given the fact that Shale is in the stage of infancy in this country.</p>
<p>To conclude, oil &amp; gas industry could be one of the largest contributors towards the&nbsp;<em>Make in India </em>vision and it will become a reality once a comprehensive plan is made and implemented for sustaining the energy needs of this country.</p>
<p><em>(The author is Tax Partner at EY India. Nikita Nanda, senior tax professional, EY contributed to the article. Views expressed are personal)</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/i/InfographicGE_IndiasCrudeOilImport_4940_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-04 15:48:12</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>