<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-fm-commits-to-containing-fiscal-deficit-at-35gdpfy17_5690361.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: FM commits to containing fiscal deficit at 3.5% of GDP in FY17]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Jaitley had set a tall target of containing India's fiscal deficit to 3.9 percent this fiscal year, 3.5 percent in FY17 and 3 percent in FY18]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Finance minister Arun Jaitley once again reiterated his commitment to containing fiscal deficit at 3.5 percent&nbsp;of GDP in FY17. He also said the government will be able to meet its FY16 fiscal deficit target at 3.9 percent of GDP.<br /><br />He also also sought to assure that the development agenda will not take a backseat and a committee would be set up to review the working of Fiscal Resposibility and Budget Management (FRBM).<br /><br />He said: "Different schools of thought have argued either in favour of fiscal consolidation and stability or for a less aggressive consolidation and for boosting growth. I have weighed the policy options and decided that prudence lies in adhering to the fiscal targets. Consequently, the fiscal deficit in RE 2015-16 and BE 2016-17 have been retained at 3.9 percent&nbsp;and 3.5 percent&nbsp;of GDP respectively. While doing so, I have ensured that the development agenda has not been compromised."<br /><br />Jaitley had set a tall target of containing India's fiscal deficit to 3.9 percent this fiscal year, 3.5 percent in FY17 and 3 percent in FY18.</p>
<p>In recent times, this 3.5 percent&nbsp;target had become the focus point of many a debates with many arguing that the government can loosen the fisc to push growth as long as the quality of the fisc is maintained. <br /><br />The Reserve Bank governor Raghuram Rajan on the other hand has repeatedly warned that such a move will be hazardous for India's long-term prospects and one must not look at short-term gains while foregoing long-term benefits.<br /><br /><em><strong>For entire presser watch accompanying videos..</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Rupee_up_down_fiscal_deficit_356x200_3409_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 12:10:51</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>