<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-niti-aayog-to-identify-public-cos-for-stake-salesays-panagariya_5703961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: NITI Aayog to identify public cos for stake sale,says Panagariya]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Arvind Panagariya, Vice-Chairman of NITI Aayog, however, declined any comment on whether the privatisation process will be extended to other profit making companies as well. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The NITI Aayog has&nbsp;been assigned the&nbsp;task of&nbsp;identifying&nbsp;the public sector units that need to be monetised and advise on how much needs to be divested, says Arvind Panagariya,&nbsp;Vice-Chairman of NITI&nbsp;Aayog.<br /><br />He, however, declined to&nbsp;comment&nbsp;on whether the privatisation&nbsp;process will be extended to profit making companies and kept only for lossmaking ones, saying it was too early to get into that.&nbsp;<br /><br />On the legal and related&nbsp;obstacles envisaged in exiting the divested units completed, like in the case of BALCO, Panagariya says, "When we get to this job, we are going to look at all the parameters. There are legal barriers as are being pointed out. Our job really is to quickly try to identify a few units with which we can proceed."<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Arvind Panagariya with Shereen Bhan of CNBC-TV.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: You have been tasked now to look at what we can do as far as the strategic stake sale policy is concerned, the Finance Minster saying that the Niti Aayog will decide which candidates, the Niti Aayog will decide what Central Public Sector Enterprises (CPSE) should monetise so on and so forth. When can we expect the blueprint for strategic sales?</strong><br /><br />A: We have been assigned the task. But what we have been assigned is the first step towards this strategic sale. So, we identify the PSUs, the specific units that have been prioritised and we suggest how much to disinvest. The rest of it then goes to the ministries concerned, etc. So, we plan to move pretty rapidly. Actually, I have started talking to some of the people who understand this area better.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Within government or outside of government?</strong><br /><br />A: I am trying to pick the brains of those who know this field well, also outside the government. I just want to know, because there was a disinvestment commission before and therefore there is some knowledge as to how exactly we should identify the specific units, how much to disinvest and so forth. So, we are already on the job.<br /><br /><strong>Q: So, we are talking about privatisation and the Minister of State for Finance also clarifying that it is not just going to be limited to loss making PSUs, it will include profit making public sector companies as well.</strong><br /><br />A: That we have to wait and see. We have to do the full assessment of what are the good candidates and certainly, in certain areas, they are regarded as strategic for the government, disinvestment will not take place.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Which I would imagine a thing like defence, etc. But outside of that, is everything on the table? What would be the driving parameters?</strong><br /><br />A: Let us not jump the gun.<br /><br /><strong>Q: What would be the driving parameters as far as this strategic stake sale policy is concerned?</strong><br /><br />A: All that requires identification, thinking, discussions, so let me not take a position on that just yet.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Let me ask you this. We have had the government get out of companies like BALCO in the past, but still not be able to give up the residual stake that the government holds, even though there is a willing buyer. There are all kinds of issues, of course, litigation, and then you do not know whether the Mines and Minerals (Development and Regulation) (MMDR) Act requires to be amended, so on and so forth. What are the obstacles that you envisage on account of this?</strong><br /><br />A: Now, when we get to this job, we are going to look at all the parameters, all the possibilities, including the one that you have just pointed out, shares in the PSUs that have been privatised now, but we will take a call at that stage. Now, there are also legal barriers as you are pointing out, those also we have to identify. But our job really is to quickly try to identify a few units with which we can proceed.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Can you give us a broad timeline by when we could expect that first list being finalised or at least by when we could expect a guideline in a sense to be finalised?</strong><br /><br />A: No, at this stage, I will not speculate.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Let me then ask you as far as the overall Budget is concerned and we had this conversation on the day of the economic survey and it seems like it has panned out the way that we spoke. It is a Budget that is focused very clearly and very squarely, on the agriculture sector and its effort to try and revive rural economy. Do you believe that the Finance Minister has delivered on that front?</strong><br /><br />A: Very well so. There is broad sight to it which is that whereas urban demand has actually kicked off reasonably well, rural demand has been tepid, so the Budget also tries to address that. But in addition, I think it is a very specific measure that the Budget takes towards rural electrification, rural roads, towards irrigation, towards building a supply chain from farm to the market. So, large number of very specific measures to revive the rural economy and then also to bring relief to the poor. So, there is health insurance for the below poverty line (BPL) households and there is also for the female members of the households who are doing most of the cooking in households where bio fuel is used predominantly, there is the promise to bring LPG to them.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/banking_Rupee_note_budget_2016_356x200_4651_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 18:37:01</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>