<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/60-80-mkt-damage-done-expectationsbudget-low-khemani_5538741.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[60-80% mkt damage done; expectations from Budget low: Khemani]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Despite the current global volatility and the resultant India impact, Vikas Khemani of Edelweiss Securities has not seen any domestic redemptions. Though he says there is a slowdown in domestic inflows]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>While the current market mood is a little pessimistic, the long-term outlook continues to be positive, says Vikas Khemani of Edelweiss Securities. "Since the mood was bullish for quite some time, most investors didn't see this global volatility coming and hence are not sitting on too much cash to buy now," he told CNBC-TV18. Investors are still struggling with losses, he adds.</p>
<p>However, he believes that 80% of the damage is done, though the mood has shifted to sell on rallies from buy on dips. But then again, market mood changes very fast, he adds.</p>
<p>Despite the current global volatility and the resultant India impact, Khemani has not seen any domestic redemptions. Though, he says, there is a slowdown in domestic inflows. He believes this is the best time to increase investments. Having said that, he also expects to see another 3-6 months of uncertain environment and volatile markets.</p>
<p>On the upcoming Budget, he says the market is not expecting much from it. "It is well sensitised to the constraints that the government is working with," Khemani adds. The market, according to him, is only looking for directional moves from the government as to how it plans to revive the economy, especially rural India,&nbsp;and is hoping that it doesn't hear any destabilising calls on the lines of rumours surrounding long-term capital gains, among others.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Vikas Khemani&rsquo;s interview with Latha Venkatesh and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Latha: What is the mood looking like; did people express a feeling that there was value yesterday around that 6,900 mark? Any interest at all? </strong><br /><br />A: I think there is definitely sense of value, sense that the long-term outlook is good but right now most of the people who have been invested into market all along are struggling with the current portfolios and handling their portfolio losses. I think in that sense mood is slightly concerned or pessimist. <br /><br />I think it clearly depends and I don&rsquo;t think there are many investors who are sitting on huge amount of liquidity to kind of buy at this point in time because I think mood has been bullish for quite some time and what we saw, the kind of volatility which came from the global markets, in some sense was unexpected or in some senses most people did not predict and that is by and large kind of determining the mood.<br /><br />Even the institutional investors who were there at our conference, I think most of the people especially the foreign institutional investors (FIIs), are struggling with outflows which they are getting into in the emerging market funds. So, in that kind of situation, even if your view is that there is not too much downside from here in the market or large part of the damage is done, I would tend to believe that maybe 60-80 percent damage is done, I think only last bit left and now we have to wait and watch how long it will take, is it more time correction or is it more value correction. However, broadly large part of the damage is done. So, in that situation now people are taking stock, reviewing their portfolio.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: The question is in the immediate term are your high net worth individuals (HNI) clients or clients in general so deep in losses or so wanting to payback even margins that they will use every rally to actually offload. Is that likely to be the first reaction? </strong><br /><br />A: I think the mood has definitely shifted from buy on dips to sell on rallies. That mood is definitely there. However, the way I have seen is that mood changes very fast in the market, so, today let us say some global announcements come, we had yesterday good events, so all those things can change the mood quite rapidly. <br /><br />So, I am not very worried about. Good part is that everybody is positive on India from a medium-term to long-term perspective. I think you have to overcome this current ongoing volatility infused specifically by the global markets.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: Your tone is very similar to what you had spoken about the last time we had a dealing room check with you. Are you noticing a lot of redemption pressure from retail? I ask you this because after six long years we saw some confidence return into retail last year but now are you noticing a lot of calls for redemption on domestic?</strong><br /><br />A: Good part about that is that we have not seen any domestic outflows or domestic redemption but the inflows which were coming in have slowed down and that is natural. Specifically the retail investor or investors don&rsquo;t like to scale up their investments when markets are falling and specifically in this kind of environment. However, ironically this is the best time to scale it up but nobody can blame investors because I think the environment is right now fairly gloomy from what you hear. <br /><br />However, the good news is that it is SIP, it is long-term sustainable so I think the trend is continuing, it is not negative. The pace of flows have slowed down but it is not negative yet and I don&rsquo;t think it is changing because this is a long-term retail small investment which is coming and the savings are getting to the markets in a structural manner. So, I don&rsquo;t think it is changing to negative anytime soon. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: What did your investors, both domestic and global, tell you at the conference? Is this a low expectation Budget so no monstrous pre-Budget rally and monstrous post-Budget sell-off, can we go with that kind of an assumption? What would your assumption be?</strong> <br /><br />A: Good part is that there are no expectations or the expectations have kind of got toned down significantly. Things are always good when expectations are low because then the disappointment would be low. The only thing the market is going to watch out is that how this government is going to balance because there is a lot of demand on the government in terms of spending and at the same time the tax collections are kind of slow and revenues are not sort of looking rosy, so, how they are going to balance. <br /><br />However, at the same time markets are also sensitized with the limitations they are working within. So, I don&rsquo;t think there are many expectations. In fact markets are saying that as long as something de-stabilising is not done then we are okay. Like you would know that rumours of long-term capital gains and all those things are happening so if they don&rsquo;t happen I think market would be happy. So, market is well sensitized I would say.<br /><br />However, at the same time, market would look for some sort of guidance, some sort of that how they are going to pump prime the economy from a structural perspective especially the rural economy. On that part I think there are some expectations that government will do something to boost the rural economic demand or have some spending in that part of the economy.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: What is your advice to all the investors who are watching you right now, is this a time to perhaps buy in or just better to wait till the Budget passes and if you are advising buying now then what sectors are you looking at?</strong> <br /><br />A: The way I look at it is volatility is not behind us and Budget is just one more event. So, I don&rsquo;t think Budget is the only way to look at markets from a buying perspective. We will have still three to six months of uncertain environment specifically from global side. Right now policymakers are kind of worrying about how to settle it down and there will be lot of measures done I would like to believe. You might see a sort of market stability coming in but this problem is not going to go in a hurry. <br /><br />However, this is the best time I think as far as India is concerned in my opinion to build your exposure towards equity because whatever is happening, structurally things are moving. So many corporate&rsquo;s we meet, ground level things have started, green shoots are visible now. It is only matter of time that they will start reflecting into the earnings, maybe six months away, maybe nine months away &ndash; I do not know but green shoots are definitely visible. &nbsp;<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: Where are you seeing green shoots because yesterday we were speaking with the management of Britannia, Varun Berry, and he said that demand is still very subdued especially in the rural markets, where are you noticing green shoots?</strong> <br /><br />A: Green shoots are largely coming from the investment side. If you speak to EPC company, if you speak to cement company, if you speak to companies into irrigation sector, they are saying the outlook is very positive. In fact the order book which is the lead indicator of any EPC company, is a lead indicator according to me, and it is only matter of time that it will start reflecting into topline and bottomline. They are busy and that is what India needs right now. <br /><br />So, in my opinion likes of Britannia and all, they have had good years for like four to five years so a) their base is high and no doubt that rural demand is slow but I think there is reason behind that. We had two years of bad monsoon, if monsoon hopefully picks up this year, I see natural revival of demand coming through in the rural part of the economy. We have had poor commodity prices, low government spending and bad monsoon, all together; I don&rsquo;t see this continuing for long.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: It is good to hear because for the last six months or eight months we have only heard people speaking about urban consumption and consumption plays. You would think that they are overvalued and that you would now start looking for value in capital goods?</strong> <br /><br />A: Yes we have been quite constructive about capital goods sector because look at capital expenditure which is planned whether it is railways, roads and somebody has got to do this and it is not in air, there are concrete plans there and they are being awarded, funding is organised so they are not talks only. <br /><br />So, it is only matter of time it will start reflecting and I do believe that people get surprised the kind of growth this sector can deliver. Right now again it is getting sort of marred by the sentiment but that is our job to overlook the sentiment and look at beyond sentiments and fundamentals and then evaluate stocks. <br /><br /><strong>Sonia: I wanted your view on banks especially on PSU banks. A lot of efforts are being made by government, by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to solve the stressed assets issue or to at least improve it. So far banks are at new lows but what do you do with this space now?</strong> <br /><br />A: It is going through tough time but I think Rajan spoke in one of his interviews about what is the AQR plan and this has been in work for quite some time and coincidently it has got hit around the global volatility and all those things. So, it has been felt in little bit more impact but I do believe that in some sense it is once uncertainty is behind, market will start looking forward because markets always look forward. <br /><br />So, if markets know that this is the pain and if you look in US, when the stress test of the banking sector happened, after that banking sector did very well. However, till the time Fed did not do that, there was uncertainty, we do not know how much more pain is there. So, I think RBI is in some sense in my opinion conducting similar stress test kind of situation in Indian banking sector. <br /><br />Once you know that what is the pain, investors can factor in whatever and we are trying to do from our research similar exercise, you will soon see that out that what could be the biggest pain, what could be the impact on the earnings over next three to four years and how you should see now the sector and you&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; will see in next 8-10 days that being out. So everybody is trying to see what is the end and then you kind of look forward.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: What about drug stocks because we got this news from <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/cipla/C">Cipla</a> completing its acquisition and the combined revenue for InvaGen and Exelan was USD 230 million. So, this is some news coming in from Cipla. Basically drug stocks, do you think they have been beaten down enough?</strong><br /><br />A: This whole segment is going through interesting phase in terms of clean up of or FDA wanting them to upgrade their facilities to meet the international standard, they are tightening the norms and we are going through the pain related to that. However from a longer term perspective, this is very good for setting the base for a nice foundation of long-term. We do believe that pharmaceutical sector, the kind of chemistry skills we have, the kind of skill set India has it could become a very large sector, it could become even larger than IT sector. <br /><br />So in that sense I feel that it is a nice cleanup, foundation building happening and which is creating pain in the system but good companies will come out, good companies will scale up and we remain very constructive on the sector. Obviously you have to look at company which can live up to this kind of scrutiny and the regulatory aspects and there are companies which are gearing up so we are very positive on the overall segment.<br /><br /><em>(Interview transcribed by Priyanka Deshpande)</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/b/BSE_Sensex_Indian_Markets_nifty_midcap__stock_356x200_4753_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-18 09:16:33</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,C,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>