<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-fm-maintains-status-quofy17-bk-recapitalisation-at-rs-25k-cr_5678721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: FM maintains status quo on FY17 bk recapitalisation at Rs 25k cr]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In their pre-Budget expectation list, most industry experts had expressed hope that the funding is not only hiked but also front-loaded as the deadline set for cleaning up of balance sheets is March 2017.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Shweta Mungre</strong><br /><em>money<strong>control.com</strong></em><br /><br />The Finance Minister, in his second full year Budget announced on Monday, maintained status quo&nbsp;on the recapitalisation limit for public sector banks at Rs 25000 crore, even while stating that the government remains committed&nbsp;to easing off the stress in the banking system and will be open&nbsp;to fund further, if&nbsp;needed.<br /><br />He also announced&nbsp;that the Bankruptcy code will introduced in the Parliament in FY17.and that RBI Act will be amended to provide framework for monetory policy code.&nbsp;<br /><br />Highlighting that the Bank Board Bureau will be operationalized during 2016-17 and a roadmap for consolidation of public banks&nbsp;will be spelt out, the FM said, the process of transformation of IDBI Bank has already started and the government consider the option of reducing its stake to below 50 percent.</p>
<p>In their pre-Budget expectation list, most industry experts had expressed hope that the funding is not only hiked but also front-loaded as the deadline set for cleaning up of balance sheets is March 2017.<br /><br />Considering the rising stress on the public sector banking system, the government, in mid-2015, had announced capital infusion of Rs 70000 crore into these banks over four years up to FY19, in four tranches of 25,000 crore each for FY16 and FY17 and Rs 10,000 crore each for the following two fiscals.<br /><br />The Macro-Economic Survey tabled on Friday had also highlighted that the trouble exists on twin balance sheets, one being corporate India and the other the banks that have lent to them, the survey pointed out that between FY10 and the first half of FY16, there has been total capital infusion of nearly Rs. 1.02 lakh crore in some banks put together.</p>
<p>Comprehensively resolving this challenge would require 4 Rs: Recognition, Recapitalization, Resolution, and Reform, the Survey had noted.</p>
<p>In 2014-15, the government ended up infusing only about Rs 6,990 crore, compared to the budgeted Rs 11,200 crore. Similarly, despite the mounting worry, the initial budgeted allocation for 2015-16 was only Rs 7,940 crore.&nbsp; The restriction on funds access to poorly managed banks might still keep credit growth subdued and not alter the situation much.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/banking_Rupee_note_budget_2016_356x200_4651_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 12:05:46</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>