<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/cnbc-tv18-comments/budget-2016-eliminate-dividend-taxreits-experts-say_5516981.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Eliminate dividend tax on REITs, experts say]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Developers say that more clarity on policy parameters like taxation before jumping on board.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Over a year ago, market regulator SEBI cleared the way for Real Estate Investment Trust (REIT) listings in India to help developers take advantage of the massive rental income potential in the country -- up to Rs 52,000 crore according to some estimates. This would also reduce the risks involved in real estate investments. <br /><br />But developers say they want more clarity on policy parameters like taxation before jumping on board.<br /><br />&ldquo;The government has done a lot to push for REITs but the taxation issues still persist. We are hoping that this budget addresses those issues and then we will definitely see multiple REIT listings come out,&rdquo; says Ajit Kumar Chordia, President CREDAI, Chennai.<br /><br />The key tax at play here is Dividend Distribution Tax (DDT), since REITs essentially allow investors to pool money to buy listed units of real estate properties and using rental income from these projects to pay dividend. This means 15 percent of the dividend paid out goes to the taxman.<br /><br />Now globally, DDT has not been much of an issue because REITs offer much higher returns than fixed instruments in banks. But that gap is so low in India that there is no incentive for investors to move money from fixed deposits to REITs. <br /><br />&ldquo;The application of DDT takes away from the attractiveness of REITs as fixed instruments are providing competitive coupon rates. This is why developers want the government to do away with it,&rdquo; says Shobhit Agarwal, MD - capital markets at JLL. <br /><br />However, tax experts say removing REITs from the DDT net may not be a viable option for the government.<br /><br />Hemal Zobalia, Tax partner at Deloitte says: &ldquo;Honestly, while the industry is asking for reduction in there, it seems difficult to happen because if you take mutual funds and AIF, there's no such exception. If you treat REITs on par with mutual funds, it possibly looks difficult for the DDT to come under a waiver in this budget.&rdquo;<br /><br />Apart from a DDT waiver, players hope budget 2016 will bring clarity on a few unintentional anomalies as well -- like a 3-year lock-in period when most equity mutual funds work with a 12-month lock-in period.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/r/realty3_4028_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-16 21:56:26</Entry_Date><Category>CNBC-TV18 Comments</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>