<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-uday-kotak-happyfms-fiscal-deficit-target35_5692221.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Uday Kotak happy with FM's fiscal deficit target of 3.5%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Uday Kotak, Executive VC & MD, Kotak Mahindra Bank is slightly disappointed with the FM keeping the bank recapitalisation at Rs 25,000 core but is glad that the government has stuck to fiscal plan with 3.5% fiscal deficit target. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Uday Kotak, Executive VC &amp; MD, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/kotakmahindrabank/KMB">Kotak Mahindra Bank </a>is slightly disappointed with the FM keeping the bank recapitalisation at Rs 25,000 core but is glad that the government has stuck to fiscal plan with 3.5% fiscal deficit target.</p>
<p>Maintaining fiscal deficit target at 3.5% in spite of outlays for 7th pay Commission and OROP is very positive.</p>
<p>According to him the bond markets have seen a huge relief though the stock market seems to have taken some measures has negative.</p>
<strong>Below is the verbatim transcript</strong><br /><br /><strong>Udayan: The market is down, bank stocks are down very sharply because of just a Rs 25,000 crore recap and not a credible plan to fix this whole banking assert problem. Are you disappointed? Would you have expected more in this Budget given that there has been so much trouble around it?</strong><br /><br />Kotak: The fact that the government has had the courage to control deficit at 3.5 percent down from 3.9 percent this year with higher Pay Commission and One Rank, One Pension (OROP) itself is a very significant thing for Indian bond markets in particular. And we underestimate the impact of bonds on equity markets and this is a huge relief to the bond markets, you can see bond yields having dropped significantly. And I would strongly encourage people to keep in mind that there is a trade off between some of the areas where tax is collected versus a very significant discipline in the light of what has happened. <br /><br />On the specific issue of bank recapitalisation, I would have liked to see a little more, but I am sure that between RBI and the government, they have a game plan and I would expect the RBI to respond to the fact that the government has maintained its discipline with some sort of a response very soon.<br /><br /><strong>Udayan: The other thing which might have led to a big disappointment in the market is the slew of new taxes. First, the dividend distribution tax of 10 percent coming in on dividends above 10 percent, additional securities transaction tax (STT), and then the large corporates continue to pay 30 percent tax. That 1 percent deduction has not kicked from them this year. How do you see these three in the light of the market&rsquo;s disappointment?</strong><br /><br />Kotak: I think there is a trade off which has been done to maintain 3.5 percent. Personally, I do believe dividend distribution tax plus tax in the hands of the individuals, both are double taxation because the same income is being taxed in the hands of the corporate in the first place. <br /><br />Having said that, we are where we are and if the trade off was that a little more money is paid by higher income brackets, versus fiscal discipline, the trade off has been made by the government. And I respect the trade off though I personally may not like it.<br /><br /><strong><em>Watch the video for the entire discussion</em></strong>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/u/Union_Budget_2016_2_356X200_4020_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 13:00:22</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,KMF,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>