<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/24x7booking/hello-gst-positivesnegatives-forinfrastructure-sector_4913961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Hello GST: Positives and negatives for the infrastructure sector]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In a CNBC-TV18’s special series ‘Hello GST!” Menaka Doshi today discusses the impact of the Goods & Services Tax (GST) on the infrastructure sector. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[In a CNBC-TV18&rsquo;s special series, "Hello GST!", Menaka Doshi today discusses the impact of the Goods &amp; Services Tax (GST) on the infrastructure sector. <br /><br />Pratik Shah, Partner &amp; Head &ndash; Indirect Tax Practice at SKP, says that currently infrastructure projects cannot claim credit for taxes paid on inputs and capital expenses, which are a part&nbsp;of&nbsp;the total cost. <br /><br />GST will provide for credits in all segments, making it advantageous for the sector by reducing cost and working capital requirements. <br /><br />V Lakshmikumaran, Managing Partner at Lakshmikumaran &amp; Sridharan says that currently, certain major infrastructure projects are given exemptions under service tax, which under GST will be under input taxes. These input taxes will be added costs for the project. <br /><br />Besides this, the law will also have clear classification on&nbsp;what will be considered as &lsquo;goods&rsquo; and as &lsquo;services&rsquo;, which does not exist in the current system. <br /><br />The clear cut definitions will help reduce litigation and bring more clarity into the system, Shah says. <br /><br />However, Shah expects the various exemptions like excise duty, service tax and VAT, available to the sector under the current schemes, to be pruned under the GST. <br /><br />Rate of tax although is expected to be in range of 12-18 percent, which could increase tax rate on infrastructure projects, especially if supply chain is not optimized. <br /><br />Another advantage under GST would be that &lsquo;goods&rsquo; and &lsquo;service&rsquo; should zero-rated and taxes paid on input services should available as refund,&nbsp;Lakshmikumaran says.&nbsp;<br /><br /><strong><em>Watch video for more.</em></strong>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/g/GST_shutterstock_356x200_0826_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-11 16:05:28</Entry_Date><Category>24X7booking</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>