<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2016-indirect-transfers-–-need-to-rationalise-law_5661901.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Indirect transfers – need to rationalise law]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Backdrop of the amendment in 2012 was to cover large and strategic transactions which could result in change in control and management of Indian companies but cannot be taxed as they do not have direct nexus with India. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Alok Mundra&nbsp;</strong></em><br /><br />The Finance Act, 2012 introduced retrospective amendment to levy capital gains tax on indirect transfers of Indian capital asset where substantial value of transaction happening in overseas entity is derived from India. However since many terms in the amended law were not defined, it resulted in higher uncertainty in the context of international M&amp;A transactions. The most common issues which surfaced are, how one should determine substantial value, how one can attribute capital gains to India where overseas company have other assets across the world, computation mechanism of capital gains and attribution thereof to India, applicable tax rate, how does one look at multilayer structure where transfer might take place as part of group reorganization without change in the ultimate ownership at group level etc.<br /><br />In order to dispel concerns raised on account of GAAR, Government of India has appointed a committee under the chairmanship of Dr. Shome. In order to deal with the concern raised by various stakeholders on interpretation issues on indirect transfer law, the same committee was asked to provide suggestions. Eventually, few recommendations have found place in statute in 2015 through insertion of new explanations.<br /><br />In the interim, one of the issue &lsquo;substantial value&rsquo; was defined by the Delhi High Court in a writ filed in 2014 against the Moody&rsquo;s-Copal Advance Ruling. The Delhi High Court, dismissed the writ by upholding the Authority for Advance Ruling (AAR) order in favour of the taxpayer. In arriving at the conclusion, the Court, relied on the provisions of the Direct Taxes Code Bill 2010, recommendations of the Dr Shome Committee, and other international commentaries (i.e. OECD and UN Conventions), to observe that a 50% threshold should be applied to determine &lsquo;substantial value&rsquo;. Government has included same threshold in the statue and removed ambiguity surrounding the term &lsquo;substantial value&rsquo;.<br /><br />In order to avoid potential and unwarranted litigations in future, Government through budget 2016, needs to provide further clarification around various aspects of indirect transfer. One such area is to widen the ambit of exemption on group reorganisation beyond amalgamation and demergers. Often group reorganisation in the overseas jurisdiction may take place through simple transfer of shares and same may not be taxable in that jurisdiction. Further such transfers may not result in any change in the ultimate beneficial interest of the group but still such transfers do not enjoy exemption from taxability in India. Even in the case of amalgamation and demerger, exemption is restricted to only companies involved in the restructuring therefore such exemption need to be extended to the shareholders who would receive shares in the surviving entity in lieu of extinguishment of their shares in the other company.<br /><br />Backdrop of the amendment in 2012 was to cover large and strategic transactions which could result in change in control and management of Indian companies but cannot be taxed as they do not have direct nexus with India. Therefore, investors were demanding that there should be certain threshold and transaction below such threshold should be not covered by amended provisions. In 2015, Government provided certain exemption but it was restricted to situation where seller neither has management and control in overseas entity nor indirectly owns more than 5% voting power in relation to company which owns asset in India. The limit of 5% condition is not in consonance with other condition of management right or control and therefore if this limit is enhanced to 26% it can bring similarity in both the conditions for exemption.<br /><br />Currently law provides broad principle in determining how fair value to be calculated which requires to take into account fair value of assets (tangible and intangible) without factoring liabilities. It is well accepted principle that shareholders will get the value for net value of company after factoring the liabilities of the company. Therefore, law can remove this discrepancy. Government can adopt similar valuation mythology as provided in section 56(2)(viib) of income tax act which provides options to shareholders to use different methods including net asset method. <br /><br />Law also recognises the fair allocation of tax which is attributable to Indian assets. However currently no specific methodology is prescribed for allocation of such income and therefore it is important that computation method of capital gains and method to allocate the gain attributable to Indian assets to be provided to avoid disputes on tax liability.<br /><br />Budget 2016, is opportunity for government to consider various recommendations suggested by Dr. Shome Committee to bring much needed clarity in interpretation of law impacting indirect transfer. <br /><br /><em><strong>Author is Partner, Tax, KPMG in India </strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>The views and opinions expressed herein are those of the author and do not necessarily represent the views and opinions of KPMG International or KPMG in India.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/u/Union_Budget_2016_3_356X200_4040_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 10:00:21</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>