<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-tax-easing-to-bring-cheers-to-fmcg-sector-says-ey_5328921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Tax easing to bring cheers to FMCG sector, says EY]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[While it is expected that the service tax rates could be increased to bridge the gap with the tax rates under the proposed GST regime, the FMCG sector is hoping that the Budget does not contribute to higher tax rates and keep the service tax rates at the present rate of 14 percent.
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Aashish Kasad</strong>, <br /><strong>Partner and India Tax Leader<br />Retail and&nbsp;Consumer Products Sector, EY</strong></em><br /><br />The fast moving consumer goods (FMCG) sector, one of the prominent contributors to India's Gross Domestic Product (GDP) annually, has been witnessing challenging times in the current fiscal year on account of several factors including weak monsoons, declining commodity prices, intense price competition, etc.<br /><br />The government has taken certain steps to encourage investment by relaxing license rules and easing conditions of foreign investment regulations in the space.<br /><br /> However, given the challenging business environment, the industry is seeking government support to fuel the demand engine through various Budget proposals.<br /><br />A move which could see a shift in the long-term indirect tax policy, introducing the&nbsp;Goods and Services Tax (GST) is one of the key priorities of the government and is sure to bring both certainty and cheer. <br /><br />The sector would eagerly look forward to having a more inclusive and less restrictive Cenvat credit rules which would help plug the leakage of tax credits. <br /><br />While it is expected that the service tax rates could be increased to bridge the gap with the tax rates under the proposed GST regime, the FMCG sector is hoping that the Budget does not contribute to higher tax rates and keep the service tax rates at the present rate of 14 percent.<br /><br />The FMCG sector has generated employment for millions over the years and the Budget 2015 incentivised further employment generation through a positive amendment to the employment-linked tax incentive. <br /><br />Budget 2016 could provide an impetus to the Skill India movement by incentivising corporates to directly skill labour by incorporating more business friendly enabling provisions.<br /><br />Incentivising innovation and research in developing world-class quality products could enable the Indian FMCG sector achieve higher growth. The government could consider reviewing the Eleventh Schedule to reduce the negative list of products in this regard.<br /><br />Corporates have been keen to backward integrate the supply chain and support farmers by directly purchasing agricultural products, which would risk mitigate farmers from the vagaries of weather and provide them with more predictable prices for their produce. Tax incentives on such backward integrated operations by companies could support the agro-industry in also reducing cost inflation on processed food items. <br /><br />Lastly, there have been big-ticket tax litigation surrounding expenses such as royalty, AMP spend, cost allocations, etc. where the government could consider pro-actively issuing guidelines to curb conflicts, uncertainties and unwarranted litigation. <br /><br />The FMCG sector sincerely hopes that the Finance Minister (FM) will recommend some tax-friendly measures to positively stimulate the business environment and uplift industry sentiment.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/budget_2016_356X200_2750_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-05 15:29:00</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>