<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/macro-economic-survey-2016-sensex100-pts-fy16-subsidy-bill-could-to-be-below-2gdp_5660381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Macro Economic Survey 2016: Sensex up 100 pts; FY16 subsidy bill could to be below 2% of GDP]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Bank Nifty gained more than 1 percent after the government, in its Economic Survey 2016-17 says it has given power to banks to recover money from debt ridden promoters.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><strong><strong><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /><br />1:00 pm </strong></strong></strong></strong>Equity benchmarks remained strong after Macro Economic Survey. The Sensex rose 165.92 points to 23141.92 and the Nifty advanced 52.80 points to 7023.40, led by banks.<br /><br />PNB, Bank of Baroda, HDFC Bank and Axis Bank gained 1-2.6 percent. Major lender SBI rallied 3.5 percent.<strong><strong><strong><strong><br /><br />12:59 pm </strong></strong></strong></strong>NITI Aayog- vice chairman Arvind Panagariya says twin balancesheet problems cannot be solved by single instrument.<br /><br />According to him, the government should allow 100 percent FDI in asset reconstruction companies.<br /><strong><strong><strong><br />12:57 pm </strong></strong></strong>Increase in wages and benefits recommended by the 7th pay commission are not likely to destabilise prices and will have little impact on inflation, says the government.<br /><br />Four R - recognition, recapitalization, resolution, and reform are required to comprehensively resolve the twin balance sheet challenge of public sector banks (psbs) and some corporate houses, it adds.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:54 pm </strong></strong>NITI Aayog- vice chairman Arvind Panagariya&nbsp;says Marco Economic survey is recognising instability seen in global economies.<br /><br />The government maintaining fiscal deficit target set for FY17 will be taken positively<strong>,</strong> he adds.<strong><br /><br />12:51 pm Industrial sector growth: </strong>Government says advance estimates of national income 2015-16 shows that the growth of industrial sector is estimated to be 7.3 percent with manufacturing sector growing at 9.5 percent. <br /><strong><strong><br />12:48 pm </strong></strong>"The current account deficit has declined and foreign exchange reserves have risen to USD 351.5 billion in early February 2016," the Finance Ministry tweets.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:43 pm </strong></strong>FM says average bank borrowings have risen sharply post hike in US Fed rate.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:40 pm Subsidy burden: </strong></strong>Government says total subsidy bill is expected to be below 2 percent&nbsp;of GDP in FY16.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:36 pm Market Update</strong></strong>: The 30-share BSE Sensex rose 119.93 points or 0.52 percent to 23095.93 and the 50-share NSE Nifty climbed 37.80 points or 0.54 percent to 7008.40.<br /><br />Bank Nifty gained more than 1 percent after the government, in its Economic Survey 2016-17 says it has given power to banks to recover money from debt ridden promoters.<br /><br />It further says corporate and bank balancesheets remain stressed. <br />Underlying stressed assets in corporate sector must be sold or rehabilitated, it advises.<br /><br />Govt could sell some non financial cos to recapitalisation of&nbsp;PSU banks.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:34 pm Risk to higher inflation arises </strong></strong>if wage hikes spill to private sector, says the government, adding it expects RBI to meet 5 percent inflation target by March 2017.<strong><br /><br />12:32 pm Exports slow down</strong> may continue for a while before picking up in FY17, says government, adding oil prices spike may drag consumption and hurt monetary easing prospects.<strong><br /><br />12:29 pm </strong>Government says underlying stressed assets in corporate sector must be sold or rehabilitated.<br /><br />Growth will face considerable headwinds if global demand remains weak, it adds.<strong><br /><br />12:27 pm Tax revenue </strong>likely to be higher than bugeted levels in FY16<br /><strong><br />12:25 pm </strong>Govt could sell-off certain non financial companies to recap PSU banks<strong><br /><br />12:24 pm Monetary policy: </strong>Government says effective stance on monetary policy could be relaxed. It expects RBI to meet 5 percent inflation target by March 2017.<strong><br /><br />12:22 pm </strong>Global volatilities' impact on rupee to be less than other emerging market economies<strong><br /><br />12:20 pm CPI inflation: </strong>Finance minister Arun Jaitley says FY17 CPI inflation is expected to be in range of 4.5-5 percent.<strong><br /><br />12:15 pm </strong>Government says corporate and bank balancesheets remain stressed.&nbsp;<strong><br /><br />12:13 pm Fiscal Framework: </strong>The government says time is right for a review of medium-term fiscal framework as it committed to fiscal consolidation.<br /><strong><br />12:10 pm Fundamental task of Budget: </strong>The government says current fundamental task of Budget is to preserve fiscal sustainability, adding 7th pay&nbsp;commission recommendations complicated FY17 fiscal task.<br /><br />Govt is need to be in a strong position to repay debt of today and public investment needs to be increased further.<strong><br /><br />12:07 pm CAD</strong>: Govt sees FY17 current account deficit at 1-1.5 percent&nbsp;of GDP.<br /><br />It expects 8 percent&nbsp;economic growth in next couple of years.<br /><br />It&nbsp;proposes widening tax net from 5.5 percent&nbsp;of earning individuals to over 20 percent.<strong><br /><br />12:05 pm Fiscal deficit</strong>: The government says FY16 fiscal deficit of 3.9 percent&nbsp;seems acheivable but&nbsp;FY17 is expected to be challenging from fiscal point of view.<br /><br />It sees medium-term growth trajectory at 7-7.75 percent&nbsp;with downside risks&nbsp;due to global economic condition.<strong><br /><br />12:00 pm Market Check</strong><br /><br />The market continued to trade marginally higher in noon trade with the Sensex rising 55.91 points to 23031.91 and the Nifty up 17.10 points to 6987.70.<br /><br />The market breadth remained weak as about two shares declined for every share advancing on the BSE.<br /><br />The government has tabled Macro Economic Survey 2016-17 in parliament. According to sources, the government expects FY17 GDP growth at 7-7.5 percent.<strong><br /></strong>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_markets_nse_bse_stock_markets_356x200_3132_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 12:00:50</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>