<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-fm-announces-plan-expenditure-at-rs-55-lk-cr_5690861.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: FM announces plan expenditure at Rs 5.5 lk cr]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The higher allocation is on account of the implementation of One Rank One Pension (OROP) and 7th Pay Commission]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Finance minister Arun Jaitley has announced a 15.3 percent increase in&nbsp;plan expenditure to Rs 5.5&nbsp;lakh crore in Budget 2016-17. He also pegged non-plan expenditure at Rs 14.28 lakh crore, taking total expenditure to Rs 19.78 lakh crore.<br /><br />Jaitley said in his Budget speech: "Plan allocations have given special emphasis to sectors such as agriculture, irrigation, social sector including health, women and child development, welfare of scheduled castes and scheduled tribes, minorities, infrastructure, etc."</p>
<p>The higher allocation is also on the back of implementation of One Rank One Pension (OROP) and recommendations of the 7th Pay Commission.</p>
<p>As expected, the finance minister also spoke about doing away with plan and non-plan expenditure from FY18. The focus will be on distinction between capital and revenue expenditure, he said. At an earlier meeting, Union Finance Secretary Ratan Watal had said that the government was mulling doing away with plan and non-plan expenditure in order to link expenditure to outcome more efficiently and instead replace it with 'capital and revenue' spending.</p>
<p>In Budget 2015, Jaitley had announced estimated plan expenditure at around Rs 4,65,277 crore, marginally lower than the revised estimate of Rs 4.67 lakh crore for 2014-15. The Rs 34,000-35,000 crore which was allocated for MGNREGA in 2015-16, has not only been spent fully, but more resources have been given to it. The finance minister has also said actual spending under the scheme in the fiscal year ending March 31 'would be highest'.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/r/rupee-new_2811_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 12:10:09</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>