<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/see-improvementsales-for-auto-industry-next-fiscal-crisil_5628301.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[See improvement in sales for auto industry next fiscal: CRISIL]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[After the gradual recovery in some segments this fiscal, CRISIL Research expects more broad-based growth in domestic automobile sales volume in 2016-17 as consumer sentiment is expected to improve on the back of a pick-up in real income growth and lower cost of ownership]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><em>Below is the state of the auto industry by CRISIL Research</em></strong><br /><br /><strong>Improving sentiment, softening rates, and low fuel prices to propel growth</strong><br /><br />After the gradual recovery in some segments this fiscal, CRISIL Research expects more broad-based growth in domestic automobile sales volume in 2016-17 as consumer sentiment is expected to improve on the back of a pick-up in real income growth and lower cost of ownership. But revival in rural demand, critically dependent on a normal monsoon, remains a monitorable for growth in motorcycles, light commercial vehicles (LCVs) and tractors.<br /><br /><strong>Commercial vehicle sales to accelerate in 2016-17</strong><br /><br />We expect commercial vehicles sales to grow 7-9% in 2016-17, a tad faster than an estimated 5-7% in 2015-16. As replacement demand stabilises in medium and heavy commercial vehicles, growth in the segment will moderate to mid-teens from over 20% growth in the past two years. By contrast, LCV sales will grow at 4-6%, after three years of decline, due to improvement in private consumption and financing.<br /><br /><strong>Cars &amp; utility vehicles demand growth to touch double digits in 2016-17</strong><br /><br />Sales of cars and utility vehicles (UVs) rebounded strongly in 2015-16 and growth is likely to improve to 11-13% next fiscal, led by faster economic growth and better consumer sentiment (driven by rising affordability and competitively priced launches) along with interest-rate cuts and payouts arising from the Seventh Pay Commission recommendations and the One Rank One Pension plan.<br /><br /><strong>Two-wheeler sales to recover in 2016-17 on normal monsoon</strong><br /><br />Two-wheeler sales grew by a marginal 1.4 % in 2015-16 (April-January). Motorcycle sales fell 2.2 % as demand from the rural market, which accounts for nearly 45% of domestic motorcycles demand, declined because consecutive below-par monsoons lowered farm incomes. <br /><br />CRISIL Research expects two-wheeler sales to rebound in 2016-17, growing by an estimated 10-12% on the back of higher farm incomes and continued preference for scooters. Sales volumes for motorcycles will recover, growing by 6-8%. Pay increases linked to the 7th Pay Commission recommendations will boost scooter sales.<br /><br /><br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2016/c/crisil_autograph_2016.JPG" alt="" align="left" /><br /><br />]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/c/CRISILLOGO_2_356_1907_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 16:00:23</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>