<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-allocation-to-health-ministry-hiked-by-rs-4000-cr_5709041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget allocation to Health Ministry hiked by Rs 4,000 cr]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Besides this, the government will also open around 3,000 medical stores to provide quality medicines at affordable prices across the country and initiate a National Dialysis Services Programme under which it will provide dialysis services in all district hospitals.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Budgetary allocation for the Health Ministry in 2016-17 stood at over Rs 38,000 crore, an increase of over Rs 4,000 crore over the previous year, even as the Centre decided to launch a new health protection scheme under which a cover of up to Rs 1 lakh per family will be provided to common people.</p>
<p>Besides this, the government will also open around 3,000 medical stores to provide quality medicines at affordable prices across the country and initiate a National Dialysis Services Programme under which it will provide dialysis services in all district hospitals.</p>
<p>The budget allocation for Health Ministry, including plan and non-plan head is Rs 37,061.55 crore. The allocation for Department of Health Research, also falling under the Ministry, is Rs 1,144.80 crore. The total allocation for the Ministry is Rs 38,206.35 crore, an increase Rs 4,375.75 crore over the current fiscal.</p>
<p>"A serious illness of family member(s) causes severe stress on the financial condition of poor and economically weak families, shaking the foundation of their economic security.</p>
<p>"In order to help such families, the government will launch a new health protection scheme which will provide health cover up to Rs one lakh per family," Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said while unveiling the Budget 2016-17 in Parliament today.</p>
<p>He said for senior citizens, who are 60 years of age and above, an additional top-up package up to Rs 30,000 will be provided.</p>
<p>On the schemes and outlay for the health sector, Health Minister J P Nadda said the budget has given the required impetus to the sector and the Ministry is geared up to implement the announced schemes.</p>
<p>"The new health protection scheme will provide the much required financial cover for the family with special focus on senior citizens who have been provided an additional top-up package up to Rs 30,000," he said.</p>
<p>Terming the budget as "visionary, forward-looking and progressive", Nadda said it takes care of the aspirations and goals of a cross-section of masses, including rural people.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget7_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 21:40:05</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>