<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/hoping-budget-will-streamline-taxescars-motherson-sumi_5422241.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Hoping Budget will streamline taxes on cars: Motherson Sumi]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[There is still need to focus on increasing the ease of doing business and single window clearances all over India. It is still difficult to put up new plants in India, said Vivek Chaand Sehgal, Chairman, Motherson Sumi Group.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[India is currently on the brink of 2016 Union Budget &ndash; What does it have in store for tax payer, for the industries and more importantly will it be a &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo; Budget. &nbsp;<br /><br />Vivek Chaand Sehgal, Chairman, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/autoancillaries/mothersonsumisystems/MSS01">Motherson Sumi</a> Group in an interview to CNBC-TV18&rsquo;s Latha Venkatesh and Guest Editor Manish Chokhani, Director, Enam Holdings spoke about the benefits of Make in India for the auto sector and vice versa. He said manufacturing in India has the potential of not only increasing employment but would also be a solution to problems faced by international companies. India can manufacture and then export.<br /><br />From the Budget per se, he would look forward to streamlining of the tax structure for cars, have the ability to reduce tax burden on common man, excise duty etc.<br /><br />&ldquo;Auto sector is a direct and indirect employer,&rdquo; he said, adding that India has the most intelligent engineers, intelligent workforce.<br /><br />Talking about the governments initiative of &lsquo;ease of doing business&rsquo; he said there is still need to focus on increasing the ease of doing business and single window clearances all over India. It is still difficult to put up new plants in India because the facilities are available only in few states, he said. <br /><br />He not worried about the turmoil in global markets impacting the car industry as such, especially when around 85 million cars are manufactured every year and with the robust new launches happening all over. <br /><br />According to him in the last 30 years the total car production in the world has never come down, so even if one particular country is going through troubled times it does impact the overall industry per se.<br /><br />Vivek Chaand Sehgal has first started business with Rs 350 crore and turned to a Rs 3500 crore business with an employment of 75000 workers globally. They employ around 40000 skilled labour in India currently, and all this before the &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo;, said Manish Chokhani while praising Sehgal.<br /><br /><strong><em>Below is the transcript of Vivek Chaand Sehgal&rsquo;s interview with Latha Venkatesh and Guest Editor, Manish Chokhani on CNBC-TV18.</em></strong><br /> <br /> <strong>Latha: First, your expectation from the Budget to make it a Make in India Budget.</strong><br /> <br /> A: Basically, what we are looking for is the ease of doing business as I said before. The ability, we still have to go to multiple authorities to get our approvals and things like that. So, somewhere unification, a single window kind of a thing is always very helpful, so we see that in some states, we see that in some places, but generally, all the laws are moving separately, so it is always a damper to put up more facilities and things like that. Having said that, we have got about nine new plants coming up in India and that is something which we are taking care of what the customer wants us to do.<br /> <br /><strong> Manish: So, maybe you want to just expand a bit on that on how you see. There is a lot of turmoil in the world. These car companies, someone is having a recall, someone is having some other problems, but 85 million cars a year are getting sold in the world. India is barely 2.5 million. You are going to be 3 percent of your business in India long-term. So, maybe just talk about the industry in general and where you are going.</strong><br /> <br /> A: Basically, as you put it very correctly, we believe India manufacturing is a great solution to the problems that the international companies are facing. I think the ability to produce good quality parts here by Indians and then exporting it out from India to sort out the problems of the company we take over. <br /><br />So, basically, Motherson Sumi is a company which takes over companies which are in trouble globally and then through our way of looking at the problem and trying to solve that problem we, sport goods out of India, services out of India, to take care of the high costs and things over there, thereby making these companies that much more profitable and sustainable in the future.<br /> <br /> It also opens up the doors for our car makers to bring those particular models into India, because they know that capable companies are here in India which can take care of production and things like that. Auto sector by itself is globally one of the largest direct and indirect employers. So, automotive is not just some industry, it is a very relevant industry for any economy. If you look at it globally, car companies going bust, even the US government has to take it over and sustain it. And then of course, turn it around and make it profitable and then eventually sell out of it. But, what revolution Maruti Suzuki has brought in India is for everybody to see. <br /> <br /> So, I believe that automotive is a great area for India to grow in and we have all the skill sets. We have brilliant engineers, we have brilliant workforce which is really capable of taking care of the needs of the car makers. <br /><br /><strong> Latha: We do have a here and now market and a here and now investor as well. So, I just want you to read the green shoots. There is so much pessimism about growth globally. So, your idea of the recession in the car industry globally, but more importantly, in India itself, what are the original equipment manufacturer (OEM) guys telling you? Is it that you are seeing lower orders month-on-month (M-o-M), lower pace of growth of orders or actually the opposite, a higher pace or a faster pace of growth of orders in India?</strong><br /> <br /> A: The orders, the kind of new launches that are taking place is just simple to see that. If there is no growth then why would so many new launches be taking place. For every new launch, new parts are being made, new factories are being set up, new things are happening, anything old is also co-surviving with that. The car makers business, the life-cycle is getting smaller and that actually gives tremendous amount of opportunity for us auto components. <br /> <br /> I have in the last 30 years that we are in the automotive industry never seen a year where the total car production in the world has come down, so while one particular sector, one particular country may be seeing some ups and downs and that is normal as any country you take up, you will find the same. So, we do not get worried about this particular thing because over a period of time, it sort of adjusts. And as I say again and again, in the last 30 years, I have never seen global car production coming down as a total number. Even today, 85 million cars are made and the beautiful part is that the value of these cars is generally going up year-on-year. <br /> <br /> So, sometimes, too much focus on numbers also distracts people, but the value of the car going up is also something because these are aspirational things. Customer wants to buy better cars, bigger cars or whatever, but that particular thing itself brings value. And when value is coming in, generally, your employment will go up, you factories will go up. For us, we think it is an amazing industry where you can actually predict five years into the future.<br /> <br /> <strong>Manish: To just come back to her hear and now, I just want you to reiterate in a way that the best time for you was when the last crisis occurred in the world where the car companies basically came and handed over their suppliers and said, Chaand, will you please run this for us and buy this at two cents on the dollar and one is hoping that times like this, when you say there is turmoil in the world, you get deals like that again coming. So, it is actually the best of times for somebody like him.</strong><br /> <br /> <strong>Latha: Is that happening?</strong><br /> <br /> A: Absolutely, yes.<br /> <br /> <strong>Latha: We are not asking you for your list of buyers that you are looking at.</strong><br /> <br /> A: No, definitely, what is very important is, the ability of a company which is a strategic long-term investor and automotive, this is probably the more the turmoil, what people imagine, the more the opportunities that come to us. Of course, I cannot tell you exactly what is happening, but yes, there is a lot that is happening. Consolidation is happening, a lot of car makers calling us up, telling us look at this. So, it is a great time.<br /> <br /> <strong>Latha: Any one sentence you will look forward to in the Budget?</strong><br /> <br /> A: I hope the ability to reduce the tax burden on the people, but then under the current circumstances, we do not know what the people want. But I would definitely want the excise duty and a little more streamlining of the taxes on cars and getting out of this length of the car.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/budget_2016_3_356X200_2859_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-11 13:01:03</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,MSS01,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>