<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/real-estate/budget-2016-real-estate-sector-should-be-given-infrastructure-status_5628641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Real estate sector should be given infrastructure status]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Development of real estate sector is a key for infrastructure development and smart city, considering both commercial and residential space.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Rubi Arya</strong></em><br /><em>Milestone Capital Advisors</em> <br /><br />India is looked upon as one of the most attractive emerging economies of the next decade and has already witnessed record investments across sectors. The private equity funding gained notable momentum during the crisis of 2008-09 on the back of stringent lending norms set by the Indian financial institutions and banks. The entry of private equity participants in real estate market has brought in a much disciplined approach towards construction and delivery of the projects along with better transparency.<br /><br />The proposed plan for set up of &lsquo;smart cities&rsquo; and &lsquo;housing for all by 2022 scheme&rsquo; will be highly dependent on infrastructure development of the country. The relationship between infrastructure development and economic growth is well established. While infrastructure development facilitates economic growth; economic growth increases demand for more infrastructure. Thus, development of adequate and quality infrastructure is very essential. However, infrastructure development is a challenging task including time and investment constraints.<br /><br />Development of real estate sector is a key for infrastructure development and smart city, considering both commercial and residential space. On one side it needs to consider industry parks, hospitals, healthcare facilities etc and on the other side, low cost housing or affordable housing. The sector would continue to face numerous ongoing challenges till the government introduces essential reforms for the sector. The demand-supply gap in the housing sector, especially in the affordable housing segment is expected to increase, thereby further aggravating the challenges faced by the sector. To make smart cities a reality, government should make timely and drastic changes in the current framework.<br /><br />In order to develop the real estate market further, improve market sentiments and uplift the investors&rsquo; confidence, the forthcoming budget could be an appropriate platform to start this process.<br /><br /><strong>1. Real Estate Regulatory Bill:</strong> The new bill is expected to foster accountability, instill investor faith and foster confidence in the Indian real estate industry. Customers will benefit the most as it will bring more transparency in the sector.<br /><br /><strong>2. Single Window Clearance:</strong> Obtaining numerous approvals from various authorities is a lengthy and costly process. It not only adds up to the cost of developers and buyers but also delays the construction process. The implementation of Single Window Clearance will make the whole project cycle simple.<br /><br /><strong>3. Getting infrastructure status:</strong> it has been long pending demand of real estate sector. This will not only help to mitigate the huge shortage of housing to all class of society but also in overall development of sector.<br />&nbsp;<br /><strong>4. Goods and Service Tax (GST):</strong> GST should be introduced in place of indirect taxes like service tax, value-added tax etc. Approval of GST bill will lower down construction costs, avoid multiplication of taxes and help in substituting many taxes with a single tax thereby ruling out the confusion in buyers.<br /><strong><br />5. REITs:</strong> To make REIT&rsquo;s a realty, it should be exempt from taxes like rent, stamp duty, transfer of assets and distribution of dividends so that these trusts can become fully functional<br /><br /><strong>6. Attract demand:</strong> To encourage demand for housing in the current scenario, where both interest rates and property prices are rising. An additional deduction of Rs. 1lakh (currently the limit is Rs. 2lakh) on interest for loan taken towards acquisition/construction of self-occupied house property will be a welcome step. Similarly, introduce a separate exemption for principal payment of home loan or increase the existing limit that will help to boost demand for the sector<br /><br />Last 12 months have been extremely eventful, both for the global as well as the Indian economy. While external factors have highlighted the attractiveness of India as an investment destination, there are still several reform measures that are necessary to ensure that our economy is placed firmly on a double digit growth path. If India is to fully leverage the benefits of the prevailing fortuitous external environment, serious reform initiatives will need to be launched at a domestic level. <br /><br />All the above points of expectations are relevant for the overall health of the real estate industry. With increased migration of educated middle class to cities from their villages or towns, the demand for affordable units to dwell within will be on the rise. With Smart City approvals derived by many Tier II towns, they hold high potential to provide education, healthcare and a working environment to this migrating class, thus making the footprint of affordable housing much larger. For middle class to confidently invest into this upcoming scenario, the much needed Regulatory Bill will be a great boon. With the much required transparency and timely completion of projects, the said migration will be smooth, without any hurdles.<br /><br />Also the common man&rsquo;s dreams to own a house in the rapidly growing cities and towns are fuelled only by taking home loans and the government must make the tax system even more efficient for the home loan taker by increasing the deduction possible on the interest therein, This will not only give rise to a larger off take of loans but will help the ecosystem in the long run as well. <br /><br />With the economy sitting on a cusp of rapid growth explosion, it is imperative that the budget gives the sector it&rsquo;s due recognition &amp; installs the checks &amp; balances as early as possible to make the sector an easy one to navigate through. With FDI reforms allowing NRI participation in domestic AIF funds, it is now even more important that the processes involved are streamlined and error free so as to move this sector to the next level of growth.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/r/real_estate_plan_under_construction_356X200_4828_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 16:19:23</Entry_Date><Category>Real Estate</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>