<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/paswan-terms-congress-stancegst-bill-as-anti-national_4920861.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Paswan terms Congress' stance on GST Bill as 'anti-national']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[
People want the GST Bill to pass as it would solve many problems but since the ruling NDA does not have majority in the Rajya Sabha, Congress is not allowing it to pass, the Union Food and Consumer Affairs Minister said during a programme at National Sugar Institute here.
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Union Minister Ram Vilas Paswan termed Congress' stand over Goods and Services Tax (GST) Bill as "anti-national" and said that even though the people want it to pass the party is stalling it in Rajya Sabha. <br /><br />People want the GST Bill to pass as it would solve many problems but since the ruling NDA does not have majority in the Rajya Sabha, Congress is not allowing it to pass, the Union Food and Consumer Affairs Minister said during a programme at National Sugar Institute here.<br /><br /> "Congress's stance on this Bill is anti-national and the people would teach then a lesson for it," he said. </p>
<p>Paswan assured that by the first week of April this year, the Food Security Act, aimed at providing food for everyone in the country, would be implemented in all the states except Tamil Nadu.<br /><br /> The Food Security Act would also be linked to Aadhar Card and the whole system would be online to weed out any chances of corruption, Union Minister said. Speaking at the sidelines of the programme here, Paswan alleged that "jungle raj" has returned in Bihar within two months of the Grand Alliance government coming to power and his Lok Janshakti Party would launch a state-wide protest over the issue. </p>
<p>Lalu Prasad and Nitish Kumar have been running Bihar for last 25 years and still jungle raj is present in the state. Extortions have increased and recently Rs 10 lakh and Rs 1 crore amount have been demanded from LJP MLAs Raju Tiwari and Munni Devi respectively, he alleged.<br /><br /> Distancing himself from BJP leader Subramanian Swamy's statement over construction of Ram Temple in Ayodhya, the Union Minister said, he has nothing to do with what other leaders say. </p>
<p>Comparing the Prime Minister with Arjun from Mahabharat, Paswan said, Modi like the warrior prince is "focusing only on development".<br /><br /> Commenting on NDA's defeat in Bihar Assembly polls the LJP chief said, development was the main topic of election in other states but in Bihar its was caste and religion which is also the reason why the state is lagging behind. <br /><br />Speaking on the terrorist attack on the IAF airbase in Pathankot, Paswan said Pakistan should be given a strong answer for it but talks between the two neighbouring countries should continue. </p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/g/gst-356_2700_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-08 07:55:29</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>