<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/preliminary-union-budget-2016-analysis-–-personal-taxation_5706641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Preliminary Union Budget 2016 analysis – Personal taxation]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Relief to small tax payers, simplification and rationalisation of taxation and use of technology are some important elements in personal taxation.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Amarpal Chadha</strong></em><br /><br />The much awaited tax proposals were laid out by the Finance Minister today, acknowledging the role of taxpayers in nation building. He also set the perspective of the budget by stating, &ldquo;Taxation is a major tool available to Government for removing poverty and inequality from the society. The posterity will not forgive us if we do not use this opportunity in this perspective.&rdquo; The thrust of this year&rsquo;s tax proposals fell into nine categories including relief to small tax payers, simplification and rationalisation of taxation and use of technology. Below are some of the key direct tax proposals affecting individuals in this budget: <br /><br />In order to provide relief to the small tax payers, it is proposed to increase the relief for individuals having total income up to Rs 5,00,000 to Rs 5,000 vis-&agrave;-vis existing relief or Rs 2,000. This would provide an additional relief of Rs 3,000 in the tax liability. It has been further proposed to increase the deduction available for individuals paying rent and not receiving house rent allowance to Rs 5,000 per month from the existing Rs 2,000 per month. This would result in additional deduction up to Rs 36,000 per annum.<br /><br />Appreciating the fact that pension schemes offer financial security to senior citizens and in a bid to promote National Pension Scheme (NPS), it has been proposed to exempt withdrawal of accumulated balance from NPS Trust to the extent of 40% of the total amount payable. Further, to bring in parity with NPS, it is proposed make similar amendments to the taxability on withdrawal of Provident Fund and Superannuation fund balance, arising out of contributions made on or after April 01, 2016. However, this is not applicable for excluded employees whose monthly salary does not exceed prescribed limit. Additionally, the employer contribution to recognized provident fund above Rs 1,50,000 is proposed to be considered income in hands of the employee even if within the limit of 12% of salary.<br /> <br />In order to promote housing, an additional deduction up to Rs 50,000 is available to first-home buyers for the interest payable on housing loan taken from any financial institution for acquisition of residential property subject to the satisfaction of prescribed conditions. Additionally, the time limit for completion of acquisition or construction of self-occupied house property to be eligible for higher deduction of Rs 2,00,000 for interest on housing loan has been increased to 5 years.<br /><br />In an attempt to mobilise resources, a tax of 10% on the dividend income in addition to Dividend Distribution Tax, is proposed to be levied on individuals having dividend income of Rs 10 Lakh or more. In addition, surcharge is proposed to be increased from 12% to 15% for individuals having income above Rupees one crore.<br /><br />With the intent to reduce litigation pending before first appellate authority, a Dispute Resolution Scheme has been proposed. The taxpayer may decide to pay the disputed tax and interest choose to close the litigation. In case disputed tax is more than Rs 10 Lakh, 25% of the minimum penalty would additionally be payable.<br /><br />In order to give an opportunity to the existing non-compliant taxpayers, a compliance window from June 01, 2016 to September 30, 2016 is proposed where undisclosed income prior to financial year 2016-17 can be disclosed by paying accumulated tax at the rate of 45% (30% topped with surcharge and penalty at the rate 7.5% each). The taxpayers would have time of two months from declaration to pay the amount due. Having given one opportunity for evaded income to be declared under the Income Declaration Scheme once, the Government intends to focus all resources for bringing people with black money to books.<br /><br />With the plan to use technology in taxation in a big way to make life simpler, the optional e-assessment scheme is extended in 7 mega cities. Further, e-sahyog project will provide an online mechanism to resolve mismatches. Both directed towards reducing face to face contact of the taxpayer and the IT department.<br /><br />The desire of the Government to make life simpler for law abiding citizen and provide socio-economic security to every Indian, especially the farmers, the poor and the vulnerable and the dream to see a more prosperous India, is evident in the Finance Minister&rsquo;s budget proposal.<br /><br /><em><strong>Author is tax partner, EY.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/u/Union_Budget_2_356x200_2039_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 19:55:54</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>