<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-news/budget-2016-should-be-big-step-towards-making-india-investment-destination_5587601.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Should be big step towards making India investment destination]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[With India emerging as a bright spot in today's global economy, the focus will now be on our national fiscal deficit. Finance Minister would draw some roadmap for long-term stable growth, to increase the tax-GDP ratio, while ensuring that India remains a bright spot and attractive to the rest of the world.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Nityanand Prabhu</strong></em><br /><em>LIC Nomura Mutual Fund</em><br /><br />With the Union Budget 2016 scheduled on February 29, expectations are high that the government may announce increase in tax exemption limit on savings. As private sector investment growth has remained tepid this year, higher savings are expected to make extra resources available to improve investment activity in the economy. It is believed that simplicity is the best policy. Simple and clear amendments would instill confidence and boost investor sentiment. Bankers have already sought significant hike in tax breaks to promote savings in their pre-budget suggestions to the finance ministry. The Reserve Bank of India has also pitched for the need to increase country&rsquo;s savings. <br /><br />The mutual fund industry is also looking forward to few changes. Association of Mutual Funds in India (&ldquo;AMFI&rdquo;) has sought more tax incentives on ELSS, pension products, equity fund of funds and infrastructure debt mutual funds.<br /><br />Finance ministry is also believed to be studying suggestions to raise tax exemption limit on savings to Rs.2.5 lakh per annum from Rs.1.5 lakh per year at present, and to reduce maturity period for tax-free term deposit to 1 year from 5 year. Currently, the government gives tax exemption of up to Rs.1.5 lakh a year on various investment instruments such as public provident fund, five-year tax-free deposits, equity linked savings schemes, unit linked insurance plans and so on.<br /><br />The government launched gold bond scheme and gold monetization scheme to turn idle gold holdings of citizens into productive use. These schemes, which are yet to attract large number of investors, seek to do away with the need to hold physical gold. The government last year also launched a savings scheme for the girl child &ldquo;Sukanya Samriddhi Account Scheme&rdquo;, which gives 9.2 per cent interest rate for 2015-16 on principal of up to Rs.1.5 lakh. This savings scheme provides tax exemption on interest component also at the time of withdrawal. This is a long-term savings scheme, with the amount maturing when the daughter turns 21.<br /><br />With the Union Budget 2016 knocking at the door, the stock market is getting heated-up with speculations and expectations from it. The previous two Union Budgets saw the NDA government offer myriad incentives to businesses in a bid to boost investment and economic growth. However, this time around, the government is expected to focus more on infrastructure, agriculture and on restoring the health of the banking system. There could also be specific measures to ease the stress. With the recent direction from the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to the commercial banks to accelerate provisioning requirement from April 1, 2016 for the existing stock of restructured loans, the December quarter balance sheets of most banks have impacted negatively. At present, banks are facing pressure on profitability due to higher provisioning for bad loans. The ultimate aim of RBI is to clean up banks' balance sheets by March 2017. Besides this, there is also an anticipation that the NDA government would continue to keep up the positive economic outlook of India by bringing in major indirect tax reforms and addressing business concerns. <br /><br />In FY17, the government should focus on passing of the Constitutional Amendment Bill for GST as it would not only help the government create a positive environment, but also work as a giant step towards reinforcing the perception about India as the next investment destination. With India emerging as a bright spot in today's global economy, the focus will now be on our national fiscal deficit. It is anticipated that Finance Minister would draw some roadmap for long-term stable growth, to increase the tax-GDP ratio, while ensuring that India remains a bright spot and attractive to the rest of the world and continues to attract foreign funds.<br /><br />The honorable FM had also announced a phased reduction of the corporate tax rates from 30% to 25% in next 4 years in Budget 2015. This was intended to be done by removing various income based exemptions available to Corporates and reducing the tax rates. Industry would expect some more follow up changes in this direction. <br /><br />Expectations are always high prior to the budget, however it remains to be seen what lies in store for the common man or a small investor!]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/m/mutual_fund_356X200_2820_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 11:21:46</Entry_Date><Category>MF News</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>