<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-india-prioritised-expenditurerural-farm-infra-naresh-takkar_5701661.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 India: Prioritised expenditure on rural, farm, infra: Naresh Takkar]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Union Budget has prioritised expenditure on the rural, farm and infrastructure sectors, with robust allocations for roads and railways that would support economic growth, says Naresh Takkar, MD & Group CEO, ICRA.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Naresh Takkar,&nbsp;</strong><strong>MD &amp; Group CEO, ICRA<br /></strong><br />"Despite the substantial rise in its salary and pension bill, the Government of India has laudably stuck to the target of paring its fiscal deficit to 3.5&nbsp;percent&nbsp;of GDP in its Budget Estimates (BE) for 2016-17. The Government&nbsp;had to resort to various revenue augmentation measures to create fiscal space, some of which may be inflationary, such as the cesses that have been imposed. While the overall tax revenue growth assumed in the Budget appears realistic, the achievement of the targets for inflows from spectrum auctions and disinvestment would crucially affect fiscal trends in 2016-17. The Union Budget has prioritised expenditure on the rural, farm and infrastructure sectors, with robust allocations for roads and railways that would support economic growth. With little room to augment capital spending, the quality of the fiscal deficit is projected to worsen in 2016-17 BE as compared to 2015-16 RE."&nbsp;</p>
<p>"Although the FM did reiterate the Government's commitment to the PSU Banks, the Budget has restricted the allocation for Bank recapitalisation at the Rs 25,000 crore that was announced in the Indradhanush, despite the rise in provisioning post Banks&rsquo; Q3FY16 results. The limited focus on the National Investment and Infrastructure Fund for funding investments is another key disappointment."</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Arun_Jaitley_budget_FM_budget_Finance_356x200_4344_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 17:48:44</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>