<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/cpses-contribution-dipped-by-rs-20000-crfy15-eco-survey_5662581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[CPSEs contribution dipped by Rs 20,000 cr in FY15: Eco Survey]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["This was mainly on account of a decrease in their contribution to dividend, corporate tax and custom duty in 2014-15," as per the 2015-16 report card of the state of the economy tabled by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in Parliament.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The contribution of Central Public Sector Enterprises (CPSEs) to the exchequer decreased by nearly Rs 20,400 crore to Rs 2,00,584 crore in 2014-15, the Economic Survey said today.</p>
<p>The CPSEs had contributed Rs 2,20,981 crore to the central exchequer in 2013-14.</p>
<p>"This was mainly on account of a decrease in their contribution to dividend, corporate tax and custom duty in 2014-15," as per the 2015-16 report card of the state of the economy tabled by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in Parliament.</p>
<p>CPSEs contribute to the central exchequer by way of dividend payment, interest on government loans and payment of taxes and duties.</p>
<p>There was, however, an increase in the CPSEs contribution to excise duty, dividend tax, sales tax and service tax.</p>
<p>Besides, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/oildrillingandexploration/oilnaturalgascorporation/ONG">ONGC</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/miningminerals/coalindia/CI11">Coal India</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/power-generationdistribution/ntpc/NTP">NTPC</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/miningminerals/nmdc/NMD02">National Mineral Development Corporation</a> (NMDC) and Power Finance Corporation were the top five profit-making CPSEs during 2014-15.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Bharat Sanchar Nigam Ltd, Air India, Mahanagar Telephone Nigam Ltd, Hindustan Photo Films Manufacturing Company and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/refineries/mangalorerefinerypetrochemicals/MRP">Mangalore Refinery and Petrochemicals </a>were the top five loss-making CPSEs.</p>
<p>The net profit of profit making (157) CPSEs stood at Rs 1,30,363 crore in 2014-15, while net loss of loss-making (77) CPSEs stood at Rs 27,360 crore.</p>
<p>Out of 298 CPSEs under the administrative control of various ministries/departments, 235 were in operation and 63 were under construction upto December 2015.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/e/ECONOMIC_SURVEY_economy_busget2016_356x200.jpg_2543_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 14:38:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,ONG,CI29,NTP,NMD01,MRP,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>