<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/cnbc-tv18-comments/farmers-plight-gidcs-negligence-hits-gujarat-farmers-hard_5152421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Farmers' plight: GIDC's negligence hits Gujarat farmers hard]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Excited by the Rs 350 crore offer, villagers gave their consent. But a year ago, came the big blow when GIDC decided to not buy the land.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Gujarat government is acclaimed for its simple, speedy and rewarding land acquisition process in Sanand, which lit the fortunes of several villages overnight.</p>
<p>Nearly 8 kilometers from the imposing Tata Nano factory in Sanand lies Kalana, a small village of 1,500 people where the Gujarat Industrial Development Corporation (GIDC) agreed to purchase 365 <em>bighas</em> of land in Kalana in 2013.</p>
<p>Excited by the Rs 350 crore offer, villagers gave their consent. But a year ago, came the big blow when GIDC decided to not buy the land.</p>
<p>What irks villagers more is GIDC's silence on when it would release their land from its database.</p>
<p>Until that is not done, the villagers cannot farm on their land, cannot sell or mortgage it nor secure a bank loan against it.</p>
<p>CNBC-TV18&rsquo;s efforts to reach GIDC land officials were not successful, instead a meeting with the state minister Saurabh Patel happened where he said &ldquo;The government is to decide whether more land is required or not and in the future if the need arises we will go to them.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Similarly, in Khoraj, the GIDC acquired 6,000 <em>bighas</em> of land at the rate of Rs 2615800 per <em>bigha</em>. But 3 years after it began the acquiring process, 20 percent of payments are still held up.</p>
<p>In terms of the number of villagers, 120 are yet to receive their payments.</p>
<p>CNBC-TV18 met 45-year old Khoraj farmer and businessman Alkesh Modi, who filed a petition in the Gujarat High Court after the GIDC failed to compensate him for his land.</p>
<p>Modi says according to the new land acquisition act, the GIDC must pay farmers 4 times the market value of land but the GIDC is unwilling.</p>
<p>However, the GIDC is insisting to take payment as per the old act.</p>
<p>&ldquo;The GIDC is not ready to pay and is insisting us to take payment as per the old act and that too in an illegal way, through a sale deed,&rdquo; Modi added.</p>
<p>GIDC wrote a letter to the farmers telling them to accept three conditions if they want their compensation -- execute a sale deed under old compensation rates, forego interest on their land and agree not to approach the courts.</p>
<p>When asked about the stalled payments and the GIDC's letter to farmers, Patil said that he is unaware of such instances.</p>
<p>Still this remains a matter of concern as such ignorance is doing little to help these villages, which have seen the sun setting on their dreams.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/f/farmer_5656_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-25 18:30:39</Entry_Date><Category>CNBC-TV18 Comments</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>