<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/average-inflation-to-rise-next-fiscal-ind-ra_5171221.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Average inflation to rise next fiscal: Ind-Ra]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["Notwithstanding the benign retail and wholesale price forecast for 2016-17, Ind-Ra believes the inflationary challenge is far from over as food prices have more than often triggered surprises," the agency's Chief Economist Devendra Pant said in a statement.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Inflation based on wholesale and retail price indices will rise on average by 2.7 percent and 4.9 percent during the next fiscal, India Ratings and Research projected on Wednesday.<br /><br /> "Notwithstanding the benign retail and wholesale price forecast for 2016-17, Ind-Ra believes the inflationary challenge is far from over as food prices have more than often triggered surprises," the agency's Chief Economist Devendra Pant said in a statement.<br /><br /> As regards RBI's policy stance, Pant said the central bank is likely to be accommodative in the near term.</p>
<p>"If conditions permit, Ind-Ra expects a 0.25-0.50 percent cut in the repo rate during 2016-17," he said. Ind-Ra expects average Wholesale Price Index (WPI) to rise by 2.7 percent and Consumer price index (CPI) to rise by an average of 4.9 percent in 2016-17, the statement said. <br /><br />The food related headwinds in overall inflation have been a mixture of structural and cyclical factors, Ind-Ra said.</p>
<p>It added that the structural issues plaguing Indian agriculture lately are stagnation in productivity, rising cost of cultivation, changing food consumption pattern, and exploitation of supply shocks by intermediaries.<br /><br /> According to the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the consumer prices in emerging and developing economies are expected to rise to 5.6 percent and 5.9 percent in 2016 and 2017 respectively.<br /><br /> "This is also broadly in line with the Ind-Ra view on retail inflation in India which is likely to rise by an average of 4.9 percent in 2016-17," Pant said.</p>
<p>Ind-Ra said the IMF's projection of a decline in commodity prices - oil prices by 17.6 percent and non fuel prices by 9.5 percent in 2016 - is likely to keep the fuel and power component of wholesale prices in India down even next fiscal.<br /><br /> Ind-Ra thus expects the average WPI to rise by 2.7 percent in 2016-17. WPI as well as retail inflation has been on rising trend.</p>
<p>In December WPI-based inflation stood at (-)0.73 percent, while retail inflation was at 5.61 percent.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/v/Vegetables_goodfood_budget15_inflation_356x200_2151_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-27 14:57:38</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>