<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/cnbc-tv18-analyst-markets/budget-2016-what-market-wants_5181421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: What market wants]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The bulls are struggling to breathe. And this has the capital markets hoping the Finance Minister's Budget will provide the push needed to re-start the bull run. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The bulls are struggling to breathe. And this has the capital markets hoping the Finance Minister's Budget will provide the push needed to re-start the bull run. CNBC-TV18's Navin Shetty and Areeb Sherwani detail the Budget wishlist Dalal Street has put together.</p>
<p>A slowdown in China, US Fed chief Janet Yellen's rate hikes, ECB chief Mario Draghi's reluctance to close the doors on quantitative easing, uncertainty in the policy and tax regime in India -- these are just a few of the factors behind the 14 percent decline in the Indian stock markets since April last year.</p>
<p>This decline has been driven by an exodus of Rs 29,240 crore worth of foreign portfolio investors even when the domestic institutions continued to be net buyers in the Indian stock markets.</p>
<p>But market watchers and experts say this fall could have been avoided, or mitigated at least, if India wasn't plagued by poor capital formation and a lack of depth in the market.</p>
<p>They hope Budget 2016 will take steps to correct this lapse, including but not restricted to: restoration of rebate under Sec 88E against STT paid; simpler KYC process to open demat accounts; tax clarity with respect to income generated from trading in derivatives; and a speedier process for e-IPOs.</p>
<p>They also ask for incentives that will channel bank savings into the capital markets.</p>
<p>Says Dina Mehta, MD &amp; CEO, Asit C Mehta Investments, "When we are talking about ease of doing business we also need to talk about ease of investing. We talk of having a high savings rate when they are saving and depositing in the bank, and the bank deposits become an NPA, it will be very unfair to the investor."</p>
<p>Such a move will complement the Rs 4,000 crore that are flowing in via SIP investments in mutual funds.</p>
<p>A high cost of compliance is another sore point, seeing as how these costs make up nearly 30 percent of transaction costs for market players. They also ask that the government step in to rationalise dividend distribution tax, and exempt commodities transaction brokerage from tax deducted at source.</p>
<p>For increased retail participation, especially in mutual funds, market participants hope the government will initiate regulatory changes, and reduce compliance costs.</p>
<p>"Under 54EC &amp; 54ED investors in mutual funds should get tax exemption like one when you invest in REC bonds or NHAI bonds," says Rajesh Gandhi, Partner, Deloitte Haskins &amp; Sells. "Similarly, today if an investor in NPS gets a tax exemption or deduction, similar exemptions should be given when one invests in mutual funds."</p>
<p>Experts say that even some of these measures will help bring about a shift in India's investment patterns. Giving the capital markets greater depth and penetration, and adding one more layer of protection from external factors.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/b/Bse_Markets_Stock_exchange_356x200_4715_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-27 21:56:50</Entry_Date><Category>CNBC-TV18 Analyst - Markets</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>