<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/budget-2016-scrappage-policy-to-raise-demand-by-10-15-says-ashok-leyland_5604921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Scrappage policy to raise demand by 10-15%, says Ashok Leyland]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Gopal Mahadevan, CFO of Ashok Leyland, says the company is doing well in the bus segment and the 54 percent volumes growth is equally spread between trucks and buses.
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[If the scrappage policy for older vehicles is announced in the upcoming Budget, replacement demand will pick up significantly, says Gopal Mahadevan, CFO of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-lcvshcvs/ashokleyland/AL">Ashok Leyland</a>.<br /><br />Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Mahadevan says, this will&nbsp;boost&nbsp;industry demand by 10-15 percent. <br /><br />On Ashok Leyland's performance, he says, the company is doing well in the bus segment. The volume growth of 54 percent in past nine months is equally spread between trucks and buses.&nbsp;In addition, the new Atal Mission for Rejuvenation and Urban Transformation (AMRUT) bus scheme will lead to 6,000-7,000 bus orders, he says.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Gopal Mahadevan\\'s interview with Reema Tendulkar and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Sonia: Tell us what is your own expectation if this scrappage policy for older vehicles is introduced, how much of a positive could it be for a company like Leyland?</strong><br /><br />A: I think the segment would certainly benefit from what they typically call as the replacement incentive. Vehicles, which are more than 10-12 years, the government had noted earlier that they would give some kind of an incentive for that.<br /><br />The point is that this would induce a lot more replacement demand, it could get better vehicles on to the road, it would also ensure that better pollution norms are there because some of these vehicles are old.<br /><br />Having said that, I think while this is a direct benefit to the industry, the second part is to see that the economic self revives. So, investment led growth is going to be very critical in the Budget, we are hoping that the goods and services tax (GST) one way or the other gets implemented within a defined timeframe, there are incentivisation for capital investment also.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: Could you give us some numbers, how many vehicles in the industry would be more than 10 years and what percentage of the total CVs would it constitute?</strong><br /><br />A: Let me give a very brad percentage. The total annual volumes this year possibly would be something like about 260,000-270,000 units. So I would say that this would increase the demand. If they do this in safe manner, I don&rsquo;t think they want to do this overnight but if they do this in a phased manner, I expect that the demand would go up by about 10-15 percent.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: So the industry demand will go up by 10-15 percent, what about Leyland\\'s own demand because year-to-date (YTD) your volumes have gone up by about 36 percent which is quite healthy, any rough assessment of how much Leyland\\'s demand could go up by?</strong><br /><br />A: I cannot give you a kind of a forecast on that alone. All I can tell you is that on a YTD basis, the industry has grown at 30 percent, Ashok Leyland has grown at about 54 percent. For the quarter, Ashok Leyland growth has been at 38 percent in volume term as opposed to an industry growth of about 22 percent. So, if we do see this, pull effect in terms of replacement of vehicles that come in, certainly it will augur well for Ashok Leyland as well.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: You indicated that you expect this scrappage policy to be introduced in a phased manner, could you elabourate more?</strong><br /><br />A: I don&rsquo;t expect that overnight the government is going to say that they are going to fund and subsidize all vehicles beyond a particular age. We will have to wait and watch because that would be quite a bit of allocation that the centre would have to do for announcing such a policy. I do not know whether they would start with a 12-year old vehicles or 15-year old vehicles. That is going to depend and then there is also the other issue about as vehicles start aging over the next 365 days or two years then what happens to that. So, we will have to wait and watch but if they do this, it is a positive for the industry no doubt.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: The other thing that is expected in this Budget is a higher amount of orders for bus manufacturers in the new Atal Mission for Urban Transformation (AMRUT) scheme, the Jawaharlal Nehru National Urban Renewal Mission (JnNURM) scheme was lagging a bit, the states were not utilising their funds etc but what is your expectation as far as the new AMRUT scheme is concerned and how are you doing in the bus segment lately?</strong><br /><br />A: We are doing pretty well in the bus segment, as I mentioned to you this growth of 54 percent in volumes that has happened over the last nine months has been equally spread between trucks and buses. So, we are almost there in all the significant and important tenders for either STUs or for any of these schemes driven or in private tenders. So, if the AMRUT scheme does come in, it would augur well because what has happened is we have seen a little bit of slowdown in the JNNURM scheme and possibly this is where the news came will take off. Typically these schemes have about 6,000-7,000 buses per annum.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: There are reports that suggest that Nissan has slapped a notice to end the Leyland JV. Would you confirm that what would be the termination cost in such a scenario because I believe one of your technology joint ventures is a part of the BIFR with a loss greater than Rs 700 crore?</strong><br /><br />A: At the moment, all I can tell you is that the matter is subjudice and I will not be able to elabourate on this. Ashok Leyland, from its perspective, is committed to the LCV business. We are trying to do whatever is in the interest of the joint venture and also the stakeholders who are associated with the JV but let us wait and watch.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/a/ashok-leyland_356_4452_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-23 10:27:09</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,AL,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>