<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-should-arun-jaitley-let-fiscal-deficit-takebackseat_5507981.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Should Arun Jaitley let fiscal deficit take a backseat?]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[But considering the fact that the government expects full-year GDP (FY16) to grow at 7.6 percent, making India the fastest-growing economy in the world, surely there is no need to deviate from the fiscal target]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>It all started with Chief Economic Advisor (CEA) Arvind Subramanian saying India needs to move away from its stated fiscal deficit target of achieving 3.5 percent of GDP in FY17 to propel growth, after the mid-year review. It is based on the premise that both global growth and private investment are likely to remain weak, making public investment the only force that could stimulate the economy going forward.</p>
<p>From thereon, myriad discussions and debates have taken place on whether the government should move away from its fiscal roadmap to push growth.</p>
<p>But considering the fact that the government expects full-year GDP (FY16) to grow at 7.6 percent, making India the fastest-growing economy in the world, surely there is no need to deviate from the fiscal target.</p>
<p>A<a href="http://www.businesstoday.in/union-budget-2016-17/news/fm-weighs-relaxing-fiscal-deficit-targets-in-new-budget/story/227794.html">&nbsp;Business Today report</a> states that finance minister Arun Jaitley has been advised to increase the fiscal deficit target to 3.7 percent or 3.9 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) from 3.5 percent for 2016-17. While Jaitley is yet to take a call on the same, the Reserve Bank of India governor Raghuram Rajan has been continuously warning the government against the perils of such a move. To prove his point, Rajan has even cited the example of Brazil and said "the enormous costs of becoming an unstable country far outweigh any small growth benefits that can be obtained through aggressive policies".<br /><br /><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2016/c/canva-photo-editor5.png" alt="" align="left" /></p>
<p>Rajan has been repeatedly saying that India as well as the finance minister will lose credibility globally if it falls into the trap of deviating from the fiscal deficit target. Additionally, continuing on the path of fiscal consolidation will eventually put downward pressure on interest rates, thus making it cheaper for the private sector to borrow.</p>
<p>Most market watchers as well as economists agree with Rajan. Dipen Sheth, head of institutional research at HDFC Securities, earlier on Tuesday <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/budget-2016-govt-must-stick-to-fiscal-deficit-targets-says-dipen-sheth_5494481.html">told CNBC-TV18</a> that there is a storm brewing outside as well as inside India and this year is going to be volatile, and while times are tough and the temptation to take few liberties on fiscal targets is high, it would not be a good option.<br /><br />In recent times, Bimal Jalan, former RBI chief and head of the government's Expenditure Management Condition, also <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-must-set-out-fiscal-deficit-range-not-target-bimal-jalan_5482481.html">told CNBC-TV18</a> that the government needs to be fiscally responsible and there is a need to manage expenditure to the best of its ability. However, he has also said that the government need not stick to a target; but has to be within a range.</p>
<p>With hardly any recovery in corporate earnings, the only reason why India still continues to stand out despite the recent mayhem in the market is because of its strong macroeconomic position. As it is, the government will be faced with added expenditure in FY17 on account of One Rank One Pension (OROP) and the implementation of the 7th Pay Commission.</p>
<p>Despite this, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-can-breach-fiscal-deficit-target-to-fund-infra-ey_5448261.html">global consultancy firm EY recently said</a> that the government should provide more funds for development of infrastructure sector even at the cost of missing the fiscal deficit target of 3.5 percent in 2016-17.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/f/fiscal_fiscal_deficit_deficit_1312_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-16 15:37:55</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>