<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-should-relaxfisc-gap-keep-it-at-39-bofaml_4928361.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt should relax on fisc gap, keep it at 3.9%: BofAML]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley is slated to present the Budget for financial year 2016-17 next month.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Government should relax the fiscal&nbsp;consolidation roadmap in the face of challenge posed by the&nbsp;7th Pay Commission by budgeting for wider gap of 3.9 percent&nbsp;for 2016-17, which will help push GDP growth, says a report.<br /><br />"Relaxing the fiscal deficit (is the) key" because of the&nbsp;implementation of the pay panel's proposals which are likely&nbsp;to set a 0.7 percent hole in the government finances, foreign&nbsp;brokerage Bank of America Merill Lynch said today.<br /><br />Finance Minister Arun Jaitley is slated to present the&nbsp;Budget for financial year 2016-17 next month.&nbsp;"We expect the 0.7 percent of GDP stimulus from the 7th&nbsp;Pay Commission to boost consumption from the second quarter of&nbsp;2016. It's pre-condition that Jaitley relaxes the FY17 fiscal&nbsp;deficit target to 3.9 percent of GDP - same as FY16's - from&nbsp;the pre-committed 3.5 percent," it said.<br /><br />Under a medium term fiscal consolidation plan, the&nbsp;government is committed to get the fiscal deficit down to 3&nbsp;percent by 2017-18. It had already taken a relaxation for&nbsp;2015-16 to support growth and under the revised plan, it has&nbsp;to achieve 3.5 percent in 2016-17.<br /><br />The fiscal deficit stokes inflation and also crowds out&nbsp;private investment, and hence, is a key number monitored by&nbsp;both the RBI as well as the international rating agencies.&nbsp;<br /><br />BofAML sought to downplay the negative effects, saying the&nbsp;gap is "well below" the medium term average of 4.8 percent&nbsp;since FY2000.&nbsp;The stimulus received from the 7th Pay Commission, along&nbsp;with lending rate cuts and a rollover of foreign deposits&nbsp;taken in 2013, will help the GDP growth to accelerate to 7.7&nbsp;percent in FY17, it said. The government had last month cut&nbsp;its FY16 growth estimate to 7-7.5 percent.<br /><br />Reserve Bank of India Governor will not cut by more than 0.25 percent at&nbsp;the upcoming policy review on February 2, the note said,&nbsp;adding that it expects another 0.50 percent in cuts in<br />April-September 2016 to support growth.<br /><br />It said the fears of the government crowding out private&nbsp;sector are also "overdone", adding that it will have to&nbsp;increase borrowing by 13.6 percent to Rs 5,530 billion in&nbsp;2016-17.<br /><br />There is "undue stress" on reforms for pushing growth, it&nbsp;said, adding that it supports GDP expansion over a longer 5-10&nbsp;year period, whereas the current challenge is a cyclical&nbsp;recovery.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/f/fiscal_food_04jul_356200_2506_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-08 16:59:42</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>