<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/stress-testbanks-will-make-them-stronger-prime-securities_5606761.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Stress test on banks will make them stronger: Prime Securities]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[N Jayakumar of Prime Securities says, the current level of pessimism can be a perfect scenario and may lead to a rally.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Indian market is looking to inch higher&nbsp;but&nbsp;for the first time since the new government has come to power, there is&nbsp;a fair amount of pessimism, says N Jayakumar of Prime Securities.<br /><br />Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Jayakumar says this level of pessimism can be a perfect scenario and may lead to&nbsp;a rally.<br /><br />On banking sector, he says, the stress test&nbsp;that&nbsp;banks are undergoing, will only make them stronger, adding, there is no need to paint the entire public sector banking space with&nbsp;the same brush. <br /><br />Jayakumar is of the view that the government can raise equity via Differential&nbsp;Voting Rights (DVR) for public sector&nbsp;banks, which will prevent their&nbsp;holding from falling below 52 percent.<br /><br />He&nbsp;believes&nbsp;commodities have bottomed out and oil is ready for a sharp upmove.&nbsp;<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of N Jayakumar&rsquo;s interview with Ekta Batra &amp; Anuj Singhal on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Anuj: We have been having this conversation on whether Tata Motors DVR should be part of the Index. Now we have that taking place what do you see going on from here? Do you the discount will narrow down completely because there is one side which believes there are not too many Index funds so why should the discounts trim any further?</strong><br /><br />A: The issue is not about Index funds, the issue is about pricing an instrument correctly. If you notice it is not the first instance of two stocks, one voting and one non-voting both being part of the Index. Google and Google non-voting GOOGL as it is called, they traded at a discount or a differential about a percent and a half. Not today, not yesterday for years this has been the case and they are also both part of the S&amp;P.<br /><br />In fact when S&amp;P introduced this almost a year and a half or two years ago one of the things they mentioned was that the incorporation of both the lines of stock while the company remains one, Goggle in this case and two lines of stock. Essentially the two lines of stock represented a more complete market capitalisation which in fact is the case with Tata Motors DVR and Tata Motors. <br /><br />There is also a case on the Bovespa the Brazilian Exchange which has Petrobras, Vale and Banco Bradesco three different industries having companies that have two lines of stock each non-voting and voting and they trade pretty much a differential of between plus-minus 5 percent. <br /><br />In one of the case they actually traded at a premium the non-voting stocks because it has a higher dividend compared to the voting stocks. At the end of the day instruments which are identical in every aspect and if Tata Motors DVR is identical to Tata Motors equity in every aspect except that one has a 1:10 or one-tenth vote share because we don&rsquo;t have a non-voting concept in India it has one vote for every 10 shares compared to the underlying which is one for one. <br /><br />Apart from this difference, and if you eliminate the right or the pleasure of the right to vote then really speaking the underlying economic value is exactly the same. It is only in the case of a hostile takeover where voting is an important feature of the share that you are buying. Voting share actually start trading at a dramatic premium over the nonvoting. Otherwise there was no reason that they should trade more than a few percentage points apart. <br /><br />In the Indian context I expect, when we started talking about, it was almost a 47 percent differential and along the way MSCI introduce it. Well before NSE BSE was the first, February 18th of last year if there is an Asia Index circular which actually says that the Tata Motors DVR be part of the Sensex. I suspect that for a variety of reasons they did not incorporate it in the Sensex 30 but incorporated in a few other smaller Indices of the BSE series or the BSE family. <br /><br />At that particular point in time the introduction in Sensex was linked to the Nifty which has taken a much longer time. So, this discount will come down to a single digit. I may even hasten to add low single digits but certainly not more than a 5-7 percent differential so there is a long way to go still.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: let me play the devil&rsquo;s advocate here. After the correction we have the Tata Motors DVR which has a free float market cap of Rs 12,500 core. Purely on that merit does it deserve to be in the Index? There are so many stocks that I can think of Indian Oil Corporation (IOC) could be one. There could be some other stocks which could have been the part of the Index.</strong><br /><br />A: It has nothing to do with the market cap. It is a question of saying Tata Motors is part of the Index; all lines of equity of Tata Motors must be part of the Index. So for instances, if they had a compulsory convertible debenture out there which you know will convert to equity the market prices the equity accordingly. So, the convertible debenture to is equity for every calculation. <br /><br />Similarly a nonvoting stock is also equity. It is not a question of a new company being introduced in the Index. It is the question of saying should Tata Motors be in the Index? Now having taken that decision the Tata Motors is a necessary part of the Index, all lines of stock, stock being common stock, equity stock or convertible equity must be part of the Index.<br /><br />So, it is not about Rs 12,500 crore, the way I would look at it is the market cap of Tata Motors has got augmented by Rs 12,500 crore for the purpose of calculation. Over a period of time these two should be seen as the way in which people are taking a Tata Motors call. Which means if let us say the DVR is let us say approximately 10-12 percent of the free float of Tata Motors, then for every time there is a Rs 1 allocation to the Nifty or Rs 1 allocation to any Nifty stock the Tata Motors portion will get spilt as 90 percent Tata Motors and 10 percent DVR. That is an automatic way of calculating. <br /><br />So, I still maintain the Nifty 50 is still 50 companies but it is 51 lines of stock where Tata Motors has two lines of stocks represented by the voting and the nonvoting. So, it is not a new company, it is not to say that why don&rsquo;t we introduced a XYZ or let us introduce Tata Motors DVR, this is not a favour to Tata Motor DVR. This is a more correct representation of the Index weightage of Tata Motors.<br /><br />Anuj: What did you make of the recent market volatility? It has been so crunching for a lot of people, last year was bad but at least individual stocks made money, this year has been ranked by portfolios, how are you approaching the market from hereon?<br /><br />A: It is very simple. Ever since the new government came in, which was now almost two-three years ago, we are talking about virtually the entire period whether CNBC or any other channel, the one common theme across the board was people were either long-term bullish and medium-term bullish and some of them were even short-term bullish. But there was not a single person commentator otherwise who came and said that he was not bullish about India in the medium-term or longer-term.<br /><br />So there was a near consensus -- amongst fund managers, amongst local investors and over this two-year period from May 2014 to today, you had a virtual consensus in terms of what is it that people saw in the markets, everybody was bullish the Indian market. What has happened in this period is after that run to 9,100, you could almost look back and say this is the greatest period of distribution where between 9,100 and 8,000 -- the maximum time it has spent is between 7,800 and 8,300 -- in this entire period, there has been multiple rounds of distribution while India continued to remain even the most bearish of your predictors or analysts would come and say that long-term is bullish but short-term he was bearish.<br /><br />As long as that kind of bullishness in our consensus continued and as the market has shown you, we have not been able to make money as on individual stocks may have corrected. For the first time today in the last two months, you have rank bearishness setting in terms of forecast, 5,500 is freely talked about, people have talked even lower, 6,500 is almost par for the course including in-house analyst of this own channel, virtually everybody talks 6,500 and below. There is a fair amount of pessimism, fair amount of negativity and people have come back to earth, people have losses on their portfolios, they are scared and for the first time, mutual fund redemptions have started or the inflows have slowed down.<br /><br />In this context, therefore, if you wanted to ever find a picture perfect way for a bottom to be created and for a rally to develop, it is exactly this kind of a scenario that needs to play out and with this scenario for the first time I am seeing this level of pessimism. So if you ask me, markets go up and if you don&rsquo;t know a reason why they are going to go up and they go up after that, that is the beginning of the bull market.<br /><br />So if you ask me, what will make markets go up, I don&rsquo;t know, it could be a whole bunch of things but there is nothing where you can table thump and say that markets will go up and that is the perfect scenario for a rally to develop.<br /><br /><strong>Ekta: A large part of pessimism is also about the uncertainty with regards to public sector undertaking (PSU) banks. Your sense in terms of what the Budget can do to possibly change that and how important would a recapitalisation figure be this Budget?</strong><br /><br />A: My own sense is that the Budget has nothing to do with other than the recap figure and recap figures people are going completely loony, all over the place, people have talked to all kinds of few lakh crore etc. It is fair to say that when somebody as senior as the governor and somebody as responsible as the governor, in tandem with certain government officials talk about that these figures are exaggerated, we need to take that at face value. That is number one.<br /><br />I think the banks are going through a stress test they have never been through before and this stress test is only going to go make them stronger. One thing is very clear, the days of chronic capitalism are virtually dead. The days are going to delayed and getting your work done to have banks shell out loans, that is virtually gone.<br /><br />At least the haemorrhaging is stopped. Once that is stopped, what you need to do in terms of non-core holdings -- as one bank like Bank of Baroda (BoB) has shown you that their own internal working shows that they don&rsquo;t need capital from the government. So what can be more bullish than that kind of a scenario.<br /><br />For the first time, we need to be responsible and not paint the entire PSU pack with the same brush. We need to look upon each of these banks, there are some banks, which are more chronic in terms of the illness of the NPA than the others and there are some like Bank of Baroda (BoB) has shown who are able to step aside and say, we don&rsquo;t need government capital.<br /><br />What is the biggest fear in PSU banks, which is why the stocks kept going down was not the fear that the depositors would lose their money, that was never an issue. The governments made that clear. I think the fear was that there will be unlimited dilution of the kind that happened in the US. So that kind of unlimited, unwarranted dilution is the fear that has gripped the equity investors, they may not articulate it in so many words, which is the reason why the equity has kept collapsing because people are not sure that when the equity is needed, how much equity will be injected in a sense to dilute them out completely. So I think this represented a bankruptcy from an equity investor perspective which fear for instance at least BoB has put behind them.<br /><br />If individual banks start telling you that this is the capital we need, this is the capital that is allocated but as long as this is a black box which is the case for many of the PSU banks still, I think those stocks will still be under pressure but people will take heart from responsible statements of responsible MDs of some of these PSU banks. If they tell you, they don&rsquo;t need capital, they can manage without it, which means dilute non-core holdings, tier-II capital, preference equity but not a dilution of common stock, that is big news.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: There is complete pessimism right now, the consensus sell call now but the market will require a trigger to have a rally or do you think the market will rally as usual ahead of the trigger and the trigger would come six-nine months down the line. What could be that one possible trigger that could take the market higher?</strong><br /><br />A: I don&rsquo;t think the market will be accommodative enough to tell us what the trigger will be for us all to take a position and make money. If things don&rsquo;t work that way, the way things work is very clear that if the trigger was so obvious, it would not be there. So, the trigger needs to be something that you rationalise post event. The trigger needs to be something that you look back and say, I missed a sitting duck. That ought to be the case. So if you ask me, there are many things you could talk about which are there in public domain, whether PSU bank turnaround or for instance, new money but at the end of the day, there is only one line.<br /><br />Today given all the circumstances there are, we will go with the international markets. That is the least and probably the most likely outcome that is going to happen because today whether we like it or not, redemptions continue, the government institutions and mutual funds are stepping in and the foreigners are exiting.<br /><br />At some point in time, were the overseas flow to stop or miraculously turn because of something going on internationally, we will also be a sort of welcome recipient of that. Unless, of course the Budget proves us all completely wrong which shocks that we are nt expecting but with shocks that we are not expecting but if the Budget is just one other Budget largely a non-event and event out of the way by first week March then we will ebb and flow with international money, we will ebb and flow with that.<br /><br />I think the local money at best can be a holding operation. Something that softens the landing in the market if it is a hard landing and more importantly provides a cushion as a counter force or countervailing force. But, it is the international money that will provide momentum on both directions. There is a selling I would not say fatigue, but there is some kind of a selling spree, which is getting over and at some point in time, people will find value, there is reallocation among various asset classes going on worldwide and I think equity while not being -- what would help for instance is if the Dow suddenly worked not to be struggling in the 15,500 but to go back to 17,000 and you look back and say, Dow had a 10 percent move and we haven&rsquo;t seen this happening and at 17,000 it will be about 5-6-7 percent of its lifetime highs and then you starting saying stability has arisen when you are not expecting then other markets will follow suit.<br /><br />We have had a very decent four day rally and for the first time I am not a watcher of the Dow with a view to getting cues as to what to do with the Indian market but for the moment, I believe that international flows are going in the same way, we are underperforming right now because of certain fears about the Budget. I hope that some of these fears are set to rest or put to bed very quickly and were that to happen, I am of the opinion that believes that commodities are bottomed out, I believe that oil is ripe for a move -- the day oil crosses USD 36 per barrel in a couple of weeks thereafter it will be in the early USD 40s per barrel and I think some of those things were to happen, they will mark new milestones as the market tries to set its sight a little higher.<br /><br />I, for a moment, think that the Indian market is looking to inch higher and it is not ready to sell off anymore just as yet.<br /><br />With the disclosure that my family and I own DVR stocks, we did talk about it, I have not recommended it but it is a disclosure I would like to make.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_markets_nse_bse_stock_markets_356x200_3132_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-23 12:53:06</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>