<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/investors-concernedcapital-gains-aheadbudget-c-jayaram_5588421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Investors concerned on capital gains ahead of Budget: C Jayaram]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[C Jayaram of Kotak Mahindra Bank says post Budget, there is a possibility that the market may form a firm bottom on the back of feel-good factor.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Investor concerns currently are veering toward the Budget as there are obvious worries with respect to rumours of the definition of long-term capital gains period being changed, says C Jayaram of Kotak Mahindra Bank.</p>
<p>However, consensus view is that the Budget will be largely positive as expectations are low. Jayaram says, post the Budget, there is a possibility that the market may form a firm bottom on the back of feel-good factor and then move ahead.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of C Jayaram&rsquo;s interview with Ekta Batra &amp; Anuj Singhal on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Ekta: 120 companies being showcased, around 5000 one to one meetings which are lined-up can you just tell us the mood ahead of the Budget? Which is the biggest query that you are facing right now from investors?</strong><br /><br />A: It is an interesting period when we are having the conference which is just before the Budget and when the markets are going through reasonably challenging times. So, given the fact that the Budget is so close the obvious concerns are around the Budget. There is a little bit of a fear going into that right now from our capital market perspective because they have been sort of talks about whether there would be some change in terms of the way capital gains would be looked at long-term capital gains etc.<br /><br />There are concerns around what could happen there and some of those are the more immediate sort of issues which sort of concern investors.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: What is your own call? We have seen quite a bit of rally or recovery from the recent lows. What do you think could be the trigger for this market to break this down-trend that we have seen for last one year?</strong><br /><br />A: My own sense is that at this point of time assuming that the Budget would be considered broadly positive -- I think there is a good chance for that because expectations are fairly low from the Budget in terms of specifics.<br /><br />So, if you can get a good feel after that my sense is that you will probably find a bottom at these levels. Before we talk about breakouts and how the market will go up, it is important for investors to feel that there is a firm bottom in place and you consolidate at that level before taking the next moves.<br /><br />I am hopeful that post the Budget you will hopefully get in to that sort of situation where at least a firm bottom is seen at current levels we are looking at.<br /><br /><strong>Ekta: How important is the Budget for bank reforms according to you?</strong><br /><br />A: I am not sure that it is that critical because from a banks perspective, the two important things have been the recapitalisation of public sector banks and then the big issue of how the non-performing assets (NPAs), which now are starting to get recognised more aggressively how they will be handled. Neither of them are Budget issues in that sense, the recapitalisation of banks -- the last time around the Finance Minister had talked about a program of how we would recapitalise it. He will probably top-up that little more given the current situation. I think that is the expectation.<br /><br />On the other issue, the whole issue of the recognised NPAs as of now and then how they would handle that going forward, my sense is that while they may be an indication in the Budget as to how they propose to handle it, specifics would probably have to wait till later.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: You had <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software/infosys/IT">Infosys</a> CEO in your conference. It is a stock that has done well, though the sector hasn&rsquo;t done well. How would you approach the IT space from here on? There is the currency depreciation benefit but there are some headwinds as well. Do you think this sector could take leadership for the market?</strong><br /><br />A: Vishal Sikka&rsquo;s presentation was very inspiring. It gave us the impression that as far as Infosys is concerned they are looking at a completely different way of addressing the technology opportunity.<br /><br />Having said that, you mentioned that depreciation does help them at some level but it is more fundamental. Going forward, over the next few years, you will see some separation in the IT industry from players who have moved on at some level to another sort of zone altogether in terms of addressing market opportunities, which are there.<br /><br />Some of these will play out over a period of time and while obviously there will be winners by virtue of their adopting the right model, my sense is that it is not as if across the board you will see all companies doing well. You will see some losers as well.<br /><br /><strong>Ekta: We will have a lot of PSU banks, which will have to buffer themselves beyond the government recap money, which is given to them via sale of non-core assets. We are hearing the likes of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/infrastructure-general/larsentoubro/LT">Larsen &amp; Toubro</a> (L&amp;T) also now possibly looking to sell some amount of land. What is your sense in terms of how easy it is going to be to absorb such kind of assets in this market?</strong><br /><br />A: It will be difficult to generalise across the entire base of non-core assets because different companies have different types of non-core assets. Clearly, you can&rsquo;t sort of say that this is most vibrant market to be selling anything at this point of time, having said that, some of them will be forced to look at sales of some type.<br /><br />Like I said it depends on the specific asset we are talking about whether it is in the context of real estate or whether it is in the context of, for example holding which they may be having in some other companies. You will have to go more micro and figure out whether specific non-core asset will get the value which they deserve.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Since you interact with lot of global investors as well and some of them were part of your conference as well what has been the mood on India? We have seen relentless selling by foreign institutional investors (FIIs); to be fair it has been a global phenomenon as well. However, this is the kind of selling that we haven&rsquo;t seen for some time, almost on a daily basis. How are FIIs looking at Indian market and do you get a sense that the flows are about to reverse anytime soon or are we likely to see FII outflows for a long period of time?</strong><br /><br />A: From their perspective and you have different types of global investors, you have people who run emerging market funds; you have people who run India dedicated funds. There is no question about the fact that inflows into broader emerging markets and in a sense even India dedicated funds have significantly come off in the last few months. There have been redemptions on a regular basis from these funds.<br /><br />Broadly, the mood globally is in a sense negative about emerging markets. One can argue the fact that within the emerging markets pie, India does look better than a lot of other markets. That is small conciliation because what you are getting is probably a larger share of a much smaller pie.<br /><br />Broadly, it still continues to be outflows as far as they are concerned. My own sense is that, that is a phenomenon, which might lessen in intensity but I don&rsquo;t think you are likely to see significant inflows for another couple of months at least.<br /><br /><strong>Ekta: You have an interesting company Vedanta, Tom Albanese who is showcasing at your conference as well. Your sense in terms of how commodities would play out may be in rest of the 2016 and what are the kind of investor queries which are coming up specifically may be for Vedanta?</strong><br /><br />A: I will not comment about Vedanta specifically but at a broader level that is the sector which obviously is going through probably the most challenging phase, which I have seen for a long time. The consensus still seems to be that the commodities cycles have not turned. Oil, clearly the belief is that for the rest of the year we are likely to see a muted prices certainly not going above USD 40-45 per barrel.<br /><br />For a lot of the other commodities as well, it doesn&rsquo;t seem as if the cycle has changed definitely. So, to my mind, you will see challenging periods for many of these companies not just the domestic companies but even on the global front you can see the largest companies going through fairly difficult times.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_budget_2016_Jaitley_FM_NDA_356x200_5412_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 12:09:16</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,KMF,IT,LT,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>