<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/budget-could-be-+ve-trigger-like-aviation-prabhudas-lilladher_5321581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget could be +ve trigger; like aviation: Prabhudas Lilladher]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Dilip Bhat, Joint MD of the Prabhudas Liladhar says that aviation sector is a good hiding place for next two to three years. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Dilip Bhat, Joint MD of the Prabhudas Liladhar says that mutual funds, which are in sweet spot right now, are bound to feel redemption pressure. Other segments like gold and real estate have lost sheen, he adds. <br /><br />Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Bhat says that one promising sector for coming two or three years is aviation. The sector will continue to see tailwinds, both in terms of passenger load and oil prices, he says.&nbsp;<br /><br />Bhat&nbsp;says the current dip is a good buying opportunity in the sector. While <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/transportlogistics/interglobeaviation/IA04">IndiGo</a> disappointed the streets with Q3 results, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/transportlogistics/spicejet/SJ01">Spicejet</a> took off this time, he adds. <br /><br />In the banking sector, lot of stressed asset pain is behind us, he says that the sector will continue to test patience in near-term. <br /><br />The upcoming budget could be a positive trigger for the market, he says adding that the expectations are low at this point. <br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Dilip Bhat&rsquo;s interview with Nigel D&rsquo;souza on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: What is your take? There have been rumours, there have been some redemption pressures. Some of these mutual funds redemption pressure, what is the flow scene like currently?</strong><br /><br />A: As far as the mutual funds are concerned, they are bound to face some kind of redemption pressure, but having said that, after a very long time, the mutual funds are in a very sweet spot in the sense that all other vertical class of assets whether it is gold, real estate, all have really lost the sheen. So, the flows will not see a redemption in any big way in my opinion. I think they will start coming into the mutual funds gradually as the year goes by. <br /><br /><strong>Nigel: There were a lot of initial public offerings (IPO) that came out towards the latter part of last year and things look quite good. Any IPO that came out, they gave good returns at least the last three or four. InterGlobe, that is one stock and the aviation space on the whole, there was a bit of catch up that was playing out over there. Unfortunately, things not really going according to the plan. What is your take on the aviation space?</strong><br /><br />A: That is one sector that we will continuously see a good amount of tailwind whether it is by way of oil cost, or whether by way of the passenger load factor or both of them will provide a good tailwind. <br /><br />Of course, IndiGo was the one where there was some disappointment because second quarterly results and third quarterly results were not really up to the mark, but SpiceJet really showed that they could earn very good profits plus as what I understand that they have also repaid something like Rs 1,200 crore if the CEO is to be understood, I think he has repaid, so there generally a good amount of free cash. So, the aviation sector is something one should look at and look at the falls.<br /><br /><strong>Nigel: So, this current dip you believe is a good buying opportunity?</strong><br /><br />A: Very much. Aviation sector provides a good hiding place, at least for the next one and a half to two years and also showing a good growth.<br /><br /><strong>Nigel: We have been talking to a lot of experts. Everyone says India story is looking good, we are going to see some recovery in store, but the tone of the RBI governor really does not seem to be in sync with what is going on. Over the last few days, I have heard some criticism as well come in for our RBI governor. What is your take on that? A bit of a divergence over there?</strong><br /><br />A: I think RBI governor really is one of the few people who arguably one can say, understands the economy inside out, not just the Central Bank portion of it. He also understands the economy, so one has to in my opinion, one has to believe what he says and he is very clear in what he says that you have to compromise growth. <br /><br />Growth is not going to come, but fiscal prudence need not be compromised on that. So, that is a very important statement and that itself will set the tone for the markets.<br /><br /><strong>Nigel: I think that your target for the end of this year is around 9,000 odd. RBI governor&rsquo;s tone is going to be monitored very closely, but some of these banking stocks, they have mouth watering valuations. Do you believe the banking space is going to lead us towards that target of Rs 9,000 odd and how confident are you of the next 12 months in terms of the Nifty? What is the target over there?</strong><br /><br />A: When you are talking about the banking sector, you are largely talking about the public sector and maybe now, ICICI also has joined the bandwagon. So, surely a lot of pain is behind us at the moment and probably if one were to go into forward, by December, 2016 we would probably be over the hump. <br /><br />So, as far as the banking sector is concerned, by own consensus that of course, they will test your patience, but if you are really in for the long haul, apart from the private sector banks, even the public sector merits a lot.<br /><br /><strong>Nigel: I was just listening in to Latha: She was talking about the advance decline ratio, not looking so good and we have been seeing that on a periodic basis, sometimes the Nifty is higher with a gain of about 50-60 points and yet the advance decline ratio is nothing really to write home about even in terms of stocks at lower circuits. We have been seeing around Rs 200-300 on a constant basis. What is your take? Flavour totally out of the midcaps and smallcaps space?</strong><br /><br />A: I think my reading of the entire situation is that there is a fear factor and if you see the way the markets have been behaving in such a volatile way, even at a drop of a bad news, the market just sells off. <br /><br />So, at the moment, it is a fear factor which is really prevailing in the market and that is pretty overwhelming, but we all go through those phases in the markets. So, I will not read much beyond that. I think we are running into the Budget very soon and hopefully we will see a lot of action on the Budget. So, pre-Budget rally anytime should be in the offing as far as the market goes.<br /><br /><strong>Nigel: But this is the lowest expectation you have had getting into Budget. Do you think that could be good in hindsight?</strong><br /><br />A: Sure, if you see even in the Parliament, nobody is even talking about passing the goods and services tax (GST). So, the expectations are really very low at the moment and that in a way should act as a good trigger for the markets.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/asian_markets_356_3011_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-05 10:29:55</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,ML04,IA05,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>