<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/stocks-views/budget-2016-buy-sbi-hul-sks-microfinance-lic-housing-ashwani-gujral_5690341.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Buy SBI, HUL, SKS Microfinance, LIC Housing: Ashwani Gujral]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ashwani Gujral - Fund manager at ashwanigujral.com recommends buying State Bank of India, Hindustan Unilever, SKS Microfinance and LIC Housing Finance.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Ashwani Gujral - Fund manager at ashwanigujral.com told CNBC-TV18, "Since we all are supposed to be positive for the day, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/statebankindia/SBI">State Bank of India</a> (SBI) is a buy with a stop loss of Rs 150 for target of Rs 164. Anything positive will lead to a rally and that should be the guess that people should be taking."<br /><br />"<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personalcare/hindustanunilever/HU">Hindustan Unilever</a> (HUL) is a buy with a stop loss of Rs 840 for target of Rs 875. It has been positive in a good market and should do well," he said. <br /><br />"<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-general/sksmicrofinance/SM11">SKS Microfinance</a> is a buy with a stop loss of Rs 460 for target of Rs 500."<br /><br />"Generally, Budgets tend to be good for housing finance, all housing finance companies have gone through a correction, so <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-housing/lichousingfinance/LIC">LIC Housing</a> is a buy with a stop loss of Rs 400; look for a targets of Rs 421."<br /><br />"<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/pharmaceuticals/aurobindopharma/AP">Aurobindo Pharma</a>&nbsp;is up another 5 percent, so that is a buy with a stop loss of Rs 638 for target of Rs 660."&nbsp;<br /><br />"<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/breweriesdistilleries/unitedspirits/US">United Spirits</a> which was the sell on Friday also is now moving in the correct direction which is down. It is a sell with a stop loss of Rs 2,720; look for targets of Rs 2,580."&nbsp;<br /><br />"<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-housing/dewanhousingfinancecorporation/DHF">DHFL</a> has opened up fairly well, it is a buy with a stop loss of Rs 154, target of Rs 168."<br /><br />"<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/diamondcuttingjewellerypreciousmetals/pcjeweller/PJ">PC Jeweller</a>&nbsp;is sell with a stop loss of Rs 312, target of Rs 285. Even <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software/tataelxsi/TE">Tata Elxsi</a> is down. Also&nbsp;you have the Budget sensitivities like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/infrastructure-general/nationalbuildingsconstructioncorporation/NBC01">NBCC</a> which is a buy with a stop loss of Rs 850, target of Rs 915. You can look at a <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/hospitalsmedicalservices/fortishealthcare/FH">Fortis</a> which is a buy with a stop loss of Rs 164, target of Rs 178."<br /><br />"For <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/cigarettes/itc/ITC">ITC</a>, 10 percent move from the lows may indicate that it has&nbsp;bottomed out for a bit and you may have a Rs 315-320 type of rally on the stock."&nbsp;<br /><br />"If you have to be long, probably you could look at something like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/foodprocessing/heritagefoods/HFI">Heritage Food</a> where advantages are given to dairy, etc. It&nbsp;is a buy with a stop loss of Rs 535 and target of Rs 585."&nbsp;<br /><br />"In banks, maybe <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/statebankindia/SBI">State Bank of India</a> (SBI) and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/icicibank/ICI02">ICICI Bank</a> where there are a lot of shorts but not in general all banks, I believe may be 1 percent or 2 percent more on Bank Nifty is possible, 14,350-14,400; but not much more than that."&nbsp;<br /><br />"<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/engines/cumminsindia/CI02">Cummins India</a> is looking extremely weak, so that is a sell with a stop loss of Rs 815 for&nbsp;target of Rs 790."<br /><br />"<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/miscellaneous/titancompany/TI01">Titan Company</a>&nbsp;is a sell with a stop loss of Rs 325 and target of Rs 300 with the government going after luxury items."]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Buy_now_356x200_2413_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 09:37:30</Entry_Date><Category>Stocks Views</Category><sc_id>,SBI,HL,SM15,LIC,AP,DHF,MC08,PJ,TEI,NBC,FH,ITC,HFI,ICI02,CI02,TI01,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>