<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/rbis-move-as-expected-banking-keybudget-2016-uday-kotak_5269101.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[RBI's move as expected; banking key in Budget 2016: Uday Kotak]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Uday Kotak, Vice-Chairman and MD of Kotak Mahindra Bank says the key would be the banking sector, adding, "the government will be making capital commitment for the public sector banks".]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Today's monetary policy announcement was in line with expectation says Uday Kotak, Vice-Chairman and MD of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/kotakmahindrabank/KMB">Kotak Mahindra Bank</a>. Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Kotak says the Reserve Bank of India would look at signals on inflation and the fiscal policy, which is expected soon, to continue with the monetary accommodation.<br /><br />On the upcoming Budget, he says, the key would be the banking sector, adding, "the government will be making capital commitment for public sector banks."<br /><br />"At the same time, we want to make sure that the fiscal deficit is in control. Otherwise, that puts pressure on the bond markets and bond yields go up," he adds.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Uday Kotak&rsquo;s interview with Ritu Singh on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: What is your view on today's monetary policy announcement?</strong><br /><br />A: Today's monetary policy was completely on expected lines. The governor and the RBI have made it clear over last few quarters in fact, saying that they would obviously look at number one, signals on inflation and number two, more importantly, fiscal policy which is expected very shortly in terms of continuity of the monetary accommodation. And if we see progress on fiscal discipline which is now expected by the end of this month, in terms of what is the fiscal deficit, we would be getting a clearer view of how we go into the future.<br /><br /><strong>Q: The governor also gave a figure for gross value added (GVA) growth for FY17 at 7.6 percent. Do you think that that is a reasonable figure, as he puts it, or are we still short of what is expected out of India right now?</strong><br /><br />A: My personal view is that even 7 percent is a damn good growth in today&rsquo;s world. Therefore, whether it is 7, 7.5, 7.6, 6.8 percent, it does not really matter that much as long as we build a stable and sustainable growth rate with very strong macro-economic stability. <br /><br /><strong>Q: I also quickly wanted to get a word on the bank non-performing asset (NPA) clean-up that the governor has put into the deadline. Do you think too much pressure is being put on the banks too soon for them to be able to take these hits in the next two quarters?</strong><br /><br />A: Keep in mind finally if the government has to provide the capital, it begins to put pressure on the fisc, and over time, in a deflationary or a low inflation situation, the debt burden keeps on increasing over time. And therefore, I am a believer of facing reality, being pretty surgical and logical about it, and moving on. And that is something which is extremely important.<br /><br /><strong>Q: The Budget is coming up. Any key expectations from the banking sector?</strong><br /><br />A: The banking sector would basically, I think look at what the capital commitment is that the government will be making for the public sector banks, that is important. At the same time, we want to make sure that the fiscal deficit is in control, because otherwise, that puts pressure on the bond markets and bond yields go up. You are already seeing bond yields under pressure upwards partly coming out of conversion of discom debt on to state government balance sheets and therefore, we must look at fiscal deficit consolidated between centre and the states.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Since you spoke of bond yields and liquidity, was it a bit of disappointment that Reserve Bank of India (RBI) did not announce measures to ease liquidity in the system? Do you think there was a strong case for that?</strong><br /><br />A: You have got to know that probably government will increase spending between February and March. So, some of it may be coming out of surplus government balances. So, as they get spent you get money back in the system. I have been in the financial sector for the last 35 years and there is one thing I know February-March and early April are always tight periods of the year and I do believe that interest rates will get soft some time after middle or end of April.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/u/Uday-Kotak-356_2309_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-02 19:42:57</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,KMF,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>