<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/chinas-export-model-stillway-to-go-for-india-panagariya_4911321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[China's export model still the way to go for India: Panagariya]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[It may be in the news for the wrong reasons but the economic miracle produced by China is still something that India should take lessons away from, opines NITI Aayog Vice Chairman Arvind Panagariya.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>It may be in the news for the wrong reasons but the economic miracle produced by China is still something that India should take lessons away from. <br /><br />That is the takeaway from an interaction with Arvind Panagariya, Vice Chairman of NITI Aayog, who argues that India needs to take a number of steps to improve its export competitiveness -- not least, figure out a way to deal with the threat of depreciation of the Chinese currency.</p>
<p>Panagariya was speaking to CNBC-TV18's Shereen Bhan in an exclusive interview.</p>
<p>The economist maintained that even as the global growth has slumped, India should focus on "doing the right things" -- things that would help it increase its market share in the global exports market, even if growth in the overall pie is slow.</p>
<p>"How fast the global economy grows is less important," he said. "Let me explain. China has been growing at 10 percent for three decades. But between 1995 and 2013, OECD growth was only 1.4 percent. It's because China did the right things."</p>
<p>Panagariya cites the example of merchandise exports growth. "Its share in the world market grew from 2.3 percent in 1992 to more than 12 percent today. Today, our share is only 1.75 percent in merchandise exports. So we need to take this to 6 percent in the next five-six years," he opined.</p>
<p>But even if India starts to follow in footsteps of China, it faces several headwinds: key being China itself. <br /><br />Thanks to the slowdown, the Chinese currency has been caught in a downward move, after the country moved to a semi-floating regime, a move that some analysts said was a deliberate move to weaken its currency and give exports a leg-up.</p>
<p>Panagariya conceded that the yuan depreciation was a challenge. "If our currency appreciates relative to the yuan, it impacts our ability to export to the markets where we are competing with China," he said, adding that part of the reason that Indian exports have now declined for 11 months in a row is because the rupee has fared relatively well against peers.</p>
<p>But currency devaluation was one trick that China handily used to its advantage during the 90s, much to the chagrin of the West, something that India surely cannot do now in this age of global awareness, right?</p>
<p>Panagariya is not ruling out the option of India going down that way.</p>
<p>"Certainly, we have had a history of intervening in the foreign exchange market," he said.</p>
<p><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Arvind Panagariya's interview with Shereen Bhan on CNBC-TV18.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Q: Could you first comment on growth. The last conversation you had with me, you said that you were confident of 8 percent growth being achieved. Now the midyear economic review, the government has itself scaled down the growth target to between 7 and 7.5 percent. Do you believe 8 percent and 8 percent plus kind of growth numbers are looking farfetched at least in the foreseeable future?</strong></p>
<p>A: I think in view of the numbers that we have had for the first two quarters of the current fiscal year, perhaps getting to 8 percent for the entire year might be difficult although even that cannot be ruled out because some of these growth estimates get revised later on. So, we could yet see some upward revision.</p>
<p>However, I still remain optimistic that at least for the fourth quarter, when we get there, we would be touching 8 percent and that is consistent with the government's forecast of average of 7.5 percent if the first two quarters are not revised.</p>
<p><strong>Q: If I would ask you to comment on what we are seeing happen as far as global factors are concerned, China is the big dragon in the room so to speak and we are seeing how the Chinese stock markets are reacting practically every other day to the news that is coming in from China. That is worrying global markets at this point in time including ours. How concerned are you about the impact of the slowdown in China on global growth, our exports have been declining for 10 straight months, what will it mean then for India because without export led growth the 8 percent plus kind of number looks a far cry?</strong></p>
<p>A: To me at the end of the day global economy is whether or not or how fast global economy grows is less important. What's important is what we do here at home. Let me explain. Now, China grew from 1995 onwards or even before that actually but at 10 percent China has been growing for last three decades. Take the figures from 1995 to 2013 for Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) growth, only 1.4 percent.</p>
<p>It is not as if China grew because OECD countries were growing very rapidly. It was because China did the right things and its own share in the world markets merchandise exports rose from 2.3 percent in 1992 to today more than 12 percent. That is what we need to do; do the right things so that we acquire. Today our share in the world exports is only 1.75 percent; this is on merchandise exports, services will be a little bit more. Take this to 6 percent in the next five to six years, I think that is what we need to do.</p>
<p><strong>Q: At this point in time it doesn&rsquo;t look like the export picture is going to improve significantly even though the government is putting out arguments saying that the fall is really not that significant if you actually do away with the fall as far as oil is concerned, but we will get to export later. However, a quick comment on the recent yuan devaluation and what that will mean as far as Indian exports are concerned?</strong></p>
<p>A: If yuan depreciates and therefore we, relative to yuan, appreciate, it does impact our ability to export to the markets where we are actually competing with China. So, not only relevant for the Chinese market but it is also relevant for the third market where we are competing against China. So, it certainly matters and in that context clearly part of the reason our exports are doing not quite very well is that rupee actually though it may not have appreciated a whole lot against the dollar, against a lot of the other currencies, it has appreciated in real terms particularly.<br /><br />_PAGEBREAK_</p>
<p><strong>Q: Let me ask you about the next big economic event and that a lot of people believe could be the next trigger as far as trying to jumpstart growth in the domestic market and that is the Budget. The consultation process has now started. What can the contribution be as far as the Niti Aayog is concerned from the Budget perspective? I know that the Prime Minister has setup groups to look into what could be the possible ways that we could see recommendations being implemented in the Budget. What are the timelines that we are looking at and what is the emphasis of the slant of what the Prime Minister's ask is?</strong></p>
<p>A: The Prime Minister is quite open in his purpose in constituting these groups has been to get the ideas for big changes that may possibly be made. We will have to wait and see what the groups themselves come back and report. Niti Aayog's contribution is continuously there. As the vice chairman of Niti Aayog, I sit on most of these meetings where expertise in specific areas exists within Niti Aayog, we have members who specialise in social sectors, members who specialise in agriculture, they are again, if there are issues related to that that are being discussed at meetings with the Prime Minister, the members go and sit there. So we very actively participate in this.</p>
<p><strong>Q: What would you like to see in the Budget? What should be the emphasis of this Budget because if I could call this is the halfway mark Budget so to speak, this is going to be the third full Budget of this government and the implications of this Budget will be felt in that sense in the election year. So it is a crucial Budget for this government. What should the emphasis be as far as Budget 2016 is concerned?&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>A: Absolutely it is a critical Budget. I completely agree with you and it is little premature for me to speculate, nevertheless I will suggest one area where I would like to see action happen. At the end of the day, we just discussed and I firmly believe, in the end the large markets are outside, these are the export markets. We tend to focus more on the domestic market, which is relatively small; take electronics industry, our domestic market is 65 billion, the global market is 2 trillion plus - that is where we need to set out eyes and so I would like to see us in the next Budget begin to turn back to the policies that we were moving towards ten years ago, which was to be open, liberal and capturing the world markets. We did that very successfully. At the start of 1991, our exports to gross domestic product (GDP) ratio was only 7 percent at its peak, it went up to almost 24-25 percent and that happened during a period in which the GDP was growing rapidly. We are talking about exports to GDP ratio, GDP in the denominator is growing at 8 percent and export had to grow a lot.</p>
<p><strong>Q: What about agriculture because the agricultural distress that we are seeing in large parts of the country at this point in time and there seems to be a sense that it has not been addressed. I know the prime minister held a meeting to discuss issues like crop insurance and so forth but what would the recommendation from your end be as far as agriculture is concerned?</strong></p>
<p>A: We had a task force on agriculture that the Prime Minister announced on February 8, 2015; an occasional paper based on that task force has been posted on our website and we suggested number of different measures, but broadly three important areas. One, measures that improves the productivity in agriculture and these have to do with proper seeds, fertiliser use etc, large number of using hi-tech agriculture, whole host of measures there and then ensuring that the farmers get remunerative prices. Here the states have to carry out reforms on which we are having discussions with the states on a continuous basis, ongoing basis. I have gone to Andhra Pradesh, I have gone to Rajasthan and we discussed these things at the meetings but also more broadly through various other channels.</p>
<p><strong>Q: What would the specific recommendations be, of course things like minimum support price (MSP) or higher MSP etc will be something that government will look at but what would be the other key specific recommendations?</strong></p>
<p>A: The very important part of the reform, which has not gone fast enough in the last 10-12 years, is the Agricultural Price Marketing Committee's Act reform. A large number of products still remain outside of this reform process and that is where give farmers full rights to sell whoever they want to sell likewise on the buyer side, allow multiple buyers to enter the market and that will generate the competition, it will also reduce the participation of too many intermediaries and give farmers better remunerative prices. So that's one set of recommendations this paper makes.<br /><br />_PAGEBREAK_<br /><br /><strong>Q: Let me ask you then about what the road ahead looks like as far as the NITI Aayog is concerned. It has been one year for you here in office, trying to sort of play facilitator as far as this Team India project is concerned and at the same time try and put recommendations on board and operate as a think-tank to try and push the knowledge economy as well as innovation. What do we see from hereon and do you believe that you have been able to align the functioning of the NITI Aayog with the objectives that the PM had set out?</strong><br /><br />A: We are only one year old but I would like to think that we have laid the foundation for what the PM wants to do. We are a downsized the institution, we have reorganized institution. According to the priorities and needs of the PM, we have in the meantime also done good bit of work which in a way promotes already the Federalism or corporative competitive federalism agenda of the prime minister.<br /><br />We have brought out three reports of the groups of chief ministers and this is completely unprecedented that the central government on issues that are central government issues the governments sought the advice of the chief ministers and NITI Aayog quietly in the background nudged the chief ministers, nudged the states to come to a consensus and quite remarkably we have in three different areas reports by the Chief Ministers, which represents the consensus of the chief ministers, which will be now taking forward.<br /><br />Also the institutions working with the states has now shifted down. Previously NITI Aayog or its predecessor institution, the Planning Commission, used to give funds, allocate funds to the states. We no longer do that. So our relationship with the states is now very different. Instead of chief ministers repeatedly coming to the Planning Commission to get their share of the funds, now we have a two-way flow. So members visit the states likewise the officials from the states visit here. We also need to develop the institution as a think-tank, so we are inducting some new blood into the institution.<br /><br />Apart from the reorganisation that I mentioned, we will be bringing in lots of younger people into the institution. There is a whole set of young professionals we will be bringing in the next couple of months. We are almost there.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Have you been able to identify the people that you would like to bring in? Any particular areas that you would like beef up capability?</strong><br /><br />A: Our canvas is extremely wide. Therefore we purposely chose to look very widely. So we are talking in terms of from 30-40 young professionals to be inducted very soon into the institution.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Where are you looking at bringing these people in from, what is the catchment area?</strong><br /><br />A: It is all India in fact, there are people who were doing their degrees abroad -- Indians who were interested, they have applied. So the catchment area is virtually global as long as the institutions' requirement is met. We are also going just this week we are in the process of interviewing candidates for some officers on special duty. These are also from outside. So we are trying to get there to get the speed on the think-tank function of the institution.<br /><br /><strong>Q: At the last conversation that we had, you had said that you would undate us on the review of the 12th plan and you were waiting for the date from the PM -- this is proving to be a challenge, getting time from the PM, isn&rsquo;t it because that review hasn&rsquo;t happened so far?</strong><br /><br />A: PM is a busy person. He has to worry about the international aspects of the policy, national aspects of the policy.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Let me ask you about India's position at the World Trade Organisation (WTO) and there has been a fair degree of criticism on what India has been able to achieve or not achieve&nbsp; at the latest round in Nairobi. One can believe that it is in a sense status quo, we haven&rsquo;t lost anything but we haven&rsquo;t gained anything either. The other camp believes that we have weakened our case and the US has been able to, in that sense, bully everybody else into finally giving up on the Doha round, which is going to be bad news for countries like India. Do you believe that we are facing that situation where the Doha development round is practically going to come to an end?</strong><br /><br />A: We should look at the situation objectively. To me it seems that this is the first time, the United States almost looked isolated during the negotiations. It wanted to close the round completely and it didn&rsquo;t get too many sympathisers on that site.<br /><br />On the other hand, India's position was that we want Doha round to continue and there were lots of takers of that position. So in broad sense, I don&rsquo;t think we were the ones isolated. We also got the declarations on the two specific things that we are pushing for, which is the food stock results, there is a clear agreement, declaration in Nairobi on that and we were also pushing for the special safeguard for agriculture. On that also we got it.<br /><br />So in fact in terms of our own accomplishments what we ask for, we have more or less got -- Doha round itself. WTO is an institution that works with consensus. Now even if one member says that I don&rsquo;t want to negotiate the Doha round any further, you cannot make that member negotiate, especially when that member happens to be as powerful as the United States. So we certainly cannot force the US to negotiate the Doha round, US likewise cannot force the Doha round to be closed.<br /><br />So Doha round remains open at Nairobi except that whether we would see the negotiations progress as per the original agenda of the Doha round that is certainly is in question because US is not keen on doing that.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Let me ask you about the high speed rail project and there has been two camps on how one should read this. One camp believes that Japan is putting in the money so to speak and India is the big beneficiary here. The other camp believes that perhaps this is another indication of lopsided priorities and maybe we should focus our attention on upgrading our current railway infrastructure which is in dire need of upgrade. You have been personally involved with the high speed rail project, where do things currently stand and what would your rationale be?</strong><br /><br />A: For this project, the money came from the Japanese and much of it is more or less grants in aide, it is a highly concessional loan and therefore more concessional than even the International Development Association (IDA) loans of the World Bank which we always think always being aide. So this is coming as aide from Japan about 80 percent of the project cost.<br /><br />So in no way, does undertaking this project undermine our ability to carry out the other projects that we were going to carry out. So that is one thing to remember that it is not this or that. This has been additional project that we got and once we look at it that way that this money was available only for the high speed rail then the attractiveness of the project looks that much better because now it brings jobs here, it will create employment opportunities here. It will change our own Ahmedabad-Mumbai corridor for the better, a lot of economic development would happen as a result, lot of externalities do come with these kind of large scale projects.<br /><br />So I think this is a win-win for us. This is not in any way lost. As far as the statistics are concerned, we are now moving quite rapidly to start drawing the plans as to what very much retail kind of plan with the deadlines on various steps, how this will be done and all. So lots of visits are going to happen by me as well as foreign secretary through Japan and likewise. <br /><br /><strong>Q: As early as this month?</strong><br /><br />A: As early as this month, foreign secretary today is in Japan. I will, very likely, be going at the end of the month. There will be visits from the Japanese officials.<br /><br /><strong>Q: What is the first big deadline that we should be watching out for as far as this project is concerned?</strong><br /><br />A: First, we have to lay out the plan as to - the first big line of course if you are thinking in terms of first the land acquisition will have to happen and then actual construction has to start and you have to watch out for when the laying down of the line begins.<br /><br /><strong>Q: So the irrigation of course is one of the PM's big projects, one of the flagship projects, the Sinchai Yojna but specifically on the NREGS because again there has been a lot of back and forth on what the number looks like as far as the Budget paper is concerned but then what is released on the ground and given what we are seeing as far as the rural economy is concerned that there needs to be a bigger emphasis on the NREGS perhaps even a greater allocation?</strong><br /><br />A: I would also like to see some changes happen in the scheme itself. So that the asset creation aspect is strengthened, today its relatively weak. So, we should do that but yes, I think alongside we do need right now the rural expenditures to rise because that is where the demand has been tepid.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Key priorities for the NITI Aayog in 2016, the two-three things that you would like to get done.</strong><br /><br />A: Certainly we want to beef up in a big way and double up the think-tank function of this institution which has many different aspects that is what we would want to do.<br /><br />Secondly, my priority also is to take the message of economic reforms to the states continue to do that and we have had some success and in particular as I mentioned things that are already in the pipeline, things like labour reforms etc those we continue to talk about but one specific one that I want to see some success in 2016 is something on land leasing laws and digitisation of land records.<br /><br />Third, we hope that we can continue to play a crucial, critical role in influencing the central government's policies towards export orientation of the economy.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/arvind-panagariya-356_0329_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-07 14:36:55</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>