<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/budget-2016-govt-must-stick-to-fiscal-deficit-targets-says-dipen-sheth_5494481.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Govt must stick to fiscal deficit targets, says Dipen Sheth]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Dipen Sheth, head of institutional research at HDFC Securities says there is a storm brewing outside as well as inside India and this year is going to be volatile. Times are tough and the temptation to take few liberties on fiscal targets is high, but it would not be a good option, he adds.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Dipen Sheth, head of institutional research at HDFC Securities feels that maintaining fiscal discipline is critical for the government despite the current pain. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Sheth says there is a storm brewing outside as well as inside India and this year is going to be volatile. Times are tough and the temptation to take few liberties on fiscal targets is high, but it would not be a good option, he adds.<br /><br /> Pointing out the decline in savings rate in our economy to 30 percent from 35 percent, he says it is more like punishing savers, adding, "The more you punish savers, the more you postpone your pains into the future."&nbsp;</p>
<p>Referring to the non-performing liabilities&rsquo; crisis faced by the domestic banking system, he says he hopes the government will get stricter with defaulting corporate.</p>
<p>"I wish the government would do something that would bring the skin in the game back for a lot of errant promoters who have overleveraged and where apparently the money has gone elsewhere not into projects, " he says</p>
<p>"It is going to be very tough going, but so, the asset quality restructuring is a good place to start. You start recognising the problem. Then, you start addressing the problem," he adds.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Dipen Sheth&rsquo;s interview with Sonia Shenoy and Latha Venkatesh on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Sonia: You were listening in to what Udayan was saying. Do you think that this time in the Budget, because of the slower growth recovery. That may perhaps prompt a potential rethink of the government&rsquo;s policy stance away from fiscal consolidation and towards maybe increasing aggregate demand.</strong><br /><br />A: Times are tough and the temptation to take a few liberties with fiscal discipline is high. We look at it differently. The way we see is that this is actually the time when you need to stay the course and send out a signal that you are very serious about fiscal consolidation. In fact, these are challenging times and they call for tough actions. So many of the tough actions should actually take place outside of the Budget, but the Budget itself is the big bang policy statement for at least for fiscal policy. And where you are going to collect your money, where you are going to spend it. I think this headroom for fiscal indiscipline was actually available during the honeymoon phase of this government. The first or maybe even the second Budget. That is when the whole world was with you and everybody was madly in love with you so to say. And, they would have given you that leverage to do this. <br /><br />Right now, the world is in trouble, I completely take the point that revenues are going to be challenged. But then structurally, you cannot seem to let go of the reins at a times like this. So, there are ways and there are means. And if there is one headline message that I want to share with you people today, it is not just that the arithmetic of the Budget has to add up to fiscal consolidation. I will look for changes in character and changes in the rules of engagement with its citizens that the government should send out this time, not the arithmetic but the algebra of the Budget is going to be very important.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: As Dipen says, good behaviour on the macro front which is about one of the few things we have to boast about will perhaps, be very important in the Budget, not much will be gained by reneging on it and in any case, since I look at the bond markets every now and then, I can tell you the appetite also is not there in the bond markets to buy something like Rs 20,000 crore every week which is what will be needed if you go to a 3.9 percent fiscal deficit.</strong><br /><br />A: I do not want to sound like a theoretical economist here. The sad thing is that the more fiscal, in prudence that you indulge in just because there is pain right now, the more you are setting yourself up for longer term pain. Unless you are able to align the interest rates in India with global interest rates and that can only happen out of fiscal consolidation, you are punishing savers. This used to be a 35 percent savings economy, we are below 30 percent right now. And the more you punish savers, the more you postpone your pains into the future, you are just ignoring the basic problem. I mean 15 years ago, debt to GDP states and centre combines was something like 85 percent. We are down to some 67. Now, out of that 67, 49-50 would be the centre&rsquo;s share. This 67 has to come down meaningfully and the centre is more than three fourths of this. And, I really do not see debt coming down in absolute terms for the government. But debt to GDP can come down. So, again, nominal GDP is not growing the way it should have.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: So, even the debt to GDP would not come down?</strong><br /><br />A: Yes, so it is a very challenging time. You have got challenges on both revenues and expenditures.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: The market has had a double whammy. On one hand weak global cues and on the other hand, no improvement on earnings. Do you get a sense that our markets will now start to underperform even if the global markets stage a recovery?</strong><br /><br />A: Underperformance or outperformance versus global markets is something that at our level, I do not think we look at so seriously. What is important to see is where were we a year ago, we were 20 percent higher. Where are we today? We are at that 7,000-7,500 kind of band. There are serious problems. There are macro problems, there are structural so despite all the inflation falling off, the fisc kind of attempting to get into control, and there are policy problems. And again, I will come back to the Budget and say that this offers a great opportunity for the government to signal its intent to do deep fundamental reform and much of that is still pending, land labour, taxes, you name it. We are talking of financial system stress. And you have seen what has happened in this quarter, especially with the PSU banks and the asset quality ratio (AQR) going the way it has. And we talk of skin in the game. <br /><br />So, I wish the government would do something that would bring the skin in the game back for a lot of errant promoters who have overleveraged and where apparently the money has gone elsewhere not into projects, it is going to be very tough going, but so, the AQR is a good place to start. You start recognising the problem. Then, you start addressing the problem. Addressing the problem does not mean that you sell it off to an asset reconstruction company. Try buying a car and not paying the an instalment for a month. Somebody will be at your door to take the car back. Now, that is your skin in the game when you do not pay your instalment. Where is the skin in the game for a whole lot of these projects. So, some of them are stalled because of government inadequacies. A lot of these are going nowhere. Just because projects were inflated, money was taken out. Now, if you are not going to agree to this, then you are just looking the other way and denying the problems. So, this is actually the time this dry cleaning needs to walk the talk, the Budget is a good place to start.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: How do you look at a stock like Bank of Baroda? The numbers were qualitatively different from other public sector banks. Their problem to begin with was smaller than other banks. So, do you think at some level, this becomes a buy at all?</strong><br /><br />A: The way to look at Bank of Baroda, let me use this metaphor. Forget the arithmetic, look at the algebra. They have done in one quarter, what other banks were reluctant to do in two. This has a nameplate which says public sector bank. It is becoming increasingly private sector in character. All the problems are know, all the upsides can only now be fantasised about. So, that is the challenge for buyers to come in. There is very clear commentary from the management on two fronts. As much of the pain that could be made visible, that could be prudently recognised, even where technically it may not have been a non-performing asset (NPA), they have gone ahead and said that we sense pain coming up here and we will take this as an NPA now. Rs 15,600 crore slippage or something, some absurd figure like that. <br /><br />So, if this is not a clean up what is? This is the kind of signal that I am waiting for from the mandarins in the Finance Ministry to put things right in their house. The new CEO has made it very clear. The character of the bank is now changing. There is adequate capital. He is saying 18-24 months, it is unlikely. So, if there is a very good credit growth or something, then we might need capital, otherwise, we will monetise some idle assets. We have got enough capital on the books right now. What else do you want?<br /><br />So, optically, you are looking at a 1.5-1.6x kind of valuation, but when was the last time? So, we were doing some arithmetic this morning and when was the last time you could see a bank at 8x price to earnings ratio (P/E)? That is on FY18 basis. After factoring in terrible slippages, 3 percent annualised over the next two years. I think the character is changed here.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: What would you advice your high networth individual (HNI) traders now? Are you telling them to use all the rallies to exit because you will get better valuations for that category? There are some category of investors as Udayan was telling us who will not look at their stocks at all. They would have bought it years ago, but those who are active but investors, would you use any short covering bounce to exit or would you advise them to buy some stocks?</strong><br /><br />A: You mentioned traders and investors in the same breadth and I am not comfortable with that. You started off by saying what are you telling your HNI investors and now, you are saying what should investors do. So, you need to make up your mind, are you an investor or a trader in this market. So, if you are a trader, you will find reasons to buy and sell every morning and I am really not in that business. If you are an investor, then times are difficult, there is a storm brewing outside of India, there is a storm brewing inside of India, the next one year is going to be a year of reckoning and if you have the guts to take a 10-15 percent draw down from here, you should be a very aggressive investor right now. Nothing in the daily news papers or in the channels is going to scream out buy at you. But, when it will, you will have bought at bargain basement prices. So, that is the general message that I would have for people. Now, it does not look very convincing because this is the message I have been saying for the last 15 odd percent fall in the market, but that is where you are.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/h/Hdfc_356X200_2900_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-16 11:02:59</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>