<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-duty-revisioniron-ore-aluminium-to-boost-vedanta_5697321.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Duty revision on iron ore, aluminium to boost Vedanta]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Shares of the company, controlled by billionaire Anil Agarwal, rose as much as 3 percent after a Budget document said the import duty on aluminium will be raised to 7.5 percent from 5 percent while the export duty on low-quality iron ore fines would be scrapped.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>India said on Monday it would raise the import duty on aluminium but cut the export tax on low grade iron ore, a move that would benefit <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/miningminerals/vedanta/SG">Vedanta</a> Ltd the most as it is a big producer of both commodities.</p>
<p>Shares of the company, controlled by billionaire Anil Agarwal, rose as much as 3 percent after a Budget document said the import duty on aluminium will be raised to 7.5 percent from 5 percent while the export duty on low-quality iron ore fines would be scrapped.</p>
<p>The current duty on iron ore fines, mostly mined in the western state of Goa, is 10 percent. The government will also scrap the 30 percent export duty on low-quality iron ore lumps.</p>
<p>"The iron ore duty cuts will help miners liquidate stocks at a time when international prices are low," Mines Secretary Balvinder Kumar, who proposed the revisions, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The aluminium duty will boost local manufacturing by stemming the flow of cheap imports from countries like China, he said.</p>
<p>India unveiled a largely pro-poor Budget on Monday, announcing new rural aid schemes and skimping on a bank bailout, in a strategy shift that seeks to boost Prime Minister Narendra Modi's ruling party in coming state elections.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/2/2016-02-29T094156Z_1_LYNXNPEC1S0NS_RTROPTP_2_VEDANTA_356.JPG]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 15:29:21</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,SG,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>