<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/cnbc-tv18-comments/age-old-demands-top-developers-wish-list-for-upcoming-budget_5131741.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Age old demands top developers wish-list for upcoming Budget]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Age old demands like infrastructure status, easier credit and fewer regulations still top the wish-list of developer’s. However, MCHI-CREDAI hope that Arun Jaitley will be generous this year.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Some green shoots are visible for the Indian real estate sector, even if the recovery has not matched the hopes of developers, they do expect a helping hand from the Finance Minister in the upcoming Union Budget.</p>
<p>Age old demands like infrastructure status, easier credit and fewer regulations still top the wish-list of developer&rsquo;s. However, MCHI-CREDAI hope that Arun Jaitley will be generous this year.</p>
<p>&ldquo;It is extremely important that various facets of real estate are looked at on par with infrastructure because essential job creation and momentum in the economy is going to come from real estate, so it is very important that we look at real estate on par with infrastructure,&rdquo; Dharmesh Jain, President of MCHI-CREDAI said.</p>
<p>Developers admit that the government has given hope in a few areas, like the affordable housing for all mission, but lack of incentive for the same is a major concern.</p>
<p>&ldquo;We have heard a lot about affordable housing, we hope something is done on ground. Probably some scheme like 81B which was in existence several years back. Something like that will give a huge incentive to developers to construct affordable housing,&rdquo; Sandeep Ahuja, CEO of Richa Realtors said.</p>
<p>However this year the wish-list is not limited to the budget but developers also want faster progress on critical legislation like the real estate regulation and development bill which got sent to time-out in the winter session.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I would say that we are ready for it, we will also be expecting lot of transparency to come into the section and it will help the sector weed out developers who are scrupulous and fly-by-night,&rdquo; Ahuja added. &ldquo;Probably there will be commotion for a year or two, for developers to get used to the compliance system, but in the long run this will help the sector be far more professional than it is today.&rdquo;</p>
<p>For the real estate sector, the upcoming Budget, like the Budgets before it, is a source of hope. Hope that old business will be dealt with, and new business will be given its due -- and with this long list of demands and suggestions, the Finance Minister will have a lot to consider when he returns from Davos.<br /><br /><em><strong>Watch video for more.</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/r/realty3_4028_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-22 22:41:53</Entry_Date><Category>CNBC-TV18 Comments</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>