<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-earmarks-rs-1400-cr-for-dmic-project2016-17-budget_5729921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt earmarks Rs 1,400 cr for DMIC project in 2016-17 Budget]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The DMIC project has been planned as a global manufacturing and investment destination around the high speed 1,483 km length of western dedicated freight corridor of the railways as the backbone.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The government has earmarked Rs 1,400 crore for development of the Delhi-Mumbai Industrial Corridor (DMIC) in the Budget for 2016-17.</p>
<p>However, in case of Amritsar-Kolkata Industrial Corridor (AKIC) project, a token amount of Rs 3 crore has been set aside by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley.</p>
<p>The DMIC project has been planned as a global manufacturing and investment destination around the high speed 1,483 km length of western dedicated freight corridor of the railways as the backbone.</p>
<p>The project envisaged to provide modern infrastructure through smart futuristic and sustainable industrial cities across six states including Haryana, Uttar Pradesh and Rajasthan.</p>
<p>Similarly, the AKIC has been proposed to give a boost to industrial development in the densely populated states of northern and eastern India.</p>
<p>Further for the 'Make in India' initiative, the government has alloted Rs 324.35 crore in the Budget 2016-17.</p>
<p>As a whole, the Department of Industrial Policy and Promotion (DIPP), the allocation has been raised to Rs 3,026.55 crore from Rs 2,435.75 crore in the revised estimates of 2015-16.</p>
<p>According to the Budget document, the Department of Commerce will get Rs 4,362.8 crore next fiscal, marginally higher than Rs 4,338.65 crore in revised estimates for 2015-16.</p>
<p>It has earmaked Rs 725 crore for various export promotion schemes; Rs 1,200 crore towards duty drawback scheme and Rs 1,000 crore for interest subsidy scheme.</p>
<p>These allocations assume significance as exports are in negative zone since December 2014.</p>
<p>Jaitley in his Budget speech yesterday said that more support will be provided to exporters to give a boost to overseas shipments.</p>
<p>Under the duty drawback scheme, the government refunds duties on imported inputs for export items.</p>
<p>Exports dipped for the 14th month in a row, down 13.6 percent in January to USD 21 billion due to fall in shipments of petroleum and engineering goods, although trade deficit showed improvement.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/r/rail-corridor_356x200_0325_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-02 07:38:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>