<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-news/budget-2016-time-to-realigntax-treatmentvarious-financial-products_5605481.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Time to realign the tax treatment of various financial products]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[ELSS should be offered more tax incentives. Also the differential tax treatments that are given to various investment instruments need to be corrected.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Rajnish Narula</strong></em><br /><br />It&rsquo;s that time of the year when industries line up outside the finance ministry to make representations on their expectations from the forthcoming Union Budget 2016; expecting dole outs that would put them in better stead in the years to come. Fortunately the current government, as highlighted by various intellectuals, has been more receptive and has been taking feedback all the year round making the budget-day a customary event of review and course correction. While a majority of industries expect the government to focus on them and keep their interest in mind, the mutual fund industry has been an exception. In spite of it being highly regulated and under continuous scrutiny of the society and media, it has never made a representation for its own benefit and the only proposals it has been making are to do with the larger benefit of its customers i.e., investors. Continuing with the long standing tradition of keeping the &lsquo;investor&rsquo; at the centre of all our actions, I would like to encapsulate our budget expectations within the following broad underlying principles:<br /><br />1. Striving towards greater financial inclusion and promoting financial savings over physical savings<br />2. Channelizing financial savings into long term risk capital for industrial growth of the country<br />3. Removing impediments and anomalies to bring-in simplicity and ease of investing <br /><br /><strong>Financial inclusion and financial savings:</strong><br /><br />Mutual fund, as an avenue for investment, is the closest to the word &lsquo;democracy&rsquo; &ndash; signifying &lsquo;Of the people, By the people and For the people&rsquo;. By structure, it is a pool of small investments working only for the benefit of its participants. No other investment avenue can possibly claim its sole objective as &lsquo;investors&rsquo; benefit&rsquo; as a mutual fund can. As such mutual fund investments should be encouraged at all levels. Our Union Budget 2016 expectations are along similar lines:<br /><br /><strong>Jan Nivesh:</strong> As a step closer towards financial inclusion, there must be an announcement of a drive to link accounts opened under the Jan Dhan program to a new folio and automatically invest an amount above a certain minimum balance into a liquid fund. This would help even the uninitiated to get exposed to investments in mutual funds.<br /><br /><strong>Encouraging financial savings:</strong> In line with the government&rsquo;s efforts to divert savings from physical assets like gold, real estate, etc. there should be a provision similar to the erstwhile sections 54EA and 54EB which allow capital gains tax exemption from sale of long term assets like real estate, if invested in certain specified instruments. Mutual funds (both debt and equity) should be allowed as eligible instruments for this exemption.<br /><br /><strong>Help building risk capital:</strong><br /><br />For the growth of securities market, it is imperative to channelize long-term savings into it. Mutual funds can play a significant role in bringing greater depth to the markets (both debt and equity) and reduce excessive reliance on foreign flows. At a time when equity markets are witnessing huge volatility, in part due to FPI flows, we should make every effort to strengthen the domestic participation. Increasing the holding period beyond 12 months to qualify as a long term capital asset in case of equity (or equity mutual fund) investments would definitely impact market sentiments and retail participation, with no clear visibility on whether it would add immediately to tax revenues. Hence, we suggest it should not be done, at least, not at this stage.<br /><br /><strong>Alignment of tax benefit for pension products:</strong> Mutual funds have the experience and performance history to prove their expertise in managing long term money of investors. There is enormous scope of innovation in retirement / pension products that mutual funds can offer and hence a separate exemption limit similar to NPS u/s 80CCD of Income Tax Act, 1961 with an &lsquo;EEE (Exempt-Exempt-Exempt) status&rsquo; should be seriously considered. This will help provide long term risk capital to businesses from money collected in the accumulation phase of investors.<br /><br /><strong>Encourage ELSS:</strong> On similar lines as above investments in ELSS could either be eligible for tax benefits under a separate section or a separate carve-out from the existing limit under section 80C (currently Rs.1,50,000) be made for investors investing in ELSS funds. This also clearly aligns to the trend world-over of moving towards market linked return schemes as against government announced, assured returns saving schemes. Today, section 80C has a majority of such assured returns schemes which will add to the government&rsquo;s fiscal burden in the years to come.<br /><br /><strong>Make it simple and easy to invest:</strong><br /><br />Ultimately, it is simplicity and ease of investing which will encourage the masses to invest. A few expectations on these lines are as follows:<br /><br /><strong>Aligning various instruments</strong>: Today a number of similar instruments have differential governing laws, rules and taxations although the underlying investments may be same or similar. This makes the decision-making difficult for the investor who has to rely on advice which may not always be to his/her benefit. Some examples of such differential tax treatments are:<br /><br />&bull; Taxation on listed debt securities vis a vis debt mutual funds<br />&bull; Tax treatment on switch between different funds of mutual funds vis a vis similar switch in funds from other financial entities<br /><br /><strong>Easing the process for the investor</strong>: India, as a country has come a long way in its quest towards curbing unaccounted money and yet there is a lot to be still achieved. But, on the issue of enabling a uniform KYC for all financial instruments, it would help if the government could give some timeline for coming out with the guidelines for the same.<br /><br />There are many more expectations but I would limit them to a few very important ones list above.<br /><br /><em><strong>Author is CEO India, Canara Robeco Asset Management Company</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/u/Union_Budget_2015_4_356x200_3103_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-23 11:09:06</Entry_Date><Category>MF News</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>