<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/macro-economic-survey-2016-govt-must-retain-35-fisc-deficit-goalfy17-gdp-growth-7-75_5661041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Macro Economic Survey 2016: Govt must retain 3.5% fisc deficit goal ; FY17 GDP growth 7-7.5%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Survey said that the fundamental task of the Budget should be to preserve fiscal sustainability. This is on the lines of what RBI Governor Raghuram Rajan has been arguing all along; that fiscal prudence was essential for sustainable growth.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />Even as the debate over fiscal prudence versus growth rages, the Macro Economic Survey for 2016 has voted for&nbsp;fiscal discipline, saying that 'credibility and optimality argue for adhering to 3.5 percent fiscal deficit target' for FY17. The Survey said that the government needs to be in a strong position to service its debt. <br /><br />At the same time, the Survey has also forecast a difficult year ahead, with GDP growth for FY17 expected to be flat or lower at 7-7.5 percent.<br /><br />The Survey has projected a GDP growth of 7-7.5 percent for FY16, and the Central Statistical Organisation expects the economy to grow 7.6 percent this year.<br /><br />At the same time, the Survey also recognised the challenges in meeting the fiscal deficit target for FY17, in view of a slowing world economy, and the higher expenditure due to implementation of One Rank One Pension (OROP) and the Seventh Pay Commission report.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br /><br />At the same time it has said that India needed a more relaxed&nbsp;monetary stance, meeaning that interest rates&nbsp;should be cut.<br /><br />Last year, the RBI had cut benchmark rates soon after the Union Budget, saying it was convinced by the government's commitment to fiscal consolidation.<br /><br />The Survey said that the fundamental task of the Budget should be to preserve fiscal sustainability. This is on the lines of what RBI Governor Raghuram Rajan has been arguing all along; that fiscal prudence was essential for sustainable growth.<br /><br />A higher fiscal deficit means the government will have to borrow more, in the process pushing up interest rates in the system.&nbsp;<br /><br />Economists welcomed the realistic projection, while saying that the Survey was now overcompensating for last year's estimates of 8-8.5 percent when it had considered only the positive aspects of the global economy. This time, they seem to be focussing on all the things that could go wrong with the economy, economists say.<br /><br />The Survey has express confidence that RBI's consumer inflation target of 5 percent by March 2017 will be achieved. However, economists feel that could be a challenge given the implementation of&nbsp;the Seventh Pay Commission Report and OROP.<br /><br />Some economists feel that even if the target of 5 percent consumer inflation is achieved, the average for FY17 as a whole could be higher. Some economists even felt that the government may defer the payout of house rent allowance under the Seventh Pay Commission so as to keep a leash on inflation, especially on house rents.<br /><br />The Survey said that public spending needed to be increased and that GDP growth could climb to 8 percent over the next couple of years.<br /><br />The Survey expects current account deficit for FY17 to be between 1-1.5 percent, adding that it would be more than adequately funded through stable capital flows.<br /><br />It also said that the&nbsp;government should plan for 'currency realignment' following the adjustments made by China in its currency. In other words, the Survey is saying that rupee should be allowed to weaken some more.<br /><br />Some economists have argued that a weak rupee was the best way to counter dumping and shore up exports. Also, in Real Effective Exchange Rate (REER) terms, the rupee&nbsp;has room on the downside though it is hovering around a 30-month low.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/f/fiscal_fiscal_deficit_deficit_1312_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 12:49:44</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>