<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/stocks-views/budget-2016-buy-ongc-hindalco-sell-bel-tvs-motor-sudarshan-sukhani_5690621.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Buy ONGC, Hindalco; sell BEL, TVS Motor: Sudarshan Sukhani]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Sudarshan Sukhani of s2analytics.com is of the view that one can buy ONGC and Hindalco Industries and advises selling TVS Motor and BEL.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Sudarshan Sukhani of s2analytics.com told CNBC-TV18, "<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/oildrillingandexploration/oilnaturalgascorporation/ONG">Oil and Natural Gas Corporation</a> (ONGC) and <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/aluminium/hindalcoindustries/HI">Hindalco Industries</a> are buying ideas. The charts are supportive, so irrespective of what China is doing or what crude could do, I think ONGC and Hindalco so far are giving a sense of a rally that is likely to continue."<br /><br />"Sell <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/electricals/bharatelectronics/BE03">Bharat Electronics</a>. The stock is making lower highs, lower lows and underperforming the Nifty as well. Nifty is not doing anything anyway. So, there is a consistent downtrend here and the same applies to <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personalcare/godrejindustries/GI23">Godrej Industries</a> &ndash; lower highs, lower lows and underperforming, so you keep on selling it," he said. <br /><br />"<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-23wheelers/tvsmotorcompany/TVS">TVS Motor</a> has a disturbing chart because it has not underperformed yet but it is in a very large consolidation. My assumption is that this would break on the upside has been bellied. It is actually now almost on the verge of a breaking on the downside and has been an outperformer. So, if TVS breaks on the downside which is what the charts are suggesting, that is disappointing. However, it is a short sell."]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/buy_sell_356x200_0925_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 10:10:43</Entry_Date><Category>Stocks Views</Category><sc_id>,ONG,H,BE03,GS,TVS,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>