<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/budget-2016-govt-has-put-emphasisrural-eco-infrastructure-says-mehta_5697761.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Govt has put emphasis on rural eco, infrastructure, says Mehta]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Dharmesh Mehta of Axis Caital says while the capitalization of public sector banks is smaller than expected, there are positives like no move on the long-term capital gains tax. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Dharmesh Mehta of Axis Caital says while the capitalization of public sector banks is smaller than expected, there are positives like no move on the long-term capital gains tax. <br /><br />&ldquo;He (Jaitley) has maintained a great balance between spending versus pushing infrastructure and rural economy in that sense,&rdquo; says Mehta.<br /><br />Mehta believes that event risk in domestic market is over and the market will now follow the global cues. <br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Anuj: You are always an optimistic so would you say that this is a good Budget and secondly from here on what is the next trigger for the market?</strong> <br /><br />Mehta: It is great Budget with the kind of expectations we had luckily that has not come true, so clearly it is a good Budget. Looking at the current environment globally and in India, I don&rsquo;t think so Finance Minister had any great room to do anything heroic in this Budget. <br /><br />In fact he has maintained a great balance between spending versus pushing infrastructure and rural economy in that sense. <br /><br />Not giving into the long-term capital gains tax fear which we all had. Yes, the capitalisation of PSU banks is much smaller than what we expected but then who says that you can&rsquo;t do in between. <br /><br />So, clearly he has kept that option open. However, there are lot of small positive steps which have been taken to push the economy given the current limitation which he had. <br /><br />So, I think so the event risk is over now we will be back to global markets, what is going to happen in that and India will react to those news. Obviously, he has given you one hope of a rate cut by maintaining a tight fiscal deficit.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Doesn&rsquo;t look like there was anything negative for a stock like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personalcare/hindustanunilever/HU">Hindustan Unilever (HUL)</a> to react the way it is doing right now in Budget?</strong><br /><br />Mehta: There wasn&rsquo;t anything negative but as I said the global markets are bad so people are going to take some bets off the table and may be the foreigners are selling today because of the global environment. Not to forget on the year-to-date also India has been down in line with the global markets. Though one month it looks much underperformers, overall if you look at year-to-date we are in line with the global conditions. <br /><br />So, as I said the event risk is over where could have been much more down then we should have been, that is behind us. Now we are working as per what the global conditions are and may be standout may be in few months time. If hopefully the RBI Governor hears us and does a rate cut you have got a lot of strong chances of outperforming the global markets.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_economy_growth_GDP_356x200_2811_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 15:42:29</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,HL,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>