<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/infra-cess-likely-to-be-passed-onto-customers-completely-maruti_5713701.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Infra cess likely to be passed onto customers completely: Maruti]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Speaking to CNBC-TV18, RC Bhargava, Chairman of Maruti Suzuki says the infrastructure cess will be a burden to growth, especially look at the current volatility in the market.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Union Budget 2016 imposed a 1&nbsp;percent tax deducted at source (TDS) on luxury passenger vehicles costing more than Rs 10 lakh. A 1-4 percent infrastructure cess has also been imposed on PVs of varying categories.<br /><br />RC Bhargava, Chairman of Maruti Suzuki, says that while no company has yet&nbsp;made a decision on whether to pass on or absorb the cess, they will likely pass on the complete burden&nbsp;to the customers.&nbsp;<br /> <br />For Maruti, the TDS on luxury vehicles will likely not have much impact as the company does not have models in&nbsp;the&nbsp;price band, Bhargava said.&nbsp;<br /><br />He also&nbsp;discussed&nbsp;his growth outlook, saying that given the slowness in the economy,&nbsp;double-digit growth in FY17 looks challenging&nbsp;--&nbsp;something that he&nbsp;said would come about&nbsp;only if there was&nbsp;a pick-up in rural demand.<br /><br />The reduction in petrol prices is a certain positive for small cars and the decreasing gap between diesel and petrol cars will be advantageous for the latter, Bhargava adds. <br /><br />While the company&rsquo;s retail sales have been better than last year, some impact of Haryana agitation will be visible in February sales, he says.<br /> <br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of RC Bhargava's interview with Latha Venkatesh and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Sonia: I wanted to first ask you about this one percent to four percent infrastructure cess, how much of a deterrent would it be and would it be passed on entirely to customers?</strong><br /><br />A: Every company has to make its own decision and I don&rsquo;t think any company has yet made a decision whether they will pass on or absorb the entire amount or part of that amount but my guess is that companies will pass on the entire burden of this cess to the customers and at a time when the market is already struggling to grow a little bit, I think this burden will be a deterrent to growth.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Will you be more selective in passing on the hikes. Will it be passed on more to the SUV guys, the bigger chaps and you will be more slow in passing the one percent on the smaller cars?</strong><br /><br />A: No, the normal practice has always been that taxes and cesses are passed on fully as they apply to each model. That has been the past practice that I know of and SUVs in any case are burdened with a much higher cess. <br /><br />So, I don&rsquo;t think they can take anything extra from the smaller cars onto them at all. So, I think as far as I can see, the result will be that each model will have to pay extra according to the cess, which is liable to be imposed on it.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: A couple of other things, a passenger vehicle where the value exceeds Rs 10 lakh will attract a 1 percent TDS then there is an R&amp;D tax deduction that has been reduced from 200 percent to 150 percent, how much of an impact would all of that have you think?</strong><br /><br />A: That tax above Rs 10 lakh is something which is not likely to apply to us because I believe this Rs 10 lakh is the ex-factory price and we don&rsquo;t have a passenger vehicle, which is Rs 10 lakh ex-factory. So on that aspect, there will be no impact at all. The reduction in the deduction of the R&amp;D expenditure will apply not in this coming financial year but the subsequent financial year. So in 2016-2017 also this will have no impact.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: You have mentioned that all of this put together would have some impact on demand. Can you give us a sense of what the demand hit could be for the industry and for the company because so far this year, your sales trajectory has been quite good. Year-to-date (Y-T-D) the sales have grown 11 percent, do you think it will be tough to do double digit growth in the year to come?</strong><br /><br />A: I think next year double digit growth will be a big challenge with all that is happening unless this is a factor, which we cannot predict if there is a very good monsoon and rural demand picks up and the economy also as a result of some of the measures, which this Budget is proposed also starts growing something close to 8 percent then I think the cess will probably be absorbed to a large extent in terms of the customers' ability to pay.<br /><br />The reduction in petrol prices took place yesterday are very positive for the small car segment particularly because this small car segment is largely petrol. This Rs 3 reduction with the gap between petrol and diesel coming down to Rs 10 is going to give a big boost to petrol car sales.<br /><br />So, at this point making a prediction on what next year would be a little bit hazardous, I would like to see the impact of all these in the market in the next month or two and then take a judgement as to what next year is likely to be -- it reached double digit or will it not double digits.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Two months sales figure December and January are going to be confusing because of one of events, February in Haryana and the Chennai floods. So if you can look through all these disturbances and tell us how demand was? Were January and February better than a year ago January-February or even the months preceding, is there at least some tepid recovery?</strong><br /><br />A: As far as Maruti is concerned, our retail sales were higher than last year. The wholesale is different because that depends on how much inventory you want to carry but certainly this month, this Haryana agitation will have hit sales and that is why I am saying that let us watch what happens now in March and see whether the demands are picking up or not.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: I wanted to have a little bit of discussion on the yen impact on Maruti because that is something that has been concerning a lot of the street. As we speak today, the dollar-yen is at 112.5 so it is a multi-month high for the yen and as we know more than 25 percent of your costs are yen denominated. How is Maruti strategizing, what are the hedges, how much lower will your exposure to the yen be because of localisation over the next six months?</strong><br /><br />A: The yen does keep fluctuating. We have gone through periods when the yen remains around 100 to the dollar for a long time but the difference now is that the dollar itself has gone up against the rupee and it is now around 68-67/dollar, it keeps around that area now so that does have an impact.<br /><br />The import from Japan had been reduced and that trend will continue but not in a very large extent because most of the possibilities of indigenisation of inner parts have been fulfilled and unless the electronic industry develops in India, no major reductions are likely to happen.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: As a percentage of sales, can you quantify that for me? How much has the imports from Japan reduced as a percentage of sales?</strong><br /><br />A: I won't have the figure how much imports from Japan have reduced. That would only be possible after I check out the numbers from the people concerned but I am saying that the one extra factor, which has come in is that we have just started exporting cars to Japan. Those are yen denominated and if that export continues to be successful and if these cars are well accepted in Japan and the demand grows that will to some extent offset import from Japan.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Is there more to be squeezed in terms of margin improvement?</strong><br /><br />A: Very difficult to say because the commodity prices are going to remain favourable going forward at least for the next many months. We do hedge something around 30-40 percent of the commodities anyway though we have been going slow because prices have been falling. The other factors will now depend on how the demand grows because the major consideration on margins is that discount factor. How much discounts are necessary in the market and that depends very much on the market demand and that is why this cess will be a little negative.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/m/maruti356_2240_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 10:51:22</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>