<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/it/budget-2016-boost-to-technology-sector-means-boost-to-‘digital-india’_5629021.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Boost to technology sector means boost to ‘Digital India’]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[More budgetary support for creation of technological infrastructure is required to complement Government’s flagship initiatives such as ‘Digital India’, ‘Start-up India’, ‘Smart Cities’ and ‘Skill India’.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>BMR Advisors</strong></em><br /><br />In Financial Year (&lsquo;FY&rsquo;) 2015, the Indian IT-BPM (Business Process Management) industry is estimated to have accounted for USD 146 billion, growing by 13 percent over FY 2014 . The Indian IT industry today is India&rsquo;s largest and most diverse private sector employer, with a direct workforce of more than 3.5 million and supporting over 10 million indirect jobs. The industry is estimated to contribute over 9.5 percent of India&rsquo;s GDP and over 38 percent of total services export. Continuing with the momentum generated by his visit to the US, the Prime Minister renewed his pledge to further the course of &lsquo;Digital India&rsquo; initiative. Recognising the need to provide a fillip to the burgeoning tech start-up sectors, the Government rolled out an ambitious &lsquo;Start-Up India&rsquo; policy. These policy announcements coupled with renewed interest in investments in the technology sector have fuelled the growth of the technology sector. Proof of the pudding is in eating; implementation of these policy initiatives is key to match the expectations of the industry. A few more tax and policy initiatives are required to propel this key flagship sector of India to the next stage of growth and evolution. <br /><br /><strong>Key expectations</strong><br /><br /><strong>Policy reforms</strong><br /><br />&bull; More budgetary support for creation of technological infrastructure that is required to complement Government&rsquo;s flagship initiatives such as &lsquo;Digital India&rsquo;, &lsquo;Start-up India&rsquo;, &lsquo;Smart Cities&rsquo; and &lsquo;Skill India&rsquo;.<br /><br />&bull; Facilitate enhanced digital literacy in India by providing improved connectivity and access to technology supported by Government process re-engineering &ndash; this will empower citizens, start-ups and large organisations to experience digital transformation.<br /><br />&bull; Encourage more participation in Government&rsquo;s IT projects by SMEs and small innovative companies by simplifying procurement processes, revisiting bidder eligibility criteria, etc.<br /><br />&bull; Relax Reserve Bank of India&rsquo;s 2009 guidelines (subject to suitable safeguards) on additional authentication for Card Not Present (CNP) transactions, as per which a manual authorisation by customer is required every time &ndash; this will immensely help SaaS (Software as a Service companies).<br /><br />&bull; Robust implementation of the &lsquo;Start-up India&rsquo; policy; more coordination with and participation from state governments to make this a success.<br /><br />&bull; Extend benefits of &lsquo;Focus Product Scheme&rsquo; and the &lsquo;Served from India Scheme&rsquo; to all categories of IT products and services, respectively.<br /><br />&bull; Extend benefits under &lsquo;Service Exports from India Scheme&rsquo; to all categories of IT and ITeS, including Software Technology Parks of India (&lsquo;STPI&rsquo;) units. <br /><br /><strong>Direct tax</strong><br /><br />&bull; Extend R&amp;D incentives to the IT services sector &ndash; important now as the Indian IT service industry moves into a more mature and innovative stage.<br /><br />&bull; Extend weighted deduction on skill development incentives to the IT services sector considering that significant expenditure is incurred on employees&rsquo; skill development and skill upgrade to avoid skill obsolescence.<br /><br />&bull; Align &lsquo;royalty&rsquo; definition with conventional and acceptable international standards by providing explicit exclusion for standard payments, such as, routine telecommunication / connectivity charges, payments for shrink wrapped software, etc.<br /><br />&bull; Provide concessional tax withholding rate on payments to SMEs and start-up software companies.<br /><br />&bull; Reduce the margins under the transfer pricing safe harbour rules (which today vary from 20 to 30 percent) to help SMEs in easing their compliance burden.<br /><br /><strong>Indirect tax</strong><br /><br />&bull; Provide a robust alternate scheme of upfront exemption / drawback for IT / ITeS sector, particularly services exported from registered export oriented units, in addition to the current scheme of refund of service tax credits.<br /><br />&bull; Clarify that the place of provision of software development and related testing activities involving usage of prototypes / goods shall be determined with reference to location of the service recipient under Rule 3 of the Place of Provision of Services Rules, 2012.<br /><br />&bull; Clarify on the scope of &lsquo;intermediary&rsquo; services, especially in the context of marketing call centres engaged in the provision of ITeS not being an intermediary service.<br /><br />&bull; Address dual tax levy on software ahead of GST by removal of service tax levy on electronic supply of packaged software that is liable to VAT / sales tax. <br /> <br /><br />&bull; Extend customs duty exemptions and excise duty concessions notified for mobile phones and tablet computers (exemption for parts, components and accessories including sub-parts with a concessional rate of duty on finished product) to all types of personal electronic gadgets including customer premise equipment forming a part Information Technology Agreement or ITA list of goods.<br /><br />&bull; Prescribe accelerated rate of depreciation for ITA goods under the CENVAT Credit Rules, 2004, including a recommendation for such rate to also be adopted under the Foreign Trade Policy. <br /><br />&bull; Provide &lsquo;Declared goods&rsquo; status to all ITA goods, including parts and accessories, with specific reference to their 8 digit tariff code with a view to harmonize VAT / sales tax rates on such goods across States. <br /><br />&bull; Enhance the rate of abatement prescribed for IT hardware as well as software notified for MRP based central excise valuation. <br /><br />While the industry welcomes the slew of reforms initiated by the Government under its flagship initiatives like &lsquo;Digital India&rsquo;, &lsquo;Start-up India&rsquo;, etc, a smooth implementation of these is keenly awaited and hence, there is cautious optimism. The IT sector also expects swift redressal of its long standing concerns on tax reforms. <br /><br /><em><strong>1: The IT-BPM sector in India: Strategic Review 2015 by NASSCOM</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/d/digital_marketplace_shutterstock_356x200_4753_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 16:44:06</Entry_Date><Category>IT</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>