<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/corp-affairs-min-gets-rs-344-crore-budget-outlay_5701041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Corp Affairs Min gets Rs 344 crore Budget outlay]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Out of the total Rs 324.43 crore from non-plan segment, Rs 159 crore has been set aside for secretariat economic services and Rs 137.43 crore towards corporate law regulation related activities.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Corporate Affairs Ministry will have a budgetary outlay of Rs 344.43 crore for the next financial year, with most of the amount coming from non-plan segment.</p>
<p>The Ministry implements the Companies Act.</p>
<p>Out of the total Rs 324.43 crore from non-plan segment, Rs 159 crore has been set aside for secretariat economic services and Rs 137.43 crore towards corporate law regulation related activities.</p>
<p>According to a document of the Budget for 2016-17 period, the plan allocation for the Ministry stands at Rs 20 crore.</p>
<p>However, the latest outlay is lower than the amount of Rs 411.53 crore in the revised budgetary figures for the current financial year (2015-16).</p>
<p>The secretariat economic services takes care of expenditure of the Ministry, Investors Education and Protection Fund (IEPF) and e-governance project (MCA 21), among others.</p>
<p>The Ministry is implementing the new companies law, whose most provisions came into effect from April 1, 2014.</p>
<p>In his budget speech, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said a bill to amend the Companies Act, 2013, would be introduced in the current session of Parliament.</p>
<p>The amendments would seek to remove difficulties and impediments to ease of doing business.</p>
<p>"The Bill would also improve the enabling environment for start-ups. The registration of companies will also be done in one day," the Minister said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget11_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 17:20:02</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>