<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/corporates-expect-budget-to-lower-costdoing-biz_5685081.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Corporates expect Budget to lower cost of doing biz]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[India Inc expects the Budget to
simplify tax laws and increase compliance, apart from
improving both the ease and cost of doing business.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>India Inc expects the Budget to simplify tax laws and increase compliance, apart from improving both the ease and cost of doing business.</p>
<p>"Just as the government has done a commendable job in improving the ease of doing business, we would like more initiatives to reduce the cost of doing business as well," Tata Steel Managing Director T V Narendran said, adding that he expects the government to further build on its reform agenda.</p>
<p>Debjani Ghosh, Managing Director of Intel South Asia, said, "The Budget needs to walk the talk and show real execution towards the government's intent of making it easier to do business." <br /><br />Hemant Kanoria, Chairman and Managing Director of Srei Infra Finance, said the Budget should focus on streamlining regulations to reduce tax uncertainties and improve the 'ease of doing business'.</p>
<p>"The finance minister must make provisions to broaden the tax net, and one way to achieve this is to increase PAN registrations, which will result in substantial reduction in black money transactions.</p>
<p>"This will also make the proposed requirement of PAN card for purchases above Rs 1 lakh easy to implement," Muthoot Pappachan Group Chairman Thomas John Muthoot said.</p>
<p>Daksha Baxi of Khaitan &amp; Co said Finance Minister Arun Jaitley should simplify and bring clarity in tax laws, which will undoubtedly improve tax compliance, thereby increasing revenue.</p>
<p>"Removal or significant reduction in MAT rate will put significant cash flow in the hands of taxpayers to make much needed investments," Baxi said.</p>
<p>Yes Bank Managing Director Rana Kapoor said he expects the Budget to do everything to restart capital formation and investment cycle.</p>
<p>The finance minister also needs to restore the confidence of the private sector by furthering the reform process that is already under way to improve ease of doing business and de-stress the capital markets, he said.</p>
<p>"The private sector has subdued animal spirits which need to be revived. We need to get more high-octane energy in the economy, the catalyst for which is good capex spends and an accelerated resolution and reforms process," Kapoor said.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/budget_2016_income_tax_calculator_356x200_2043_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-28 13:44:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>