<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/budget-2016-spicejets-ajay-singh-wants-airlines-to-be-exemptedmat_5624501.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: SpiceJet's Ajay Singh wants airlines to be exempted from MAT]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[It is requested that airlines should be exempted from application of MAT till all the accumulated book losses (including unabsorbed depreciation) are set off against future book profits, says Ajay Singh, CMD of SpiceJet.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Direct Tax Proposals &ndash; Income Tax</strong><br /><br /><em>1. Exemption from Minimum Alternate Tax (MAT)<strong><br /></strong></em><br />Airlines in India have been operating in a hostile cost environment and being a long term gestation industry, there has been a huge amount of accumulated book losses (including unabsorbed depreciation) in the whole sector. It is requested that airlines should be exempted from application of MAT till all the accumulated book losses (including unabsorbed depreciation) are set off against future book profits.<br /><br /><em>2. Reinstatement of Sec 10 (15A) of the Income Tax Act<strong><br /><br /></strong></em> Exemption from withholding tax on aircraft / engine lease rental payments and obligations arising out of lease agreements.<br /><br />Lease rentals for aircraft and aircraft engines were exempt from Income Tax under section 10 (15A) of the Income Tax Act, 1961. This exemption has been withdrawn wef April 1, 2007 and withholding tax was imposed. <br /><br />All the Lease Transactions take place outside India and there is virtually no tax revenue on this account to the Government of India. This section should be reinstated with the additional benefits to Indian Leasing Companies and Leasing Transactions done in India. It will help in smooth leasing of aircraft and aircraft engines in India.<br /><br /><em>3. Exemption from applicability of Section 206AA of Income Tax Act in respect of Non-Residents payments.</em><br /> <br />Due to non-availability of requisite services in India, airlines enter into various agreements with foreign entities that insist on recieving payments net of Indian taxes. <br /><br />To avoid issues with Indian tax authorities, the foreign entities do not want to take PAN in India and airlines are forced to pay taxes on behalf of these entities. Such amounts are disproportionately high and add to airlines losses. It is requested that the provisions of Section 206AA should not be made applicable to foreign entities.<br /><br /><strong>Indirect Tax Proposals &ndash; Service Tax</strong><br /><br /><em>1. Increase of abatement available to the Air Transport of Passengers from 60 percent to 80 percent so that the effective service tax rates comes down to 2.8 percent</em><br /><br />The upper limit of Service Tax on ticket price, upto March 2012, were Rs.150 and 750 in respect of domestic travel and international travel respectively, however w.e.f. April 1, 2012, a new scheme of service tax has been introduced wherein the service tax is charged on the full amount of the ticket with an abatement of 60 percent. This change has made air travel more costly. In view of the fact that airline industry is in its nascent stage that too in a hostile cost environment with highly price sensitive customers, it is requested that the abatement on service tax on ticket price should be increased to 80 percent.<br /><br />We would further like to request that it may be clarified that the above abatement is always applicable to all the passenger related revenues earned by the airlines.<br /><br /><em>2. Availability of CENVAT Credit on Excise Duty Paid on ATF</em><br /><br />As the fuel cost in the Aviation Business comprises more than 50 percent of the total cost, therefore it is requested that CENVAT benefit may be allowed against excise duty paid on ATF.<br /><br /><strong>External Commercial Borrowing (ECB)</strong><br /><br />1. Enhance the individual airline limit to be based on the capability / capacity of the airline to service ECB, based on its revenue projections; Don&rsquo;t restrict this to end-use obligations. Allow the servicing of this borrowing through domestic earnings..<br /><br />2. Don&rsquo;t put a limit on Sectoral utilization.<br /><br />3. Extend this scheme of availing ECB by five (5) years.<br /><br /><strong>Justification:</strong> ECBs help airlines / the aviation sector to source working capital funds from foreign lenders at competitive rates for longer terms. Ministry of Finance allowed a separate window in 2012 for Civil Aviation sector in India to raise money through ECB. The overall ECB ceiling for the entire civil aviation sector was USD one billion and the maximum permissible ECB that can be availed by an individual airline company was USD 300 million up-to 31st March 2015. <br /><br /><strong>Aircraft acquisition and leasing</strong><br /><br />- We need to allow our financial institutions to purchase aircraft and lease it to airline operators. Right now only scheduled operators are allowed to import aircraft on complete acquisition basis without import duty.<br /><br /><strong>Justification:</strong> Currently foreign institutions own aircraft and lease it through tax friendly countries thereby avoiding withholding taxes. In contrast if Indian FIs/banks are allowed to acquire the aircraft then they would required to pay custom duties; further the Indian operators who would lease these aircraft from Indian entities (FIs and Banks) would be required to pay rentals with service tax. <br /><br />Also this will help the airlines on foreign exchange exposure.<br /><br /><strong>ATF to be considered as declared Goods</strong><br /><br />Recommendations for immediate action to bring ATF cost at par with other competitive markets: <br />-&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;ATF pricing should be based on actual costs not import parity<br /><br />-&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;All the elements of cost should be based on actual cost of efficient operations in a transparent manner and should be subject to audit and validation by airlines<br /><br />-&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;Private sector oil companies should be permitted at all the airports in open access<br /><br />-&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;ATF should be notified as &lsquo;Declared Goods&rsquo; with concessional rate of 4 percent as VAT<br /><br /><strong>Justification:</strong> The cost of Aviation Turbine Fuel (ATF) in India is amongst the highest in the world. ATF costs, on average, 55 percent more than leading aviation markets.<br />&nbsp;<br />India is ATF Surplus. India produces approx. 11.50 million metric tons of ATF per annum whereas the annual consumption is only about 5.50 million metric tons. Yet, we follow an &lsquo;Import Parity Pricing&rsquo; mechanism. The problem with this approach is compounded by high tax rates at the central and state level.<br />&nbsp;<br />Import Parity Price formulae includes costs that do not exist at all. All such cost are added on an ad valorem basis i.e. as a percentage of base cost. As the crude prices goes up all such cost in formulae also go up even when there is no actual cost increase. In addition to this the advantages of lower crude oil prices are not being passed on to airlines even after taking into account the INR/USD exchange rate.<br /><br /> Between June 2014 and January 2016 crude oil prices have fallen by 74 percent, however ATF prices have been reduced by 45 percent only. Even if we consider USD appreciation of 11 percent during this period, ATF prices should have been reduced by 71 percent. Oil companies are still holding 26 percent price difference with them.
<p>ATF pricing is virtually monopolized by PSU oil companies as open access at major airports is highly restricted to PSU oil companies only and there is no competition from the private sector. PSU oil companies offer Plats based pricing (pricing based on actual cost) to foreign carrier but not to Indian carriers which is highly discriminatory.</p>
ATF continues to be treated as a &lsquo;luxury good&rsquo; and is heavily taxed. Besides custom and excise duty, sales tax is as high as 30 percent and most of the states are charging in excess of 20 percent. Losses of the airlines are primarily driven by high sales tax on ATF as there is no set off available to airlines against the sales tax on ATF. Revenue to all the sates on account of sales tax on ATF is only about Rs. 180 crore per month.<br /><br /><strong>Lower taxes on MROs in India</strong><br /><br /><strong>Justification:</strong> Indian MRO&rsquo;s are cost in competitive due to high incidence of taxes ranging from service tax, local state vat. As a result Indian MRO&rsquo;s are expensive when compared to places like Sri Lanka, Dubai, China etc. This results in loss of job opportunities in India and valuable foreign exchange.<br /><br />- Indian MRO&rsquo;s are subject to Service Tax at 14 percent<br /><br />- High royalty charges charged by Airports (range from 13 percent to 30 percent)<br /><br />- There is local sales tax also which are charged adding to the cost<br /><br />- Custom does not allow 24/7 clearance of aircraft parts which could help in quick turnaround<br /><br /><br />]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/u/union_budget_2016_356X200_3935_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 11:36:27</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>