<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/cnbc-tv18-comments/excl-budget-2016-document-likely-to-getnew-look-this-year_5633821.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Excl: Budget 2016 document likely to get a new look this year]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Union Budget 2016 is likely to see a number of changes to the way it approaches the method of putting out estimates of expenditure.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Union Budget 2016 is likely to see a number of changes to the way it approaches the method of putting out estimates of expenditure.</p>
<p>Sources say the Committee of Estimates headed by Lok Sabha MP Murli Manohar Joshi has recommended to Finance Minister Arun Jaitley that he tweak the way a distinction is made between plan and non-plan expenditure.</p>
<p>Plan expenditure is expenditure allocated to various schemes through different ministries and is generally considered as more growth-oriented while non-plan expenditure is one that the undertakes in order to keep the house running: defence spending, interest payments, subsidies and salaries etc.</p>
<p>Critics have in the past said the government should do away with the distinction, saying it is a Soviet-era relic of central planning.</p>
<p>It is, however, not clear whether the Finance Minister will do away with plan versus non plan distinction -- though sources say some rationalization will be carried out.</p>
<p>Further, the Budget will see a split in Volume 2 of the Expenditure Budget, with deals with ministry-wise fund allocations.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry will also merge 10 demand for grants into heads that are related to specific ministries: for instance, demand for grants for the Army, Navy and IAF may be merged.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_budget_2016_Jaitley_FM_NDA_356x200_5412_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 19:45:17</Entry_Date><Category>CNBC-TV18 Comments</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>