<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-india-clean-environment-cess-to-hike-cils-avg-coal-price-by-20_5698121.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 India: Clean Environment Cess to hike CIL's avg coal price by 20%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Renaming the Clean Energy Cess as Clean Environment Cess, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech for 2016-17 today proposed to raise the cess on coal, lignite and peat from the current Rs 200 a tonne to Rs 400 per tonne.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Clean Environment Cess proposed in the Budget is likely shoot up <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/miningminerals/coalindia/CI11">Coal India</a>'s average notified coal price by around 20 percent.</p>
<p>"Our average coal price (notified segment) is Rs 1,000-1,100 per tonne and an increase of Rs 200 per tonne is almost 20 percent rise in coal price," a Coal India official told PTI.</p>
<p>Renaming the Clean Energy Cess as Clean Environment Cess, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech for 2016-17 today proposed to raise the cess on coal, lignite and peat from the current Rs 200 a tonne to Rs 400 per tonne.</p>
<p>Referring to the cess, sources said that this will have a negative impact in terms of power tariff will be much more for south India power plants that procure mostly low-grade coal which is priced at Rs 700-800 per tonne from Mahanadi Coalfields.</p>
<p>This will be because the Rs 200 per tonne additional levy will jack up the coal price by as high as 25 percent, sources said.</p>
<p>Coal India sells almost one-third of its coal output in grades 10 to 13 and the same is priced at about Rs 700 and 800 per tonne, respectively.</p>
<p>The higher grade coal price goes up to Rs 3,500 a tonne from Coal India in which impact would be less.</p>
<p>The development will have a negative impact on state-run CIL at a time when coal prices globally are crashing and the Coal PSU is struggling to sell more coal and dilute its stock in excess of 40 million tonnes.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/c/coal_2834_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 15:50:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,CI29,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>