<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/what’s-cheaper-what’s-dearer-after-arun-jaitleys-budget_5706181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[What’s cheaper, what’s dearer after Arun Jaitley's Budget?]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Here is the list of items getting cheaper and costlier for you post Arun Jaitley’s Budget 2016.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<a href="www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/things-that-have-become-cheapercostlierbudget-2016-_5611761.html" target="_blank">Click Here</a>
<p>Check out the list of items getting cheaper and costlier for you post Budget 2016 announced by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley.</p>
<p><strong>Water pumps:&nbsp; Cheaper</strong></p>
<p>Budget proposal Excise duty on electric motor, shafts, sleeve, chamber, impeller, washer required for the manufacture of centrifugal pump being reduced to 6%.</p>
<p><strong>Travel by ropeway, cable car or aerial tramway:&nbsp; Cheaper</strong></p>
<p>Budget proposal exemption to the services of transport of passengers, by ropeway, cable car or aerial tramway being withdrawn from 14 percent.</p>
<p><strong>Solar Lamp : Cheaper </strong></p>
<p>Exempt from excise duty from 12.5%</p>
<p><strong>Paper: Cheaper</strong></p>
<p>Basic customs duty on wood in chips or particles for manufacture of paper, paperboard and news print being reduced.</p>
<p><strong>Set top box:&nbsp; Cheaper </strong></p>
<p>Parts and components, subparts for manufacture of&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Routers, broadband Modems, Set-top boxes for gaining&nbsp; access to internet, set top boxes for TV,digital video&nbsp; recorder (DVR)/network video recorde (NVR),&nbsp; CCTVcamera/IP camera, lithium ion battery.</p>
<p><strong>Microwaves :&nbsp; Cheaper<br /><br /></strong>Nil basic customs duty being extended on magnetron of capacity of 1 KW to 1.5 KW for use in manufacture of domestic microwave ovens.</p>
<p><strong>Branded Clothes :&nbsp; Costlier</strong></p>
<p>Excise duty on branded readymade garment and made up articles&nbsp; of&nbsp; textiles of retail sale price of Rs 1000 or more being changed.</p>
<p><strong>Footwear:&nbsp; Costlier</strong></p>
<p>LCD/LED/OLED Panels:&nbsp; Cheaper</p>
<p><strong>Jewellery:&nbsp; Costlier</strong></p>
<p>Basic Customs Duty (BCD) imitation jewellery being increased to 15% from 10%.<br /><br /><strong><em>For slideshow <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/things-that-have-become-cheapercostlierbudget-2016-_5611761.html" target="_blank">Click Here</a></em></strong></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Arun_Jaitley_budget_FM_budget_Finance_356x200_4344_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 19:47:07</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>