<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-can-opt-for-longer-route-to-3-fiscal-deficit-targetsurvey_5585841.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt can opt for longer route to 3% fiscal deficit target:Survey]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The survey, conducted by Deloitte India, also opined that a business-friendly tax administration and speedy resolution of tax disputes were critical for the success of Make in India campaign.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Government can change its fiscal targets and instead go for a longer route to the 3 percent target to support demand till the time private sector recovers, a survey of tax and finance executives has revealed.</p>
<p>The survey, conducted by Deloitte India, also opined that a business-friendly tax administration and speedy resolution of tax disputes were critical for the success of Make in India campaign.</p>
<p>"Majority (62 percent) of the survey respondents believe the government can change its fiscal targets and instead opt for a longer route to the 3 percent target for the fiscal deficit.</p>
<p>"The purpose is to have a counter cyclical policy and support demand till the time the private sector is able to recover. An overwhelming, 90 percent said public sector needs to give a boost to infrastructure spending," said findings of the pre-budget expectations survey by Deloitte India.</p>
<p>As per the survey findings, 30 percent respondents expected an increase in the basic exemption limit from Rs 250,000 to Rs 300,000.</p>
<p>Further, similar to that of bringing down the corporate tax rate and phasing out the deductions/exemptions majority were of the view that the individual tax rates should be brought down over time.</p>
<p>The government had last year postponed reduction in fiscal deficit target by a year. The government is targeting a fiscal deficit of 3.9 percent of GDP in the current fiscal.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley will present the Budget in Parliament on February 29.</p>
<p>The survey, Deloitte India said was conducted in January with tax and finance executives of over 130 mid to large Indian companies and MNCs based in India.</p>
<p>Almost 79 percent of the respondents opined a business friendly tax administration and speedy resolution of tax disputes were critical for the success of 'Make in India'.</p>
<p>On phasing out of tax holidays or incentives and reducing the corporate tax rate from 30 percent to 25 percent, as many as 58 percent agreed that complete phase-out of tax incentives is a good measure and will reduce litigation.</p>
<p>The survey further said majority of the respondents have expressed a desire that the scope of Section 80C of the Income-tax Act be pruned to cover investment linked deduction, with an enhanced limit (higher than Rs 150,000).</p>
<p>In addition, the category of specified expenditure under Section 80C (such as tuition fee, repayment of housing loan principle) should be carved out as a separate deduction.</p>
<p>Over 70 percent of the respondents were also of the view that for ease of doing business, having a transparent system driven by process with minimum discretion is the most important factor.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/f/fiscal_money_356_1143_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 09:14:05</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>