<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rail-budget-2016-spendingcapacity-expansion-will-be-welcome-says-dastidar_5624441.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Rail Budget 2016: Spending on capacity expansion will be welcome, says Dastidar]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ghosh Dastidar, former member of traffic of Railway Board, says, of late project implementation has improved a bit, so if capital is available, then it will be used. But, the government needs to ensure that capital is spent on productive asset creation]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Investors as well as the industry is expecting Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu to increase capital outlay for FY17 BE by 20-25 percent to Rs 1.25 lakh crore year-on-year (YoY). Wagon procurement is also expected to increase to 18000-19000.</p>
<p>The industry is also expecting healthy improvement in allocation towards Dedicated Freight Corridor, coaches, MEMU and EMU.</p>
<p>Despite the expected increase in capital outlay, there is a worry on whether this will lead to any pre-determined goal. Ghosh Dastidar, former member of traffic of Railway Board, says, of late project implementation has improved a bit, so if capital is available, then it will be used. But at the same time, the government needs to ensure that capital is spent on productive asset creation, such as capacity enhancement projects, he says.</p>
<p>As far as the PPP model goes, Sachin Bhanushali, CEO of Gateway Rail Freight, while the model has not always worked for the Indian Railways, it is still a monopoly and is short of resources. Hence, the Railways has no other alternative but to depend on private capital to enhance capacity and improve the quality of infrastructure, he says.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Ghosh Dastidar &amp; Sachin Bhanushali&rsquo;s interview with Anuj Singhal, Latha Venkatesh and Guest Editor Nirmal Jain, Chairman of IIFL on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Nirmal: There are news paper reports that the capital outlay may increase by 50 percent this year for railways or even if it does by say 25-30 percent or such some significant number, do you think we have manufacturing capacity and administrative set up to handle that kind of increase in outlay?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Dastidar:</strong> Off late, their project implementation has improved a bit. So, if capital is available then probably they may spend. However, one thing one has to be very particular or cautious about is that whatever money they are going to spend is spent on productive asset creation, like capacity enhancement projects.<br /><br />Normally, Indian railway's biggest problem today is capacity constraint. If you spend that money in not so important projects like new railways, which are going to remote areas or advanced border areas then whole purpose probably will be defeated.<br /><br /><strong>Nirmal: There is a lot of talk and thrust on public-private partnership (PPP) model. This model hasn&rsquo;t worked in many other infrastructure sectors the way government or people would have expected. How optimistic you are on this PPP model in railways and in which segments of railways you think this can work well?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Bhanushali:</strong> I completely agree with you that the PPP model has not been a sparkling success in Indian context; particularly so within the Indian railways context. Indian railway is a monopoly and is short of resources. So, it has no alternative but to depend on the private capital in enhancing its capacity as well as improving the quality of infrastructure so that the services are available for the trade in general.<br /><br />Terminals and capacity on the line are the two areas where there have been shortages. The dedicated freight corridor project, which has been implemented primarily aims at increasing the doors of the line capacity.<br /><br />Development of terminals and creating a third party common service providers like the container train operators was one area where a lot was expected from railways. Railways, unfortunately in the past, has disappointed the investors as well as the entrepreneurs.<br /><br />A couple of things, which have happened in the past is that the implementation of the policies hasn&rsquo;t been to the favour of the investors and the entrepreneurs and the goal posts have shifted over a period of time. There is always a tendency on the part of railways to take more on to their side rather than leaving it on the investor&rsquo;s side.<br /><br />Unless this mind set is changed, unless there is an effort to make private investment in terminals as well the services, like the freight services or onboard services on passenger trains, are made more attractive to the investors at least not for super normal returns but for normal returns, new capital is not likely to come and PPP is not likely to succeed in Indian railways.<br /><br /><strong>Nirmal: When you say in the past experience has been disappointing, is past is last two years or may be several more years?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Bhanushali:</strong> I would say over eight years because the first implementation of the PPP initiative in its true sense started with the container train operator&rsquo;s model. Last nine years the container train operator sector in which is about in which about Rs 6,000 crore have been invested is trying to struggle and come to reasonable cash flow return if not profitability. It has not been able to do so.<br /><br />The tariff and non-tariff actions taken by railways have eliminated the domestic market for this particular sector, which was a big promise when it was open. So, the failure to come up to the expectation of investors as well as entrepreneurs, has been consistent across last eight years.<br /><br />There has been a bit of an attitudinal change after the new government came in. However, the new government at present seems to be concentrating more on resources mobilisation rather than addressing these issues.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: That is what I was coming to. What was the big announcement from Suresh Prabhu last year that he is raising capex by 50 percent to Rs 1 lakh crore and that he is looking at off balance sheet money of Rs 8.50 lakh crore. Did the railways bid out more last year in any area that you are aware of?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Bhanushali:</strong> As far as resource mobilisation is concerned, I think it involves two stages as Nirmal Jain was mentioning earlier. First is that you have to look for resource and get people to commit money. That part has been done well. Over a period of next five years Rs 800,000 crore were to be provided to the capital budget. Half of that has been tied up with World Bank as well as with LIC by Suresh Prabhu that is a sparkling success.<br /><br />The real taste of the pudding is in eating it so this money needs to be converted into investment in productive projects of creating line capacities, development of terminals, creating logistic parks where in multiple types of cargoes can be handled and there are rail and road switching hubs which are made available. The overall commercial viability or rather feasibility of rail product per se should also improve.<br /><br />The last part of it improving the visibility of rail product -- very little has been done. The Rail freight as well as the rail haulage charges which are levied to us have been increased to such a stratospheric level that with these input cost it is impossible to compete with the road sector. Road sector also has been benefited because of the softening of the petroleum prices. So the economic reality of market is something that the railways has not been able to address as far its own demand supply configuration is concerned.<br /><br /><strong>Nirmal: On this issue, now there is a weakness in the general economy and also as Sachin Bhanushali is pointing out that traffic is moving to road, do you expect that government will have the courage or the real ability to balance the freight and passenger tariff anomalies that have been widening over the years?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Dastidar:</strong> I don&rsquo;t think so, in India the freight rates are one of the highest in the world and passenger fares are one of the lowest in the whole world. It is the lowest, cheaper than the Bangladesh railway also. This I pointed out to the Railway Minister two to three times and requested him and board members also that railways' finance is bad because from freight side, they cross subsidise the passenger, loss in passenger service is to the tune of Rs 30,000-35,000 crore.<br /><br />I said that their effort should be to make breakeven and at the same time the freight side there should not be any increase. In fact, there is a justification for lowering it. However, since the balance sheet has to be balanced probably they are not being able to raise the passenger fare or rather not up till now prepared to do that and unless that is done, the freight is not going to be reduced. Unless that is reduced, the Indian railways freight side will be less competitive compared to the roadways.<br /><br />If you remember the results in 1990&rsquo;s, you will find the only way they used to adopt for balancing the balance sheet is to increase the freight rate and also to increase the passenger fare of higher class that is air condition class. The result was you see the entire 90&rsquo;s the incremental growth was minuscule 10-12 or 15 million tonne per annum.<br /><br />However, early 2002 to say 2009-2010 we tried and was to some extent successful in holding the freight rate. That is why in my time, it was 65 million tonne incremental growth in one year, my successor's year it was 66 million tonne. Now again it is coming back to that 10-12 million tonne incremental growth. So, I am not all that optimistic.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Railways_rail__356x200_1230_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 12:45:45</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>