<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/nifty-still-above-7000-market-eyes-macro-economic-survey_5659281.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Nifty still above 7000, market eyes Macro Economic Survey]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Coal India, Axis Bank, SBI, L&T and M&M are top gainers while Hero MotoCorp, Bajaj Auto, Bharti Airtel, Tata Steel and Maruti were losers in the Sensex.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /><br />11:55 am Budget outlook:&nbsp;</strong>Keki Mistry- Vice Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, HDFC says, he expects some changes in the income tax norms in the upcoming Budget but is unsure whether tax rates will be re-jigged or the tax slabs will be changed. Mistry believes it is important to increase the tax exemptions on home loans and even a marginal increase will pep up the home-buyers sentiments. Considering the increase in house prices has been significantly higher than increase in exemptions, even a little raise of about Rs 50,000 will go a long way in improving sentiment, he says.<br /><strong><br />11:45 am Macro outlook:&nbsp;</strong>Maintaining fiscal deficit at 3.5 percent of GDP is very important for the Indian economy, says Edward Teather, senior economist Asean &amp; India of UBS Investment Bank. The current structure is such that the pressure of the 7th Pay Commission is much higher on the states rather than the Centre. In such a scenario, the Centre has to show the way forward, he says. However, there is also a need for investment lift-off and for that to happen, the government will have to mobilise the savings in the economy and make it available to the private sector, says Teather. He believes constraining consumption is the need of the hour. Meanwhile, Vivek Rajpal, rates strategist at Nomura India, says a 3.5 percent number will provide relief to the bond markets. A combination of 3.5 percent fiscal deficit, open market operations (OMO) and an interest rate cut by the Reserve Bank will ensure that bond rates move closer to the 7.6 percent level.<br /><strong><br />11:30 am Subsidy:</strong> Government plans to directly transfer the fertiliser subsidy to farmers and a pilot project for the same is also being considered in 20 districts. The Department of Fertilisers (DoF) is working on a road-map to capture the details of farmers so that sales data can be captured and subsidy can be transferred to farmers' accounts directly, according to a Parliamentary Standing Committee report. "The Department (DoF) is working closely with the Mission Directorate (DBT) to implement DBT in fertilisers," the report added.<br /><br /><strong>Don't miss: <a class="bl_14" title="Govt plans DBT in fertiliser subsidy" href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-plans-dbtfertiliser-subsidy_5657361.html">Govt plans DBT in fertiliser subsidy</a></strong></p>
<p>The market is still holding gains as the Sensex is up 95.80 points or 0.4 percent at 23071.80 and the Nifty is up 32.85 points or 0.5 percent at 7003.45. About 893 shares have advanced, 1018 shares declined, and 137 shares are unchanged.</p>
<p>Coal India, Axis Bank, SBI, L&amp;T and M&amp;M are top gainers while Hero MotoCorp, Bajaj Auto, Bharti Airtel, Tata Steel and Maruti were losers in the Sensex.</p>
<p>Gold fell for the second straight day and prices shed another 0.36 per cent to Rs 29902 per 10 grams in futures trade today as participants engaged in booking-profits at prevailing levels, even as the metal maintained an upward trend overseas.</p>
<p>Continued profit-booking by speculators, dragged down gold prices at futures trade, but a firming trend overseas, capped the losses, analysts said. Globally, gold climbed 0.6 per cent to USD 1,240.04 an ounce in Singapore</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Stock_bse_nse_markets_sensex_dalal_street_graph_356x200_4055_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 11:00:23</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>