<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/fii-view/bad-newschina-could-take-markets-lower-andrew-holland_5587081.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Bad news from China could take markets lower: Andrew Holland]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Andrew Holland, CEO of Ambit Investment Advisors, says the quality of stocks that are rallying is quite uninspiring and there could be a swift trading move to 7600.
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Equity market is seeing a short-covering rally and any bad news from China, particularly yuan devaluation, could drag markets lower, says Andrew Holland CEO&nbsp;of Ambit Investment Advisors.<br /><br />Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Holland says the quality of stocks that are rallying is quite uninspiring and there could be a swift trading move to 7600. He further expects short covering in banks and metals space.<br /><br />Holland is of the view that cues from FOMC chief Janett Yellen's commentary is confusing and that the current correction in global markets is not a sign of recession. He advises investors to avoid trading.<br /><br />As far as the Budget goes, he will watching the event more for directions. According to him, banking sector needs to be fixed on priority.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Andrew Holland\\'s interview with Latha Venkatesh &amp; Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Latha: How are you looking at this somewhat kind of a comeback? Have you reduced your net shorts in the market, are you at the moment net long?</strong><br /><br />A: Yes, we have reduced our shorts and we are net long. We are thinking that the rally that we are seeing is a short covering rally. A lot the stocks moving today are not stocks we would naturally go and buy. So the quality of the rise is not inspiring us at the moment to be honest. <br /><br /><strong>Sonia: Purely for trade, would you advise making money in some of these beaten down spaces like metals, public sector undertaking (PSU) banks etc?</strong><br /><br />A: If markets remain more positive globally then this will pay off, but you got to be very quick. So it is not something that we are trying to play. It\\'s too much trading and you got to think about the longer term direction of the market rather than thinking about the very short-term. So it is not something that we are participating in at the moment. <br /><br /><strong>Sonia: What are you participating in. What are the pockets where you still see some amount of value on the upside and ahead of the Budget is there anything that you would be bullish on?</strong><br /><br />A: You hit the nail on the head. There is value and the value just not in our market, there is value elsewhere but here is the dilemma that we have at the moment and in terms of having any conviction one way or the other is that it is what is happening globally more to do with profit recession, not a recession in terms of economic recession. If it is a profit recession then always seen in the excesses of maybe monetary policy being taken out of valuations and the valuations have come down; kind of 87 when you saw market crushing because valuations were not going to justify the earnings growth. We didn\\'t actually have recession globally. So if that was the case then we have seen a very swift move downwards and that\\'s probably reflected and therefore you can start to repair after that because the data that is still coming out of the US is pretty strong but the problem with that last year is that if you through in China devaluation then all that premise goes away. <br /><br />The reason I am throwing China in there is that\\'s where we all are thinking the problem is going to emanate from, but go back to Japan and Europe over the past two years, they depreciated their currency hugely and still managed to not disrupt the world. If China can package something which we all get more excited about and still get depreciation. Does it have to be so bad and that\\'s where we are and that is the dilemma whether to go long or to go short. I think it depends now on how China reacts to all of that fears and they still need to do that fiscal stimulus which have been talking about now for many-many months and it is still yet to come. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: You would trade this rally only up to what-7,500. What kind of extent of pullback can you give it in the best case?</strong><br /><br />A: I think most people are thinking that rally could--because the concern about targets on the charts could get towards 7,600 again but it could change very quickly by any negative impact of oil price, China fears or appreciating yen, things could change overnight. So it's a rally which you have to be very quick and nimble to participate and that's why I say it's more trading than an investment.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: 7,600 is a distance from where we are now. What will bridge that space, which stocks?</strong><br /><br />A: It goes back to the short covering and that would be the big lead and the banking sector will be part of that, metals will be part of that. So beaten down sectors, beaten down companies would participate but at the moment the quality of the stocks is not lending itself to any kind of real optimism that the rallies, you could get that high and just saying what the market is kind of projecting at the moment once you cross those levels. <br /><br /><strong>Sonia: We were speaking with Udayan a while back and he said he won't be surprised if the market revisits the lows that we saw in the month of February, if it revisits it in the next couple of months or so. Would you concur with that view?</strong><br /><br />A: That would happen if global markets take a leg down and goes back to the fears about China and devaluation, capital flows from China and that story is still ongoing whilst market might edge up, its edging up with still looking over your shoulder what China might do or might not do and that is where we are. It is horribly confusing. <br /><br />However, when I listened to Janet Yellen, she said interest rates could go up or could go to negative rates and that is confusing message and we all are looking at central banks and trying to work out. Is the tool box they have at the moment, the right tool box or they needing new one. If those questions continue then market will go low because faith at the central banks could pull out of the mess that maybe we are going to what which they had done previously. So that is the fear there.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: You watch ITC?</strong><br /><br />A: Usually it doesn't have this kind of move ahead of the Budget in terms of the expectations. I have read in newspaper that tax on cigarettes could go up significantly. So the usual play will be there in terms of ITC, it's going to get hit. <br /><br />As I said I am not a big fan of trying to think about the Budget is going to bring but this time for foreign investors, given the Modi's Make In India, the Startup India, everything India - that unless we deliver on some structural reforms and kick-start this economy and the Make In India will just become a phrase that we can use but it is not doing anything in terms of moving the economy and getting things kick-started on the ground and that is where we are. So it an important Budget from that perspective without going into any details of what the finance minister can and cannot do. However, you would know this more, unless the banking sector is fixed and these are a lot of fixing, a lot of things just do not happen. I mean working capital is a key for a lot of companies and if they cannot get that the problem just exacerbate.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/asian_markets_markets_bse_nse_stock_356x200_3926_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 10:37:20</Entry_Date><Category>FII View</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>