<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/5-fold-hikegovt-budget-for-funding-start-ups_5850881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[5-fold hike in govt Budget for funding start-ups]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[According to Ashutosh Sharma, Secretary, Department of Science and Technology (DST), in the 2016-17 financial year, it will provide seed capital to 50-80 new ventures with funding ranging from Rs 50 lakh to Rs 1 crore per company.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>A five-fold hike has been made by the government in its Budget for funding start-ups in the next fiscal, a move which is in line with Prime Minister Narendra Modi's ambitious 'Start-Up India' initiative.</p>
<p>According to Ashutosh Sharma, Secretary, Department of Science and Technology (DST), in the 2016-17 financial year, it will provide seed capital to 50-80 new ventures with funding ranging from Rs 50 lakh to Rs 1 crore per company.</p>
<p>For the next fiscal year, the government has increased the overall funding to startups from Rs 40 crore to Rs 200 crore, he said.</p>
<p>"Funding has always been a problem for start-ups. With the seed money, the start-ups can approach venture capitalists or other funding agencies," Sharma said.</p>
<p>DST is a major funding agency for new ventures related to science and technology.</p>
<p>"Earlier, we would provide Rs 10 lakh per start-up but, this year, we have increased the funding substantially," he said.</p>
<p>Referring to an internal study done by a consultancy firm on behalf of DST, Sharma said that over the last nine years, it has invested Rs 200 crore in start-ups and its value had risen to Rs 4,000 crore with 10,000 jobs, too, being created.</p>
<p>The government will also open 25 new technology-business incubators to provide relevant training. Incubators are a major source of funding to these new ventures.</p>
<p>The government has also earmarked Rs 10 crore for creating "world class" incubators.</p>
<p>Sharma said one of the reasons for hiking the funding for start-ups was that new ventures other than IT have limited scope of raising money.</p>
<p>"Sixty percent of the funding would go to companies that are into hardware and manufacturing business," Sharma said.</p>
<p>Asked whether it was a risky preposition to fund start-ups and allocate more money to them, Sharma said many who start a new venture are PhD holders or qualified persons with knowledge in their field.</p>
<p>"So, they know what they are doing. More importantly, the proposal will be thoroughly scanned before giving money to the start-ups," Sharma said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/s/startup_villege_3353_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-11 08:10:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>