<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-expectations-miningmetals-sector_5308221.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget Expectations: Mining and metals sector]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Under the direct tax regime, one-tenth of the expenditure on prospecting, extraction and production of mineral during 5 years ending with the first year of commercial production is allowed as a deduction from total income. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>Prashant Khatore</strong></em><br /><em>EY India</em><br /><br />The outlook for mining and metals industry remains volatile globally with a sharp fall in commodity prices. Weak prices coupled with operational challenges relating to environmental and ecological concerns, social impact, health and safety of workforce, physical and economic resettlement, land rights, sharing of benefits etc make the sector vulnerable.</p>
<p>At the policy level, the Government has legislated the Mines and Minerals (Development and Regulation) Amendment Act, 2015, mandated the setting up of District Mineral Foundations (DMFs) and launched programs meant to provide for the welfare of areas and people affected by mining related operations, thus bringing reforms in the sector and thrust on fast-tracking projects. The tax environment and wish list however remain desired.</p>
<p>Under the direct tax regime, one-tenth of the expenditure on prospecting, extraction and production of mineral during 5 years ending with the first year of commercial production is allowed as a deduction from total income. <br /><br />Mining activities from the initial stage of reconnaissance operations to prospecting and ultimate production have a long gestation period and the 5 year time limit is inadequate to commercialize the operations. <br /><br />As has been a long industry demand, it is desired that amendment be brought to amortize the expenditure incurred during the period of 10 years, instead of the 5 years. <br /><br />Further, mining industry, being a highly capital intensive industry, providing more generous depreciation allowance at 60 percent on plant and machinery used in field operations and aligning the same to that applicable to mineral oil concerns would be a welcome step.</p>
<p>From an Indirect taxes perspective, any increase in service tax rate with the objective of harmonizing the same with GST rates would further increase the cost of mining in India, specifically where the output product is exempt from Excise duty. This would be a dampener for the industry. <br /><br />Also, given the surge in import of aluminum products, to safeguard the local industry, import may be regulated by increasing the basic customs duty on aluminum products from 5 percent to 10 percent. <br /><br />Further, an export duty may be levied on export of alumina, so as to discourage export of the same and encourage domestic supply at competitive prices.</p>
<p>Budget 2016 is anticipated to bring structural reforms to stimulate the economy and it is hoped that the sector remains high on priority for the government.<br /><em><br />(The author is Tax Partner at EY India. Views expressed are personal.)</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/m/mining_5408_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-04 15:27:29</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>