<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/insurance/budget-2016-insurance-sector-gets-special-attentionfm-arun-jaitley_5695921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Insurance sector gets special attention of FM Arun Jaitley]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Though there is no increase in income tax deduction for the insurance premium payment, finance minister offers the insurance buyer cheaper insurance policies.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />Budget 2016 had many announcements for the insurance sector, that are expected to offer more options to the insurance buyers in India.<br /><br />&ldquo;The budget proposal to launch a new health protection scheme will ensure penetration of health insurance and promote financial inclusion. The proposal for additional Rs 30,000 health cover for senior citizens will help reduce the burden of healthcare expenditure for the aged,&rdquo; says Sandeep Patel, MD &amp;CEO of Cigna TTK Health Insurance Company. The scheme should offer a helping hand to those 'Below Povery Line families' who are not covered by any health insurance scheme. <br /><br />It was widely demanded by insurance sector that the service tax on the insurance products should be removed. Finance Minister has heard this demand, though partially. Service tax on service of life insurance business provided by way of annuity under the National Pension System regulated by PFRDA will be exempted with effect from 1st April 2016. These services attracted a composite rate of tax at 3.5%. EPFO services too will be exempt from service tax, which are taxed at 14%. Composite rate of service tax on single premium annuity policies being reduced from 3.5% to 1.4% of the premium charged, with effect from 01.04.2016.<br /><br />Service tax on the services of general insurance business provided under &lsquo;Niramaya Health Insurance Scheme' launched by National Trust for the Welfare of Persons with Autism, Cerebral Palsy, Mental Retardation and Multiple Disability will be exempted, with effect from 01.04.2016. Extant premium attract service tax at 14%. <br /><br />A cut in service tax on the insurance policies should reduce the premium for these policies. This makes them affordable. Union Budget 2016 announced Government has approved the path breaking Crop Insurance Scheme- Prime Minister Fasal Bima Yojana. For effective implementation of this scheme a sum of Rs 5,500 crore is provided by Finance Minister. Finance Minister also announced that public sector general insurance companies will be listed on stock exchanges. <br /><br />There was a popular demand to increase the tax deduction limit of Rs 50000 to Rs 2 lakh under section 80C of the Income Tax Act. However, there is no such increase announced by the finance minister.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/a/all_insurance_356X200_5351_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 14:49:53</Entry_Date><Category>Insurance</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>