<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-a-toss-between-lower-fiscal-deficitgrowth_5141821.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: A toss between lower fiscal deficit and growth]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The upcoming Budget, which will be presented on February 29, will see Finance Minister Arun Jaitley trying to balance pressures from the Pay Commission report, and his promise to lower corporate tax and raise capex]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Finance minister Arun Jaitley can achieve a 20 percent plus capex jump in FY17 (30 percent in FY16) and a 20 basis points (bps) lower fiscal deficit, says research firm CLSA. "The target of a 40 bps reduction in the deficit (3.5 percent) will require greater sacrifices on growth, which is not desirable, given the state of local/global economies," it further says.<br /><br />Given the state of economies around the world, there is no denying that an added stimulus to prop the domestic economy (Indian) is needed, but equally true is the fact the there is limited headroom.</p>
<p>The upcoming Budget, which will be presented on February 29, will see Finance Minister Arun Jaitley trying to balance pressures from the Pay Commission report, and his promise to lower corporate tax and raise capex. Government's plan capex is up 57 percent&nbsp;year-to-date (YTD).<br /><br />Jaitley will, however, be aided by a higher collection of taxes on fuel and services, savings coming in from fertiliser subsidy and higher spectrum revenues. The government is also likely to meet its Rs 14.5 trillion tax collection target for FY16 and a further 15-17 percent tax growth in FY17 is also likely. It has also been taking advantage of lower oil prices and hiking excise duty.</p>
<p>To garner more revenue, the government can perhaps raise service tax further, but such a hike can be potentially negative for services. In FY16, the government has already raised service tax from 12.36 percent to 14 percent from June and also imposed a Swachh Bharat cess of 0.5 percent on all services from November 15.</p>
<p>"The government's aim of achieving 3.5 percent fiscal deficit in FY17 may be under pressure given the weak nominal GDP growth (we estimate a 3.4 bps drag for every 1 percent lower growth rate) and implementation of recommendations of the Pay Commission (30-40 bps depending on part/full implementation, on our estimates)," the CLSA report says.</p>
<p>According to CLSA, weaker than budgeted nominal GDP growth and a likely large miss on divestment inflows may drive the government to keep spending flat YoY over December-March 2016.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/e/economy_356x200_2533_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-25 09:58:59</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>