<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/insurance/budget-2016-pension-payments-should-be-tax-exempt_5542561.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Pension payments should be tax exempt]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Among many expectations from finance minister, payments from insurance policies should be free of tax. Union Budget 2015 should extend more support to insurance sector in the form of enhanced tax incentives.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Anuj Mathur</strong></em><br /><em>Canara HSBC OBC Life Insurance</em><br /><br />The Union Budget 2016 countdown has begun and all eyes are yet again on the Finance Minister with expectations. The life insurance sector also is looking forward to the budget expectations to give boost to the sector through tax incentives. Life insurance industry today contributes significantly to the national domestic investments. Through further tax benefits the government can incentivise people to invest in life insurance products which will act as a social security measure for them. <br /><br /><strong>1.Separate deduction under Section 80C -</strong> <br /><br />Life insurance is considered as the most effective tool for the purpose of tax saving for an individual under Section 80C. However, over the period of time, various investments and expenditures such as mutual fund, bank deposits, tuition fees etc. have been included within the overall limit of Section 80C. As a result, the share of investment in a life insurance allowable as deduction under Section 80C has shrunk.<br /><br />The government took this into account when presenting the budget in FY 2014-15 and increased the overall limit under Section 80C by Rs 50,000/-. While this was a positive step in this direction, there is still a need for a separate sub-limit for insurance and pensions under Section 80C.<br /><br /><strong>2.Exemption u/s 10(10D) may be allowed on the basis of term of policy.</strong><br /><br />Currently under Section 10(10D), any amount received from insurance company (other than in the event of death) in a life insurance policy is exempt from tax only if the premium in respect of such policies does not exceed 10% of the sum assured in any year. Accordingly, a single premium policy and policy to a higher age person may not enjoy the tax benefit.<br /><br />Life insurance is a long term investment and accordingly policy term is more important than payment mode or sum assured to premium ratio. Thus, suitable changes should be made by which the exemption under section 10(10D) must be allowed on the basis of term of policy and not by sum assured to premium ratio. Alternatively, an exception can be granted for single premium policy and lower sum assured to premium ratio for higher age person. <br /><br /><strong>3.Annuity/pension payment to be exempt</strong><br /><br />Annuity is an attractive financial instrument to deploy lump sum savings so as to get a regular income. However, currently the entire annuity income is subjected to tax in the hands of the recipients. <br /><br />Annuitants are generally senior citizens and taxing them would be against welfare policy. Post-tax annuity amount may not be sufficient enough to meet the expenses at the stage of retirement as the cost of living would have also gone up when a person reaches the retirement age. This would defeat the desired objective of securing the post retirement years. <br /><br />Therefore, suitable changes should be brought in so that amount received as pension/annuity is exempted from tax. <br /><br /><strong>4.Separate deduction for amounts paid to pension funds under 80CCC</strong><br /><br />Section 80CCC allows deduction up to Rs. 1.5 Lakh for contribution made by an individual towards pension plan. However, section 80CCE keeps an overall ceiling of Rs. 1.5 lakh for deduction towards payments under section 80C, payment towards pension plans covered by section 80CCC and payment towards NPS covered by section 80CCD.<br /><br />Unlike developed nations, there is no social security system in India. Therefore, it is crucial that people save for their post retirement years. Thus, incentivising people to invest in pension/annuity plan will reduce their dependency in the older age. This will help the Government&rsquo;s objective of fulfilling its social commitment as well as raising long term fund.<br /><br />Therefore, there is a need to provide for a separate deduction limit for amounts paid to pension fund. <br /> <br /><strong>5.Service Tax exemption for the insurance premiums</strong><br /><br />Service Tax exemption for the insurance premiums considering, the insurance needs of the customer. The Government can consider extension of the exemption of service tax on mortality charges to all insurance products similar to the grant in the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana (PMJJBY) scheme.<br /><br /><strong>6. Zero rating service status to Life insurance service under proposed GST regime.</strong><br /><br />As the government is committed to implement GST, the entire country is expecting certain big announcements in the budget. The insurance industry also has high expectations from the government over GST. <br /><br />GST being consumption tax which is passed on to consumers, under the GST regime the key implication will be an increase in the cost, burdening the end consumers. Therefore, the insurance sector has an expectation from the Hon'ble Finance Minister to recognize the importance of promoting the insurance sector and give optimum treatment to life insurance service by zero-rating such services i.e. taxable supply which is subject to a rate of zero percent with full credit and refund of the input supplies. <br /><br />Zero-rating services provided by life insurance companies will encourage a healthy market (National and at State level) by ensuring that no additional GST cost is created in the chain of supply.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/u/union_budget_2016_1_356x200_3956_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-18 13:36:21</Entry_Date><Category>Insurance</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>