<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/plan-to-raise-rs-21000-cr-bonds-via-irfc-ak-mittal_5648581.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Plan to raise Rs 21,000 cr bonds via IRFC: AK Mittal]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Speaking to CNBC-TV18, AK Mittal, Railway Board Chairman says that it will partner with companies like NTPC, SAIL, Coal India to raise Rs 18,000 crore. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu today presented the Railway Budget 2016-17 and spoke about the increased plan outlay to Rs 1.21 lakh crore from around Rs 1 lakh crore in the previous Budget.<br /><br />Speaking to CNBC-TV18, AK Mittal, Railway Board Chairman says that while the Budget targets are tough, the ministry will try achieving them in the specified period. <br /><br />Mittal says that non-fare revenue will contribute Rs 10,000 crore to the total revenue by FY17. Till now, there was not much focus on non-fare revenue, he adds. The government will also try to double its non-tariff revenue. <br /><br />The government also plans to raise Rs 21,000 crore through Indian Railways Finance Corp (IRFC) bonds, he says adding that it will partner with companies like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/power-generationdistribution/ntpc/NTP">NTPC</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/steel-large/steelauthorityindia/SAI">SAIL</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/miningminerals/coalindia/CI11">Coal India</a> to raise Rs 18,000 crore. <br /><br />Discussions are on with the World Bank as well for funding, Mittal adds.<br /><br />The ministry is planning to establish a Railway Development Authority soon. <br /><br />The government plans to augment more than 1,000 additional coached in the year, he says. E-catering will also be brought under the umbrella and will be launched in about 408 stations. <br /><br />The newly proposed Tejas train will be a premium train, but with concessional fares, he says. <br /><br />"We are also considering rationalisation of freight structure because we have been out bidden on number of commodities where road sector has become substantially cheaper," he adds.&nbsp;<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of AK Mittal's interview with CNBC-TV18's Rituparna Bhuyan.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: Let me straightaway ask you about the operating ratio. We missed the target in FY16, but for FY17 it was interesting to see that you have lowered operating ratio target. Can you just explain to us the rationale behind this move?</strong><br /><br />A: Last year has been a very challenging period because bulk of the revenue in railways come from freight side and because of the growth of the economy particularly in core sectors we were not able to move the traffic as we had projected. Even then we have controlled out expenditures substantially and that is how we are able to project an operating ratio of 90 percent for the year 2015-2016.<br /><br />Next year we have projected a growth in traffic by around 50 million tonnes and we intend to introduce many new services. We intend to also substantially raise non-fare box revenue. Uptil now we were only depending upon freight and fare for the source of earning and the other non-fare box of revenue used to be only 3-4 percent. <br /><br />World over this average has been substantially higher, 15-20 percent and we have decided to have a very hard look on this aspect and increase the non-fare box revenue that may come by way of parcels, advertisement, monetisation of land and other areas of revenue and this year we intend to double that part of revenue. Simultaneously we are also working on reduction of expenditure. We are working very hard on reducing our energy bill by almost Rs 5,000 crore.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Additional to what was seen in FY16, Rs 5,000 crore less than what was seen in FY16, is that what you mean?</strong><br /><br />A: Rs 5,000 crore is the total figure that is being achieved uptil now and further other measures are being taken to reduce it further. All this combined will result in an improved performance next year also. <br /><br />Next year we also have a challenge of pay commission burden and even then we are projecting an operating ratio of 92 percent and we are confident of achieving it.<br /><br /><strong>Q: How much of hit will the railways take on account of pay commission in FY16-17?</strong><br /><br />A: We are providing in this Budget around Rs 20,500 crore.<br /><br /><strong>Q: This is for FY17 if I am correct?</strong><br /><br />A: Right.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Non-fare revenue is a new strategy. You have already had non-fare revenues but as you said it is just about four percent. How much revenue from the non-fare box do you expect in FY17?</strong><br /><br />A: We are expecting a total revenue of Rs 10,000 crore from non-fare box.<br /><br /><strong>Q: In a sense it was an unprecedented move of increasing capital expenditure (capex) to Rs 1.21 lakh crore if I am correct. So, going forward what is your strategy in funding these capex. If you can just share some numbers with us because we know that GBS is around Rs 40,000 crore. Where will the rest of the money come from regarding this?</strong><br /><br />A: Capex basically is sum total of the total investment that goes into the railways. It includes the direct infusion of the funds by means of the gross budgetary support that we get from Ministry of Finance. We get some money from road safety fund, that also through Ministry of Finance out of the diesel cess. The sum total of these two figure says around Rs 45,000 crore.<br /><br />Then we have some internal generation of revenue which is surplus from revenue minus the working expenses. That will be around Rs 12,000-13,000 crore. Then we will be generating some money from bonds through our IRFC, that will be around Rs 21,000 crore. Then another Rs 24,000 crore we will be raising through Life Insurance Corporation of India (LIC).<br /><br />And one big source that I have been saying that these are direct sources of funding but then we have various corporations going on. This year you must have heard that cabinet has approved entering into joint ventures with states. So, lot of projects will be taken up along with state corporation where the cost of the project will be shared by the railways and state.<br /><br />Similarly we are taking up many projects which are customer specific like NTPC plants. Some line is to be to laid specifically for that purpose. Something for Steel Authority of India (SAIL), Coal India. <br /><br />So, all these stakeholders, the customer funding that will come which we have given the name as extra budgetary resources through partnership. That will be around Rs 18,000 crore and this all sums up to around Rs 1,21,000 crore.<br /><br /><strong>Q: If you can also tell us about institutional financing, what is the strategy forward on institutional financing? We have been hearing about possible tie-ups with World Bank and other institutions. What can we expect in the coming years?</strong><br /><br />A: At the moment we have a tie-up with Life Insurance Corporation (LIC)for Rs 1.5 lakh crore to be drawn over 5 years on very concessionary terms. We are also going to World Bank and they will give us some money and with that we will be funding some of our viable projects. That is still at discussion stage at the moment. However I hope by next year we should be able to finalise.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Let us talk about passenger fares. We understand that perhaps there was a political call being taken on that regarding not increasing passenger fares but going forward mid-way do we expect any rationalisation of passenger fares and what will be railways strategy on cross subsidisation of passenger fares?</strong><br /><br />A: You are aware that we get two third of our revenue from freight and only one third of the revenue from passenger side. Today the cross subsidy is of the order of around Rs 31000 crore, thereby meaning that we recover that much less which we subsidise from freight. So, over a period of time what has happened, we have highest freight rates as far as commodities are concerned and perhaps the lowest passenger fares.<br /><br />So, there is a need to correct this balance. However we carry large number of poor people and it is not possible to increase the passenger fares as perhaps is the need based on the cost of the service. There is absolutely no need or any justification for raising the passenger fares substantially. <br /><br />What we intend to do is introduce some premium services and the premium services will be charged at the price that they cost and it will be paid by the persons who are able to afford it. Conventional service for unreserved passengers, for poor classes will continue as it is. Some marginal variation rationalisations here and there are not ruled out.<br /><br />We are also considering rationalisation of freight structure because we have been out bidden on number of commodities where road sector has become substantially cheaper. <br /><br />We are having very serious look on those commodities. Whether we can marginally reduce the fares and in case it gives us the volumes which compensate for the revenue loss by reducing the freight rate itself we will go in for it. So, all that analysis and study is going on.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Railways_rail__356x200_1230_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 17:48:47</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><sc_id>,NTP,SAI,CI29,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>