<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/govt-is-trying-to-facilitate-entrepreneurship-jayant-sinha_5023441.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt is trying to facilitate entrepreneurship: Jayant Sinha]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Minister of state for finance Jayant Sinha says he has taken advantage of commerce ministry's consultations with start-ups and identified four key areas that the government needs to focus on. The government is also taking a lot of steps to streamline compliance, he adds]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The government is only trying to facilitate entrepreneurship, says minister of state for finance Jayant Sinha. The government's Start-Up India campaign which will be launched on Saturday.</p>
<p>Sinha says he has taken advantage of commerce ministry's consultations with start-ups and identified four key areas that the government needs to focus on. The government is also taking a lot of steps to streamline compliance, he adds.</p>
<p>Additionally, he says that his ministry will tackle taxation issues for VCs and entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>Sinha, however, says companies must distinguish between company-specific and sector-specific issues. "There is a need to look at issues that are cross-cutting industry wide," he adds.</p>
<p><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of the interview..</strong><br /><br /></em><strong>Shereen: Let me recap what were the Budget announcements in 2015, so, I am not asking you to tell us what Budget 2016 will tell us but in the Budget of last year the announcements related to startups space included a Rs 1,000 crore self employment and talent utilisation fund for incubators, ebiz portal which integrates 14 regulatory permissions, a Microfinance Unit Development Refinance Bank or what is called the Mudra Bank, royalty tax paid by entrepreneurs slashed from 25 percent to 10 percent, a Rs 10,000 crore India Aspiration Fund. These were some of the big ticket highlights of Budget 2015.</strong><br /><br /><strong>State governments are doing their own thing, Kerala has its own startup policy, the Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister has just announced his efforts to try and nurture the ecosystem, Karnataka is doing its bit but I am going to get you to start by responding to a comment that has just come in on my Twitter timeline and the gentleman Lalit Advani says when the government decides to get into a sector it creates a riot royal mess. How do you respond to that?</strong><br /><br />Sinha: All we are trying to do is what government&rsquo;s around the world have done very successfully which is to facilitate entrepreneurship, to get rid of hurdles and obstacles and then get out of the way so that these wonderful ladies and gentlemen can do what they do so outstanding well which is to innovate and scale up their businesses. Government&rsquo;s job is really in a sense to be the ground&rsquo;s person and the empire but the players have to be on the field, they have to make the centuries, they have to get the wickets and take the outstanding catches; that is really what they have to do, our job is to support them.<br /><br /><strong>Shereen: Your job is to support them but let me ask you this specifically now because what can the central government do in terms of playing facilitator. I can understand that your role would be significant when it comes to taxation and a lot of people actually have tax related woes, not just big corporates but even startups, how do you deal with employee stock ownership plan (ESOP) and so on and so forth, the angel tax for instance. So, long list of what ought to be done on the tax front. Is that largely going to be the remit of the central government because when it comes to actual approvals, when it comes to clearances that is the domain of the state government?</strong><br /><br />Sinha: How is it that governments can work with an entrepreneurial ecosystem is a matter that has been studied extensively around the world. Obviously, as we formulated our policies, we have taken advantage of that research. In fact I myself led one of those research efforts in fact for the United Progressive Alliance (UPA) government into 2010-2011 when we issued a very wide ranging set of recommendations on what should be done for the entrepreneurial ecosystem in India. So, we have taken advantage of that report, we have taken advantage of report that Professor Tarun Khanna did for NITI Aayog. We have taken advantage of all of the consultations that the commerce ministry has been doing with startups more recently in preparation of Startup India, Standup India.<br /><br />Based on all that research and our own practical knowledge, I myself have been a venture capitalist for many years, based on all of that very practical knowledge there are four major areas that this research tells us that government can really facilitate.<br /><br />Number one, of course, has to deal with financing. What can we do about financing and there we have already taken big step forward with the India Aspiration Fund; we can talk about that in detail.<br /><br />Number two, is in terms of compliance and there we have already started with ease of the doing business and we are doing a lot of work there and there is more to come.<br /><br />Number three, is the area that you brought up which is taxes. It is related compliance in a way but we want to really help in streamline taxation. Again that is an initiative that is underway for all types of businesses and all individuals and of course we will pay special attention to startups as well.<br /><br />Finally, it is all about innovation. So, as far as innovation is concerned, we really have to make sure that our universities, that our entrepreneurs, our innovators are able to work through incubators, through research universities, through collaborations so that we have the big and great ideas that can really spur the entrepreneurial ecosystem forward.<br /><br /><strong>Shereen: Thank you for articulating the four pillars so to speak on which the policy or whatever you announce is going to be based on but if I can ask you for specifics now because while you talked about financing, when we look at the wishlist that has come in from young entrepreneurs, the number one issue that they have is compliance. It is the ease of doing the business under that umbrella and then compliance within that ambit. Again I come back to my point, how much can you actually control when it comes to compliance, when it comes to the ease of doing business, how much can the centre really do?</strong><br /><br />Sinha: The centre can do a lot. We have already done a lot. You spoke about the e-business portal, obviously as far as labour laws are concerned, EPFO is concerned, we are doing a lot to streamline and consolidate compliance into one or two online portals and really simplify that. Then there is compliance at the state level.<br /><br />Now for the state level activities, we have come up with a very elaborate and comprehensive checklist that we have handed over to each of the states in terms of what they can do to make it easy for businesses to get started in to and run their operations. We have been working on that in collaboration with the World Bank and that has been given to all the states and we are working with states to do that.<br /><br />Now, the good news in all of this is that the states are competing with each other. I was just for example in Andhra Pradesh with honorable Chief Minister Chandrababu Naidu and he is throwing open the doors for entrepreneurship and for innovators to come and get started. Similarly in Maharashtra, Karnataka, West Bengal, all these different states are competing with each other to be able to attract entrepreneurs because we know that is where the jobs are and that for a politician is obviously the huge payoff here in that sense.<br /><br /><strong>Shereen: Let me ask you on tax and I am not asking you to give us a sense of what the Budget will look at in 2016 when you announce it at the end of February but do you acknowledge some of the issues that I am going to read out to you as problem areas that you could help address. In general updation of tax clause given the new regulatory environment, rationalising ESOP norms for promoters and employees this is a big wish as far as the start up ecosystem is concerned, reworking the income tax to allow the carry forward for losses beyond eight years. Are these issues that you are cognisant of, are these issues that you would like to address or can address?</strong><br /><br />Sinha: These are issues we are very cognisant of. Since the last 18 months we have been engaged with the Indian venture capital associations in a series of discussion around how to streamline taxation not just for entrepreneurs but also for the venture capital funds themselves because you have to remember that we have to build up a domestic venture capital industry as well and so we have already made a number of very major changes through the taxation regime for alternative investment funds around passed through and so on and of course we have been meeting with entrepreneurs as well. So, we are very familiar with all of these issues, we are tackling them.<br /><br /><strong>Shereen: Will you tackle them in Budget 2016?</strong><br /><br />Sinha: We are tackling them.<br /><br /><strong>Shereen: How many of them will you tackle in 2016?</strong><br /><br />Sinha: We will keep tackling them. You keep bringing them to us, we will keep tackling them.<br /><br /><strong>Neeraj Kakkar, Co-Founder &amp; CEO, Hector Beverages: Is compliance as well as innovation because what has happened over last few years is some of the laws written specifically in manufacturing sector they are out of date right now, they were written 20-30 years back. I am in food and beverage sector. When I am trying to launch a new food something on cutting edge, which is being launched in west or any other place do the laws prevent me from doing it. So, in some sense the regulatory environment is kind of preventing innovation and that is for non-tech sector because tech sector the laws are not there and probably there is far more openness. But for other sectors that is a huge hurdle to cross. If you have to innovate the regulation and law would prohibit you from doing that. So, is there a redressal mechanism in this new policy where I can go and tell can you help me out with this?</strong><br /><br />Sinha: The answer is yes, but first let me congratulate you on your wonderful products at Paper Boat. I am a very satisfied consumer and have often held up Paper Boat as an example of terrific innovation that is happening in India. So, fantastic work.<br /><br /><strong>Shereen: And they have done it despite of all the hurdles and obstacles that he has pointed out to you.</strong><br /><br />Sinha: Hopefully it will get better from here on. So, as far as various different industries are concerned obviously what we are trying to do with start up India, stand up India is to put in place an enabling framework that cuts across industries. It is not industry specific. Now, the issues that you are bringing up for manufacturing, there are similar such issues in many other sectors. In medical devices there are real issues around regulation. In education there are real issues. In renewable energy there are very significant issues as well. So, sector after sector you will find hat there laws, regulations policies that inhibit innovation and disruption and so on and we can't in an event like this tomorrow address it at an industry by industry level.<br /><br />There my recommendation would be that you have an industry association, you get together as an industry association and you come forward with what you think the policy changes should be. Do it as an industry, show that it is in the national interest, it benefits the consumers, it is not narrow minded and parochial simply to increase profits for companies but it is for the welfare of consumers. Write it out and bring it to the concerned ministry and I am sure they will work closely with you to see what can be done to make those changes.<br /><br /><strong>Shereen: So, we need a CII or a FICCI for start ups now?</strong><br /><br />Sinha: No, you don't necessarily. What you do need is to be able to distinguish between company specific issues and industry wide issues. So, if you come forward as a single company then their challenge always is to figure out is it just a company specific matter or is it industry wide matter.<br /><br /><strong>Shereen: I think the lot of the issues that Neeraj Kakkar was probably talking about are issues that the manufacturing sector at large faces. However, the second point that he made on a redressal mechanism because while we are talking about single window clearances and so on and so forth a lot of the problems that some of these young entrepreneurs face who did they go to. Do you go to the Department of Industrial Policy and Promotion (DIPP), do you go to the finance ministry. I mean can there be a redressal mechanism to try and address the concerns that may sometimes be specific to companies of their size and scale?</strong> <br /><br />Sinha: Again as I said if there are cross cutting in issues that cut across industries, right, then I think the ministry is the place to go to. They are very open, they are very responsive, so you can certainly go to them and say these are cross cutting industry wide issues and so go to the industry ministers for that. If there are issues that are specific to an industry then of course you will have to go to that ministry. If it is in medical device obviously you will have to go to the concerned ministry. If it is in food and beverages may be you will have to go to the food processing ministry. So, there is way you have to decide what is the nature of policy intervention that you want. <br /><br />Now recognise also that policy making, law making, regulations this is a dynamic iterative continuous process. It is never done. It is a process where we have to continuously get feedback from our consumers which are all of you and we have to then respond to that.<br /><br /><strong>Shereen: I am glad that you are saying that policy making needs to be dynamic, it needs to be iterative but let me use the e-commerce example now and time is of the essence as far as a lot of these entrepreneurs are concerned. We have been waiting for months now to get clarity on what the e-commerce guidelines will be. Will you have an e-commerce regulator? What is going to be the provision when it comes to FDI into e-commerce, Business-to-Consumer (B2C) e-commerce companies? Time is of the essence for people like them?</strong><br /><br />Sinha: There are many policy issues where you have to balance many stakeholders. You have to understand exactly what will serve the national interest. There are concerned ministries that are associated with many of these major policy issues. In this particular case obviously it is the commerce ministry that is looking into this set of issues and I am sure they will come up with a comprehensive solution to all of these.<em><br /></em></p>
<p><strong>Shereen: Let me labour on this because it is actually causing not just heartburn but is also causing companies to actually relocate out of India to other jurisdictions. So, when we are talking about start-up India, should this not be number one priority that actually address the regulatory ambiguities on a timely basis?</strong></p>
<p>Sinha: If it is a tax matter then let us talk, let us figure out what the ambiguity is and what the confusion is and we will try and deal with that. If there are other policy matters then obviously you have to go to the concerned ministry. Many people will be at start-up India tomorrow, obviously the commerce minister will be there as well and you can certainly bring this up with her as well.</p>
<p><strong>Shereen: Rohit how many times have you visited the commerce ministry on trying to sort of understand what the FDI predicament is going to be for the sector?</strong></p>
<p>Rohit Bansal, Co-Founder &amp; COO, Snapdeal: Actually a few times. However the question that I had was slightly different and maybe slightly more over arching than specific about commerce because I think that topic has been discussed so many times. What happens especially given in our technology industry, one is as entrepreneurs we are extremely delighted at the number of times government calls us to get our feedback which is very valuable because it is actually for the people that you are making law. It is very important and very good that our feedback gets taken in.</p>
<p>What happens especially in the technology industry, one of the important things is as many new sectors get created which probably had no definition in the past. We would broadly classify them into what are principle companies and what are platform companies. Commerce, market places are a subset of platform companies but companies like cab aggregation, food ordering, Google, Twitter etc.</p>
<p><strong>Shereen: So, basically regulation is not keeping pace with innovation in that sense?</strong></p>
<p>Bansal: Companies which are platforms by large where the content is created by someone else, on Google for example if I post content, Google is not really responsible for that content. Sure Google has to comply, making sure that some content which is objectionable shows up they should help the government take it down but they are not responsible for that content. Similarly what is owned by a platform versus what is not owned by a platform, many times is very blurry.</p>
<p><strong>Shereen: So, what is it that you would like them to do?</strong></p>
<p>Bansal: If we are able to clarify further as to what is in the domain of platforms and what is not in the domain of platforms, that will be very helpful because otherwise what can tend to happen is the laws which are written many years back around let us say for example how should goods taxation work in the country they are subject to interpretation of different establishments.</p>
<p>Sinha: That is a very valid point. As I just said policy making is a dynamic process. The way we can do it collaboratively in the most effective manner possible is for you all to come to us, if it is a taxation issue you come to us in the ministry of finance, if it is a policy making matter on e-commerce obviously the commerce ministry is responsible and you tell us where the shoe pinches, where is the pain point. Tell us specifically in terms of the policy, the language where you feel that there is a lack of clarity. Tell us what the alternative language would be. How would you actually define it specifically. Then we can get into discussion around is it possible, not possible, what are the benefits, what are the advantages.</p>
<p>As far as policy making is concerned you obviously want to get on with your business and scale it quickly that is what you need to do on your end, that is why the collaboration is required because for us there is a slightly other set of priorities that we have to think about. We have to make sure that it is fair to everybody, that it is transparent, that the national interest is not compromised in any way, the tax revenues are not reduced in any manner. So, on our end we have a very legitimate set of issues as well. So, the dialogue really is about trying to understand you have to do what you have to do and accomplish, we have to make sure that as custodians of your best interest and as stewards the responsibilities that we have, how can we best serve those interests as well. That is the process by which we then formulate policy.</p>
<p><strong>Shereen: Have you tried to do that Rohit?</strong></p>
<p>Bansal: Yes we have. The government is pretty receptive about all these ideas. We get called a number of times but as well all discuss the pace of innovation in technology is pretty fast hence companies would always expect governments to be faster.</p>
<p>Deepinder Goyal Founder &amp; CEO, Zomato: I have a question which zooms out even more. We are pretty much the only tech company based out of here which is trying to build a global business. It is very hard for us to build a global business out of India. Had we been based out of somewhere else it would have been relatively much easier. There are some things like you can't transfer money outside of India very easily, there are these Fema regulations and the RBI questions you like 20 times for every time you are about to remit even USD 100000 transaction outside of India. We understand why those laws were made but those laws hurt us quite a bit. Those laws were made because somebody misused some other laws. How do we balance the good and the bad here?</p>
<p>Sairee Chahal Co-founder, Fleximoms: We know that India raised one of the highest amount of FDI last year. I definitely feel that simplifying specially at an angel level transactions. My other concern is definitely the ESOP taxation and I think that is definitely hurting. It was a huge enabler of getting more people into the eco-system.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/j/jayantsinha_2411115_356_2300_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-15 16:56:28</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>