<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/capital-goods-ind-to-see-gradual-increaseorder-book-crisil_5630901.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Capital goods ind to see gradual increase in order book: CRISIL]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[CRISIL Research expects the order book for capital goods industry to increase gradually in the medium to long term, led by large investments in the power transmission and distribution (T&D) segment. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><em>Below is snapview of the state of capital goods industry by CRISIL Research</em></strong><br /><br /><strong>Order book to grow but margin expansion curbed</strong><br /><br />We expect revenue growth to remain sluggish in the near term due to declining order book and continuing execution delays. In fact, for the top six players, the order book fell by 1% in the first nine months of the current fiscal over and above a 2.4% fall in the last fiscal. <br /><br />However, the order book is expected to increase gradually in the medium to long term, led by large investments in the power transmission and distribution (T&amp;D) segment. Augmentation of inter-regional capacities in the north (investments - Rs 125 billion), south (Rs 530 billion), and north-east (Rs 51 billion) will drive investments in transmission whereas higher government outlays under the Integrated Power Development Scheme and Deendayal Upadhyaya Gram Jyoti Yojana (Rs 1,160 billion by 2021-22) will boost investments in power distribution. Higher investments in railways and metro projects will also support order inflows. On the other hand, demand from the boiler turbine and generator (BTG) segment will remain low due to weak power demand and stretched financials of power generation players. <br /><br />Competition from domestic and Chinese players remains intense in BTG and T&amp;D equipment segments. In the 10 months of the current fiscal, orders bagged by Chinese players in the sub-station and transformers rose multi-fold to Rs 15 billion compared with Rs 2 billion in the previous year. Nearly 44% of BTG orders placed over April 2013-December 2015 were also bagged by Chinese equipment suppliers, despite imposition of customs duty.<br /><br />The industry is plagued by working capital issues because of huge delays in payments from clients, which has raised interest costs sharply and hit profitability. This, coupled with high competition caused aggregate operating margins to decline by 290 basis points (bps) to 10.5% in the last fiscal, and by 1,280 bps to (6.6)% in the first nine months of this fiscal. <br /><br />However, excluding <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/infrastructure-general/bharatheavyelectricals/BHE">BHEL</a> (having lions share in the set), aggregate operating margins improved by 40 basis points (bps) to 6.9% in the last fiscal, and by 74 bps to (7.4)% in the first nine months of this fiscal led by execution of high margin projects in the power T&amp;D segment. Further, the margins are expected to rise due to execution of high-margin orders (in substation, transformers, etc.) in the high voltage segment.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/c/CRISILLOGO_2_356_1907_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 17:53:43</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,BHE,</sc_id><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>