<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/nifty-soars-500-pts-sensex1650-ptsbudget-lows_5731561.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Nifty soars 500 pts, Sensex up 1650 pts from Budget lows]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[SBI, ICICI Bank, BHEL, Adani Ports and Axis Bank are top gainers in the Sensex.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /><br />9:55 am&nbsp; New business:&nbsp;</strong>IDBI Bank has set an aggressive three-year target of doubling its business and sharply reducing bad assets, the lender said, a day after the government said it would consider ceding control of the state-run bank through a share sale. The bank said it expects to double its business to 10 trillion rupees (USD 147.2 billion) and cut its gross non-performing assets (NPAs) to less than 3 percent by financial year ending March 2019. That compares to gross NPAs of 8.94 percent in the most recently concluded Oct-Dec quarter when the company posted a loss of Rs 2184 crore (USD 321 million).<br /><strong><br />9:45 am Post Budget interview: </strong>"In the long sweep of history, we need 10 or 15 years really to know whether a Budget has been truly historic or not," Minister of Finance (State) Jayant Sinha said at the 'CNBC-TV18 Mint Budget 2016: The Verdict' in the capital on Tuesday. "In the meantime, you get flashes," he added, referring to the rally in the stock and bond markets. According to Sinha, the reaction of the bond market was a better indicator of the credibility of the Budget. The decline in yield on 10-year government bonds to 7.62 percent from 8 percent showed the bond market was convinced about the Budget. The fall in yields would reduce the government's debt burden and give it more finances to implement the various schemes for the deserving, he said.</p>
<p><strong>9:35 am FII view: </strong>Sakthi Siva of Credit Suisse says, &ldquo;With India's price-to-book versus return on equity (ROE) premium dropping below 40 percent for the first time since May 2015, the key question for investors is whether valuations have corrected enough. We think not yet and are waiting for India to drop out of the Expensive 4 club before reducing our underweight call. We did upgrade Indonesia when it dropped out of the Expensive 4 club last August. We continue to prefer cyclicals regionally and in India. Top picks from the CS regional portfolio are HCL Tech and Hindalco. <br /><strong><br />9:25 am Market check: </strong>In a super rally post Budget also boosted by strong Asian cues, the market is making mighty gains. The Nifty is up 500 points, Sensex rises 1650 pts and Nifty Bank surges more than 1500 points from Budget day lows&nbsp;&nbsp;<br /><strong><br />Don't miss: <a class="bl_14" title="ATF price up 12%; non-subsidised LPG rate cut by Rs 61.5" href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/atf-price12-non-subsidised-lpg-rate-cut-by-rs-615_5730541.html">ATF price up 12%; non-subsidised LPG rate cut by Rs 61.5</a><br /></strong></p>
<p>After a super rally, the market seems to be gushing with buyers in last month of the financial year. The Sensex is up 397.05 points or 1.7 percent at 24176.40, and the Nifty up 116.25 points or 1.6 percent at 7338.55. About 753 shares have advanced, 69 shares declined, and 23 shares are unchanged.</p>
<p>SBI, ICICI Bank, BHEL, Adani Ports and Axis Bank are top gainers in the Sensex. M&amp;M, Sun Pharma and Coal India are major losers in the Sensex.</p>
<p>The Indian rupee extended upmove on Wednesday by opening at 67.74 a dollar, up 12 paise compared to 67.86 in previous session. This consistent recovery is led by rally in equity markets on hopes of rate cut post pricing in Union Budget.</p>
<p>The dollar rebounded against the yen and hit one-month highs against the euro after strong US manufacturing data supports views of higher US interest rates.</p>
<p>NS Venkatesh of IDBI Bank said, "The USD-INR strengthened yesterday and will take cues from the way the equity market as well as the crude prices behave. The pair is expected to trade between 67.80-67.90/dollar."</p>
<p>Asia markets were higher in morning trade, taking early cues from overnight gains in Europe and US. Wall Street enjoyed its strongest session in a month on Tuesday, led by financial and technology stocks after encouraging US factory and construction data suggested the world's biggest economy was regaining momentum.</p>
<p>Oil prices dropped in the wake of industry data that showed a huge build in US crude stockpiles.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Bull_bear_Sensex_nse_bse_markets_up_markets_bull_bull_sensex_red_356x200_4652_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-02 09:15:26</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>