<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-india-fm-moots-new-commodity-products-deeper-corporate-bond-markets_5695661.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 India: FM moots new commodity products, deeper corporate bond markets]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[A complete information repository for corporate bonds, covering both primary and secondary market segments will be developed jointly by Reserve Bank of India (RBI) and Sebi.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Sebi will develop new products like options in the commodity derivatives market and also take a slew of measures to deepen the corporate bond markets.</p>
<p>"New derivative products will be developed by Sebi (Securities and Exchange Board of India) in the commodity derivatives market," Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said in Union Budget for 2016-17.</p>
<p>The markets regulator last year begun regulating the commodity derivatives market as well.</p>
<p>The commodity market has been demanding for long the introduction of options contracts to deepen the market.</p>
<p>However, a proposed increase in securities transaction tax for options may come as a dampener.</p>
<p>Jaitley, however, said transaction in foreign currency for sale of commodity derivatives taking place on a recognised association established in international financial services centre will not be liable to commodity transaction tax.</p>
<p>To facilitate deepening of corporate bond market, he said a number of measures will be undertaken including introduction of an electronic auction platform by Sebi for primary debt offer to develop an enabling ecosystem for the private placement market in corporate bonds.</p>
<p>A complete information repository for corporate bonds, covering both primary and secondary market segments will be developed jointly by Reserve Bank of India (RBI) and Sebi.</p>
<p>Further, a framework for an electronic platform for repo market in corporate bonds will be developed by RBI.</p>
<p>"LIC of India will set up a dedicated fund to provide credit enhancement to infrastructure projects. The fund will help in raising the credit rating of bonds floated by infrastructure companies and facilitate investment from long term investors," the minister said.</p>
<p>RBI will issue guidelines to encourage large borrowers to access a certain portion of their financing needs through market mechanism instead of the banks. Investment basket of foreign portfolio investors will be expanded to include unlisted debt securities and pass through securities issued by securitisation SPVs (Special Purpose Vehicles).</p>
<p>He further said that the enactment of Insolvency and Bankruptcy Code would provide a major boost to the development of the corporate bond market.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget4_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 14:30:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>