<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-new-textile-policy-likely-to-be-out-by-april_5544481.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: New textile policy likely to be out by April]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The minister said consultations with all stakeholders are in progress, confident that the policy will be released during the upcoming Budget session of Parliament.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Government may unveil the new national textile policy by April this year, Union Textiles Minister Santosh Gangwar said today.</p>
<p>The new policy aims to achieve USD 300 billion textile exports by 2024-25 and create an additional 35 million jobs.</p>
<p>"The long-awaited National Textile Policy is nearing finalisation and is likely to be issued before the end of April 2016," he told reporters at a seminar during the Make in India Week here.</p>
<p>The minister said consultations with all stakeholders are in progress, confident that the policy will be released during the upcoming Budget session of Parliament.</p>
<p>It also seeks to address concerns related to skilled workforce, labour reforms, attracting investments in the textile sector and providing a future road map for the textiles and clothing industry.</p>
<p>Keeping in view various domestic and international developments in the textile industry and the need for a road map, the Ministry of Textiles had initiated the process of reviewing the National Textiles Policy, 2000.</p>
<p>Addressing the seminar, Gangwar said area-specific schemes have been formulated for the entire textile value chain.</p>
<p>The government has also sharpened its focus on reducing transportation cost, which has come down by almost 25-40 percent for cotton seed.</p>
<p>He pointed out that the ministry has given approval to 24 new textile parks.</p>
<p>On Regional Trade Block Agreements such as Trans Pacific Partnership (TPP), the minister said the government is working towards a Foreign Trade Agreement (FTA) with the European Union and holding discussions on the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP).</p>
<p>The government is also in the middle of reviewing existing trade agreements such as Indo-ASEAN FTA and Indo-Korea Comprehensive Economic Partnership Agreement.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/t/textile-sep-356_2800_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-18 15:00:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>