<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2016-17-see-introductionreitsindian-market-soon-gopalkrishnan_5701601.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2016-17: See introduction of REITs in Indian market soon: Gopalkrishnan]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Scrapping of dividend distribution tax on Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs) would help developers to raise funds, as this makes investments attractive for investors, says Venkatesh Gopalkrishnan, President and CIO of Shapoorji Pallonji Real Estate.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Venkatesh Gopalkrishnan, President and CIO of Shapoorji Pallonji Real Estate:</strong><br /><br />&ldquo;The Exemptions provided on housing loan interest for first time home buyers and affordable housing would provide a boost to the stressed residential sectors and is likely to spur supply of affordable homes demand. Scrapping of dividend distribution tax on Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs) would help developers to raise funds, as this makes investments attractive for investors. It is considered to be one of the biggest hurdles left in making REITs financially viable for Indian commercial stakeholders. With most of the hurdles getting removed, we may see introduction of REITs in the Indian market soon. <br /><br />Also, the move to provide 100 percent deduction for profits to an undertaking from a housing project for flats upto 30 sq m in four metro cities and 60 sq under <br />certain conditions will provide the necessary motivation for developers to develop good quality affordable houses thus catering to the large demand in this segment. <br /><br />The government's service tax exemption on houses less than 60 sq m, and the additional exemption of Rs 50,000 for housing loans up to Rs 35 lakhs for homes not above Rs 50 lakhs will both likely improve first-time home buyers' sentiment.&rdquo;]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/b/building_real_estate_1_356X200_1850_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 17:42:09</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>