<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/udf-presents-people-friendly-budget-aheadassembly-poll_5444101.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[UDF presents people-friendly Budget ahead of assembly poll]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The budget, presented by Chief Minister Oommen Chandy, spared the common man of any additional tax burden, gave thrust to infrastructure development, boost to agricultural and social sectors, besides setting apart Rs 200 crore as subsidy to students who have availed educational loans, but are unable to repay.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>With an eye on the upcoming assembly polls, the Congress-led UDF government in Kerala today presented the 2016-17 Budget, promising free rice for BPL families and waiving tax on income from agriculture, amidst protests and boycott by the CPI(M)-led LDF.</p>
<p>The Budget, presented by Chief Minister Oommen Chandy, spared the common man of any additional tax burden, gave thrust to infrastructure development, boost to agricultural and social sectors, besides setting apart Rs 200 crore as subsidy to students who have availed educational loans, but are unable to repay.</p>
<p>It was after a 29-year gap that the Kerala Assembly saw a Chief Minister presenting the state Budget, which turned out to be the longest taking nearly three hours.</p>
<p>Chandy is the fourth Chief Minister of the state to present the Budget. Chandy took over the Finance portfolio after former Finance Minister and Kerala Congress (M) leader K M Mani quit in November 2015 over the bar bribery scam.</p>
<p>In a bid to have 'plastic-free Kerala', the Budget imposed a 20 percent tax on all plastic bags, including non-woven polypropylene bags and a five per cent surcharge for plastic bottled drinks.</p>
<p>Chandy said the government expects to mobilise Rs 10 crore through this and the amount would be utilised to encourage anti-plastic movements.</p>
<p>The Budget proposed an additional resource mobilisation of Rs 112 crore, a major portion of which will come through one-time settlement of cases in the registration department.</p>
<p>The Budget showed a total deficit of Rs 2041.22 crore and revenue of Rs 84,092.61 crore.</p>
<p>As soon as the Budget presentation began, LDF members, holding aloft placards and banners saying 'corrupt Chief Minister should quit', raised slogans demanding Chandy's resignation and then marched out of the house.</p>
<p>They also alleged that the Budget had been 'leaked' before its presentation.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/t/tax-deduction-356x200-2_2933_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-12 16:22:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>