<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-news/budget-2016-if-held-for-three-years-gainsdebt-funds-should-not-be-taxed_5595181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: If held for three years gains in debt funds should not be taxed]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[While this will not make debt funds on par with equity as equity funds have a holding period of only 1 year to qualify as long term this will go a long way in making debt funds more retail friendly.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Sunil Subramaniam</strong></em><br /><em>Sundaram Mutual Fund</em><br /><br />The Union Budget 2016 will be crucial to determine whether the NDA government can fulfill its promises on the economic front. While the last two budgets were more in the nature of laying the framework for growth this budget has to ensure that all the promises and expectations are fulfilled.<br /><br />The backdrop is challenging coming against a global environment of slowing growth and a domestic economy which has refused to revive. However this also offers an opportunity for the finance minister to effect wide ranging reforms &ndash; to repeat the oft used clich&eacute; &ndash; &lsquo;never let a crisis of to waste&rsquo;. The expectations from the various stakeholders are:<br /><br /><strong>Expectation of the MF Industry:</strong><br /><br />1. Making taxation of debt funds on par with equity funds by having a zero percent capital gains tax on long term investments (i.e. holding period of 3 years and above). While this will not make debt funds on par with equity as equity funds have a holding period of only 1 year to qualify as long term this will go a long way in making debt funds more retail friendly.<br /><br />One of the first steps to increase penetration of mutual funds is to make it more tax attractive and efficient and removal of capital gains tax will certainly achieve this.<br /><br />2. Increase service tax limits for brokerage payments to ensure that small distributors are suitably incentivized to enter and continue in the business of being financial advisors / intermediaries in the MF business. Propose limit for service tax exemption of Rs 25 lakh per year. Operationally it should operate like TDS with a refund wherein the distributor submits his total brokerage and the service tax deducted and if the total brokerage for the year is less that Rs 25 lakh the assessee will be eligible for a refund.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/m/mutual_funds_(4)_356X200_2932_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 17:18:06</Entry_Date><Category>MF News</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>