<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/cnbc-tv18-comments/budget-2016-govt-may-reduce-headline-corporate-tax-rate-by-1_5331461.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Govt may reduce headline corporate tax rate by 1%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Sources say this 1 percent corporate tax cut may cost the exchequer Rs 6,000-7,000 crore]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>There is a glimmer of hope for India Inc after all. Corporates may have to pay lower taxes from the next financial year. CNBC-TV18 learns that finance minister Arun Jaitley may reduce the headline corporate tax number by 1 percent in the upcoming Budget.</p>
<p>The finance minister had announced his intention of rationalising the corporate tax rate in the country over five years.</p>
<p>This of course will be accompanied by a proper roadmap in terms of rationalisation of corporate tax exemptions. The government has been talking about it since November 2015 when they had first put out the first draft of the roadmap. So, this is going to be fine tuned further in the coming Budget.</p>
<p>Sources say this 1 percent corporate tax cut may cost the exchequer Rs 6,000-7,000 crore. Now, in case the government is unable to meet its direct tax collection target, which is very much likely. If the entire Budget estimate is kept as is then the hit may actually go up to as high as Rs 14,000 crore odd.<br /><br />So one percent is on the cards, it could also be up to one percent, but then it becomes debatable as to what the actual benefit will be that will be passed on to the industry.</p>
<p>On the other side, in terms of exemptions roadmap, definitely those sunsets which are expiring in the current financial year, there is a very less possibility of any of them getting any further extensions, that is one. Second, in terms of those incentives which don't have a sunset, definitely there will be clarity on that front. There are four to five sectors which the government has already highlighted, the infrastructure sector is also a part of them, along with SEZs.</p>
<p>So, most likely what we are picking up is that SEZs &mdash; that may have some kind of announcement coming in terms of sun-setting their incentives; not very sure as to whether the infrastructure or various sectors under that will actually be touched at directly in terms of the sunset.</p>
<p>The third element to the exemptions roadmap which is basically the weighted deductions per capital expenditure and also the other sections which cover various exemptions under the title of rate reductions. Here what we are picking up is that there is going to be a tweaking of these exemptions, clearly on the cards of doing away tax exemptions completely.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/i/income_tax_356X200_2309_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-05 16:50:00</Entry_Date><Category>CNBC-TV18 Comments</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>