<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-cues/budget-2016-cues-to-watch-out-before-market-opens-aheadfms-speech_5688861.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Cues to watch out before market opens ahead of FM's speech]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Reduction of cess on crude oil will have a positive impact of USD dollars per barrel on ONGC. A weightage average excise hike of anything above 15 percent on cigarettes will be negative for ITC.
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau </strong><br /><br />Finance Minister Arun Jaitley will present Union Budget 2016 in Parliament today and the&nbsp;market may see wild swings depending on the announcements. Investors will be keenly watching if the FM will allay investor concerns over long term capital gains tax. On Friday, the market snapped three-day losing streak with the Sensex rising more than 250 points intraday. The 50-share NSE Nifty started off March series on a positive note after losing 6 percent each in previous two series (January and February), up 59.15 points or 0.85 percent to 7029.75. The 30-share BSE Sensex climbed 178.30 points or 0.78 percent to 23154.30 while the broader markets underperformed benchmarks with the BSE Midcap rising 0.3 percent.<br /><br />According to CNBC-TV18, in best case scenario, the Nifty could make a move to 7250-7300. However, the big question will be if fresh selling emerges if Nifty goes to 7250. In worst case scenario, Nifty could break recent low of 6,869, say CNBC-TV18 analyst.<br /><br />The banking sector is looking forward to budget with great expectations. According to CNBC-TV18, PSU banks can expect a fatter recapitalisation cheque from the FM and may see Rs 30,000 crore to 35,000 crore fund infusion. The centre may also stick to the 3.5 percent deficit target by cutting 7th pay commission outgo by as much as&nbsp; Rs 15000-25000 crore.</p>
<p>Reduction of cess on crude oil will have a positive impact of USD dollars per barrel on ONGC. A weightage average excise hike of anything above 15 percent on cigarettes will be negative for ITC.<br /><br />UltraTech Cement, part of the Aditya Birla conglomerate, has agreed to buy Jaiprakash Associates Ltd's cement plants for an enterprise value of 165 billion rupees, the companies said on Sunday.<br /><br />UltraTech Cement, part of the Aditya Birla conglomerate, has agreed to buy Jaiprakash Associates Ltd's cement plants for an enterprise value of Rs 16500 crore, <br />UltraTech, beating competition from domestic and international bidders for the assets, and Jaiprakash said they had signed a memorandum of understanding for 12 plants whose capacity totals 22.4 million tonnes a year.<br /><br />Globally, US markets closed mixed on Friday, giving up most of their opening gains as oil reversed and inflation data increased expectations for a rate hike in the coming year.<br /><br />Markets in Asia opened higher with Japan extending gains. But analysts expect some rocky trading this week amid a deluge of economic data in the region.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/BUDGET2016_Finance_minister_Arun_jaitley_FM_sensex_bse_nifty_markets_stocksmarkets356x200_3415_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 07:00:46</Entry_Date><Category>Market Cues</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>