<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/sell-into-pre-budget-rally-market-lacks-leadership-dimensions_5474081.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Sell into pre-Budget rally; market lacks leadership: Dimensions]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[According to Ajay Srivastava, CEO, Dimensions Consulting, a key concern for the market is the lack of leadership. He says many midcaps are doing much better operationally, compared to the large caps, which are floundering at the moment.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Investors should restrict the share of equities in their portfolio to 35 percent for the time being,&nbsp;Ajay Srivastava, CEO, Dimensions Consulting tells CNBC-TV18.<br /><br />He advises investors to sell into a pre-Budget rally if it happens, as there are enough signs of weakness in the economy.<br /><br />According to Srivastava, a key concern for the market is the lack of leadership from large caps. He says&nbsp;many midcaps are doing much better operationally, compared to the large caps, which are floundering at the moment. Such a trend is not sustainable and not conducive to an uptrend, he says.<br /><br />Srivastava is bullish on midcap MNC companies, pharma and construction companies.<br />
<p><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Ajay Srivastava's interview with Latha Venkatesh &amp; Sonia Shenoy.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Sonia: The bruises of the last one month have not died down just yet and that is the fear whether this bounce back will get sold into. What is the sense you are getting?</strong></p>
<p>A: It is not that whether it should be sold into. I think investors should wait patiently and settle down preferably before the Budget into this market because this to my mind is more a technically induced euphoria. Fundamentally both globally the challenges remain. India challenges are getting bigger by the hour. Therefore, the construct in market in my view is the fact that you would try to sell down at least C and B grade stocks into a rally rather than build in to B and C grade stocks. A grade stocks constitute different category. These are long-term investments and the question is what proportion they constitute of a net worth. If it's significantly large, you want to pare it down, if it's not so large, you want to continue A grade stocks.</p>
<p><strong>Latha: High tide raises all boats and low tide brings even good ships down. Is there something that you would latch on to now because the index is still closer to 7,000? Are there some good bargains out there which you would buy for the long-term?</strong></p>
<p>A: These kind of skirmishes in the market, as I call them, bring a lot of good stuff as well down with it and therefore as I said A category stocks, you want to buy into, build in a portfolio but what you have to ensure is that they do not become unreasonably large part of your net worth or your portfolio as such because the market is not supporting you on that respect. So the answer is yes, there are maybe about 20-30 or little more candidates to nibble into it at this point of time but keep your equity profile low at this point of time compared to a normal trending up situation where you may even want to go to 70 percent equity. This is a time to be 30-35-40 percent equity, not more than that.<br /><br />_PAGEBREAK_</p>
<p><strong>Sonia: You were telling us that it's better to sell all the vulnerable stocks before the Budget. In the Budget everyone is talking about the possibility of the timeframe of the long-term capital gains tax going up from one year to three years. What is your sense if that comes through and don't you think in a way that could perhaps be beneficial in the longer run because it could prevent volatility and prevent investors from exiting their holdings in one year?</strong></p>
<p>A: It is not about the measure as such. I think it is timing and the optics of the measure. On one side you are encouraging the rest of the India to go into the equity culture. The one area is reasonable timeframe for a person to hold investments and if you give him a bit of a tax break, in any case you are giving foreign institutional investors (FIIs) full tax break. People who come to FIIs, whether short-term, long-term, they have tax free. So to take away Indian investor, the small modicum of comfort or added return of long-term capital, zero taxation for a one year holding. I do not think it is a great deal and if we make it three years, in any case most promoters get out of the ambit when they sell the shares in bulk in the market at this point of time. So tax is already out of it. You already got Securities Transactions Tax (STT) there, so I am saying is it the right strategy when you want more people to come into the capital market rather than supporting it and making at par with FIIs - that's more important. The whole agenda of the government is - FII and foreign direct investment (FDI), I think it's time for the government to say local investor is equally important, let us support it.</p>
<p><strong>Sonia: Suppose the long-term capital gains tax is brought back, it will create lot of nervousness of course. What could the downside for the market be if that comes through?</strong></p>
<p>A: I do not think on a standalone basis long-term capital gain tax can bring the market down drastically. I don't think so. It's a negative but that is all about it. I do not think it is going to shake the market by 200 points on Nifty or 500 points on the Nifty. I do not think so. I think it is a sum total of what transpires in the Budget and what we are seeing ongoing in the economy at this point of time because in the euphoria people are ignoring the Index of Industrial Production (IIP) data which came in, people are ignoring that the gilt yields are back at the pre rate cut level of 7.72 and 7.75, state loans are at 8.5 percent on the yield side. So yes, there is a technical euphoria but there is an economic paradigm which is weakening the country is the credit costs are not going down, the credit system is not working efficiently. So in that context look at the Budget and say is it directional in terms of a change. You saw Indradhanush being announced six months back, it failed miserably. Now we see new bank reform measures come in but 51 percent owned by the government - that is not going to cut ice. It may cut an ice with an equity investor on an arbitrage or transitional point of view saying too much has fallen, let's go for 10 percent kicker but that is not going to change the paradigm of nationalised banks - that is where you are looking at Budget to say is privatisation there, are significant moves there, is a rural infrastructure movement there or not because if it is not there then you do not want to be in the market for a fairly long time.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Latha: Midcaps interest you?</strong></p>
<p>A: Of course. As I said there are a few of our favourite themes and I love most of the MNCs and they qualify mostly in the midcap category. I do not have to say about pharmaceuticals. I want to keep buying pharma as much as I can. So that's whole gamut of stocks you carry with you. I am okay with construction companies at this point of time because that is going to be the first ones to get the benefit of, if there is a big economic recovery or a government infrastructure push takes place. What I am worried about for the market is that the big leaders are not moving, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/infrastructure-general/larsentoubro/LT">Larsen and Toubro</a> (L&amp;T) is not moving, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/cigarettes/itc/ITC">ITC</a> is still investing in a food park; they haven't made money out of hotel and food parks and they still want to invest in it. So the leadership is going to come from where and you cannot have a market which has got strong midcap performers and a very laggard top 50 - that doesn't work out in the long run. So the issue is, we need to focus upon is for the market to move is that top 50, how will they move and there the problems are much more than what we visualise.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/ajay-srivastava-15216_1908_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-15 09:57:41</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,LT,ITC,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>