<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/fii-view/budget-2016-room-for-rbi-to-cutapril-bullishitc-says-ridham-desai_5712021.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Room for RBI to cut in April; bullish on ITC, says Ridham Desai]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ridham Desai, Head-India Equity Research & India Equity Strategist, Morgan Stanley believes there is a room for rate cut for RBI now but does not expect them to advance it by a month and do it in between two policies.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Budget 2016 was not damaging and kept the course is the word coming in from Ridham Desai, Head-India Equity Research &amp; India Equity Strategist, Morgan Stanley.<br /><br />With the world currently being in a challenging spot, the Budget chose not to take risks and retained its focus on fiscal prudence because fiscal expansion could have hurt India in case things turn for the worst in the world, says Desai.<br /><br />According to him the market volatility on the Budget day is not a new development, in fact yesterday it was less volatile. The selling in the market yesterday was more due to global factors and not because of Budget believes Desai, adding that there is selling happening all across the world especially with US economy still mixed and Europe on the brink of deflation.<br /><br />Desai believes there is a room for rate cut for RBI now but does not expect them to advance it by a month and do it in between two policies. The cut could come about in the April policy, he adds.<br /><br />According to him the markets are more driven by Fed rate decision than what is happening in China. <br /><br />Sector specific he says with the Budget keeping its focus on rural spending, the space looks good and moreover, the monsoons too are likely to be good especially with worst of El-Nino behind us. He also likes select private sector banks and is bullish on the railways post the government&rsquo;s focus on infra spending.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/cigarettes/itc/ITC">ITC</a>, he says will need just a 4-5 percent hike to offset the excise increase and is overweight on the stocks with a target of Rs 400 per share.<br /><br />With regards to market per se, the bear case target for Sensex is 22000 by December, says Desai. <br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Ridham Desai&rsquo;s interview with Latha Venkatesh and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Sonia: It is the first day post the Budget, do you think that is now behind us and the street is going to start focusing on the weak global cues once again?</strong><br /><br />A: Absolutely. I think there is nothing in the Budget that is alarming. We have seen in the past, Budget&rsquo;s have this uncanny way of upsetting market but I don&rsquo;t think this Budget is damaging to the market. I think it has kept the course; we have called it par for the course.<br /><br />Finance Minister has retained focus on the fiscal deficit. I think he has certainly been influenced by what is happening in the world over the past few weeks. He had a choice to pump prime or to remain on the path of fiscal consolidation and I think he has chosen to not take the risk because had he gone for a fiscal expansion, there was a risk that if things turn really bad in the world, India could have got hit. So, he has kind of preserved his ammunition for another day and I think that is good news for India. In a world that is very challenged, I think it is not a bad thing.<br /><br />So, in all, overall I think this is okay. This is nothing to get upset about. I think the market did its typical yo-yo yesterday, in fact my observation is actually less than what it has done in the last 25 years. We have done bigger yo-yo&rsquo;s on Budget days. This was a pretty benign yo-yo actually, it just did one. We have done a few in the past.<br /><br />The impact is reducing. This is not just the Budget related selling; there is a lot of selling happening in the world. A lot of emerging market outflows have been seen and India is participating in that. India has been a late participant; it did not see those outflows in the early days, now there is a bit more that is happening today. So, I don&rsquo;t think the selling was per se Budget related so the Budget thing I think is behind us.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: I want to get just one more Budget related issue out of the way before we discuss other macro cues as well. Do you think there are some earnings downgrades coming? There were some brokerages who are worried that he corporate tax downtick did not come &ndash; the 30 percent becoming 29 percent &ndash; but some exemptions nevertheless got rolled off. So, some of them are preparing minor downward tweaking of earnings per shares (EPS).</strong><br /><br />A: It is possible. There are few new taxes that have come in and on the corporate tax, I would say it was slightly disappointing because the expectation in the market place was that yes, the exemptions will go but it will accompanied with a 1 percent cut. The silver lining here is that new companies will have the option to may 25 percent which means that the roadmap for corporate tax is clearly laid out. I also think that the exemptions have been tapered off at a slow pace, than at least what I was expecting. I thought it would go in a more accelerated fashion, so these exemptions linger on for the next 3-4 years on average. So, there could be some scattered EPS cuts, but nothing dramatic. I do not think anything has changed on the corporate earnings front, or the macro front overnight from the Budget itself.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: The long-term capital gains (LTCG) is coming so do you think this will be an overhang for foreign institutional institutions (FIIs)?</strong><br /><br />A: I have to remind everyone of the direct tax code (DTC). When the direct tax code was being discussed, the theme was that no income stream should be left without taxation, so, the days for tax free income was going to come to an end. Then of course DTC never happened and it got shelved. However, over the last two years, we have seen this government implement provisions of the DTC, so, for example, the exemptions that have been removed for corporate India. I will give you another illustration from this Budget; look at the treatment of provident fund (PF). The fact that it would be taxed on receipt is a concept which is coming directly from DTC.<br /><br />So, if you ask me, I think the message from the Budget is, okay, this is not the appropriate time to tax capital gains because market is weak and here is a good message from the government which is they are sensitive to the equity market. I would say that this is a silver lining which is that they don&rsquo;t want to do something which will directly hurt stocks, which will directly hurt the market sentiment but at a later date whenever things are slightly better and whenever the market has the appetite to absorb it, I won&rsquo;t be surprised if this comes back on the agenda. So, it is temporarily delayed; the same thing with dividends.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: I completely take your point and ideologically I support the view that you should not have these kinds of tax free incomes as well, the manner in which the government has handled in terms of respecting the equity market is taken, what I am only saying is that for the market, all these overhangs remain. So, do you think that we are now going to see practically no reason for the market to rise? You do not have economy reasons, you do not have FII reasons. From a trader and an investor perspective, this is a negative.</strong><br /><br />A: This is not an overhang as such. For a trader, what is going to happen in a year or two years is not an overhang. What is going to happen tomorrow or the next three weeks is probably a more important thing. The more important thing is, is the RBI going to cut, not whether the government eventually change the regime.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Let us come to that. Will that make a difference? We are expecting the cut today or tomorrow.</strong><br /><br />A: I heard you on television yesterday talking about this, but I do not see why the RBI should come in the middle of two meetings and cut rates.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: I am just assuming. If they come, what is your view?</strong><br /><br />A: Frankly, I do not understand the logic. I think there is a meeting in April and that is when they probably will consider it. I do not see why they should come in the middle.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: I am asking you hypothetically. Assuming it comes today, usually I was expecting around 8:30. If not today 8:30, then tomorrow 8:30. If it comes, is that a near-term positive or like on March 3, 2015, it will be an occasion to sell?</strong><br /><br />A: This is an ongoing adjustment. India has transitioned to a lower fiscal deficit in a higher real rate environment which is helping our macro recover. And in the context of that, we have managed to bring down inflation, so there is probably some room and we do think that there is some room for a rate cut in April. Whether that has advanced to March and done in April, I do not think is such a big debate. But frankly, I do not see why they should do it inter-meeting. They will probably stick to their April calendar. I will be very surprised if they advance it a month and bring it to March and again, it will be par for the course for them to cut. It is very much in line with our expectations.<br /><br />On the Budget deficit, I would have said it was slightly lower than our expectations, because we were thinking that the government would give a little bit this year and do 3.7 percent. So, we were pleasantly surprised that the Finance Minister stuck to 3.5 percent. The numbers do not necessarily add up if you get very aggressive, but I think there is room for the government, both on the revenue side as well as on the expenditure side. So, I think they will be able to achieve it and their track record suggests that we have to believe 3.5 percent. The bond market believes 3.5 percent and that is because of the track record that they have established.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: The biggest malaise in the last six months has been in the state owned banks and that recapitalisation figure yesterday left us wanting more. Is there anything to suggest that there could be a recovery any time soon or this is a space that is going to be down in the dumps for a while?</strong><br /><br />A: From the government&rsquo;s perspective, they were very clear that they were not going for large scale state owned enterprise (SOE) recapitalisation. So, this was the number that was in the public domain from the government, so there should not be a surprise. However, we are arguing that there is a bigger recapitalisation required and I think it is front ended, it will really help the economy. So, that is a difference of opinion that is there between us and the government.<br /><br />So, the plan for the SOE banks, I see from the government&rsquo;s perspective, is a very honourable one, which is that they want to change the culture. In the past we have seen SOE banks make bad loans, getting bailed out with tax payers money, then again going out and making bad loans. They want that lending culture to change. That is great for the long-term. It is great for the medium-term as well.<br /><br />But the risk in the short-term is that the SOE banks are not in the position to actually create a fresh credit cycle and being 70 percent of the system as they are, that leaves a little bit of risk. If you want to take that risk out, then a front ended capitalisation is what we think should be done, but I do not think the government wants to do it that way, they want to do it the long-term way. <br /><br />_PAGEBREAK_<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: I don&rsquo;t want you to wear your optimistic hat now, you have to wear your realist hat and tell me do you think that there is anything to suggest that foreign institutional investors (FIIs) will stop selling India because we have seen more than Rs 25,000 crore of selling since the start of the year in the cash markets. Do you think that will continue?</strong> <br /><br />A: I think that links back to what is happening in the emerging world. There is a fair bit of turmoil in the world; things are not looking very rosy. I think the signals from the US are mixed though lately growth signals are picking up, consumption in America is really strong. Private consumption is growing at 3 percent; that is a really good number but capex is weak. So, the aggregate growth number is weak. <br /><br />Europe is struggling. We saw the downside surprise in inflation which is why our market got smacked yesterday because there is a threat of deflation sitting in Europe. Japan tried negative interest rates; that is not working. China has got its own set of problems, so this is a very challenged world and in this challenged world people want to shed some of the risk that they have on their portfolios and that is what they have been doing for the past 12 months and India is facing that pressure. <br /><br />I sense that investors, medium to long-term continue to be quite constructive on India. They are not actually giving up. The core positions are pretty intact. What I think is happening is that the skimming at the top is happening, so, the people are just shedding some of the excess that they may have held beyond what they want to hold for the long-term. Maybe we are coming to the end of that road of selling because we have seen a fair bit. <br /><br />However, it again hinges on how US data behaves. We probably discussed this when I was here a few days ago, the debate is whether the markets are being driven by China or by the Fed? I think that this year it has been about the Fed. It is about the markets belief that the Fed may have erred in raising rates and if evidence emerges from the US that the Fed did not err because US data growth is good, I think you will find that the market will come back. As odd as it may sound, but if the probability of a Fed rate hike starts rising instead of falling, I think you will find India will actually start doing better. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: This half of the world is still weak, isn't it? Today the PMI numbers from China are weak, from Japan are weak &ndash; they are weaker than last months. 48.4 has become 48 for China. So do you think that because of this, because of the emerging market (EM) basket and its impact on India, India could see 6,500; what kind of a downside?</strong> <br /><br />A: In our bear case, we are at about 22,000 on the index and that is pretty much the downside we see in a lot of other markets as well which is that we came very close to those bear cases last month. However, we didn&rsquo;t actually quite get there. It seemed like a lot of markets actually bottomed out there. It in fact feels like India also has been bottomed out. We had a good test yesterday, it is hard to always pinpoint this in the short run and I am very bad at doing this but it does seem that it is not readily agreeable to go down below the levels that it has tested in the last month but we will see. <br /><br />What I am sensing is that a lot of emerging markets&nbsp; which we broken last year, like Brazil, like Russia, like Turkey have put in very firm bottoms in the month of February and are up for the year. They are in positive territory for the year. So, it tells you that the worst bit of world equity markets if they are up then the guys who are doing slightly better, like the India and US, should probably come back now. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: So you are advising your clients to buy and if yes what in India?</strong><br /><br />A: I will make two more points. The trailing one month return which is the pre-Budget return was &ndash; 7 percent on the Nifty. That makes it the second worst month before the Budget in India&rsquo;s history. The worst was 1998 when we were down about 8.5 percent. Even in 2008 we were not down more than what we were down in the last one month. So, this feels like really bad. 1998 was the Asian financial crisis, 2008 was the global credit crisis, even 2001, was not as bad as it was in 2016. So, keep that in mind, expectations were very low regarding the Budget and I think the sentiment is very feeble. <br /><br />The second point I will make is that we run a proprietary sentiment indicator which captures a lot of market data from the options market to trading volumes, to flows and everything and that has hit a buy signal for the ninth time in the last 15 years and the previous occasions are 2011 December, 2008 October, 2006 May, 2004 May, 2003 May, 2001 September. <br /><br /><strong>Sonia: What is the biggest parameter in them?</strong><br /><br />A: It is an equal weighted index. So, we have a few indicators that we compile, all measured as standard deviation (SD) from average so that indicators measure as an SD and it is currently at &ndash; 1 SD which is basically a trough point. So, the sentiment looks very broken and certainly when the sentiment is this broken, it is not a good time to sell. <br /><br />I don&rsquo;t think this is a V-shaped recovery. I think it is going to take some time, there is a bottoming out process that is happening and it is time to actually engage in stocks. <br /><br /><strong>Sonia: There was a big rural push in the Budget are there any rural specific sectors that you will be looking at?</strong> <br /><br />A: The nature of the rural push is that the government did not cut spending because the rural expenditure budgeted in Finance Minister&rsquo;s Budget is the same as last year. The nominal growth is 10.8 percent which is exactly in-line with his assumption on nominal GDP growth. He assumed around 11 percent nominal GDP growth. So, the percentage of spending to GDP is unchanged. <br /><br />However, my worry was that it would have been cut because in year in which he is trying to drive down the deficit by 40 basis points, he had to choose between rural spending and infrastructure spending and I thought he would have attacked rural spending. Instead he has not done that, he has raised more taxes and that is how he is kept rural spending intact. So that is good. <br /><br />I am no weather man but the early signs are that the&nbsp; El Nino, the worst of that is behind us and La Nina tends to follow such heavy El Nino&rsquo;s. So, there is a wonderful chart on the US weather bureau which you can see going back 50 years, the El Nino and La Nina events. So, maybe we get better weather, we get a little bit of support from the government and that means I think rural economy should do slightly better. I think rural consumption will improve. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: So, what would it be? FMCG stocks, consumer durables?</strong><br /><br />A: When consumption improves, you buy discretionary over staples because staples has not really borne the brunt as much as discretionary. For example, tractors. Tractor sales went down like this when the rains failed and when rural spending was weak and that would probably recover when spending goes up. So, you want to support discretionary stocks which have rural exposure.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Any of the financials simply because it is 35 percent of the basket?</strong><br /><br />A: I think private sector financials are doing okay and very slowly India's banking sector is getting privatised. So, that theme remains. There is no reason to abandon those stocks. Some of those have become quite attractive over the past month or so. Some of them had not corrected, have actually now corrected, so they are giving you good entry levels. So, consumption in private sector financials and you want to nibble at industrials. <br /><br />This Budget had a very strong infrastructure theme like last year. And last year, the government demonstrated its ability to execute. So, there is reason to believe that this 40 percent spending Budget on the roads sector for example will executed this year. And likewise, in the railways. I am actually very optimistic on the railways. What I am seeing in the railways is actually more powerful. And I heard a few sceptics on your channel yesterday on the railways, but I do not agree with them.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: I went through the minute numbers in the expenditure Budget and I will tell you last year Rs 44,000 crore was allocated for roads, Rs 40,000 crore plus was allocated. Mr Gadkari has managed to spend Rs 41,000 crore whereas Mr Prabhu was given Rs 40,000 crore, he could manage to spend only Rs 32,000 crore. So, actually, roads have demonstrated that they can spend, railways have not demonstrated it yet.</strong> <br /><br />A: No, but because in the roads sector, the problems were not as deep as they were in the railways.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: So, what kind of industrials therefore? EPC guys is what you are looking at?</strong><br /><br />A: I think people who build. But even the asset owners should actually do better. So, look at the road companies for example. Their tariffs are linked to WPI. So, there is reason to believe that the worst for the WPI is over.&nbsp; So, their tariffs will actually do better. And in fact, when I was here last, we spoke about traffic growth. It is actually improving and there is this plan to get private bus services on the roads and on the highways. So, I think traffic growth will also improve through the years. So, not only asset owners as well as builders, I think both will actually do well in the next 12-18 months.<br /><br /><em>(Interview transcribed by Priyanka Deshpande and Stanford Masters)</em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Sensex_Budget2016_nifty_bse_nse_stockmarkets_jaitley_FM_finance_Down_stock_markets_356x200_4912_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 09:17:17</Entry_Date><Category>FII View</Category><sc_id>,ITC,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>