<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/wealready-realising-make-in-india-dream-ashni-biyani_5249001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[We are already realising 'Make In India' dream: Ashni Biyani]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Future Group's next-generation head Ashni Biyani says all eyes are on how the government intends to improve liquidity in the market. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[With the Budget around the corner, fast moving consumer goods (FMCG) companies are hoping that the government unveils incentives not only to improve the ease of doing business but also drive consumer spending. <br /><br />In an exclusive chat with CNBC TV-18's Priya Sheth,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-investments/futureconsumerenterprise/FVI">Future</a> Group's next-generation head Ashni Biyani says all eyes are on how the government intends to improve liquidity in the market. <br /><br />She is of the view that while everyone is looking forward to the Goods and Services Tax (GST), enhancement of ease of doing business still remains important. <br /><br />Furthermore, she also expects the government to announce implementation of the Pay Commission recommendations in the upcoming Budget.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Ashni Biyani&rsquo;s interview with Priya Sheth on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: What are you looking forward to in Budget 2016?&nbsp;</strong><br /><br />A: Obviously, the GST is something that everyone is looking forward to. I think it can be a key step in the way forward from the ease of doing business standpoint. We work in multiple states. Our distribution of our products, brands, our retail stores are all over the country, so that is a keys step that we see enhancing the ease of doing business. It is a one step, very simple, but very effective measure. If the government can achieve that, it is something that we really look forward to in this coming year. <br /><br />The other thing we are looking forward to is the new Pay Commission that may get announced in this Budget. That will bring out a lot of spending. A large part of our customer base is the government sector and it will be exciting to see if the Pay Commission gets announced, then it will have a certain liquidity as well in the market.<br /><br /><strong>Q: There are several tax incentives that players like you would possibly want from the government. Run us through maybe two or three key incentives that you are looking forward to?</strong><br /><br />A: Like I said anything that helps us ease the way in which we do business and reduces the number of variable involved from a taxation point of view anything like that would be something that we would be something that we would look forward to.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Apart from being a retailer, you are also a manufacturer. This Budget, how would it shape that aspect as well?</strong><br /><br />A: Manufacturing is the key leg in that. The whole Make in India dream is something that we are already realising. And with any tax benefits coming, costs getting reduced, the customer is eventually going to benefit. I think any cost reduction will help us reduce the cost. Hopefully the consumer will spend more or will buy more and we have always believed that consumption will lead to development and that is the theme that we are going to stick by.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/Ashni0615_ashni-biyan_650x455_0019_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-01 21:55:57</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,FVI,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>