<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/bjp-asks-mps-to-take-budget-topeople_5817801.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[BJP asks MPs to take Budget to the people]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[At a meeting of the BJP parliamentary party, where Prime Minister Narendra Modi was present, party chief Amit Shah told MPs that the they should take "Budget to the people" by highlighting the schemes and ensure that the benefits reach grassroot levels.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of the Assembly elections in five states, the BJP has asked its MPs to play a proactive role in making people aware about the Union Budget presented in the current Parliament session, emphasising that it has something for all sections.</p>
<p>At a meeting of the BJP parliamentary party, where Prime Minister Narendra Modi was present, party chief Amit Shah told MPs that the they should take "Budget to the people" by highlighting the schemes and ensure that the benefits reach grassroot levels.</p>
<p>Speaking to reporters after the meeting, Parliamentary Affairs minister M Venkaiah Naidu said that Shah told MP that the it is a "popular Budget which is being appreciated by all sections" including opposition parties.</p>
<p>"The party President told MPs that they should take the Budget to the people make them participants in the Prime Minister's programme 'Sabka Saath, Sabka Vikas'," Naidu said.</p>
<p>MPs have been asked to become the focal point in the implementation and monitoring of schemes like Prime Minister Fasal Bima Yojana, Mudra Bank, Rural electrification scheme and Jan Dhan Yojana.</p>
<p>Naidu also told reporters that the Real Estate regulation Bill is on top of the government's agenda. The Parliamentary Affairs Minister said he had yesterday written to Rajya Sabha Chairman M Hamid Ansari to give priority to the proposed legislation.</p>
<p>He added that since it was not present in the agenda, he had asked for revised schedule of Rajya Sabha.</p>
<p>The minister also said that there could be a discussion on the Ishrat Jahan issue as some members have given a notice in Lok Sabha over the matter.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_budget_2016_Jaitley_FM_NDA_356x200_5412_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-09 11:28:02</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>