<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/cabinet-clears-new-aadhaar-bill_5738161.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Cabinet clears new Aadhaar Bill]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech for 2016-17 announced government plan to give statutory backing to Aadhaar.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Cabinet has cleared new Aadhaar Bill which will be introduced in Parliament soon, official sources said.</p>
<p>"Cabinet has approved new Aadhaar Bill. It will be brought in Parliament in next few days," official sources told PTI.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in his Budget speech for 2016-17 announced government plan to give statutory backing to Aadhaar.</p>
<p>"We will undertake significant reforms, such as the enactment of a law to ensure that all government benefits are conferred upon persons who deserve it, by giving a statutory backing to the Aadhar platform," Jaitley had said in budget speech.</p>
<p>Till date over 98 crore Aadhaar numbers have been generated. Per day average of 26 lakh biometric and over 1.5 lakh e-KYC transactions are made. Aadhaar numbers have been seeded in 11.19 crore DBTL accounts out of total 16.5 crore DBTL beneficiaries.</p>
<p>There is already a National Identification Authority of India Bill, 2010, pending in the Rajya Sabha.</p>
<p>The statutory status will provide a legal foundation to Aadhaar for expanding its use for a range of developmental purposes.</p>
<p>It has been suggested that all benefits, subsidies or services funded from the consolidated fund of India should be through Aadhaar platform.</p>
<p>Jaitley said that a critical component of minimum government and maximum governance is to ensure targeted disbursement of government subsidies to actual beneficiaries.</p>
<p>"First, we will introduce the targeted delivery of financial and other subsidiary benefits services by using the Aadhar framework. The bill will be introduced in the current budget session of Parliament.</p>
<p>"The Aadhar number or authentication shall however not confirm any rights of citizenship or domicile," he said.</p>
<p>The finance minister said the public money should reach the poor and deserving without any leakage.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/m/Modi_Narendra_PM_Cabinet_356x200_3735_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-03 08:34:06</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>