<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2016-possibilitychangetax-slabsexemption-limit-us-80c_5648001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Possibility of change in tax slabs and exemption limit u/s 80C]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Since the previous budget disappointed the salaried class with no change in the tax slabs, it is likely that this could see a change in this budget.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Shweta Jain</strong></em><br /><em>International Money Matters</em><br /><br />Every year, a month before the budget comes, what comes are anticipations, expectations and wishlists. More often than not, it is a non event sometimes grabbing more attention than it deserves. This 29th Feb too we will have crores of people stuck to their television screens eagerly listening to the Finance Minister Mr. Arun Jaitley&rsquo; Union Budget 2016. Well, before we move to the actual budget, here is a list of things we could see and also a few we would like to see.<br /> <br /><strong>Personal Finance</strong> &ndash; Since the previous budget disappointed the salaried class with no change in the tax slabs, it is likely that this could see a change in this budget. However, with the 7th Pay Commission and One Rank One Pension (OROP) being implemented, it would add to the budgetary constraints of the government. There is also the possibility that the change in these tax slabs and exemptions could be linked to inflation. Also, an increase in the exemption limit under Section 80C would provide a boost. <br /><br /><strong>Entrepreneurs</strong> &ndash; With the push by the government towards the &lsquo;Start Up India, Stand Up India&rsquo; initiative, we may see more tax breaks, concessions and budget allocation towards developing the infrastructure and skills to encourage entrepreneurship in the country. <br /><br /><strong>Real Estate</strong> &ndash; With real estate prices remaining high despite a slowdown in the sector, the government could increase the current Rs. 2 lakh exemption on the interest on home loans. Also, passage of the Real Estate Bill in the budget would mean more protection for the consumers in the form of ensuring timely delivery of projects by the builders. <br /><br /><strong>Health Care</strong> &ndash; With the 2015 budget seeing a cutback for spending on health care to 1.2% of GDP, numerous reports questioning this stance alongside the government&rsquo;s &lsquo;universal healthcare&rsquo; mission could lead to the government placing more emphasis on health care infrastructure and education in the 2016 budget. <br /><br /><strong>IT</strong> &ndash; The allocation towards the Digital India program and improving rural connectivity and access could see an increase. It could also lead to aid for educational institutes and courses focused on technology. <br /><br /><strong>Investors</strong> &ndash; There remains the possibility that equity funds will no more enjoy the tax free holiday and may be taxed in a manner similar to debt funds with 3 years deciding long term or short term capital gains. <br /><br />Apart from the gold monetization and gold bond schemes getting a further push, physical gold investments may be discouraged by imposing a wealth tax on it.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/u/Union_Budget_2016_2_356X200_4020_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 17:28:05</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>