<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/see-mkt-bottom-@68-72k-fm-can-relax-fisc-deficit-tgt-quantum_5639421.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[See mkt bottom @6.8-7.2k; FM can relax fisc deficit tgt: Quantum]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Sanjay Dutt, director of Quantum Securities, says the Union Budget will be taken positively if the FM indicates aggressive government spending to boost investment cycle]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Indian market is probably going through a bottoming process at around the 6,800-7,200 range, is the word coming in from Sanjay Dutt, director of Quantum Securities. He advises investors to look for good quality stocks at this point as equities will not go out of fashion and India will continue to remain a preferred investment destination.</p>
<p>On the upcoming Union Budget, which will be presented on February 29, he says even if Finance Minister Arun Jaitley relaxes the fiscal deficit target it won't be looked at negatively. The Budget will be taken positively if the FM indicates aggressive government spending to boost investment cycle.</p>
<p>On PSU bank recapitalisation, Dutt says more than the amount that the government can or will deploy in these banks, a real bite the bullet plan &mdash; a bad bank or a combination of a bad bank and the bankruptcy law &mdash; is needed.</p>
<p><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Sanjay Dutt&rsquo;s interview with Latha Venkatesh and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Sonia: Perhaps it is a good day to get you in. Your namesake walks scot-free today after 40 months in prison. Any bonhomie for the markets or is the market going to be in this prison it has created for itself on the downside?</strong></p>
<p>A: I have been in a prison longer than that because seeing this market makes me so frustrated. It is actually one of the most complex periods we are going through. If you look at the entire financial assets canvas the world over, it is completely full of landmines which none of us are able to game and even central bankers are quite perplexed, I am sure because one day you deal with USD/JPY and next day you are dealing with the British exit (Brexit) and how the pound is going to behave. And all these have implications across commodities and equities in debt, etc.</p>
<p>In those cross currents, it is in that background where we are stuck with Indian equities and we are ourselves are dealing with problems, with our local banks, non-performing asset (NPA) provisioning, etc. So, to cut out the rambling that went through, we would probably be going through a bottoming process which we are going through right now around this 6,800-7,200 range. This is the time, when you need to really strap up and look for individual opportunities and buy them, equities will not go out of fashion. India would remain an investment story for the rest of the world. We just have to ride out the storm. That is what I think.</p>
<p><strong>Latha: What will you look at as positives from the Budget, both railway and the general Budget?</strong></p>
<p>A: Given the fact that the expectations have turned to really nothing at this point of time, right from fiscal deficit slippage to long-term capital gains tax, etc. any of these really do not fall in place. We do not get any surprised on the capital gains tax. We do not get any surprises on the fiscal deficit front and the finance minister is able to actually balance this whole outflow on account of the One Rank One Pension (OROP) as well as the Pay Commissions, etc. and manage to come out with a decent Budget with reasonable incentives to kick-start the investment cycle and growth. It would be taken as a very positive Budget, because expectations are really nothing at this point of time.</p>
<p><strong>Sonia: So, what would be more important for the market, the fact that he meets the fiscal deficit target or if he relaxes the fiscal deficit target and gives more impetus to growth?</strong></p>
<p>A: Even if he relaxes the fiscal deficit target a little bit and decides to go for aggressive government spending for a short period, the markets would not look at it negatively, because the only source where you can see investment expenditure coming in is from the government right now, and the markets will not be that negative about it. Of course, economists will go on endlessly talking about it and of course, we will start looking at the bond yields again and worry about all that, but the markets would still take that positively because as long as there are steps to kick-start the investment cycle, there are steps for a good amount of government expenditure to boost the economy.<br /><br />_PAGEBREAK_</p>
<p><strong>Latha: Is there any recapitalisation number or announcement on banks that will want to keep you continued with that positive sentiment you had with some of the public sector undertaking (PSU) banks?</strong></p>
<p>A: I have got it wrong in the last 6-9 months, so I may get it wrong again. But the fact is that more than the capitalisation plan, a real kind of bite the bullet solution to solve this problem, whether it is moving out the assets into a so-called, &lsquo;bad assets bank&rsquo; or whatever, but real comprehensives solutions for that aggressive steps could be taken, whether it is combination of bankruptcy law along with the bad bank. These kind of things are more important that just a bank capitalisation figure. We know that the government will have to increase the allocation on bank capitalisation more than the Rs 70,000 crore that was talked about because that will not be enough. We have already seen some of the leading chairmen of the biggest banks voicing major concerns on that.</p>
<p>More important are what are going to be the concrete steps to sort out these problems and how they are going to be executed in a time bound manner. That is a key issue, more than just another Rs 40,000 crore or Rs 50,000 crore being allocated.</p>
<p><strong>Sonia: Three experts told us that this is perhaps a good time to be cherry picking into stocks and looking at quality names. So, if one wants to be ahead of the curve and you any way cannot time the market, if you want look at some quality names now, where should you look, because even quality like the likes of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-housing/housingdevelopmentfinancecorporation/HDF">HDFC</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/hdfcbank/HDF01">HDFC Bank</a>, etc. are hitting new lows every day? What would your top two or three names look like to buy now?</strong></p>
<p>A: I will take a contrarian bet on the commodity cycle at this point of time and look at something like top-notch names in the steel sector because if we are going to talk about aggressive allocations coming out of the Budget and rule out on infrastructure, etc. in the years ahead. Steel is one place where good quality private companies have been beaten down to bare bone levels at this point of time. So, whether it is the general group of whether it is some other companies, and like you were just mentioning copper a while back, some of the commodities are showing some early signs of, it is not turning up obviously, but at least the declines stemming and a bottoming process coming in. And if that be the case then these companies will adapt to that. These companies, most of them have already restructured their debt and are in a much better shape than things were about a year-and-a-half- two years back.</p>
<p><strong>Sonia: You mentioned that 6,800-7,200 is the level where you see a bottoming out process for the market. What gives you the confidence that the market will not fall below this zone?</strong></p>
<p>A: If you go back and see what we experienced about two weeks back or a week to 10 days back when we did reach that 6,900 plus-minus level, we saw a good amount of aggressive buying coming in some good quality names. Even names like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/statebankindia/SBI">State Bank of India</a> (SBI), where we had some massive provisions coming in, etc. and the bank Chairman clearly saying that there will be more provisions ahead, but the stock did not make a new low. So, those are clear indicators that even at those levels, some of the stocks have stopped falling. So, there is a basic value that smart money is putting in there. But obviously, that 6,800 will not hold if we see a carnage across the world and we see some more emerging markets kind of risk-off trades, more aggressively being put in place, exchange-traded fund (ETF) money being taken off.</p>
<p>But, if things remain as they are in this environment, with oil being where it is today, that is what gives me confidence that that 6,800 level would hold and I do not see any reason why as of now, for it to really break, because you break up the Nifty and you see values that are allocated to various components, you more or less come to a reasonable figure, both in terms of earnings multiples, price to book, and everything else. So, you come to a reasonably good figure, good chance that that level would hold.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/m/markets_sad_nifty_356x200_0730_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 09:57:52</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,HDF,HDF01,SBI,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>