<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rbi-may-slash-policy-rate-by-25-basis-pointsfeb-2-bofa-ml_5208261.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[RBI may slash policy rate by 25 basis points on Feb 2: BofA-ML]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[According to the global financial services major, a rate reduction is likely as inflation may be in line with RBI's January 2016 under-6 percent target.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[The Reserve Bank of India is approaching the end of its rate-cutting cycle and is expected to go for a final 25-bps repo rate cut at its policy review<br />meet on February 2.<br /><br />According to the global financial services major, a rate reduction is likely as inflation may be in line with RBI's January 2016 under-6 percent target.<br /><br />"We continue to expect a final 25 bps RBI repo rate cut on February 2. That said, RBI is approaching the end of its rate-cutting cycle," Bank of America Merrill Lynch said in a research note.<br /><br />BofA-ML sees "compelling reasons" for a rate cut on Tuesday. First, inflation print could be in the comfort zone of RBI in the near term.<br /><br />Second, growth remains weak and a rate cut would provide an additional impetus to the fledgling recovery.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br />BofA-ML's assessment is policy easing should back up the rupee as well by attracting inflows. The other supporting factor, it argued, is fiscal deficit,<br />which is "well under control".<br /><br />On inflation outlook, BofA-ML said CPI is likely to bounce back to around 5-6 percent in 2016-17. The global brokerage firm noted that RBI achieving 5 per<br />cent 2016-17 target will depend on how weather phenomenon El Nino plays out, the 7th Pay Commission impact and oil price movements.<br /><br />BofA-ML's lead indicators are projecting 5 percent GDP for the December quarter as per the old series. In the new GDP series, "we are tracking 7-7.5 percent, without any improvement over September's 7.4 percent", the report added.<br /><br />"Even if Arun Jaitley retains the 2016-17 fiscal deficit at 3.9 percent of GDP, like FY16, instead of cutting it to the pre-committed 3.5 percent, it will be well below the 4.8 percent average since 2000," the report added.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/r/RBI_reserve_bank_of_India_RBi_356x200_5123_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-29 12:52:22</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>