<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/macro-eco-survey-2016-fdi31-at-36248-bn-during-april-november_5664241.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Macro Eco Survey 2016: FDI up 31% at &#36;24.8 bn during April-November]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[With a view to liberalise and simplifying the FDI policy and to provide ease of doing business climate in the country, the government has undertaken various reforms, the survey added.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) into the country increased by 31 percent to USD 24.8 billion during April-November, Economic Survey said today.</p>
<p>FDI in April-November 2014 stood at USD 18.9 billion.</p>
<p>With a view to liberalise and simplifying the FDI policy and to provide ease of doing business climate in the country, the government has undertaken various reforms, the survey added.</p>
<p>It said that FDI inflows have increased into sectors like computer software and hardware, services, trading, automobile industry, construction activities, chemicals and telecommunications.</p>
<p>"Out of FDI equity inflows of USD 24.8 billion during 2015-16 (April-November), more than 60 percent have come from two geographically small countries named Singapore and Mauritius," the survey said.</p>
<p>Further, it said after the launch of 'Make in India' initiative in September 2014, there is a nearly 40 percent increase in FDI inflows during October 2014 to June 2015 over the corresponding period of the previous year.</p>
<p>Under the programme, the government has awarded a record 56 defence manufacturing permits to private sector entities in the past year, vis-a-vis 47 licences granted in the preceding three years.</p>
<p>"Several countries such as Japan, China, France and South Korea have announced their intention of making huge investments in India in various industrial and infrastructure projects," it said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/f/FDI_budget_2016_356x200_4131_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 15:22:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>