<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/expect-removalreit-tax-anomaliesbudget-xander-group_5390541.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Expect removal of REIT tax anomalies in Budget: Xander Group]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The challenge with real estate investment trusts (REITs) in India, at the moment, is that legislation, especially taxation, needs to be thought through a little more," says Sid Yog, founder of Xander group]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Sid Yog, founder of Xander group, with over USD 2 billion worth of assets under management, is confident Budget 2016 will remove tax anomalies in real estate investment trusts (REITs).</p>
<p>"The challenge with REITs in India at the moment is that legislation, especially taxation, needs to be thought through a little more," Yog says, adding some tweaks are required for them to be a platform attractive to investors.</p>
<p>The government is aware of the issues and we expect changes in tax laws accordingly, he adds</p>
<p>If the anticipated changes happen then Xander will use REITs as the platform to exit its investments in offices and shopping malls, he says.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Sid Yog&rsquo;s interview with CNBC-TV18's Malvika Jain.</strong></em><br /><br />A: (starts in the middle of an answer..) where the investments are mature or for the nature of investments that would qualify for a Real Estate Investment Trust (REIT) type of exit we would consider REITs both in India or in other parts of the world.<br /><br />The challenge with REITs in India at the moment is that legislation, especially taxation needs to be thought through a little more and some tweaks and changes are required for them to realistically be a platform that is attractive for investors.<br /><br />I hope the government is going to do something in this Budget. Comments by the ministers and others in the government seem to suggest that they are aware of the issues and are trying to sort through that. If that happens yes, of course that could be a potential avenue for exits from some of our investments which are of that nature, income generating etc.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/x/Xander_2_356_1535_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-09 22:18:05</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>