<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/fii-view/budget-must-focusinfra-spending-rural-newton-investment_5654101.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget must focus on infra spending, rural: Newton Investment]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Rob Marshall Lee, Newton Investment Management says the government must look at infrastructure spending and rural consumer that have been suffering due to reversal in some subsidies like MNREGA.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Despite global headwinds and fluctuation in the domestic market, Rob Marshall Lee, Newton Investment Management still remains long on India. <br /><br />&ldquo;In the shorter term, it is quite well held by international investors,&rdquo; he says adding that &ldquo;(it&rsquo;s) no surprise to see the stock market correcting a little bit particularly in the run up to the Budget.&rdquo;<br /><br />Lee is bullish on consumer stocks, but recommends staying away from the public sector banks. However, he says, there is opportunity in some private banks. Lee is also bearish on highly geared infrastructure stocks. <br /><br />Discussing the upcoming Budget, Lee says the government must look at infrastructure spending and rural consumer that have been suffering due to reversal in some subsidies like MNREGA.<br /><br />&ldquo;That said India does have a bit more room for manoeuvre particularly with the oil price falling back so far,&rdquo; he adds.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Rob Marshall Lee's interview with Latha Venkatesh on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: A word on India vis-a-vis emerging markets. Until now India stood out in the emerging market (EM) basket. It was often called the good house in a bad neighbourhood. Do you still see India that way?</strong><br /><br />A: I think so still. We have been long India since 2011-12, still see no reason to change that. In the shorter term, it is quite well held by international investors. So, no surprise to see the stock market correcting a little bit particularly in the run up to the Budget.<br /> <br />If you look for growth around the world at the moment, it is a pretty rare commodity and India is just emerging from a credit cycle. It is still a bit tricky. The earnings are a bit all over the place, so some good some bad, but I still think in terms of where you are going to find well underpinned structural growth driven by economic reforms, improved access to credit and just coming from a low base, from depressed margins and so on, I think India has plenty of potential. <br /><br />Of course, you have the demographic factors, a potential for catch-up productivity and so on top.<br /><br /><strong>Q: When you last spoke to us you had 30 percent of your EM equity fund invested in India, is it still the case that way and which are the sectors you are invested in?</strong><br /><br />A: It is about 30 percent of the portfolio and that remains very consistent; haven't changed things very much. We still remain tilted towards the consumer stocks. We haven&rsquo;t been too heroic, so we don't hold that much in the banking sector. Although, we do see opportunities in some of the private sector banks. We still stay clear of the state owned banks - PSUs. <br /><br />However we haven&rsquo;t been heroic in terms of investing in lots of infrastructure companies, some of them are highly geared situations. Instead, we have kept our focus on the consumer and as we see a recovery that is where we would prefer to be. <br /><br />The consumer has broadly been rebuilding their balance sheets. Also you have a lot of good quality companies who are still making decent profits at the bottom of the cycle but we could potentially grow from here.<br /><br /><strong>Q: What about sectors like infotech and pharmaceuticals?</strong><br /><br />A: We have one or two exposures there, quite happy to hold on to them. The highest quality ones amongst the IT companies still remain good companies for the long term. Well managed high return on capital. <br /><br />So, we are quite happy to have an exposure there to specific ones. The only downside is there has been a lot of cutting of expenses in the banking sector in the western world. That is one of the key short term problems.<br /><br />Longer term there is obviously the transition to the cloud and that is a potential threat to these businesses but actually in the next 5 or 10 years it could be a great opportunity for Infosys and TCS and so on of the world to help that transition, help companies to go through that. They are actually well positioned to do that.<br /><br />On the pharmaceutical side, it is just very specific. We like companies which are not purely reliant on generic penetration into cheap markets; we like some companies with some innovation and actually see quite a bit of value in some of those stocks right now.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Coming to the annual government Budget which would be announced on Monday, what are you looking forward to in the Budget?</strong><br /><br />A: Not too dramatic a shift really. The shift from paying lots of subsidies and towards more expenditure on long term growth drivers, more expenditure on infrastructure is very important. <br /><br />So, we don't want to see too much shift from that. It has been good to cut down -those subsidies to make the fiscal situation more sustainable and redirect it towards the coal sector, the roads and so on. That is a very good thing the dedicated freight corridor. So, we would like to see more of that.<br /><br />I think in the real world - the rural consumer - has clearly been suffering from the reversal of some of the subsidies there - MNREGA etc. So, politically it is quite possible to have a bit more of a push from that.<br /><br />In terms of the pay commission, we know broadly what is happening there. The question is really more about the timing, whether we see a one off move or whether it is spread over two or three years. We would like to see it spread over a couple of years and then just want to make sure the shop is kind of kept reasonably secure, we don't want a dramatic shift in too many things.<br /><br />That said India does have a bit more room for manoeuvre particularly with the oil price falling back so far. So, with that in mind I can see a bit more kind of bigger room for the government there.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_markets_nse_bse_stock_markets_356x200_3132_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 22:28:53</Entry_Date><Category>FII View</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>