<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-positive-step-to-promote-real-estate-growth-kamal-khetan_5704121.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Positive step to promote real estate growth: Kamal Khetan]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Kamal Khetan – CMD, Sunteck Realty is of the view that the Finance Minister has taken a cautious, yet courageous path with his Budget announcements. It will reap long-term benefits for the economy on a whole.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kamal Khetan &ndash; CMD, Sunteck Realty</strong></p>
<p>"The Finance Minister has taken a cautious, yet courageous path with his Budget announcements. It will reap long-term benefits for the economy on a whole. The FM in order to promote REITs in the country has provided an exemption to Dividend Distribution to SPV&rsquo;s where the REITs have specified shareholding.</p>
<p>On the affordable housing front the government seems to take active steps towards its Housing for All Mission, wherein various sops have been provided. Exemption from service tax on construction of houses up to 60 square meters under any scheme of the Central or State Government including PPP Schemes and 100% deduction for profits to an undertaking in housing project for flats up to 30 sq. meters in four metro cities and 60 sq. meters in other cities, approved during June 2016 to March 2019 will definitely encourage the developers to take Affordable Housing projects in a big way.</p>
<p>There is a good encouragement to the first time home buyers by way of Deduction for additional interest of Rs. 50,000 per annum for loans up to Rs. 35 lakh sanctioned in 2016-17, where the cost of the house does not exceed Rs. 50 lakhs. Rent deduction under HRA for individuals within the income bracket of Rs. 5 lakhs has been increased from Rs 24,000 to Rs 60,000. This would lead to additional tax savings and more disposable income.</p>
<p>We have to go through the fine print but this is a very positive step to promote growth of real estate in the country. It will have a two-fold impact &ndash; one &ndash; it will lead to additional sources of capital for developers and two &ndash; it will allow various stakeholders to participate in the real estate growth story of the country by unlocking value.&rdquo;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_economy_growth_GDP_356x200_2811_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 18:43:15</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>