<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-has-no-big-idea-pro-poor-projectionrhetoric-cong_5701881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget has no 'big idea', pro-poor projection a rhetoric: Cong]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Congress Vice President Rahul Gandhi asserted that the budget's "mere rhetoric", without vision or action, will fool neither farmers nor the poor of this country while former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh said it was a "nit picking" budget and there is "no big idea" in the annual exercise.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Congress today trashed the Union Budget, saying it "lacks" vision and conviction and has "no big idea" and that the government's projection of it being pro-poor was "mere rhetoric".</p>
<p>Congress Vice President Rahul Gandhi asserted that the Budget's "mere rhetoric", without vision or action, will fool neither farmers nor the poor of this country while former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh said it was a "nit picking" Budget and there is "no big idea" in the annual exercise.</p>
<p>Gandhi also took a jibe at the NDA government on MGNREGA spending, reminding it that it had "mocked" Congress earlier over the rural jobs scheme.</p>
<p>"Modiji spent the first 2 years mocking the Congress Party's focus on farmers, MNREGA, Rural dev &amp; social spending.</p>
<p>"Now mere rhetoric, without vision or action, will fool neither farmers nor the poor of this country," Gandhi said on Twitter.</p>
<p>In further tweets, Gandhi said that the Budget "lacks both vision &amp; conviction." He said the exercise was a list of "new promises without any account of the failure of tall promises made in last 2 Budgets".</p>
<p>He, however, thanked Finance Minsister Arun Jaitley for accepting his recommendation on removing import duty on Braille paper to help the visually impaired.</p>
<p>"It's a nitpicking Budget. There is no big idea except one idea, which was yesterday mentioned by the Prime Minister himself that the government plans to double the farmers' income in next five years, which he also dismissed as an impossible dream.</p>
<p>"I think that is an impossible dream and there is no inclination or no way of telling the country how will it be achieved because it implies a 14 percent increase in foreign income for each of the five years," Singh said.</p>
<p>An ace economist, Singh at the same time said that he was glad that the Finance Minister was able to stick to fiscal deficit target that was outlined by him.</p>
<p>In a tweet, party spokesperson Manish Tewari termed the Budget "high on rhetoric, flawed on comparison, low on imagination, bereft of ideas, services oligarchs, constricts freedom of RBI.DEAD SCUD.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget4_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 17:56:05</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>