<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-major-boost-to-deptspace_5707461.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget: Major boost to Dept of Space]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In 2015-16, the revised Budget for DoS was Rs 6959 crore, of which Rs 1359 crore was earmarked for various projects.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>In a boost to the Department of Space (DoS), the Union Budget 2016-17 allocated Rs 7509 crore to the department, an increase of around Rs 550 crore as compared to the last Budget.</p>
<p>Of the Rs 7509 crore Budget allocation, Rs 1509 crore has been earmarked for different projects.</p>
<p>In 2015-16, the revised Budget for DoS was Rs 6959 crore, of which Rs 1359 crore was earmarked for various projects.</p>
<p>ISRO is the only science related department/ ministry, which has seen such a whooping hike in its Budget.</p>
<p>The Department of Atomic Energy, which as the DoS comes under the Prime Minister's Office, has witnessed a wafer thin cut in its Budget.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley allocated Rs 381 crore for Vikram Sarabhai Space Centre while Satish Dhawan Space Research Centre Rs 173 crore.</p>
<p>Last year, the non-plan outlay for different projects was Rs 1359 crore as compared to Rs 1509 crore this year.</p>
<p>Money has also been earmarked for Chandrayaan 2, GSLV Mark III project and the INSAT satellite system.</p>
<p>The Department of Space will implement important missions like the proposed SAARC satellite mission later this year.</p>
<p>In the Union Budget 2016-17, the Ministry of Science and Technology has been allocated Rs 9,488 crore as compared to Rs 10,361 in 2015-16 while the proposed allocation to Ministry of Earth Science is Rs 1,418 crore in 2016-17 which was Rs 1,672 crore in 2015-16.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget1_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 20:28:07</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>