<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/fy17-fiscal-deficit-target37-38-acceptable-economists_5601881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[FY17 fiscal deficit target of 3.7-3.8% acceptable: Economists]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In an interview with CNBC-TV18, Kotak Mahindra Bank Chief Economist Indranil Pan, Bank of America-Merrill Lynch Chief India Economist Indranil Sengupta and SBI Chief Economic Advisor talked about where the government should set next year's fiscal deficit target and what their expectations from the Union Budget are.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>In an interview with CNBC-TV18's Shereen Bhan, IDFC&nbsp;Chief Economist Indranil Pan, Bank of America-Merrill Lynch Chief India Economist Indranil Sengupta and SBI Chief Economic Advisor talked about where the government should set next year's fiscal deficit target and what their expectations from the Union Budget are.<br /> <br /><strong>Excerpts from&nbsp;the interview on CNBC-TV18.<br /> </strong><br /> <strong>Q: Which camp do you belong to? The camp that believes that a minor slippage is no big deal or the camp that believes that the Finance Minister must stick to the path of fiscal consolidation which means 3.5 percent in FY17 on the fiscal deficit?</strong><br /> <br /> <strong>Pan:</strong> I belong to the camp which looks at the fiscal consolidation but not exactly at 3.5 but 3.7 is our number.<br /> <br /> <strong>Q: So, you do believe that slippage is what we are likely to see and do you believe that that is necessary at this point in time to try and pump prime the economy and stimulate growth?</strong><br /> <br /><strong> Pan:</strong> Pump priming the economy may not be the best suitable word at this point in time because as we all know there is a huge amount of committed expenditure from the government which along with the fact that they also need to stick to their expenditure plans and pump up the planned expenditure of the economy so far as to support growth given the fact that the private sector is not investing. That is actually what is leading to the slippage in the fiscal deficit rather than a pure pump priming in the truest term.<br /> <br /> <strong>Q: Do you belong to the Indranil Pan or do you belong to the camp that believes that the government will be able to achieve 3.5 percent and should achieve 3.5 percent or stick to that number?</strong><br /> <br /><strong> Sengupta:</strong> I agree with Indranil. Our own number is 3.8 percent of gross domestic product (GDP). If you look at growth in the whole GDP series growth is around five percent. So, this is sheerly the time for the Finance Minister to be supporting growth rather than fiscal consolidation. Once the growth cycle revises there will be lot of time and scope to consolidate on the fiscal side.<br /> <br /> <strong>Q: Are you in the Indranil camp or outside of it?</strong><br /> <br /><strong> Ghosh</strong>: My view is a mix of both. The need of the hour is to stick to the fiscal consolidation path but given the fact that there is an additional liability of 1 percent of GDP this year -- if you consider the Pay Commission, the OROP, the bank recapitalisation. So, if you take that number into consideration our number is actually coming at 3.8 percent of GDP.</p>
<p><strong>Q: How do you then contend with what governor Rajan has been saying that we need to stick to the path of fiscal consolidation and he is not the only one, there is a Rajan camp as well that believes that given where oil prices are today there is really no need in that sense for the government to slip on its fiscal deficit commitment and the target that it has set out. What will that then mean in terms of the possibility of the RBI cutting rates?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ghosh</strong>: I will give an example over here. I think the point which we are missing out here is that we are also missing the revenue deficit numbers. If you look at the FRBM targets very carefully, there is a fiscal deficit target which goes down to 3.5 percent this year, 3 percent next year. However there is also a revenue deficit target which is at 2.8 percent this year goes down to 2 percent next year.</p>
<p>So, my point is that if I am looking purely at the numbers our projection shows that the government is very well likely to attain the 2.8 percent revenue deficit target this year. Next year also the target is 2.4 percent and if the number are any indication given the bonanza it is getting from these oil price decline and other things I think next year 2.4 percent also looks sacrosanct.</p>
<p>So, from that point of view even if the government misses the core fiscal deficit number of 3.5 percent this year, I don't consider it as a matter of fiscal deterioration. In fact if I look for the revenue deficit as a percentage of fiscal deficit then it is actually going to around 60-65 percent over the next two years. So, that in my part is the more important number to look at this point.</p>
<p><strong>Q: What would be the key highlights or the key numbers that you are going to be watching out for from the economy survey as well as what the Budget intends to do?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Sengupta</strong>: Like I said we are looking at a Budget by fiscal deficit of 3.8 percent of GDP and we think that this translates into a net borrowing of Rs 5,250 billion overall. So, that is number one.</p>
<p>Number two we think that the Finance Minister is going to focus on reviving rural India. There could be some more incentives for Make in India and we expect a 1 percent cut in the corporate tax rate.</p>
<p>Finally there will be a consumption stimulus that will come through by the seventh pay commission and we need to see when that is implemented. The seventh pay commission is a boon to the economy at this point in time. If you recall the Sixth pay commission was the one big reason why India avoided the plumage of the Lehmann collapse. So, from that perspective the seventh pay commission will also help to revive demand at this point in time.<br /><br /><em>(Interview transcribed by Swapnil Deshpande and Binu Panicker)</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/f/fiscal_money_356_1143_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 22:18:59</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>