<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/insurance/evaluate-before-you-opt-for-traditional-insurance-policies_5073181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Evaluate before you opt for traditional insurance policies]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Traditional insurance policies offer lower coverage as compared to term insurance for the same amount of premium. At the same time traditional insurance policies offer lower rate of returns as compared to other options.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Steven Fernandes</strong></em><br /><br />Virendra Singh (38) works for a multinational garments brand as sales manager and draws a good salary. His wife is a homemaker and fully involved with her two kids. Being introduced to buying insurance policies at an early age by his father, Virendra has continued the tradition and has purchased several insurance policies for himself and his family members over the years. He holds nearly 16 traditional insurance policies which according to him takes care of his children&rsquo;s educational requirements, their marriage and even his own retirement. The total life cover is only Rs. 33 lakh while he pays an annual premium of over Rs. 2 lakh.<br /> <br />Anil Das (33) claims that he has planned both his daughter&rsquo;s (four &amp; one year old) educational funding through traditional insurance plans. Only time will tell if the insurance plans will be able to cope up with the inflation related to educational expenses. <br /><br /><strong>Reason for most buying traditional policies</strong><br /><br />There are several reasons why traditional insurance policies are bought. Many of us have grown up with the mind-set of looking towards insurance policies as a means to investing and saving tax. Secondly most treat these type of traditional policies as providing some sort of guaranteed returns which is not the case in reality. Traditional policies have been sold emotionally for many- many years and they continue to be sold for fulfilling goals like children&rsquo;s education, marriage and even retirement. The fixed income nature of these policies (unlike ULIP and equity funds which experience volatile returns) also make it more acceptable for risk averse investors. Also with so much charges based comparison and transparency requirements (compliance) related to unit linked polices, insurance advisors find it easier to sell traditional insurance policies where there is no such disclosure required nor any data available. The first thing that most of us have done after one has started earning is to buy an insurance policy. While the very thought of buying an insurance policy early in life needs to be applauded, caution needs to be exercised while selecting the type of policy. It is here that most of us end up making mistakes. <br /><br />Even though much has been spoken and written about the merits of opting for a &ldquo;Pure Insurance&rdquo; policy (Term insurance) which provides adequate cover at a low cost, people seem to ignore these policies as most are still to come to terms with the fact that they don&rsquo;t yield anything on surviving the policy term. Secondly it&rsquo;s very easy to compare returns on products like fixed deposits, mutual funds, ULIPs, etc on a regular basis, but there is no authentic data available on the exact maturity value of traditional policies. <br /><br />Most traditional insurance policies are with profit policies where the insurance companies announce bonuses based on the surpluses that are generated after expenses every year. Going by historical data on the bonus rates of most insurance companies over the last 10 years, the bonus rate seems to be indicating a downward trend. But then even considering the most optimistic bonus rates the overall return over 15 to 20 years seems to be in the range of 5 to 6%. Insurance advisors will argue that 80C tax benefits derived from these investments have been ignored in the overall returns calculations. But then there are other alternative investments which yield more as well as provide deductions under section 80C. For example, PPF which is a 15 year product provides 8.2% tax free returns and ELSS schemes have provided double digit returns over a similar time period. <br /><br />Let&rsquo;s consider an example. A Rs. 10 lakh traditional policy for a 35 year old taken for a period of 20 years cost approximately Rs. 50000 per year. Considering the current average bonus of Rs. 4500 per lakh sum assured, the approximate maturity amount after 20 years comes to around Rs. 19 lakh. Instead if the individual takes a separate term insurance of Rs. 10 lakhs for the same term, it would cost him approximately Rs. 2500 per annum. The balance Rs. 47500 can be invested in PPF which will fetch him approximately Rs. 21.73 lakhs considering 8% return and if ELSS scheme is opted for then considering an average return of 12%, the approximate value after 20 years comes to Rs. 34.22 lakh. <br /><br />While a small allocation of premium towards such policies might not affect the overall financial health of a family, the real issue arises when a substantial amount of premiums get locked in such policies. Knowing fully well that these policies will not help you beat inflation, your long term goals might get jeopardised and by the time you realise it, a significant amount of premium would have been paid. Exiting such policies also turns out to be a costly affair and also invite taxation issues if done before 5 years. <br /><br />Insurance buyers need to take time to evaluate insurance proposals before signing the dotted line. Time well spent initially in understanding the proposal will save a lot of time and avoid losses in later years. <br /><br /><em><strong>Steven is a member of The Financial Planners&rsquo; Guild , India (<a href="http://www.fpgindia.org/" target="_blank">FPGI</a>). FPGI is an association of Practicing Certified Financial Planners to create awareness about Financial Planning among the public, promote professional excellence and ensure high quality practice standards.</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/a/all_insurance_356X200_5351_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-19 17:58:42</Entry_Date><Category>Insurance</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>