<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/hope-for-gst-passage-incentivesbudget-allcargo-exec_5590681.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Hope for GST passage, incentives in Budget: Allcargo exec]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[As logistics industry is export-oriented, incentives should be provided accordingly so that companies can set up shop on the dedicated rail freight corridor wherever industrial parks are planned to be set up, says Prakash Tulsiani, ED & COO of Allcargo Logistics]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Prakash Tulsiani, ED &amp; COO of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/transportlogistics/allcargologistics/AGL02">Allcargo Logistics</a> hopes for smooth passage of the Goods and Services Tax (GST) bill in the upcoming Budget session and due recognition of logistics as an important industry.</p>
<p>Currently, any domestic cargo movement requires more consideration to the taxation structure than the need for logistics systems, Tulsiani says, adding GST would ease processes for the industry. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Logistics industry, he believes, should be made a key part of the Make in India initiative and incentives should be accordingly provided.</p>
<p>As logistics industry is export-oriented, incentives should be provided accordingly so that companies can set up shop on the dedicated rail freight corridor wherever industrial parks are planned to be set up, he says.</p>
<p>He also seeks clarity on fund allocation for Sagar Mala and inland waterways.</p>
<p>On the company&rsquo;s capacity expansion plans, he says, Kolkata CFS is under construction and should be ready within a year.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Prakash Tulsiani's interview with Reema Tendulkar &amp; Mangalam Maloo on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Mangalam: What specific announcements in the Budget are you looking for, anything that would have an immediate and a direct impact in your financial performance?</strong><br /><br />A: As regards Budget, we are looking forward for the goods and services tax (GST) approval. That will bring in a lot of changes for the way we do our logistics. Today, anything which is moving within the country, which is domestic cargo, it is unfortunate that we have to start looking at it basis the taxation rather than the logistic needs. So GST is number one on my list.<br /><br />Secondly, I would look for make in India. How do we bring benefits of make in India? For make in India and industrial production or whatever industrial parks are coming in to take effect logistics is a key play. I would like to know that we are giving a lot of focus on make in India, there are a lot of incentives, there are a lot of changes which are coming in. I would like to say because this is export oriented, also, the logistic industry, we would like to see as there are incentives given to the export industry, we as logistic service provider should also be put in the same bracket. That is we want to see what incentives can come in for the logistics industry to come in and set up shop on the dedicated trade freight corridor wherever the industrial parts are going to be set up. So that is two.<br /><br />Thirdly, we have talked a lot about inland waterways and Sagar Mala, a lot of things are happening, the policies are good, what I would like to see is implementation and fund allocation for all this.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: Could you give us an update on your capex plans, the Kolkata CFS as well as the acquisition that the board has approved?</strong><br /><br />A: We have announced in the previous quarters also and in the last quarter. First of all, it was in the CFS division of ours where we are going in and acquiring land from a port trust in Kolkata. So we will have a new CFS coming up in Kolkata where we have Rs 35 crore outlet. We expect that we will be ready within a year from now which will be sometime around January-February in next year that we will be operational on our CFS. So that is one element.<br /><br />The second one is that the board has announced in principle to go and acquire a logistics company called CCI. CCI Logistics is in a niche market and they are providing contract logistics or warehousing and distribution services to typically chemical industry, auto logistics, FMCG and Pharma.<br /><br />The board of directors have said, we will acquire this company and acquire a substantial and a controlling interest in the company wherein we already today in Allcargo also have businesses of freight forwarding and contract logistics. So this will be transferred into the new company and that is the capex, which will happen over a period of three months. I do not have the exact number right now because there are valuations, which will start right now on this new acquisition and also there are some statutory and regulatory approvals. Once that all is finalised, we will be able to come and give a number to you. So I expect within three months we should be out with a number.<br /><br /><strong>Mangalam: Can you share some financial details of the company, their topline, margins, whether it will be accretive or not?</strong><br /><br />A: I think this is sensitive and I don&rsquo;t want to colour the valuer\\'s intent. Let them do the valuation and once that is all out, we will come out and give the number. So at this stage, it will be inappropriate for me to comment on that.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/a/Allcargo_356_0404_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 14:12:16</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,AGL02,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>