<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/mf-interview/sip-losses-have-not-been-as-big-to-spark-outflow-reliance-mf_5714921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[SIP losses have not been as big to spark outflow: Reliance MF]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In the ongoing market downturn, inflows into mutual funds have held up rather well, allowing the domestic institutional investors to buy stocks and support the market even in the face of relentless selling from FIIs. This is thanks to SIPs.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Back during the 2004-2007 market boom, fund houses around the country launched multiple funds and promoted investments for retail investors without paying much heed to investment philosophy, investor horizon or risk profiling. During the 2008 downturn, they paid the price.<br /><br />Since then, fund houses have majorly promoted systematic investment plans (SIPs) -- a simple way of cost averaging investments that helps in keeping investor biases of greed and fear in check. The strategy has held them in good stead.<br /><br />In the ongoing market downturn, inflows into mutual funds have held up rather well, allowing the domestic institutional investors to buy stocks and support the market even in the face of relentless selling from FIIs.<br /><br />"Inflows into SIPs are continuing even as lump sum investments have slowed," Reliance Mutual Fund CIO Sunil Singhania told CNBC-TV18. "This is because losses in SIP portfolios have been limited, compared to the market's losses."<br /><br />Talking about his outlook, Singhania was frank in conceding that he -- as has been the case with most experts last year -- did not expect stocks to fall in the manner they did.<br /><br />"This was largely because earnings growth did not pan out. The EPS for FY16 is the same as that of FY16. The Nifty is also at the same level," Singhania said. Going forward, he said there is some expectation that at least some sectors should see a turnaround in earnings.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Sunil Singhania's interview with Anuj Singhal and Reema Tendulkar on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Anuj: What does this particular rally telling you that we are seeing today? Are we reading too much into this or is this market's way of saying that oaky we are giving a bit of salute to the Budget right now?</strong><br /><br />A: Yes, we are seeing a big rally today. There is no doubt about what you can see on the ticker but I think what has happened is that in the run up to the Budget, there were a lot of negatives, which were being talked about so the market was bracing for a more challenging Budget specifically on the capital gain side, on the equity market taxation point of view.<br /><br />To that extent, the Budget has allayed those fears. So there are definitely some additional taxes specifically on the so called super-rich whether it is the dividend tax or the crorepati tax or the cess on motor cars and so on and so forth. However, the increase in expenditure along with the fiscal consolidation map, which has been maintained, that has given a lot of hope and optimism as far as the markets are concerned.<br /><br />You also have to look at it in the light that the global markets are consolidating. So that is also helping sentiments. It is a combination of both stability in the global markets as well as so called big negatives not coming out and to that extent positive surprises being sprung up.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: What are your thoughts on the EPF tax both in terms of the employee part being locked till 58 and the employee part being taxed now, do you think this is draconian and do you expect this will be rolled back?</strong><br /><br />A: As an interested party, we will be majorly impacted. I think this is definitely a negative. If you see in India, the most honest taxpayers are the salaried employees because they have no choices. All our expenses are after taxes, our mobile phone bills, education, house rent or the society charges are all after we pay income tax and on that if your retirement is also going to be taxed, it is a little bit unfair. Hopefully, maybe it is a slip and there will be some clarification so let us hope for the best.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: What has also got the markets very excited is the possibility and hope that the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) is going to oblige and reward this fiscal prudence with a rate cut. Do you expect an out of turn rate cut? If yes, what will be the quantum of that and last time around we topped out when the RBI gave us a rate cut post the Budget, what will happen this time?</strong><br /><br />A: Very clearly, we expect a rate cut maybe in April. We don&rsquo;t expect a rate cut in the next two-three days, obviously the RBI also would like to look at the Budget in great detail and then react. We also expect another rate cut maybe post monsoon and as is expected, we also expect the monsoon to be hopefully normal and maybe we can expect one more rate cut before the end of the year. Whether the rate cut will be positive or negative, we will have to wait but our view is that we are reaching a scenario where now incremental good news is going to have a much more positive impact in the market than earlier because from a situation where we were very optimistic, we are now in a situation where everyone is a little bit sort of not as optimistic or maybe even pessimist about the market. That is the reason why every small positive is now going to have a much bigger impact on the upside as far as markets are concerned.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: This hasn&rsquo;t been a good year for portfolio investors, everyone is scared talking about bear market. Do you think the environment changes now with this Budget or do we need to see more evidence from global markets, fund flows before you start to build portfolios constructively?</strong><br /><br />A: One thing is that every equity investor has to be an optimist. So unless you are an optimist, you should not be an equity investor and we are optimist from an economy from a medium-term to longer-term perspective. There is o second doubts about it, so yes, we have seen challenges like never before in the last one year both coming from global markets as well as domestic markets. However, as we move forward, there are lot of positives which can surprise us.<br /><br />We talked about the rate cut, there are positives which can come up from the policy front, maybe the goods and services tax (GST) and the bankruptcy code gets passed, maybe the monsoon is good. The global markets are anyway stabilising, we have seen a few global emerging markets like Brazil and Indonesia move up sharply from their lows. Currencies are stabilising, oil has started to stabilise around USD 35 per barrel and moving up little bit, which should give a little bit of support to oil producing countries. So I think everywhere we are seeing a little bit of stability emerging.<br /><br />What we need for the markets to sustainably move up obviously is earnings. The earnings have not been coming over the last two-three quarters so that is one thing, which we would track very closely before we become very positive in the very near-term.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: Do you think that the Budget has done enough to improve the demand and increase the corporate earnings and when do you expect that corporate recovery to come through?</strong><br /><br />A: If we go in the details, you are right that the capex plan is only 4 percent but if you break up, the revenue estimates are also pretty modest on the tax side. Yes, on the non-tax side, they look a little bit optimistic but on the tax side, they are relatively modest at 9-10 percent. We also have to bear in mind the fact that the central government has been allocating more of its resources to the state government. So obviously they expect the state governments to reuse those resources for capex rather than they doing it.<br /><br />Third is, on the sectors, which the central government is concerned, which is rail and road, the capex has gone up quite meaningfully. So, we expect the central government to focus on the sectors where the central government is basically supposed to spend and more of the capex shifting to the state governments. So, we should not read too much into it but obviously the headline number instead of 4 percent if it will be 8 percent, it would have looked better. I think these are Budget estimate. As we move forward, there will be some disappointments, some positive surprises and we will have to see how it pans out.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Do you think the auto sector or the car sector will take this cess in its stride and move on or do you see a bit of an impact on monthly cess because of that and maybe a bit of a derating in the auto space?</strong><br /><br />A: In the near-term, obviously it takes time for it to be fully passed on. However, if you see as I mentioned earlier, this is an attempt to have an extra tax burden on the so-called super-rich. So instead of Rs 10 lakh if your car starts to cost Rs 10,10,000, you differ your decision, I think that is something which we have to wonder about. The other thing is if there is a slight reduction in interest rate then maybe your EMI even with this 1-2 percent extra that you have to pay might not go up substantially. So we don&rsquo;t expect it to cause too much of a concern as far as demand is concerned only because of this additional cess.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Other big issue that we need to discuss is this whole public sector undertaking (PSU) bank recapitalisation. Rs 25,000 crore, the market expectation was clearly much more than that but leaving that aside, what is your own call on PSU banks, valuation wise it looks so good but we don&rsquo;t know what could be the next non-performing assets (NPA) issue, how would you approach the sector now?</strong><br /><br />A: Very clearly, PSU banks are undergoing stress. There is no doubt about it and we don&rsquo;t know how much money they will need for capitalisation. One positive thing is that finance minister has clearly said that if need be, they would provide more capital.<br /><br />We have a Gyaan Sangam coming up in the next three-four days. That would be more worth pursuing and tracking than the Budget itself because that is where the direction towards the future of PSU banks per se would be more clear whether there will be more consolidation, which is what the Finance Minister has clearly said, how much capitalisation they would need.<br /><br />From our perspective we believe that the smaller PSU banks are going to face increasing challenging times as we move forward and therefore, right now some of the corporate private banks have also fallen in line and maybe at this point in time they are better bets than some of the smaller public sector banks.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: What is the broader Nifty call now? The Budget is done. We have got the sense of how the corporate earnings are likely to pan out. By the end of the year, how much higher do you think the Nifty could go and do you think we have already put a bottom in place closer to the 6,800 mark or do you see another downmove coming?</strong><br /><br />A: We do believe that we have seen the bottom. However, the pace of the upside is going to be dependent on the earnings growth. Earnings growth have been absent last two years, last two years we have seen almost flat earnings. So the earnings per share (EPS) which was there in FY14 is the same as FY16 and that is the reason why the Nifty is also almost at the same level. So we have to see the growth in earnings.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: That is not likely to come through anytime soon?</strong><br /><br />A: March earnings might not come in but maybe June quarter onwards, you will start to see a few sectors spring surprises. So this quarter, for example the impact of the MIP on steel is playing out beautifully. The prices have gone up by Rs 5,000-6,000 a tonne, maybe the steel companies might spring a surprise in the June quarter, banks have been providing very aggressively. One-two more asset sale the way we have seen the large cement asset sales of almost Rs 20,000 crore happened. If that comes into play then maybe the banks might not look as bad. So it is a very fluid situation. Let us see.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Since you head such a big mutual fund, what is happening in terms of retail fund flows? I want to know about two issues, one on systematic investment plans (SIPs), have you seen slowdown of that and two, have you started to see any kind of redemption pressure?</strong><br /><br />A: SIPs are going on the way they have been going on for the last 15-18 months. The SIP book is roughly Rs 2,500 crore to Rs 3,000 crore. However, the lump sum has slowed down. So from a runrate of almost Rs 3,000-3,500 crore lump sum every month, so total of almost Rs 6,500 crore, the net inflows have slowed down to around Rs 3,500 crore.<br /><br />Even as we speak, this month we will also see net inflows and that is being reflected in the net figures which we see every day.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: But that is a bit of a slowdown. Is that a concern?&nbsp; The other concern is -- is there a risk of this flow turning into negative, if the market hits another low and keep making these lows every three-four months?</strong><br /><br />A: One is we don&rsquo;t expect the market to hit low. The second is -- we have been managing money so long and normally when the markets have such a deep correction, investors are very concerned and you end up doing a lot of road shows and a lot of calls. This time, I think the investors have been very prudent in their investment style. So except the high networth individuals (HNI) category which has put in a lot of money, the retail has been only focusing on the SIPs. There the losses have not been all that big to cause a worry. So one year returns per se have been negative 10 percent to 20 percent for the funds but SIP investors maybe are down 5-6 percent. So, there is still hope and we are also pretty optimistic. Let us see, if the returns don&rsquo;t come for the next one to one and a half years then maybe you might see some pressure but at this point of time, investors are continuing with their SIPs and are quite optimistic.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: I was seeing the portfolio of one of your largest equity funds and that is Reliance Growth Fund and it seems to have a bit of a biased towards defensive plays, for example IT names like HCL Technologies, Infosys has a weightage close to about 10 percent, pharmaceutical names like Cipla, Divi's Laboratories have weightage close to about 7-8 percent. Do you think you will continue with this IT, pharma, defensive play or do you think it is time to up the beta considering the fall that we have seen?</strong><br /><br />A: We maintain the portfolios based on the fund philosophy and we are clear that we will have portfolios which are diversified and the sectors that you mentioned are good sectors because they are growing, so even IT is growing in rupee terms between 10 percent and 15 percent, pharma is growing much faster and they also benefit from a slightly weak rupee which we are seeing and it adds a lot of stability to the overall portfolio. So if you go down, we have a lot of economy related stocks also, so we have good exposure to private sector banks, we have good exposure to niche financials even capex companies and we will maintain that characteristic of the portfolio.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: Would you look to add any Budget plays to your portfolio. If yes, which would be the sectors where you could look to enhance your allocation?</strong><br /><br />A: Your long-term investment cannot be based on what the Budget has done in the near term. Yes, there will be some sectors which might incrementally get some benefit because of the Budget and some which might get incrementally negative but I do not think the Budget has been something which will cause us to increase our exposure to a sector by 5 percent or reduce an exposure by 5 percent.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: You hope that the market has made a bottom but from hereon do you think equities would beat rest of the asset classes in terms of returns over the next two-three years. Are you pretty sure about that?</strong><br /><br />A: We have been wrong last one-and-a-half-two years. We definitely believed equity will do better than gold but gold has gone up by 25 percent, but if you believe that the economy is going to grow, which we definitely believe and we are clear that the economy from 2 trillion is going to be 4 trillion; there is no way where equity can perform any other asset class. So my overweight would be equity.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Do you think the auto sector or the car sector will take this cess in its stride and move on or do you see a bit of an impact on monthly cess because of that and maybe a bit of a derating in the auto space?</strong><br /><br />A: In the near-term, obviously it takes time for it to be fully passed on. However, if you see as I mentioned earlier, this is an attempt to have an extra tax burden on the so-called super-rich. So instead of Rs 10 lakh if your car starts to cost Rs 10,10,000, you differ your decision, I think that is something which we have to wonder about. The other thing is if there is a slight reduction in interest rate then maybe your EMI even with this 1-2 percent extra that you have to pay might not go up substantially. So we don&rsquo;t expect it to cause too much of a concern as far as demand is concerned only because of this additional cess.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Other big issue that we need to discuss is this whole public sector undertaking (PSU) bank recapitalisation. Rs 25,000 crore, the market expectation was clearly much more than that but leaving that aside, what is your own call on PSU banks, valuation wise it looks so good but we don&rsquo;t know what could be the next non-performing assets (NPA) issue, how would you approach the sector now?</strong><br /><br />A: Very clearly, PSU banks are undergoing stress. There is no doubt about it and we don&rsquo;t know how much money they will need for capitalisation. One positive thing is that finance minister has clearly said that if need be, they would provide more capital.<br /><br />We have a Gyaan Sangam coming up in the next three-four days. That would be more worth pursuing and tracking than the Budget itself because that is where the direction towards the future of PSU banks per se would be more clear whether there will be more consolidation, which is what the Finance Minister has clearly said, how much capitalisation they would need.<br /><br />From our perspective we believe that the smaller PSU banks are going to face increasing challenging times as we move forward and therefore, right now some of the corporate private banks have also fallen in line and maybe at this point in time they are better bets than some of the smaller public sector banks.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: What is the broader Nifty call now? The Budget is done. We have got the sense of how the corporate earnings are likely to pan out. By the end of the year, how much higher do you think the Nifty could go and do you think we have already put a bottom in place closer to the 6,800 mark or do you see another downmove coming?</strong><br /><br />A: We do believe that we have seen the bottom. However, the pace of the upside is going to be dependent on the earnings growth. Earnings growth have been absent last two years, last two years we have seen almost flat earnings. So the earnings per share (EPS) which was there in FY14 is the same as FY16 and that is the reason why the Nifty is also almost at the same level. So we have to see the growth in earnings.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: That is not likely to come through anytime soon?</strong><br /><br />A: March earnings might not come in but maybe June quarter onwards, you will start to see a few sectors spring surprises. So this quarter, for example the impact of the MIP on steel is playing out beautifully. The prices have gone up by Rs 5,000-6,000 a tonne, maybe the steel companies might spring a surprise in the June quarter, banks have been providing very aggressively. One-two more asset sale the way we have seen the large cement asset sales of almost Rs 20,000 crore happened. If that comes into play then maybe the banks might not look as bad. So it is a very fluid situation. Let us see.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Since you head such a big mutual fund, what is happening in terms of retail fund flows? I want to know about two issues, one on systematic investment plans (SIPs), have you seen slowdown of that and two, have you started to see any kind of redemption pressure?</strong><br /><br />A: SIPs are going on the way they have been going on for the last 15-18 months. The SIP book is roughly Rs 2,500 crore to Rs 3,000 crore. However, the lump sum has slowed down. So from a runrate of almost Rs 3,000-3,500 crore lump sum every month, so total of almost Rs 6,500 crore, the net inflows have slowed down to around Rs 3,500 crore.<br /><br />Even as we speak, this month we will also see net inflows and that is being reflected in the net figures which we see every day.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: But that is a bit of a slowdown. Is that a concern? The other concern is -- is there a risk of this flow turning into negative, if the market hits another low and keep making these lows every three-four months?</strong><br /><br />A: One is we don&rsquo;t expect the market to hit low. The second is -- we have been managing money so long and normally when the markets have such a deep correction, investors are very concerned and you end up doing a lot of road shows and a lot of calls. This time, I think the investors have been very prudent in their investment style. So except the high networth individuals (HNI) category which has put in a lot of money, the retail has been only focusing on the SIPs. There the losses have not been all that big to cause a worry. <br /><br />So one year returns per se have been negative 10 percent to 20 percent for the funds but SIP investors maybe are down 5-6 percent. So, there is still hope and we are also pretty optimistic. Let us see, if the returns don&rsquo;t come for the next one to one and a half years then maybe you might see some pressure but at this point of time, investors are continuing with their SIPs and are quite optimistic.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: I was seeing the portfolio of one of your largest equity funds and that is Reliance Growth Fund and it seems to have a bit of a biased towards defensive plays, for example IT names like HCL Technologies, Infosys has a weightage close to about 10 percent, pharmaceutical names like Cipla, Divi's Laboratories have weightage close to about 7-8 percent. Do you think you will continue with this IT, pharma, defensive play or do you think it is time to up the beta considering the fall that we have seen?</strong><br /><br />A: We maintain the portfolios based on the fund philosophy and we are clear that we will have portfolios which are diversified and the sectors that you mentioned are good sectors because they are growing, so even IT is growing in rupee terms between 10 percent and 15 percent, pharma is growing much faster and they also benefit from a slightly weak rupee which we are seeing and it adds a lot of stability to the overall portfolio. So if you go down, we have a lot of economy related stocks also, so we have good exposure to private sector banks, we have good exposure to niche financials even capex companies and we will maintain that characteristic of the portfolio.<br /><br /><strong>Reema: Would you look to add any Budget plays to your portfolio. If yes, which would be the sectors where you could look to enhance your allocation?</strong><br /><br />A: Your long-term investment cannot be based on what the Budget has done in the near term. Yes, there will be some sectors which might incrementally get some benefit because of the Budget and some which might get incrementally negative but I do not think the Budget has been something which will cause us to increase our exposure to a sector by 5 percent or reduce an exposure by 5 percent.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: You hope that the market has made a bottom but from hereon do you think equities would beat rest of the asset classes in terms of returns over the next two-three years. Are you pretty sure about that?</strong><br /><br />A: We have been wrong last one-and-a-half-two years. We definitely believed equity will do better than gold but gold has gone up by 25 percent, but if you believe that the economy is going to grow, which we definitely believe and we are clear that the economy from 2 trillion is going to be 4 trillion; there is no way where equity can perform any other asset class. So my overweight would be equity.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/m/Mutual-Funds_16-9_356x200_3347_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 11:51:45</Entry_Date><Category>MF-Interview</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>