<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rail-budget-2016-decreasefreight-rate-more-capital-outlays-likely_5637721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Rail Budget 2016: Decrease in freight rate, more capital outlays likely]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Suresh Prabhu may actually decrease freight rates with an eye on increasing volumes and thus improve revenues, sources said. He could also bring in a new policy for cartage.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu may opt to decrease freight rates and look for other avenues to raise additional revenue in his second Rail Budget on Thursday.</p>
<p>Suresh Prabhu may actually decrease freight rates with an eye on increasing volumes and thus improve revenues, sources said. He could also bring in a new policy for cartage.</p>
<p>While falling revenues and increasing demand for funding various capacity augmentation projects demand a hike in passenger fares, the government may be wary of this with elections are round the corner in four states.</p>
<p>The cross-subsidy from freight to passenger operation has crossed Rs 30,000 crore this year while the Seventh Pay Commission burden is about Rs 32,000 crore.</p>
<p>Sources said the minister is likely to announce a new catering policy in his speech with special focus on e-catering.</p>
<p>Despite the grim economic condition, the Railway Budget is expected to increase capital expenditure to enable massive capacity creation.</p>
<p>Focus will be on safety upgradation, electrification and doubling to clear traffic bottlenecks, sources said.</p>
<p>A plan is also on to have one additional bogey in in every express and fast train to be named after the late Jan Sangh leader Deendayal Upadhyaya.</p>
<p>To improve revenues the Rail Ministry is likely to go in for a new advertising policy.</p>
<p>The ministry is also planning a new advertising policy to generate extra revenue.</p>
<p>Narendra Modi's government unveiled a USD 137 billion, 5-year modernisation plan in 2015 to overhaul the network and boost growth, but a slump in passenger and freight revenues in 2016 is straining its finances</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Indian_Railways_rail__rail_overcrowded_engine_freight_coal_356x200_1252_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 07:43:00</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>