<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/govt-should-remove-service-taxeducation-career-point_5590181.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Govt should remove service tax on education: Career Point]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In an interview with CNBC-TV18, he said that skill development and formal education will contribute to the company’s performance in the next fiscal and expects revenue growth of 40 percent for FY17.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The government should remove service tax from professional education as excess cost of skill development will hamper the 'Make in India' initiative, says Pramod Maheshawari, CMD and CEO of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/computers-software-training/careerpoint/CPI05">Career Point</a>.</p>
<p>In an interview with CNBC-TV18, he says&nbsp;that skill development and formal education will contribute to the company&rsquo;s performance in the next fiscal and expects revenue growth of 40 percent for FY17.<br /><br />Career Point recently signed a&nbsp;memorandum of understanding (MoU)with National Skill Development Corporation (NSDC) to become a certified training parter, Maheshwari says.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Pramod Maheshwari's interview with Nigel D'Souza &amp; Reema Tendulkar on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /> <br /> <strong>Nigel: The stock has been a big mover in the last couple of days. Have you received any new memorandum of understanding (MoU) from the government, any kind of new development in terms of skill development and also what is your expectation from this Budget?</strong> <br /> <br /> A: We have been actively working with National Skill Development Corporation (NSDC). We recently entered into a MoU with the NSDC and became a certified training partner for them and we will start our skill development programs from the coming academic session. Beyond this year also, we are working with Pradhan Mantri Kaushal Vikas Yojana which is also provided by NSDC and got approval with couple of sectors in training students across the nation. So, there are things developing on skill development front.<br /> <br /> The second question with respect to Budget, I personally believe that education, skill in any kind of professional education is priority sector. If government really wants to go for Make In India dreams to come true then government must focus on providing facilities to education institutions. The first and the biggest issue is the service tax implication. <br /> <br /> The government should remove the service tax from professional education because a lot of private institutions are providing professional training to the students who will contribute significantly in Make In India but there are entry barriers. 14.5 percent service tax makes cost of skill development pretty costly and not many people are takers. So, everybody is relying on the government spending. So, if government cuts the service tax it will be a big booster and perhaps will help both institutions as well as government to realise the Make In India dream. <br /> <br /><strong> Reema: Any estimates of how much it could contribute to your revenues in FY17, skill development in formal education, any numbers?</strong> <br /> <br /> A: It is really difficult to give any sense but we have been working pretty actively the government. So I believe that it will be significant but committing at this moment of time or giving any indication will be a challenge. <br /> <br /> <strong>Nigel: The last quarter around we saw fairly decent and fairly impressive margins on your informal education business. So, there the margins came in, in excess of around 30 percent. Is this sustainable going ahead?</strong> <br /> <br /> A: I believe so because if you look at our four to five years performance, earlier the business was under pressure because of decrease in enrollment due to change in examination format. However, the situation has settled down, the enrollments are increasing and we are operating leverage. <br /> <br /> So, all of our centers are currently working at under capacity and without any additional capex and operational expenditure (OPEX) as the number of students increases, the margin increases significantly. So, I further believe that margin will improve from here, there is a scope for margin expansion and you can see these will be able to see the same in the coming quarters as well.<br /><br /><em>(Interview transcribed by Priyanka Deshpande)</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/y/youth_career_356x200_5941_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-01 00:00:10</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,CPI07,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>