<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/insurance/why-you-should-buy-life-insurance-online_5266101.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Why you should buy life insurance online?]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[It offers insurance buyers wide options that help them zero on cheaper solutions in a stress free environment. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Naval Goel</strong></em><br /><em>Policyx.com</em><br /> <br />Life insurance is a tool that assists your family in meeting its basic needs and sustaining a lifestyle when you are not around to take care of them. In case of an eventuality, the insurer pays the sum assured to the nominee as stated by you. There are insurance products that offer to pay the nominees a fixed sum of money every month, for a stipulated period of time, in case of death of the life assured. Therefore, life insurance policy is an important financial product that you can add to your investment and savings portfolio. There are many websites that provide a hassle free way to get insured online, without having to run around much and by keeping documentation to minimum possible level. Let us see how it works for you to shop insurance online:<br /> <br /><strong>Estimate the amount of insurance required</strong><br /> <br />Most of us do not know how much insurance we should buy. Most experts make us believe that it is nothing but a rocket science. You have to take into account your current and future expenses. Account for inflation and factor in the outstanding loans that you have to pay. Run some future value-present value calculations and then you get the magic number. In offline world this can be a mad exercise. But in online world you get many human life calculators, which are easy to use and give you the right life insurance amount you should buy in minutes. <br /> <br /><strong>Search Online</strong><br /><br />There are hundreds of insurance products launched by a bunch of insurance companies. No matter how savvy insurance buyer you are, getting in touch with each of the these insurers and getting quotes on the right product can be a cumbersome task. An online aggregator can help you in this. It will offer you a list of insurance plans and help you compare them with each other in a single window. More important benefit is, you can see the availability of the insurance coverage, for different tenures and different sum assured with a click of a button.<br /> <br /><strong>Information matters</strong><br /> <br />Most insurance buyers complain of mis-selling. There are many cases of wrong information floating around about insurance products. But it is not the case with websites of insurance web aggregators. You get the right information about each of the products, which can be verified with the information provided on insurance portals. Some portals offer you the facility to view the insurance policies based on various decision criterions such as price, claim settlement ratio, features among others.<br /> <br />You can help yourself by providing the right inputs on the website of insurance web aggregator. After getting your information, the insurance web aggregator would provide free quotes for the same. It can also suggest additional covers you may want to buy.<br /> <br /><strong>Online means cheaper</strong><br /><br />In online world, the insurance companies typically do away with lot of administrative costs. This helps them offer covers at cheaper prices. If you buy things online, there is a fair chance that you will save a lot of money, typically in the range of 10% to 30%. <br /> <br /><strong>Reputation check</strong><br /> <br />Being online helps the insurance buyers to assess companies on various parameters. Social media helps them to listen to what other customers talk about the company. A more authentic way to judge the life insurance company is to look at the complaints filed by its customers and the claim settlement ratio. Many online web aggregators offer you that information, making your decisions more scientific. <br /> <br /><strong>Handholding</strong><br /> <br />Many insurance buyers think that there may not be anyone to help them buy the right plans. However, it is not the case. You can fall back on means like toll free telephone lines, email and online instant chats, to get your doubts solved by well trained insurance experts employed by insurance aggregators. They also help you with procedural issues, if any. All these steps make insurance shopping online a stress free experience for most insurance buyers. <br /> <br />The insurance plan you buy online is like any other legal documents that you may have. It is better to keep it safe. You should make sure that your nominee knows about it in case of any unexpected situation. <br /> <br />Having an insurance cover gives you peace of mind as you know that you and your loved ones are protected in case of any mishap. As seen earlier, buying an insurance coverage online is the best way as compared to other traditional ways.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/i/insurance_buying_356X200_4849_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-02 17:30:14</Entry_Date><Category>Insurance</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>