<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/budget-2016-sensex-nifty-skid-sharply-sbi-falls-as-banks-recap-at-rs-25kcr_5679041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Sensex, Nifty skid sharply; SBI falls as banks recap at Rs 25kcr]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The market is down as government has decided to allocate less-than-expectated banks recapitalisation amount. FM Arun Jaitley has proposed to give Rs 25000 crore for banks recap. SBI has fallen 2 percent immediately. The Sensex is down 147.79 points or 0.6 percent at 23006.51, and the Nifty is down 62.90 points or 0.9 percent at 6966.85.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau </strong></p>
<p>The market is down as government has decided to allocate less-than-expectated banks recapitalisation amount. FM Arun Jaitley has proposed to give Rs 25000 crore for banks recap. SBI has fallen 2 percent immediately. The Sensex is down 147.79 points or 0.6 percent at 23006.51, and the Nifty is down 62.90 points or 0.9 percent at 6966.85. About 871 shares have advanced, 1234 shares declined, and 131 shares are unchanged.</p>
<p>IDBI is up 6 percent as FM has said that govt has option to reduce stake in IDBI below 50 percent.</p>
<p>Here are few Budget proposal</p>
<p>Rs 25000 crore for bank recap<br />Govt has option to reduce stake in IDBI below 50 percent<br />RBI Act to be amended to provide framework for monetary policy code<br />Bankruptcy Code to be introduced in Parliament in FY17<br />Propose further FDI reforms for stock exchanges, INS, pension<br />Duty drawback schemes to be widened<br />To issue guidelines for renegotiation of PPP contracts<br />Propose Rs 31300 cr of infra bonds to be issued by various agencies<br />To introduce public utility resolution bill<br />Calibrated market prices for gas based on landed price of alternate fuels<br />Propose to develop 10 of 25 non-functional airstrips<br />To incentivise gas production from deep sea &amp; ultra deep waters</p>
<p><em>Posted by Nasrin Sultana</em><br /><em>Follow @<a href="https://twitter.com/NasrinzStory">NasrinzStory</a></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Sensex_Budget2016_nifty_bse_nse_stockmarkets_jaitley_FM_down_356x200_2624_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 12:00:07</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>