<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-india-air-travel-to-become-expensive_5699801.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 India: Air travel to become expensive]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The increase would be virtually applicable to airlines operating from all airports since the proposal for SCAs and the regional connectivity scheme are yet to be implemented.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Fliers will have to shell out more with the government proposing a hike of 6 percent in excise duty on jet fuel but it would not be applicable to the proposed Scheduled Commuter Airlines (SCAs) under the regional connectivity scheme.</p>
<p>The excise duty on ATF is to be hiked to 14 percent from 8 percent, according to a proposal in Union Budget 2016-17.</p>
<p>The increase would be virtually applicable to airlines operating from all airports since the proposal for SCAs and the regional connectivity scheme are yet to be implemented.</p>
<p>The Civil Aviation Ministry has mooted the idea of SCAs and regional connectivity in the draft aviation policy which has not been finalised yet.</p>
<p>"Excise duty on ATF, other than for supply to Scheduled Commuter Airlines (SCA) from the Regional Connectivity Scheme Airports, (is) being increased.</p>
<p>"ATF for supply to aircrafts under the Regional Connectivity Scheme will continue to attract 8 percent excise duty," Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said while presenting the Budget.</p>
<p>Interestingly, the hike in excise duty also comes at a time when airlines have been seeking lower levy on jet fuel, which accounts for more than 40 pr cent of their total operating expenses.</p>
<p>"Increase in excise duty on ATF will make the raw material costlier by around 4-5 percent. At a time when ATF in India is 60-70 percent costlier than global ATF prices, it goes against the government's stated objective to make flying affordable for the masses", Amber Dubey, partner and head- aerospace and defence at global consultancy KPMG said.</p>
<p>Currently, jet fuel prices vary from state to state depending on the Value Added Tax levied by them.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the government's latest move announced also indicates that there would be changes in proposals made in the draft civil aviation policy.</p>
<p>As per the draft policy, ATF drawn by SCA's from the regional connectivity scheme airports shall be exempt from excise duty.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/a/Airlines_aeroplane_air_go_air_356x200_5300_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 16:44:16</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>