<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rahul-takesdig-at-pm-over-mgnrega-praise_5264221.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Rahul takes a dig at PM over MGNREGA praise]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["After calling NREGA 'living monument of INC failure' Govt now hails it as cause of 'nat pride & celebration' !Shining eg of Modiji's pol wisdom", the Congress Vice President said in a tweet.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Rahul Gandhi today took a dig at Prime Minister Narendra Modi saying his government's praise of the UPA's flagship scheme MGNREGA is a "shining example" of Modi's "political wisdom".</p>
<p>He said Modi dispensation, which had called the UPA's job guarantee scheme a "living monument of Congress' failure, has now been forced to accept its success.</p>
<p>"After calling NREGA 'living monument of INC failure' Govt now hails it as cause of 'nat pride &amp; celebration' !Shining eg of Modiji's pol wisdom", the Congress Vice President said in a tweet.</p>
<p>Gandhi's reference was to Prime's Minister snide remarks about the UPA flagship scheme during the Budget Session last year.</p>
<p>"Do you think, I will put an end to the scheme. My political wisdom does not allow me to do it. This is a living monument of your failure to tackle poverty in 60 years. With song and dance and drum beat, I will continue with the scheme," Modi had said during the last budget session.</p>
<p>Ahmed Patel, Political Secretary to Congress President, also took a jibe at the Prime Minister on the issue.</p>
<p>"#MNREGA shows how Govt can create jobs where pvt sector can't. Such is its impact that those who mocked it are now rushing to celebrate. MNREGA is most transformative govt scheme in Independent India. Over 182M ppl have benefited making it the world's largest public scheme (sic)," Patel said in a series of tweets.</p>
<p>Patel said the UPA flagship programme reflected Congress' commitment to a welfare state.</p>
<p>#MNREGA reflects our commitment to a welfare state.</p>
<p>Congress President, Dr (Mamnohan) Singh,NAC &amp; entire UPA have played a vital role in its success. Even Modi govt was forced to accept yesterday that MGNREGA's achievements are a cause of national pride &amp; celebration," Patel tweeted.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/r/Rahul_Gandhi_Modi_Narendra_PM_Prime_Minister_356x200_3600_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-02 15:55:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>