<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/stocks-views/pidilite-industries-looks-attractive-target-rs-800-ravi-shenoy_5087701.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Pidilite Industries looks attractive, target Rs 800: Ravi Shenoy]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ravi Shenoy of Motilal Oswal Securities is of the view that Pidilite Industries looks attractive with a target of Rs 800.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Ravi Shenoy of Motilal Oswal Securities told CNBC-TV18, "<a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/chemicals/pidiliteindustries/PI11">Pidilite Industries</a> looks pretty attractive. From an earnings perspective, we are looking at 26 percent kind of growth and we would like to play the stock because there is a lot of money that is coming into government servant's hands because the Budget will have an additional Rs 1 lakh crore plus of additional payment because of the seventh pay commission. When such large pays come in there is a lot of home improvement that does go in."<br /><br />"If any work gets done on furniture side, Fevicol is a product that will get used over there. So, we would want to play that through Pidilite. In addition to that Pidilite also caters to the children's segment. That is a segment that is growing at a very fast pace with hobby ideas being one of the growth drivers. In addition to Fevikwik and other smaller brands that they have. So, it is a wide portfolio today as compared to what it was earlier and Pidilite also benefits from the falling crude prices that we have been seeing because raw material is crude based and as crude falls we will see more benefits coming into Pidilite," he said.<br /><br />"Pidilite typically doesn't pass that on to consumers because consumers would buy their products irrespective of what prices are. So, if you are looking at benefitting from lower crude prices from home improvement, this is a stock that one should be buying. We have a target of about Rs 800 odd on this particular stock."]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/p/pidilite_0306_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-20 15:52:53</Entry_Date><Category>Stocks Views</Category><sc_id>,PI11,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>