<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/insurance/budget-2016-link-insurance-tax-benefitspolicy-termnot-sum-assured_5476721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Link insurance tax benefits with policy term & not sum assured]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[There should be separate tax benefit available for premium paid for a life insurance policy. Also the tax benefits associated with life insurance should be based on policy term and not sum assured.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Manoj Jain</strong></em><br /><br />Union Budget 2016-17 will be the third budget of the BJP-led government, which has already moved towards facilitating increased foreign direct investment in the insurance sector. To stipulate expenses related to increasing trend of inflation, it is expected that basic exemption limit of taxation should be expanded currently from Rs 2.5 lakh to Rs 3 lakh. From a life insurance customer&rsquo;s perspective, it is expected to have separate limit exclusively for normal pension plans just like the introduction of limit of Rs. 50,000 under Section 80 C in the last budget for National Pension Scheme. <br /><br /><strong>Other expectations in terms of taxation are briefed below:</strong><br /><br /><strong>Indirect taxes - Service tax</strong><br /><br />&bull;There should be 0% service tax on the policies for sum assured less than Rs.10 lakh.<br /><br />&bull; Interest rate on delayed payment/refund of service tax <br />1. There can be penal interest charged on the non remittance of service tax collected from the policyholders at a rate of 12% per annum <br />2. There should not be any penal interest for the cases where the service tax is not collected and remitted where the matter is subject to adjudication on account of interpretation of the provisions in the Act. <br />3. Simple interest @ 6% is payable by the service tax department for delay in refund of service tax. This rate of interest may be increased to 12 %.<br /><br />&bull; In order to promote long term saving, providing rebate or waiving off service tax levied on various components of services like fund management charges, policy administration charges. <br /><br />&bull; There should be 0% service tax on premium collected under PMJJBY for the master policy holders other than banks.<br />Individual/Corporate Taxation<br /><br />&bull; All insurance policies for tax benefits eligibility, except pension products, are regulated to offer a life cover of at least 10 times the annual premium. It is required to link the benefits to the term of the policy instead of sum assured. It is proposed that for policyholders of age up to 35 years, exemption should be provided for life cover of 10 times the annual premium. For the policyholders of age above 35 yrs, exemption should be provided for life cover of 5 times the annual premium.<br /><br />&bull; To promote long term saving and age old security, pension products should be exempt in the hands of policyholders by introducing a new sub section under Section 10. To incentivize old age pension created by self funding, this should be exempt. Annuitants are generally senior citizens and taxing them would be against welfare policy. In view of this, the entire pension/ annuity receipts should be exempted from tax<br /><br />&bull; 80C - deduction from the total taxable income - Deduction under Section 80C may be allowed separately for life insurance premium on the basis of term of policy and exclusively increase deduction limit of Rs. 1.50 lakh. Over the period of time, various investments such as mutual fund, bank deposits etc. have been included within the overall limit of Rs. 1.50 lakh. Share of life insurance premium allowed for deduction has shrunk.<br /><br /><strong>Withholding Taxes</strong><br /><br />&bull; The TDS deduction should be triggered only beyond the threshold limit. The basic exemption limit may be increased from Rs. 1 lakh to Rs.2.5 lakh for individuals below age of 60years/Rs.3 lakh for senior citizens aged 60 years and above but below 80 years and 4 lakh for super senior citizens aged 80years and above.<br /><br />&bull; The threshold limit TDS on agent commission may be increased to Rs. 50,000 under section 194D from Rs. 20,000.<br /><br /><strong>Goods &amp; Service tax</strong><br /><br />&bull; Continuation of current rates of tax applicable to life insurance companies under GST Regime - Presently, service tax payable on life insurance policies vary from 1.75% to 14% depending on policy nature of policy and year of premium. Any further increase in the rates tax under GST regime would cause undue hardship to the prospective customer. Hence, we expect continuation of current rate of tax structure to be applicable to life insurance policies in GST regime<br /><br />&bull; Centralized registration of taxable entity for GST compliance by life insurance companies - Under the GST regime, the entity for levy of GST is to be defined suitably, to allow efficient tax compliance without burdening the life insurance companies with additional costs. A registered head office (which may be defined as the location at which the insurance companies have mechanical and human resources necessary for providing / receiving supplies of goods and services permanently present) of the life insurance companies may be defined as the taxable entity.<br /><br /><br /><em><strong>Author is the managing director of Shriram Life Insurance</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/budget_2016_356X200_2750_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-15 13:07:47</Entry_Date><Category>Insurance</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>