<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/infra-spending-unlikely-to-boost-domestic-steel-demand-fitch_5756721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Infra spending unlikely to boost domestic steel demand: Fitch]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The government has allocated a total outlay of Rs 2.21 lakh crore in the Budget for 2016-17 to boost infrastructure in the country.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The increased infrastructure spending in the Budget 2016-17 is unlikely to provide a boost to domestic steel demand growth, Fitch Ratings said.</p>
<p>However, the ratings agency said in a statement that demand can grow if "project execution rates pick up significantly".</p>
<p>Domestic steel producers also face over-capacity, which is likely to weigh on their profitability and credit metrics in the near term, it added.</p>
<p>The government has allocated a total outlay of Rs 2.21 lakh crore in the Budget for 2016-17 to boost infrastructure in the country.</p>
<p>"For 2015-16 fiscal, the government had Budgeted for infrastructure investment to double from actual spending in 2014-15. However, except for a pick-up in road construction (up 36 percent Y-o-Y in H1 FY'16), project implementation appears to have been weak so far in 2015-16," Fitch Ratings said.</p>
<p>Private-sector investment has also remained weak, given the stretched corporate balance sheets. As a result, steel demand growth in India has remained soft at 4.7 percent year -on-year (Y-o-Y) during April-December this fiscal, it added.</p>
<p>"We expect steel demand growth to improve slightly to 7-8 percent in 2016-17, supported by a pick-up in government infrastructure spending with better project execution," it said.</p>
<p>However, the steel industry is burdened by overcapacity.</p>
<p>Domestic capacity is scheduled to jump by about 15 million tonnes over the second half of 2015-16 and 2016-17 period, which will exceed a potential 6 million tonne increase in domestic steel demand in the next fiscal.</p>
<p>At the same time, the global supply continues to outstrip demand. Given the supply-demand growth mismatch, producers are likely to engage in price competition amid weak utilisation levels.</p>
<p>"Therefore, a recovery in sales realisation and profitability for Indian steelmakers is unlikely before fiscal 2017-18," Fitch Ratings added.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/s/steel-3566_2420_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-04 09:00:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>