<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/politics/presidents-addressbig-disappointment-congress_5609561.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[President's address a big disappointment: Congress]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["There was nothing new in the speech. It was full of slogans like 'sabka saath, sabka vikas'. There was nothing which will give any relief to the people. The atmosphere is tense in the country. There was nothing on this and also no mention of tension with neighbouring countries," Congress leader Rajiv Shukla said outside Parliament.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Congress today said the President's address in Parliament was a "big disappointment" and there was "nothing new" to offer to the public.</p>
<p>"There was nothing new in the speech. It was full of slogans like 'sabka saath, sabka vikas'. There was nothing which will give any relief to the people. The atmosphere is tense in the country. There was nothing on this and also no mention of tension with neighbouring countries," Congress leader Rajiv Shukla said outside Parliament.</p>
<p>He said, "Every thing is cliche, same thing we are hearing again and again. It is a big disappointment." "There are other problems like price rise, problems with neighbouring countries. There was nothing on these issues," he said.</p>
<p>On Swachh and Swasth Bharat campaigns, the Congress leader said, "We are hearing this for the last one year and 10 months. Even Swachh cess has been collected but nothing is visible on the ground. You will find filth in every nook and corner." President Pranab Mukherjee today addressed the joint sitting of both the Houses of Parliament, outlining the government's agenda in the coming financial year.</p>
<p>Reacting to Shukla's comment, BJP leader Ravi Shankar Prasad said, "We do not need a certificate from Congress. We have to get it from the people of India and people have given us certificate that we are working on the right direction."</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/p/POLITICS_ELECTIONS_India_Congress1_16x9_2521_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-23 15:08:04</Entry_Date><Category>Politics</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>