<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/india-faces-challengessticking-to-fiscal-roadmap-sp_5224881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[India faces challenges in sticking to fiscal roadmap: S&P]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["Although we expect the administration to pursue its stated fiscal consolidation programme, we foresee that planned revenues may not fully materialise and subsidy cuts may be delayed," S&P Ratings Services India Sovereign Analyst Kyran Curry told PTI. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>India will face challenges in sticking to the fiscal consolidation roadmap as the expected revenues may not be fully realised and subsidy cuts may be delayed, Standard &amp; Poor's Ratings Services said.<br /><br /> "Although we expect the administration to pursue its stated fiscal consolidation programme, we foresee that planned revenues may not fully materialise and subsidy cuts may be delayed," S&amp;P Ratings Services India Sovereign Analyst Kyran Curry told PTI. <br /><br />In the Budget 2015-16 government deviated from the fiscal consolidation path, postponing fiscal deficit targets by a year.</p>
<p>The original target was to bring it down to 3.6 percent of the GDP in 2015-16 but it has been postponed by a year. Now, government is targeting 3.9 percent in the current fiscal and 3.5 percent by next year.<br /><br /> "India's fiscal challenges reflect both revenue under performance and constraints on expenditure (mainly related to subsidies for food, energy, and fertilisers)," Curry said.</p>
<p>However, he said that in the medium term, S&amp;P expects improved fiscal performance primarily from revenue-side improvements, brought about by the planned introduction of the Goods and Services Tax (GST) and administrative efforts to expand the tax base. <br /><br />While RBI Governor Raghuram Rajan has cautioned against the fiscal profligacy to spur growth, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley has remained non-committal on fiscal slippages. Jaitley has said there are pros and cons of pushing growth by higher public spending and he would take a view on the issue at the time of Budget.</p>
<p>The Budget for 2016-17 would be unveiled on February 29.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/f/fiscal_money_356_1143_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-01 10:46:57</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>