<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/covered-some-distanceoperational-course-correction-spicejet_5606821.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Covered some distance on operational course correction: Spicejet]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The total payables of Spicejet, including bank debt and vendor liabilities, has reduced from roughly Rs 2200 crore at the time of change in ownership to Rs 700 crore now, says Chairman, Ajay Singh, adding the plan is to reduce this further to Rs 300-400 crore over one year.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/transportlogistics/spicejet/SJ01">Spicejet</a> has come a long way in regaining customer confidence and operational course correction, in the last one year, says the company&rsquo;s Chairman, Ajay Singh, in an exclusive interview to CNBC-TV18.</p>
<p>The total payables including bank debt and vendor liabilities has reduced from approximately Rs 2200 crore at the time of change in ownership&nbsp;to Rs 700 crore now, he says adding the plan is to reduce this further to Rs 300-400 crore over one year.</p>
<p>The airline has now reached the best on-time performance standards in the industry with significantly lower flight cancellations, he says.</p>
<p>He points out that while most other hurdles have been cleared out, the focus over the next 9-12 months will be on stickier costs like acquisition and lease rentals, maintenance cost of fleet etc &nbsp;</p>
<p>Ancillary revenues are growing steadily and expected to be 20 percent of total revenues from 16 percent now, he says.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Ajay Singh's interview with Shereen Bhan on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: If I may ask you is the operational course correction that you had undertaken when you came back to SpiceJet now over and done with. If I were to look at the numbers, fuel costs are down 35 percent year-on-year (Y-o-Y) which has been the big beneficiary. As far as aviation stocks are concerned and aviation companies are concerned, your employee costs are down 10 percent Y-o-Y, your interest costs are down 50 percent Y-o-Y. Has the operational course correction in that sense now is it 50 percent complete or is it almost complete?</strong><br /><br />A: We have come quite some distance from where we were last year. As you know last year, we had large number of flights that were cancelled just before the ownership changed and the on-time performance was at 40 percent. SpiceJet had been losing money for five years on the trot and it was just the lessors who were trying to repossess their planes, the vendors were asking for their money. So it was a very difficult situation for SpiceJet. I think what SpiceJet had lost in this period was the confidence of its customers and of its partners. We have been able to make significant recovery in the last one year.<br /><br />As you know, consumer confidence has been pretty high, the last nine months SpiceJet has flown with an occupancy factor in excess of 92 percent, which clearly shows that people have come back to fly on SpiceJet. Lessors have returned the planes, the outstanding payments which were close to Rs 22,000 crore are now close to Rs 700 crore. So, a lot of the settlements have been done, a lot of the payments have been made.<br /><br />The on-time performance is amongst the best in the industry at this time. The cancellation rate is by far the lowest of all airlines in India. So, I think we made significant progress but to say that this is all done and dusted and complete would not be accurate. There is just lots to be done for SpiceJet.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Can you give us a picture as far as your total debt is concerned, I understand it stood at Rs 1,418 crore at the end of 2015, can you update us on the debt situation and what you expect going forward? How much reduction do you expect going forward?</strong><br /><br />A: If I look at the total payables when we took over the airline, they were close to Rs 2,200 crore. This included the bank debt that was due and payments to vendors etc. At this time, that number stands at close to Rs 700 crore and part of that Rs 700 crore is business as usual debt. So that puts us in a pretty strong position and we expect that over the course of the next 12 months, we will be in a much healthier situation than we are today.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Can you quantify that for us?</strong><br /><br />A: It is tough to put an accurate number to it but we expect that we will pretty much be left with only the business as usual sort of debt, which is roughly in the range of Rs 300-400 crore. So that is where we should be in the course of this year. I think importantly what we need to do going forward is to keep working on reducing our costs. The stickier costs that we have not been able to address as well so far, which is the cost of the acquisition of planes and therefore the lease rental cost for the planes and the cost of heavy maintenance of our fleet. So those are our areas that we will work very actively on over the next 9-12 months.<br /><br />In addition to that, while we have made a significant recovery on the revenue side and despite the fact that average ticket fares have been lower by about 22-25 percent for the entire industry, revenues for SpiceJet have increased significantly both passenger revenues as well as ancillary revenues have increased significantly.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Can you give us a break up on the ancillary revenue part and how you see that going forward?</strong><br /><br />A: When we started in January 2015, the ancillary revenue accounted for about 6 percent of total revenues of the company. That number is close to 16 percent at this time. We expect to increase that further through the course of the year and we are targeting revenue of about 20 percent for ancillaries.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Let me ask you in terms of cost because the expectation now is that perhaps the best in terms of fuel cost has been enjoyed by the industry, we have seen the rupee depreciate and also prices as far as crude is concerned perhaps may have bottomed out to these levels, so what can we expect now in terms of fuel cost as well as employee cost, which are down 10 percent Y-o-Y, you were talking about further cost optimisation, can you give us a roadmap of what we can expect in terms of cost optimisation from here on?</strong><br /><br />A: There are two large pieces of costs that are still to be addressed. The first is the cost of acquisition and lease of planes and that is being addressed through a new order that we expect to place for an aircraft. As well as shifting from having a significant number of planes on wet lease to a dry lease situation that will help us reduce cost of the planes. In addition to that, the heavy maintenance cost, the engineering cost those are things that we are looking at in terms of renegotiating some of those contracts and entering into new contracts simultaneously with the acquisition of new planes.<br /><br /><strong>Q: What would that then mean in terms of&nbsp; margins you being able to bring down the cost as you just articulated?</strong><br /><br />A: I don't want to give guidance on margins as the EBITDA margins currently are in the low 30s and we expect that we should certainly be able to sustain them and hopefully improve them somewhat.<br /><br /><strong>Q: You were talking about the fleet expansion as well as the aircraft acquisition plan. We talked about it the last time you and I had a conversation, by when do we expect that order to be placed and in terms of how many aircraft you expect to add on in this particular calendar year, is there a number now that you have fixed on?</strong><br /><br />A: Firstly, on the order itself we are working very actively and aggressively with both Boeing and with Airbus and we expect to have that done soon. It is a pretty exacting and detailed exercise. We don't want to rush it because these are orders, which will live with SpiceJet for years to come. So we need to get it right and we hope to get it done soon but I don't want to put an exact timeframe to it.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Can we expect it in this half of the year?</strong> <br /><br />A:Yes certainly we hope so.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Can you give us a number in terms of whether you have fixed on the number of&nbsp; aircrafts that you are going to be acquiring?</strong><br /><br />A: It will be a significant order. The exact number depends on the commercial negotiations that we are doing. It is clear that SpiceJet needs a significantly large number of planes.<br /><br />The aviation market is growing at 20 percent. SpiceJet is already filling its planes 90-93 percent month on month, clearly we need capacity. So, the order will be large but the exact size of the order will depend upon the commercial negotiations that we are currently engaged in.<br /><br /><strong>Q: A ballpark number?</strong><br /><br />A: I have already said that this will be in excess of 100 planes. In terms of addition to the fleet, this year we are expecting to add at least 10 percent to our capacity in the summer and additional 10 percent in the winter. schedule. So, there will be significant addition to capacity this year as well.<br /><br /><strong>Q: What is the outlook now as far as ticket prices are concerned and do you believe that there is room now to see an appreciation on the price front given the competitive nature of the business as well with some of the newer players trying to eke out more market share from the incumbents?</strong><br /><br />A: What we have seen is that over the last one year ticket prices have dropped and they always drop when fuel prices come down. However the net yield for SpiceJet has increased and that has been a consequence of better revenue management.<br /><br />Going forward it is a question of how we plan our network, how we design that network, how we run our schedules and how we plan our revenue. We think that there is margin there and we can improve the net yield to SpiceJet in the coming times.<br /><br />In terms of competition, of course there will be competition but the market is really large. Currently still 2 percent of Indians are flying. All these tier II, tier III markets opening up should give plenty of room for growth.<br /><br /><strong>Q: What is going to be the aspiration there. We have talked about your regional plans and how that is linked to what you aspire in terms of market share gain?</strong> <br /><br />A: I don't want to be stressed about particular market share. I think it is important that SpiceJet grows but grows profitably. There is little point in just running after market share which in the aviation sector tends not to be so sticky. You can get temporary market share by launching massive sales and depressing your yield and fares but the moment somebody else does it, that market goes away. So, it is far more important to focus on profitability and ensuring profitable growth.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Let me also ask you about the recent Twitter war with Ratan Tata. We understand that this commentary and this chatter is perhaps around the fact that we could see a decision finally being taken by the government on the civil aviation policy which has been long pending and a final decision on 5/20 as well. The civil aviation minister has made his point of view very clear. He believes 5/20 should go. You believe 5/20 should stay. Mr Tata believes 5/20 is unfair to new airlines and it is being kept in place on account of the interest of the incumbents. If the civil aviation policy were to say that 5/20 is going to go what would it mean for companies like you and Indigo?</strong><br /><br />A: Firstly let me just clarify. We have the greatest possible respect for Mr Tata. But we believe that he is an interested party here and his group is a shareholder in the two companies that are espousing.<br /><br /><strong>Q: But so are you.</strong><br /><br />A: Of course we are and we say this openly that we are. Now the issue really is that in terms of 5/20 airlines that exist in India today the carriers like SpiceJet and Indigo and GoAir and Jet Airways. They have all been asked to serve for five years within the country and operate with 20 aircrafts and fly to remote areas as a consequence of the route dispersal guidelines and then get lucrative rights to fly abroad.<br /><br />You are saying now that we are changing this rule and now the new carriers that come in including airlines that are clearly foreign controlled which by the way is completely against this Indian law and in fact against the law in pretty much every country around the world. For these carriers you will change the rule and have them fly international without serving the domestic sector at all. We think that is not fair. What is even more unfair is the fact that the draft policy suggests that existing carriers will continue to fly to these remote areas with the fleet that they have whereas the new carriers will not be required to do so. So, that is not really creating a level playing field at all.<br /><br />Mr Tata is completely right. The policy is discriminatory. The draft policy is actually discriminatory against the existing airlines in India that have been flying for five years. You must have a level playing field. Any policy that you build has to have a level playing field. Countries around the world protect their airlines and their hub airports. The US does it, Canada does it, Europe does it, the Gulf states do it, Singapore and Malaysia do it. Why is it that today if I was to try and set up an airline controlled by SpiceJet in the Gulf or in Malaysia or in Singapore or in the US I would not be allowed to do so. But we are allowing people to come and do this in our country. We don't see how that is fair.<br /><br /><strong>Q: We don't know whether we are going to allow that to happen or not because the decision hasn't been taken yet?</strong><br /><br />A: No, we are already doing it. Today it is clear that AirAsia and Vistara are controlled by their foreign parent. There is no doubt about it. The meetings are being held.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Which is a charge that has been denied by both Vistara as well as AirAsia.</strong><br /><br />A: It is an allegation which is made by their own shareholder and by their own CEO. So, I don't know what denials we are talking about.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Give us a sense of what we should expect now in terms of network expansion, in terms of routes that you are likely to add on. What should we expect in calendar year 2016?</strong><br /><br />A: We have already said that SpiceJet as a low cost carrier believes in achieving depth rather than breadth. So, we will try and add routes within the stations where we operate currently and try not to open too many new stations. We will add frequency to the existing sectors, we will connect those stations which are within our network but which are not connected as well. So, we will continue with that policy because we believe that that helps us in reducing the cost of operations.<br /><br /><strong>Q: In terms of operating environment what is the outlook now as far as crude is concerned? You have been the big beneficiary on account of the fall in crude prices which has resulted in a significant fall in ATF costs but what do you expect from hereon as far as crude is concerned and what would that mean in terms of the business?</strong><br /><br />A: The fall in crude prices has not translated into an equivalent fall in ATF prices because some part of that has been retained by the oil companies in India. In terms of the crude prices themselves globally it seems that for the next year or two years they will remain fairly moderate. I was reading comments of Christine Lagarde today and she seems to suggest that for several years the oil prices are going to remain soft.<br /><br />Having said that I think it is important that we use the breathing space that we have got with the fall in crude prices to try and bring down costs which are costs other than fuel, so that even if oil prices were to go up in the future SpiceJet would be protected against that rise because we would have reduced other costs. So, we are working on that.<br /><br /><strong>Q: The last conversation you and I had you said that you are in no hurry to try and dilute stake at this point in time or bring in investor onboard because you wanted to improve the financial performance of the airline. Given the fact that you have now seen the fourth straight quarter of profits, do you feel that this is now the time for you to be talking to potential investors, are conversations already underway, can we see or can we expect something on that front?</strong><br /><br />A: The company doesn't need financing at this point of time. SpiceJet is generating enough cash. We are profitable, we expect to remain profitable over the next several quarters. It is just that we don't need the money, so I don't really see any reason to dilute equity at this point of time.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Are you looking at the market cap battle between you and your competitor because revenues of SpiceJet one third of IndiGo, market cap one eighth, we did have a chat about this the last time around and you couldn't figure the reason for this kind of divergence. Where do you stand on this debate today?</strong><br /><br />A: We need to focus on improving the performance of SpiceJet. We should let the stock market take care of itself. If we do well they will reward us and if we do badly they will punish us and they will figure out the distinction between or the difference between the market caps of the two companies. I don't want to comment on that.<br /><br /><strong>Q: If I were to ask you about the immediate priorities that you would like to work on as well as the short to medium term priorities, what would those levers be that you would like to leverage at this point in time as you try and get back to where SpiceJet used to be?</strong><br /><br />A: We need to work on the sticky costs, the costs related to aircraft acquisition, to maintenance and engineering, to rationalisation of airports and that capacity. So, that is going to be key, reduction of costs, the placement of orders for newer aircrafts, that is going to be a key priority for the next several months. In terms of revenue we will keep trying to increase ancillary revenue, we will keep trying to optimise passenger revenue and the network that SpiceJet is flying.<br /><br /><em>(Interview transcribed by Swapnil Deshpande &amp; Binu Panicker)</em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/s/SPICEJET_3935_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-23 12:45:59</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,ML04,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>