<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2016-17-govt-to-raise-customs-dutyaluminium-products-by-25_5696241.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2016-17: Govt to raise Customs duty on aluminium products by 2.5%]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Basic Customs Duty is being increased for primary aluminium from 5 percent to 7.5 percent and that on aluminium products from 7.5 percent to 10 percent, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said while delivering his Budget speech for 2016-17 in the Lok Sabha today.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The government today proposed to raise the Basic Customs Duty (BCD) on aluminium and aluminium products by 2.5 percent, a move that will help the primary producers of the metal by checking influx of cheap imports.</p>
<p>Basic Customs Duty is being increased for primary aluminium from 5 percent to 7.5 percent and that on aluminium products from 7.5 percent to 10 percent, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said while delivering his Budget speech for 2016-17 in the Lok Sabha today.</p>
<p>Last week, the Parliamentary Committee on Public Enterprises had recommended the government to raise import duty on aluminium and raised "serious concerns" on "adverse impact" of cheaper imports on the profitability of state-owned Nalco.</p>
<p>It said that out of total aluminium consumption in India, 55 percent is met from aluminium scrap and 45 percent through aluminium, on which the import duties are 2.5 percent and 5 percent respectively, resulting in cheap imports from countries like China.</p>
<p>These factors have led to Nalco and other domestic firms running up losses as well as losing the drive to increase their capacity utilisation since investments on the same are not likely to lead to profits, it added.</p>
<p>As a result, companies like Nalco are going for cost-cutting measures as well as retrenchments and laying off workers to survive, it pointed out.</p>
<p>The panel took the line that apart from survival of the industry, this is an alarming scenario for factory workers and hence, urgent action from the government is warranted.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/a/Aluminium_3313_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 14:46:11</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>