<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/cnbc-tv18-comments/budget-2016-infra-sectors-wishlist_5337361.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Infra sector's wishlist]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The NHAI is involved in 112 legal disputes with infrastructure companies — valued at over Rs 25,000 crore and unless these legal disputes are settled or disposed off, NHAI's target of laying o30 kilometres per day in FY16 will be in jeopardy]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Lack of funding, over-leveraged balance sheets and slow regulatory and government clearances are some of the oldest problems the infrastructure space has been facing, and solutions to these problems are part of the sector's Budget 2016 wishlist. This year, players, especially those involved in road projects, have a new and far more pressing demand &mdash; a solution to rising litigation.</p>
<p>The National Highways Authority of India (NHAI) has been set a herculean task &mdash; it has to lay over 30 kilometres per day over FY16, spending over Rs 1.6 lakh crore in the bargain. Ofcourse, FY17 targets are expected to be steeper.</p>
<p>But here's the problem: The NHAI is involved in 112 legal disputes with infrastructure companies &mdash; valued at over Rs 25,000 crore and unless these legal disputes are settled or disposed off, NHAI's target will be in jeopardy.</p>
<p>Experts say one reason for this surge in disputes is that India has poorly defined arbitration clauses, and the inability to identify the defaulting party in terms of the contractual obligations leads to a he-said,-she-said kind of situation.</p>
<p>They hope finance minister Arun Jaitley's Budget 2016 will lay down a framework to reduce this burden of litigation.</p>
<p>Sunil Kanoria, vice-chairman, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-leasinghirepurchase/sreiinfrastructurefinance/SRE02">Srei Infra</a>, says: "There is huge amount of disputes pending in arbitration matter. These disputes between the contractor, concessionaires and government are so high that it needs to be released. The construction industry , the infra sector, they are over leveraged and now if the disputes settle a lot of resources can come back to the system. Banks will again start lending and support the projects and revival can be in place. That is one suggestion and we need to make that happen."</p>
<p>Players say this should not be too difficult for the finance minister. After all, the recently released Kelkar Committee Report recommends the formation of a project review committee to solve legacy issues. And an infrastructure adjudication tribunal to hear all infra-related litigations has been suggested. It is envisaged to be one step below the apex court in terms of power, this tribunal will help expedite the dispute redressal process.</p>
<p>Manish Agarwal, partner, Pwc, says: "The committee has also said that such a tribunal should be set up through a Act of Parliament so the act of setting up of tribunal and empowering it to enable the committee and recommended by the Kelkar committee can well be out in place through the Budget."</p>
<p>Players are hopeful they will see some positive action in Budget 2016, given the government's repeated assurances that reviving the infrastructure sector is a top priority.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/i/Infra_Budget_2016_jaitley_FM_356x200_2242_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-05 21:57:04</Entry_Date><Category>CNBC-TV18 Comments</Category><sc_id>,SRE,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>