<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-india-jaitley-proposes-to-amend-sebi-act-to-increase-benchessat_5692941.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 India: Jaitley proposes to amend Sebi Act to increase benches in SAT]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[All the orders passed by the Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi) can be appealed in SAT.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley today proposed to amend the Sebi Act in order to increase benches in the Securities Appellate Tribunal (SAT).</p>
<p>Currently, SAT has only one bench which sits in Mumbai.</p>
<p>All the orders passed by the Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi) can be appealed in SAT.</p>
<p>The proposed move will help expedite cases related to securities markets.</p>
<p>SAT is a statutory body established under the provisions of the Sebi Act, 1992, to hear and dispose of appeals against orders passed by the capital markets regulator.</p>
<p>While unveiling the Budget 2016-17 in the Lok Sabha, Jaitley proposed to amend the Sebi Act to increase benches in SAT to reduce pendency.</p>
<p>As per the latest Sebi data, 520 appeals were filed before SAT during 2014-15 whereas 103 appeals were dismissed and 381 appeals were pending at the end of the year. Besides, 16 Sebi orders were upheld with changes.</p>
<p>As per the Sebi Act, the orders passed by the regulator can be appealed before SAT while the Tribunal's orders can be further challenged before the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>The success rate in the Securities Appellate Tribunal for 2014-15 stood at 90 percent compared with 88 percent in 2013-14, Sebi has said.</p>
<p>Against SAT's orders, five appeals were filed by Sebi whereas 31 appeals were filed against Sebi in the Supreme Court during 2014-15.</p>
<p>Nine appeals were disposed of where the appeals were filed by Sebi while 25 appeals were disposed of where the appeals were filed against Sebi.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget15_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 12:18:03</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>