<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rail-budget-2016-need-clarityfundingplans-announced_5646821.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Rail Budget 2016: 'Need clarity on funding of plans announced']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Talking to CNBC TV18, GP Goenka, chairman, Stone India gave his views on the Railway Budget 2016.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Talking to CNBC TV18, GP Goenka, Chairman, Stone India gave his views on the Railway Budget 2016. <em><br /><br /><strong>Following is the transcript of the interview with GP Goenka:</strong></em><br /><br />
<div style="position: absolute; left: -99999px;"><br /> Read more at: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rail-budget-2016-projections-for-fy17-somewhat-optimistic-says-bibek-debroy_5644801.html?utm_source=ref_article">http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rail-budget-2016-projections-for-fy17-somewhat-optimistic-says-bibek-debroy_5644801.html?utm_source=ref_article</a></div>
<div style="position: absolute; left: -99999px;">Following is the transcript of the interview with Bibek Debroy:<br /><br /> Read more at: <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rail-budget-2016-projections-for-fy17-somewhat-optimistic-says-bibek-debroy_5644801.html?utm_source=ref_article">http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rail-budget-2016-projections-for-fy17-somewhat-optimistic-says-bibek-debroy_5644801.html?utm_source=ref_article</a></div>
<em><strong>Reema</strong></em>: Do you expect increased business based on what we have heard from the Railway Budget?<br /> <br /> A: Where is this Rs 1,20,000 crore going to come, I have my reservations.<br /> <br /> <em><strong>Latha</strong></em>: How was the performance in terms of project ordering and tendering in the current year?<br /> <br /> A: It has not been terribly exciting so far as the Railway Budget is concerned. I am not talking of a metro part of it, but the Railway part has not been terribly exciting. Bits and pieces coming in but nowhere near what we expected and unless one knows the pattern of funding, I don&rsquo;t know if the order book is going to increase tremendously, the intent is very good, the plan is very good, the way forward is very good provided you have the funds supporting it.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Railways_rail__356x200_1230_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 16:33:22</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>