<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/arun-jaitley-cancels-meetingeconomists-aheadbudget_5656861.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Arun Jaitley cancels meeting with economists ahead of Budget]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The 90-minute meeting with the economists on Saturday, ahead of the Budget presentation for 2016-17, was confirmed by Ministry spokesperson who described it as one to explain "economic analysis of macro-economic situation" after the presentation of Economic Survey.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley's meeting with the economists just two days ahead of the Budget, which had generated a lot of curiosity, has been cancelled.</p>
<p>The 90-minute meeting with the economists on Saturday, ahead of the Budget presentation for 2016-17, was confirmed by Ministry spokesperson who described it as one to explain "economic analysis of macro-economic situation" after the presentation of Economic Survey.</p>
<p>The meeting generated a lot of curiosity with some commentators saying Jaitley might be meeting economists to get a grip on some quick-fix measures to package a bitter pill for the economy.</p>
<p>Later in the day, the spokesperson said the meeting with economists and financial experts has been called off due to pressing engagements of the Finance Minister.</p>
<p>Besides Jaitley, Minister of State for Finance Jayant Sinha and other senior officials of the finance ministry were scheduled to attend the meeting with economists.</p>
<p>The spokesperson had earlier in the day said: "CEA may brief the participants about the economic situation both global and domestic and may also brief about the economic analysis of micro and macro-economic situation made in the Economic Survey 2015-16 and the likely state of economy in the coming year and the steps to deal with the same".</p>
<p>Jaitley had met economists as part of pre-Budget meetings in January. During that round, he had also met industry captains, bankers, farmers and trade union representatives.</p>
<p>The economic survey is prepared by the Chief Economic Advisor.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/Arun_Jaitley_Budget_2016_budget2016_356x200_1950_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 08:26:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>