<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/budget-2016-sensex-nifty-open-flat-following-global-cues-sbi-up_5678381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Sensex, Nifty open flat following global cues; SBI up]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Sensex is soon down 41.01 points or 0.2 percent at 23113.29, and the Nifty is down 18.55 points or 0.3 percent at 7011.20.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /><br /></strong></strong>The market has opened in green but quickly slips into red on crucial Budget day. The Sensex is up 67.00 points or 0.3 percent&nbsp;at 23221.30, and the Nifty is up 20.70 points or 0.3 percent&nbsp;at 7050.45. About 304 shares have advanced, 95 shares declined, and 43 shares are unchanged. The Sensex is soon down 41.01 points or 0.2 percent at 23113.29, and the Nifty is down 18.55 points or 0.3 percent&nbsp;at 7011.20.<br /><br />Coal India, SBI, ONGC, Axis Bank, GAIL are top gainers while Cipla, ITC, BHEL, Lupin and Asian Ports are losers in the Sensex.<br />
<p>As Finance Minister Arun Jaitley presents Union Budget today, the market will focus on credibility of numbers. Investors will be keen to know if the govt deviates from the fiscal consolidation roadmap in order to boost growth. The other big fear the market has is the possible extension of the long term capital gains tax tenure from 1 to 3 years or the possibility of reintroduction of a tax itself.</p>
<p>The Indian rupee opened lower by 9 paise at 68.69 per dollar on Monday versus 68.60 Friday. Chief Economic Advisor Arvind Subramanian said there is more scope for lowering of interest rates by the RBI as inflation is under control.</p>
<p>"There is scope for easing monetary policy in two ways, one to inject liquidity to bring it in line with the current policy rate and second is given our inflation projections and assessment going forward, perhaps there is more scope for easing the policy rates as well," he said.</p>
<p>Chinese markets tumbled at the opening, but other markets in Asia were mixed by mid-morning, with Japan extending its gains from the previous week. Analysts expect some rocky trading this week amid a deluge of economic data in the region.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Sensex_Budget2016_nifty_bse_nse_stockmarkets_jaitley_FM_finance_Down__356x200_5038_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 09:15:11</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>