<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/infra-doesn’t-need-reformstweakingregulations-srei_5601641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Infra doesn’t need reforms, but tweaking of regulations: SREI]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Speaking to CNBC-TV18, Hemant Kanoria, Chairman & MD of SREI Infra says while various issues plague the sector, infrastructure space does not need new reforms, but tweaking of existing regulations.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Infrastructure, with lack of funding, slow clearances and pending disputes, is expected to be one of the main sectors on government&rsquo;s radar for the upcoming Budget. <br /><br />While various issues plague the sector, infrastructure space does not need new reforms, but tweaking of existing regulations, says Hemant Kanoria, Chairman &amp; MD of <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-leasinghirepurchase/sreiinfrastructurefinance/SRE02">SREI Infra</a>. <br /><br />The government needs to streamline taxation and make it less complicated, he says. Alongwith this, steps need to be taken to boost the capital debt market, he adds. <br /><br />Kanoria says with the current capital debt system, it becomes difficult for infrastructure companies to raise money. Government needs to bring in provident funds and other money insurances that can devlpo the debt market. <br /><br />The government&rsquo;s National Infrastructure Fund (NIIF), once implemented, will help infrastructure companies to deleverage and raise debt for a longer period. <br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of the interview.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: I want to start by asking you at a time when Budget is around the corner, as an infrastructure major what is your expectation&nbsp; from the Budget? What do you think should be done by the government so as to give a fillip to the overall sector?</strong><br /><br />A: Couple of things which are very important is the streamlining of taxation because till now there are lot of complications on the taxation side. I am not saying that new guidelines have to be brought in but streamlining so it becomes simpler. This has been one of the agendas of this government that they want to remove tax terrorism. That can only be done if you simplify the taxation and specifically you see that income tax officers they disallow expenses arbitrarily. They take notional income and tax on that which is also arbitrary. So, this arbitrariness needs to be removed. I think that will be one step which will be very useful in the Budget if it is announced.<br /><br />Second is on the capital markets. The capital debt market is very shallow. Today if any of the infrastructure projects need to raise money, it is very difficult for them to do that. So, therefore the corporate debt market needs to be promoted and whatever guidelines that are required for simplification, the governments also needs to bring in provident funds and pension funds and other institutional money, insurance companies and all to start investing to develop the corporate debt market. Once they have triggered it off after that I think that there will be no problem for&nbsp; the market to pick it up from there and move forward.<br /><br />The government has already taken a good step, last year they have announced the National Infrastructure Fund. As soon as it gets formed and starts off it would help the companies to a very large extent because what they propose is that they will be in a position to invest in both equity and mezzanine instruments from that particular fund. So, that will help many of the infrastructure companies to deleverage and reduce their debt and also to be in a position to raise more debt for long term if it is required. Once they get deleveraged then they become viable for other people both international and domestic institutions to give them more money on a long term basis.<br /><br />A lot of EPC projects and all have been announced. The government is on track on that. On the reforms I think that infrastructure space and infrastructure sector does not need reforms, it needs streamlining the regulations and wherever certain regulations are missing to introduce them, tweak around, wherever there have been problems - mistake either the private sector has made or the government has made to weak around those particular regulations and correct it.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Any example if you could give?</strong><br /><br />A: One is the infrastructure dispute resolution mechanism, that needs to be set in place because there are lot of disputes which are there and it is inevitable that in the infrastructure sector there would be disputes. How do you very quickly resolve it because otherwise the project suffers. If the cost of the project goes up who I s the ultimate sufferer? It is the ultimate beneficiary which is the public. So, they have to pay higher cost. It is in the interest of the government and all the constituents - financial institutions, government and the infrastructure players to complete the project within the cost and within the timeframe which has been earmarked right upfront.<br /><br />Broadly from the policy framework the government has done a lot but there are many simplistic solutions which are there, that needs to be implemented too.<br /><br /><em>(Interview transcribed by Swapnil Deshpande)</em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/i/Infra_Budget_2016_jaitley_FM_356x200_2321_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 22:09:21</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,SRE,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>