<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/stealth-bears-nowopen-dont-like-banks-shankar-sharma_5443601.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Stealth bears now in open; don't like banks: Shankar Sharma]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["India in particular has been in a bear market grip for the last one year atleast. Market has flattened out, in dollar terms it is down significantly and this qualifies as a bear market without a doubt," says Shankar Sharma of First Global]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>There is no doubt that this is a bear market and anybody who says otherwise is simply deluding himself, says Shankar Sharma of First Global. In fact, he says: "India in particular has been in a bear market grip for the last one year atleast. Market has flattened out, in dollar terms it is down significantly and this qualifies as a bear market without a doubt. The only area in the market which was in a bull market was the small and midcap space," he told CNBC-TV18. Now, the stealth bears are also coming out in the open, he adds.</p>
<p>There can be some degree of a snap back rally even globally, but this is not the bottom yet, he says. From a purely tactical point, on a longer term basis, the markets are headed a lot lower, but won't go down the same way it has been in January and February so far and there will be periodic snap back rallies and those can be good opportunities to make money.</p>
<p><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Shankar Sharma&rsquo;s interview with Anuj Singhal and Ekta Batra on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Anuj: What do you make of the last two weeks or three weeks of market mayhem? Is this similar to 2008 or is there a risk of this being a bit of a bear market? How would you characterise the market over the last two weeks?</strong><br /><br />A: This is no longer a doubt whether it is a bear market or not and anybody who is saying it is not, then I think basically, he is just eluding himself. It is very clearly a bear market and India in particular, has been in a bear market for the last year at least. The markets have flattened out. In dollar terms they are down significantly and that qualifies it as a bear market without any shadow of doubt. The only area in the market which was in a bull market was the small and midcap end of the market, but definitely, the largecaps were already in a bear market in a stealth bear market for at least a year. <br /><br />What you are now seeing is that stealth bear coming out into the open. So, to say that this is going to be over quickly or it is a short-lived bear market, again is going to be proven highly optimistic.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: I remember the last conversation that you had with us where you said that for midcaps, there could still be some hope, but the last round has belonged to severe selling in midcaps and even largish midcaps &ndash; names like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-termlendinginstitutions/powerfinancecorporation/PFC02">PFC</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/finance-termlendinginstitutions/ruralelectrificationcorporation/REC02">REC</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/plantations-teacoffee/tataglobalbeverage/TT">Tata Global's</a> of the world. They have collapsed in trade. InterGlobe has fallen 40 percent. What do you make of the this kind of selling that we have seen in these large names?</strong><br /><br />A: Midcaps are not a one way bet to heaven. As I have always said, it is a very difficult thing to get quality midcap names and then to make serious money in them. Out of 100 stocks you are going to analyse, you might find only 10 and even they are not going to be new to any kind of market prices and usually places where people have made some money are areas where most of the selling happens that we have seen time and again. So, it does not mean that if I like midcaps, midcaps will never fall 30-40 percent. In fact, they are more likely to fall 30-40 percent than a largecap. It is just that on the way back up, they, in my view, will still beat the market or let us say, beat the largecap market. But, they are very volatile animals and you could lose 40-50 percent in the course of a fortnight as we have seen in a number of stocks.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: So, for purely at index level, what is the worst? Do you think we go back to 6,350 the last peak of the previous bull market, or do you think this market has to go much lower to make a durable bottom?</strong><br /><br />A: I do not think it is a bottom yet. It might be a short-term bottom of sorts. Even globally, it could be well be that it might see some degree of a snap back rally. So, the risk is to be short at these levels rather than to be long at these levels at least from a purely tactical perspective. On a longer term basis, markets are headed a lot lower, but they will not be going down the way it has been going down for the entire month of January and February so far. There will be periodic snap back rallies. It can be quite fruitful if you can get them right. They are hard to get right, but if you get them right, you will make some good money. But by and large, the direction that I see the markets headed are definitely towards the lower end rather than the higher end.<br /><br /><strong>Ekta: On that note, how much tougher do you think it is going to get for the banking space?</strong><br /><br />A: I have been negative for quite a while now. I do not like it, because very few banks in the world have made consistent money for investors, very few. By and large, most crisis in emerging markets or developed markets are all precipitated by banks. They are the ultimate culprits of any problem that happens anywhere in the world. It is all because of reckless lending, pressure to show asset growth, lowering credit standards, so I do not like it has a business.<br /><br />Now, within that context, whatever you are seeing within the banking space is confirming what I have always believed that in the good part of a cycle they look great, but show a moderate downturn and all the hidden warts start to come out and that usually give an NPAs of 4-6 percent and those are the official ones. Unofficially the numbers are actually higher. You have virtually no networth left for a number of banks which means big recapitalisations, calls on equity holders - the usual perpetual cycle. So, if you are smart enough to time the up-cycle right, it is a great investment, but if you look at a 10-year period, most banks will never make you money.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: So, what will make money from this point on? As you said, there could be a bit of short covering bounce. Tactically, would it be the beaten down stocks like banking which is going to lead this? Any kind of short covering move or could it be something else?</strong><br /><br />A: It could well be banking. Usually these kind of rallies happen in the trashiest names in the market and right now, there are very few trashier names than the banks. They have become the real estate equivalent of 2008, real estate and infrastructure of 2008. That is where the banking stocks find themselves this year. So yes, in a snap back rally, there could be good places to make a quick buck, but that requires great fleet-footedness, very hard to do, but if you are brave enough, there should be good places to make a good 10-20 percent.<br /><br /><strong>Aunj: The other problem for this market has been that even the erstwhile defensives like IT, pharmaceutical even certain FMCG names have not been able to provide safe haven opportunities. Some of these stocks are down 30 to 40 percent. How do you react to that?</strong><br /><br />A: I said in an interview to Udayan Mukherjee may be a month back or something that this is eerily reminiscent of 2008 and the January of 2016 has been very similar in fact even the February of 2016 is very similar to the one that we saw in 2008. In 2008 nothing really escaped. The fact of the matter is in a brutal bear market that we saw in 2008 and this appears to be something similar to that, there are no hiding places, even in bonds you are going to lose money, even in stocks you are going to lose money. So, it is a tough situation there, very few rooms left to hide in. You just grit your teeth and go through with it. However, to find that you lose less money or be flat or make some money that is probably is going to be very difficult to find. So, FMCG is traditionally a safe haven but in market like this there are no safe havens.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Would it be foolish to expect a pre-Budget rally?</strong><br /><br />A: Unless something is conjured within the next few days I think that is looking remote. However, I think this market may well see the bounce that I see happening, I could be wrong. I was wrong I thought the bounce would happen about a week back but it didn&rsquo;t happen. If it were to happen this is about the time that it can happen and that would obviously be catalysed by the expectations of the Budget as well as may be some degree of global relief rallies. I think we are due for one now.<br /><br /><strong>Ekta: Any expectations specifically from the Budget which could assuage concerns a little bit?</strong><br /><br />A: I don&rsquo;t know I am not a big believer in Budgets changing market directions for any reasonable length of time. They are good for couple of days of gossip and chit-chat and that is it. Nobody&nbsp; then remembers what was there in the Budget a week later. So, I don&rsquo;t think they can directionally change anything.<br /><br />They are set of announcements and that is pretty much it. Ultimately, in India we find that there is a big gap usually between announcements and executions. Markets really pay a bit for announcement but ultimately they are going to pay for execution.<br /><br />What is unfortunate in my view is that the entire oil bonanza has been more or less eaten up by the government rather than it having been shared in equitable fashion with consumers that would have led to some degree of confidence in consumer spending. However, government having used up most of the gains of the oil fall and I find that very hard to sum up.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: Do you think if pump prices were lower by even say, 50 percent, if 50 percent of the benefit was also passed, things could have been different in India compared to what we have seen, the kind of global mayhem that we have seen in equity markets?</strong><br /><br />A: My view has been unequivocal on this. And I say this irrespective of whoever is running the country, whether it is the BJP government or the UPA government. If this had happened in the UPA, I would have said exactly the same thing, that look you cannot take away all the gains that belong, ultimately, to the people of this country. The people of this country need to benefit. Now, you are saying that you are smarter than the people of the country in spending that money that has come to you as a windfall. I do not buy that. I think the government is the stupidest spender, the stupidest savers across the world, of any capital. They will almost always make poor investment decisions or spending decisions.<br /><br />So, I am not saying that give us every bit of the gain that accrue to you, but give us 50 percent, give us 60 percent, you decide on the 40 percent, but do not treat me like a school kid or an idiot who has no clue how to spend the money. This is what I find unacceptable that the governments treat citizens of the country like kids that you do not know, I know better than you. Give me the money, I will take this money and I will spend on great programmes that will make you richer. So, I give you 30 percent, you keep 30 percent, 70-60 percent pass on to the people. That would have really helped consumer confidence and spending.<br /><br />I will tell you one more thing, the problem is, in economics like a rate-cut or a tax-cut or a stimulus of this kind, unless it is done at the right time, if you wake up six months later and do that, then the budget or the bill or the cost required is actually twice as much, because then it has then slid further down in that intervening six months period. So, same shot will not work six months down the road.<br /><br />So, you have to act and act now, if you wait six months then the size of the stimulus you need to give will be actually a lot higher than what was required today.<br /><br /><strong>Anuj: So, what is your advice? Save capital, preserve capital? Will we get much better levels to buy if this is indeed a repeat of 2008?</strong><br /><br />A: Yes and no in the sense that I do not think largecaps offer any great value yet. In my view, a number of smallcaps falling 40-60 percent, numbers have been quite good for a number of them. I would be out there buying them without any doubt. Stocks normally do not go to zero unless there is a scam or a fraud or a huge debt. So, many of them have fallen without any of these three problems. I think it is a good time to be buying those.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/s/sensex_nifty_bse_356x200_3115_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-12 16:07:50</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,PFC02,REC02,TT,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>