<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/more-spectrum-rjio-entry-may-erode-telecos-margins-crisil_5627521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[More spectrum, RJio entry may erode telecos margins: CRISIL]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[As RJio enters the market and more spectrum is auctioned in 2016-17, CRISIL Research believes margins will erode by 180 bps.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong><em>Below is the state of telecom industry as per CRISIL Research</em><br /><br />Data traffic to spur revenue growth; 4G face-off, high spectrum payouts to keep returns subdued<br /></strong> <br />India&rsquo;s mobile telephony industry revenues grew 10-11% in 2015-16, led by higher data traffic (70% year-on-year for major telecom operators). Healthy growth in data volumes and data subscribers &ndash; spurred by increasing adoption of 3G and 4G services &ndash; will lift revenue growth to 11-12% in 2016-17.<br /><br />To counter Reliance Jio Infocomm&rsquo;s (RJio) entry (expected commercial launch in March-April 2016) into the sector, leading operators have advanced their 4G launches and are already offering 4G services in many circles.<br /><br />Operators scrambling to grab high-usage, service-focused data subscribers will set off a tariff war but prices are unlikely to fall more than 20% from current levels.<br />Higher costs stemming from 4G rollouts and heavy marketing expenses have kept margins flat in 2015-16. However, as RJio enters the market and more spectrum is auctioned in 2016-17, CRISIL Research believes margins will erode by 180 bps.<br /><br /><strong>Next round of spectrum auctions to put pressure on already leveraged balance sheets of operators</strong><br /><br />The next round of spectrum auctions, expected in the next 4-5 months, will put additional pressure on the already stressed balance sheets of operators (total debt for the sector was Rs 3 trillion as of March 2015).<br /><br />Total capex over the past four years until 2015-16 is Rs 1.7 trillion; this is expected to increase to Rs. 3.2 trillion over the next 4 years. If operators additionally bid for 700MHz spectrum band, capex will further rise from these levels.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/c/CRISILLOGO_2_356_1907_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-24 16:00:35</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>