<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-scrappage-policythe-offing_5368961.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Scrappage policy in the offing]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[A '265-page document' to facilitate the scrapping of old vehicles has secured Cabinet approval and is expected to be announced in the upcoming Budget]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Budget 2016 is likely to see major announcements in pursuit of cleaner air. CNBC-TV18 learns that one of these announcements could be the country's first ever scrappage policy, to incentivise the Indian car-owner to give up old cars for newer and cleaner models.</p>
<p>Road and transport minister Nitin Gadkari is all about making rhetoric reality. Especially when it comes to promises like this one on a national scrappage policy.</p>
<p>Gadkari says: "Within a month, I will go to the Cabinet. We are already in the process, we are working on it and after the approval by the Cabinet, we will declare the policies."</p>
<p>Less than a month after this interaction, a '265 page document' to facilitate the scrapping of old vehicles has secured Cabinet approval and is expected to be announced in the upcoming Budget. This will be the country's first-ever scrappage policy, and going by Gadkari's earlier promise, will offer incentives for people who want to give up vehicles that are over 10 years.</p>
<p>Gadkari had said: "Anyone who surrenders his old car to the factory where he will get a certificate and if he can get that certificate to where he purchased the new vehicle from, he will get a Rs 25,000-30,000 discount. We are going to recommend it to the finance ministry."</p>
<p>The finer details of the policy are still under consideration.</p>
<p>But initial estimates show that if implemented, the Rs 30,000 discount the minister is talking about will cost the exchequer Rs 20,000 crore.</p>
<p>In addition, the policy proposes that the government give up a portion of the excise duty by offering a rebate of up to 50 percent to anyone who scraps an old vehicle to buy a new one. This could further skew the government's math.</p>
<p>Some of the other aspects of this policy include: <br />- An easier de-registration process to expedite turning in old cars.<br />- A roadmap for recycling of core material used in vehicle manufacturing</p>
<p>Of course, this policy will be a welcome one for the auto industry, which has been struggling with weak demand.</p>
<p>But it's not just the automobile industry that will get a new lease of life from this end of life policy.</p>
<p>Metal Scrap and Trading Corporation, for instance, is all ready to set up India's first-ever scrapping and shedding centre. A centre that's currently one year, Rs 120 crore, and a few incentives away from completion.</p>
<p>SK Tripathi, CMD, Metal Scrapping &amp; Trading Corp, says: "We are ready with the feasibility report, we are ready with the DPR and we also have bill of quantities ready. We are only waiting for some incentives to come so that feed stock for the shedding plant, which is the end of life vehicles and contempt good, etc., are available in adequate quantities, so that my shedding plant runs without any problems.</p>
<p>This centre will provide the certificate vehicle owners need to avail a discount on a new car. However, while the scrappage policy is aimed at bringing down vehicular pollution, while giving automobile and automobile-related sectors a boost, the fact that vehicle exchange is largely voluntary could dilute its effectiveness.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/a/auto_1_0608_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-08 22:07:28</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>