<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/india-needs-to-improve-fiscal-deficit-for-ratings-upgrade_5700721.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA['India needs to improve fiscal deficit for ratings upgrade']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The country's debt to GDP ratio falling to below 60 percent would bring a "clear upside" to the sovereign ratings, Curry said. It currently stands at 67 percent.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>India needs to lower its debt to GDP ratio and materially lower its fiscal deficit for a ratings upgrade, Kyran Curry, S&amp;P director, sovereign ratings in Asia, told Reuters after the federal budget was announced earlier on Monday.</p>
<p>The country's debt to GDP ratio falling to below 60 percent would bring a "clear upside" to the sovereign ratings, Curry said. It currently stands at 67 percent.</p>
<p>"We will really be looking for material gains in the government stabilising its fiscal position. So that basically means a lower fiscal deficit and material falls in its debt stock and we are not seeing that in this budget," Curry told Reuters over phone from Singapore.</p>
<p>"We are just seeing continuing a very, very slow pace in its (government's) consolidation path. And that if anything, delays a ratings rise," Curry added.</p>
<p>S&amp;P retained its sovereign rating on India at BBB-minus with a "stable" outlook saying a ratings upgrade was unlikely until next year, in a statement issued earlier today.</p>
<p>However, the next ratings move for India's sovereign credit profile would be upward, Curry said.</p>
<p>Despite hefty commitments on rural welfare and health, Finance Minister Arun Jaitley managed to stick to his fiscal deficit target of 3.5 percent of gross domestic product for the 2016/17 fiscal year that starts on April 1.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/2/2016-02-29T112303Z_1_LYNXNPEC1S0T3_RTROPTP_2_INDIA-BUDGET_356.JPG]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 17:18:30</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>