<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/india-unveils-pro-poor-budget-keeps-deficit-target_5692461.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[India unveils pro-poor Budget, keeps deficit target]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Indian Finance Minister Arun Jaitley unveiled a Budget for the poor on Monday, announcing new rural aid and health programmes in a strategy shift that could boost his ruling party in coming state elections.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Indian Finance Minister Arun Jaitley unveiled a Budget for the poor on Monday, announcing new rural aid and health programmes in a strategy shift that could boost his ruling party in coming state elections.</p>
<p>Presenting his third Budget, Jaitley reiterated a forecast that it would grow by 7.6 percent in the fiscal year that is drawing to a close. But he said the government wanted to ensure that the benefits of growth were more widely shared among India's 1.3 billion people, but that he would stick to the government's existing fiscal deficit target for the coming year.</p>
<p>"We have a shared responsibility to spend prudently and wisely for the people, especially for the poor and downtrodden," the 63-year-old finance minister said in his opening remarks to lawmakers.</p>
<p>Here are the highlights of Jaitley's Budget for the fiscal year</p>
<p>that begins on April 1.</p>
<p><strong>FISCAL DEFICIT</strong></p>
<p>* Fiscal deficit seen at 3.9 percent of GDP in 2015/16.</p>
<p>* Fiscal deficit seen at 3.5 percent of GDP in 2016/17.</p>
<p>* Plan expenditure seen at 5.5 trillion rupees in 2016/17.</p>
<p>* Proposes to set up panel to review fiscal responsibility management act.</p>
<strong>RURAL ECONOMY</strong>
<p>* Rural jobs programme allocated 385 billion rupees (USD 5.61 billion) in 2016/17.</p>
<p>* Farmer welfare Budget in 2016/17 to total 359.84 billion rupees.</p>
<p>* Rural road development to get 190 billion rupees in 2016/17.</p>
<p>* Target of agriculture credit at 9 trillion rupees in 2016/17.</p>
<p>* Interest subvention towards farm loans in 2016/17 at 150 billion rupees.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong>POLICY REFORMS</strong></p>
<p>* Bankruptcy code for financial firms to be introduced in parliament in 2016/17.</p>
<p>* RBI act is being amended for implementing monetary policy framework.</p>
<p>* To list general insurances companies on stock exchanges.</p>
<p><strong>BANKING REFORMS</strong></p>
<p>* Government to infuse 250 billion rupees capital into state-run banks in 2016/17; will find resources for additional capital for banks if required.<br /><strong><br />TAXATION</strong></p>
<p>* Will not resort to retrospective taxation in future; one time tax dispute resolution proposed for retrospective taxation.</p>
<p>* To rationalise corporate tax for new manufacturing companies.</p>
<p>* To implement general anti avoidance tax rule from April 1, 2017.</p>
<p>* Security transaction tax on options raised to 0.05 percent.</p>
<p>* Proposes to levy infrastructure cess of 1-4 percent on certain models of cars.</p>
<p>* Raises factory gate tax on various tobacco products by 10-15 percent.</p>
<p>* Proposes limited compliance window on undeclared income of domestic tax payers.</p>
<p>* Proposes new dispute resolution scheme to resolve tax disputes.</p>
<p>* Proposes to abolish 13 different levies.<br /><strong><br />BORROWING</strong></p>
<p>* Gross market borrowing seen at 6 trillon rupees for 2016/17.</p>
<p><strong>INFRASTRUCTURE</strong></p>
<p>* Allocates 2.21 trillion rupees for infrastructure development for 2016/17.</p>
<p>* Allocation for roads and highways development at 550 billion rupees.</p>
<p>* Capital expenditure on roads and rail development at 2.18 trillion rupees.</p>
<p><strong>INVESTMENT</strong></p>
<p>* 100 percent foreign direct investment to be allowed in food processing industry.</p>
<p>* Promises further reforms in foreign direct investment policy in insurance, pension, asset recast companies.</p>
<p><strong>DIVESTMENT</strong></p>
<p>* To encourage central public enterprises to divest own assets for raising resources for new projects.<br /><br /></p>
<p><strong>MARKET REACTION</strong></p>
<p>* India's benchmark 10-year bond yield falls 5-6 bps as Jaitley sets 2016/17 fiscal deficit target at 3.5 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>* India's state-owned banks shares pare gains after Jaitley announces lower-than-expected capital infusion; SBI down 0.5 percent.</p>
<p>* Indian rupee gains sharply to 68.61/dollar from around 68.70 levels on 2016/17 fiscal deficit target.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Arun_Jaitley_budget_FM_budget_Finance_356x200_4344_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 11:44:34</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>