<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-removaltax-incentives-–expectationindustry_5485041.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Removal of tax incentives –Expectation from industry]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Union Budget 2016 should introduce some measures that should offset the deductions which will be withdrawn. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Sandip Mukherjee</strong></em><br /><br />As Finance Minister (&lsquo;FM&rsquo;) gears up to present Union Budget 2016 on 29 February 2016, the expectations from the industry are sky high. Given the recent developments of slowing economy of China and the reduction in global oil prices, it is expected that the FM will focus on propelling the economic growth of our country. The FM, in his previous Budget had announced that corporate tax rate would be reduced from existing 30% to 25% with corresponding withdrawal of exemptions over next 4 years. As per the press release issued in November 2015, it is proposed to phase out profit linked, investment linked, weighted and area based deductions latest by March 31, 2017. Given the current economic scenario and the push for &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo;, such phasing out of deductions has caused a lot of heartburn in the industry and they are looking forward to some relief in the forthcoming Union Budget. <br /><br />The manufacturing industry which needs support to compete in the global market would welcome the reduction or removal of Minimum Alternative Tax (&lsquo;MAT&rsquo;) in line with reduction in corporate tax rate. It will be interesting to know what plans the FM has for the Special Economic Zones (&lsquo;SEZ&rsquo;) which has lost its attractiveness due to phasing out of the income tax deduction under Section 10AA. The existing unit holders would welcome the FM&rsquo;s proposal if he allows units in SEZ to sell in the domestic market without levy of custom duty as an offset to the withdrawal of exemption. This could boost the Government&rsquo;s policy of &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo; without any additional infrastructure need and may also act as an impetus to the existing manufacturing SEZ units. Another area which could boost &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo; is incentives for the entities engaged in scientific research and development especially since the FM plans to phase out the weighted deduction these entities enjoyed. The &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo; project would require infrastructure push and a lot of funding. The FM could consider increasing the 80C limit to a higher amount (say INR 5 lakh), which could help generate long term money for infrastructure projects. <br /><br />The proposed exemptions for the start-ups under Start-up India plan will provide support for Digital India initiatives. Access to internet connectivity in rural areas will boost the economic and domestic spending of the country as more citizens will be able to access e-commerce sites. This will provide much needed growth to the e-commerce sector. Recently the government announced the list of 20 cities selected under the &lsquo;Smart City&rsquo; initiative. It will be interesting to know how the Government intends develop Smart cities especially since the area based deductions will be phased out by March 31, 2017. The FM should look at introducing deductions like &lsquo;Investment allowance&rsquo; for industries investing in these smart cities. This could ease the pressure on the government as it will share the onus to develop the smart city with the industry.<br /><br />In general, the industry is expecting measures, which can offset the deductions proposed to be phased out, help boost the economy and ease the process of doing business in India. <br /><br /><em><strong>Author is Partner-Direct Tax, PwC India</strong></em><br /><br /><em><strong>(With inputs from Rahul Charkha)</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/budget_20161_356X200_2836_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-15 19:39:16</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>