<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/union-budget-2016-17-market-will-soon-find-something-to-cheer-says-damani_5692401.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2016-17: Market will soon find something to cheer, says Damani]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Ramesh Damani, Member, BSE said the market will surely find something to cheer soon and believes that the Finance Minister has chosen wisely by imposing STT and dividend distribution tax instead of tinkering with long-term capital gains tax.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Ramesh Damani, Member, BSE said the market will surely find something to cheer soon and believes that the Finance Minister has chosen wisely by imposing STT and dividend distribution tax instead of tinkering with long-term capital gains tax and has also kept sales tax stable.<br />
<p>Damani is not too disappointed with Rs 36,000 core disinvestment target because one has grown to expect the government not meeting the target for all these years but would be happy if they reach the target.</p>
<em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Ramesh Damani's interview with&nbsp;Udayan Mukherjee&nbsp;&amp; Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em>
<p><strong>Udayan: We spoke about dividend distribution tax. You were of the view that it should not come in, would not come in. This Securities Transactions Tax (STT) and dividend distribution tax, does it disappoint you and sort of tarnish the mood on what otherwise would have been a run of the mill Budget?</strong></p>
<p>A: I think the finance minister (FM) choose wisely, of course you can keep taxing something from various angles but given the tradeoffs that he was doing between long-term capital gains (LTCG) and dividend distribution, I think he made the wise choice. However, more importantly, it's an event out of the way. He has kept service tax also stable, so market will find good reason to cheer ultimately.</p>
<p><strong>Udayan: You had a yoyo kind of a market; first down 200 Nifty points and now off 50 Nifty points. How is the cookie going to finally crumble by the end of the day?</strong></p>
<p>A: As I said it's an event out of the way. However, what I am heartened about is that the Nifty made a panic bottom at around 6,900, it tested that a few days ago and it again it tested today and it found support. At some point this will an effective intermediate bottom for the market and we should head higher.</p>
<p>The hypothesis that I am operating on, suggests that we are have a world growing at 1 percent or 2 percent; you grow at 7 percent. When there are negative interest rates, the Dow is yielding 3 percent, suggests that people will have a relook at equities. I think the funk in equities has been far too pronounced and far too long and given the fact that we bounced off these lows, gives me some encouragement that perhaps we made an intermediate bottom today.</p>
<p><strong>Udayan: You were talking about second marriages this morning on the issue of divestment. Last year the target was Rs 70,000 crore, this year the target is Rs 36,000 crore and no mention of strategic sales as such other than the banking universe. Are you disappointed?</strong></p>
<p>A: Not really because we have grown to expect the government not meeting his divestment target. To me it would be, take <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/telecommunications-service/mahanagartelephonenigam/MTN">Mahanagar Telephone Nigam</a> (MTNL), put it on the block -- look at our investment in the education has paid off, the Indian Institutes of Technology (IIT) and Indian Institute of Management (IIM), the kind of business process outsourcing (BPO) and technology industry that has been created by initial investment into education. So if you take some of these public sector undertaking (PSUs) and transform the money or the resources into education that we better spend but some of the thinking doesn't permeate Delhi, so disappointed yes, but that was around expected lines.</p>
<p><em><strong>For entire interview, watch accompanying video.</strong></em></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/BUDGET2016_Finance_minister_Arun_jaitley_FM_356x200_0725_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 13:16:18</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,MTN,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>