<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/suresh-prabhu-to-present-his-second-rail-budget-today_5639021.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Suresh Prabhu to present his second Rail Budget today]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[While the Union Railway Minister is likely to announce special trains with higher fares, a new catering policy with focus on e-catering could also be announced.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>All eyes are on Union Railways Minister Suresh Prabhu, who is set to present his second railway Budget on Thursday.</p>
<p>While the Union Railway Minister is likely to announce special trains with higher fares, a new catering policy with focus on e-catering could also be announced.</p>
<p>Apart from these, Mumbai is expected to get air conditioned suburban trains.</p>
<p>Prabhu is also expected to make an announcement on green stations besides addition of new bogies in Express and fast trains.</p>
<p>A new advertising policy to increase revenue is also likely while a reduction in freight rates is also expected.</p>
<p>While falling revenues and increasing demand for funding various capacity augmentation projects demand a hike in passenger fares, the government may be wary of it with elections round the corner in four states.</p>
<p>The cross-subsidy from freight to passenger operation has crossed Rs 30,000 crore this year while the Seventh Pay Commission burden is about Rs 32,000 crore.</p>
<p>Sources said the minister is likely to announce a new catering policy in his speech with special focus on e-catering.</p>
<p>Despite the grim economic condition, the Railway Budget is expected to increase capital expenditure to enable massive capacity creation.</p>
<p>Focus will be on safety upgradation, electrification and doubling to clear traffic bottlenecks, sources said.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Railways_rail__356x200_1230_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 09:22:45</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>