<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/budget-2016-hope-government-increases-spendrd-says-bajajs-ravikumar_5587061.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Hope government increases spend on R&D, says Bajaj's Ravikumar]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[S Ravikumar, President Business Development at Bajaj Auto says, factors like simplicity, transparency and consistency in policies are critical in making the economy stand out globally]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>S Ravikumar, President Business Development at <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-23wheelers/bajajauto/BA10">Bajaj Auto</a> wishes the government would focus on research and development spending and facilitating rupee trade for exporters, in the upcoming Budget.</p>
<p>Government should methodically figure out where rupee trade is possible as availability of dollars is a major problem faced by exporters like us, he says. &nbsp;</p>
<p>In an interview to CNBC-TV18, on his pre-Budget wish list, Ravikumar says factors like simplicity, transparency and consistency in policies are critical in making the economy stand out globally.</p>
<p>He believes India is fundamentally much better placed than others and speed of execution by government in taking up key initiatives, would be critical.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of S Ravikumar's interview with Latha Venkatesh &amp; Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Sonia: The brass tax question on what is your expectation from the Budget and how do you think the government will be able to spur demand especially for the auto sector?</strong><br /><br />A: I will take it to a slightly larger format. I will address this question in two parts. You will find first part a bit philosophical. Second, I will come on brass tax issue.<br /><br />India, we are in a nice situation as a country today. There is a window of opportunity. History gives these types of opportunities not so often and we are well placed to take this opportunity forward. <br /><br />We have troubles all over the place. China is in a particular mode, so that is the opportunity. In this scenario without missing this window of opportunity, what the government should focus is on speed of the execution because in this place we should get our act very fast and we should capitalise on that. I think the government is at it and I would reemphasise that speed of execution. This in-turn requires our philosophy of three-legged stool, things have got to be simple; simplicity automatically gets in a lot of advantages and with that simplicity you have to be transparent, so that the world knows what everything is about and you have to be consistent.<br /><br />If these three things are practiced methodically by the government then foreign dollars will start flowing in at a much greater speed, the Indian economy will start moving at a fast pace. This is philosophical but of course the downside of it is if you do not do it then things become speculative, speculation leads to complexity, complexity is anti transparency and that is where things will be lost. Therefore, we will certainly advocate simplicity, transparency and consistency whether it is the tax regime or the retro tax effects and things like that. These are the things which have got to be taken care of.<br /><br />Coming to the specific brass tax, of course there are few issues in the economy like if the macroeconomic factors are falling in place, the demand will spur automatically. If those things are falling in place, foreign dollars will flow in, money that comes in will- the connection economy shows that it will multiple and activity will improve. In the same breath we need good monsoon and that is not in the hands of anybody, it\\'s not in the hands of the government. It\\'s a bit above all of us. We pray to god for a good monsoon this time. However, that said everything else is in the hands of the government whether it is banking or anything else, they should put house in order quickly and we should not get into any shocks whether it is the quota stir etc. These things should be contained and should be managed very well because political or other unrest or instabilities again anti foreign investment etc - that\\'s why it is on the larger front. <br /><br />Coming specifically to Bajaj Auto; we are exporting almost about 45-50 percent of our produce and we are a global company. One thing which the government can look at, at this juncture is where all rupee trade is possible. It has worked very well with Russia; it has worked very well with Iran. Many countries where the demand is intact, where the requirement of the product is very much intact, this interposition of the dollar in the trade, it is not my currency, it is not the importing country\\'s currency, this creates -- pricing and dollar impacts are there, those things can be managed but availability of dollar itself is becoming a question in some places, in fact in many places. So the government can very methodically look at where all rupee trade is possible and if they can facilitate that - that will be great.<br /><br />We saw the finance minister talking about simplifying the tax structure, reducing it to 25 percent and simultaneously moving all the exemptions and incentives and all that. It\\'s a fantastic direction, it should get speeded up. My only request in that area is remove all the exemptions, absolutely okay, no problem, remove incentives, absolutely okay, no problems but as a country, as a culture there is a large gap in research and development (R&amp;D) in development. In this area continue to facilitate, just we have miles and miles to go in that aspect. These are our specific points.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/b/bajaj_auto_356_5409_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-22 10:37:45</Entry_Date><Category>Business</Category><sc_id>,BA06,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>