<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/may-see-short-term-mkt-painlong-term-outlook-strong-pros_5396881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[May see short-term mkt pain but long-term outlook strong: Pros]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Indian market has been caught in a global storm that has engulfed equities but seasoned analysts are advising that investors should stay the course and not jump out of stocks.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Indian market has been caught in a global storm that has engulfed equities but seasoned analysts are advising that investors should stay the course and not jump out of stocks.</p>
<p>"The Indian economy is fundamentally strong. While we may see panic for the next few months, investors will come back," Edelweiss CEO Rashesh Shah told CNBC-TV18. He added that the market would also take cues from the Union Budget, which the government must ensure is reform-oriented and kickstarts consumption.</p>
<p>Valuations-wise, the Indian market has reverted to its historical average, said Sanjay Mookim of Bank of America-Merrill Lynch. "We expect earnings to grow 12 percent next fiscal, thanks to a modest consumption-led recovery."</p>
<p><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Rashesh Shah &amp; Sanjay Mookim's interview with Latha Venkatesh &amp; Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong><br /><br /><strong>Sonia: The question everyone is asking is when will this pain come to an end? We are not seeing any signs of the selling pressure getting arrested in the global markets. For our own markets, where do you see a floor or a support for the index?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Shah:</strong> It is hard to say a very definite kind of a floor on this because we think for the next at least 2-3 months foreign institutional investor (FII) selling will continue because of the global liquidity issues and the risk off situation that is going on. But, we do believe that around 7,000, there are a lot of investors getting excited again with the valuations. And the fact is India is still the only bright spot. So, I do not think Indian or foreign investors will give up on India and there can be a freefall. <br /><br />So, at a point of time, which I think is around 7,000 what a lot of people indicate, the market and the valuations look interesting. And what it needs also is a couple of months of stabilising, because market is in a freefall right now, a lot of investors who are believing in India will also hold back and wait for stabilisation. So, another 2-3 months, this kind of volatility and pain can go on, but India still fundamentally is strong, so we will get investors coming back.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: If this is, would you lay the door, lay the trigger entirely on global markets? Would for instance, Budget make a difference at all for sentiment here?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Shah:</strong> Budget will make clearly, a huge impact in terms of the confidence of the foreign investors in the India story, because that confidence is already there, but that confidence is not getting as much weightage as what is happening in the global markets. So, if the Budget indicators are strong around reform and growth and government spending and being prudent at the same time, and there are some conflicting counter-balancing issues that they have to manage, but if they do it well, the investors&rsquo; confidence3 will go up a notch. <br /><br />And as I said, once the selling abates and a little bit of stabilisation comes back, we are seeing a lot of long-term investors, pension funds, buy and hold investors are still very interested in India and even the foreign direct investor (FDI) money and private equity (PE) money and all we are seeing, there is a lot of strong interest for the long-term interest to come to India.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: I take your point about the interest in markets if it falls further but the problem I guess is the fact that there is no leadership now from sectors? Banks are under quite a bit of pressure, IT is facing a slowdown we saw Cognizant reduce its guidance, autos are going through a slowdown. So, even if you have the opportunity where do you look for ideas now? </strong><br /><br /><strong>Shah:</strong> I think eventually it has to be an India story kind of trigger, the catalyst will be India story. I don&rsquo;t think the global markets look exciting so export oriented sectors like IT and pharmaceutical may not end up being the leaders because of this global event.<br /><br />I mean everybody is worried that global we are heading for another recession and in this recession globally the policy instruments are not there with the Central Bankers anymore because you are already at either zero interest rate or negative interest rate. <br /><br />So, that global fear will continue to play out. So I would play the more India oriented sectors especially the cyclicals like eventually the banks and financial services.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: What is the sense? What is Bank of America Merrill Lynch&rsquo;s internal view? Are these buy zones, is it basement prices for range of stocks?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> Yes, we do think that there should be limited downside to Indian equities from here on. Of course we are caught in the global contagion and the risk&ndash;off that is happening. However, our base case message is that Indian earnings should start to recover in FY17. <br /><br />In FY16 we have a very tepid growth. Earnings were probably, from an Index perspective grows about 4 and 5 percent. However, we are looking for Index earnings to grow about 12 percent next year. There should be modest recovery. We are talking about consumption led sectors driving that growth rather than investment. <br /><br />In a global environment which is largely weak, India continues to stand out as that one island of growth that we can continue to look at. So, yes I would hazard to say that there should be limited downside from current levels.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: But the problem is not about the earnings growth and when it comes through &ndash; of course, we have been waiting long enough for that, for more than a year or so &ndash; the problem is what if the price correction comes to an end, but there is a long and protracted painful time correction for this market and we do not see recovery in prices any time soon? Do you fear that situation?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> That brings you to the market multiples sort of an argument. Indian multiples are now down to average levels, even after building in lower than consensus growth. So, to give you numbers, people are looking on the bottom-up basis at about 18 percent growth next year. We do not think that happens. Even if you take a very conservative view on earnings, we are at about 12 percent next year. <br /><br />The multiples are at long-term average and therefore, we say that there should not be downside. The risk-off can obviously create that downside which could then bring you into more of a buy territory. But whether there is time correction, whether the Indian market continues to tread water, will depend a lot now on global cues which unfortunately are very difficult to predict. But, if you are a long-term investor, you could start to argue that you are closer to the bottom than away from it.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: We got numbers from Association of Mutual Funds in India (AMFI) indicating that the January inflows were lower, but they were still inflows from retail investors. Do you think this kind of, even white paper headlines that stocks are falling can start affecting that retail investor systematic investment plan (SIP) investor sentiment?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Shah:</strong> On the margin, but what we are hearing and seeing is a lot of retail investors who are through the SIP mode and we are seeing the response of the initial public offering (IPO) market also. It is still fairly strong. So, I do not think the retail confidence is shaken, because there is a belief that this is a global issue and there is no bad India news that has come out or anything is going wrong with India. <br /><br />So, people will get shaken because this kind of freefall volatility does impact on the margin of few investors, but we do not think on the whole that inflows in the mutual find story works. In fact, our estimates still continue to be that for this calendar year, India should see about 80,000-85,000 crore coming in equity mutual funds for the current year which will be a strong positive, and I think that will eventually be the floor that will get created for the market.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: One them that both of you have picked out for us is the improvement in the consumption story that will play out. Even in this earnings season, we have seen some bright spots from the likes of Asian Paints, Marico, all the domestic consumption stories. Is that a space to continue investing into?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> That is something that we have been advising clients on and there are catalysts due that will continue to drive consumption growth in India. Pay Commission, for example, is a very commonly spoken of catalyst which is due next year. <br /><br />Plus, of course, the fact that lending rates should start coming down. You have seen mortgage growth across banks being very robust, retail growth is very strong and that should continue to transmit into the economy. So, yes, we have been advising clients to stay focused on the consumer focused domestic names in the country.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Would you go to any of the financials?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> Clearly, the consumer focused names will obviously continue to do well on the same argument that Indian consumer is looking strong. The question I suppose is more on the stressed assets in the private corporate facing banks. We have argued on our research that many of those banks, and I am prohibited from naming stocks specifically, but many of those banks are beginning to get to valuations where much of the stress is priced in. <br /><br />The risk I suppose is when you start to see the stock price move and when the market starts to look beyond, there is no way to argue that, but on valuations, many of the stocks are at levels where much of the potential stress is already in the share price.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: I just you mention that about Rs 85,000 crore of equity inflows is what you are expecting in this year. But what is the feedback that you have received so far? What about domestic retail investors? Is there any panic from that community and have you seen a lot of or have you heard about a lot of redemption pressures?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Shah:</strong> No, I think in this particular fall, people are still fairly steady in their outlook and a lot of SIPs are still continuing, because the first indication is that SIPs get cancelled and all, which is not happening. So, the SIPs are continuing. A lot of new conversions are slowing down, because in this kind of volatility because people will usually wait and watch and that is why we are seeing a little bit of shrinkage in terms of inflows into mutual funds. <br /><br />But, it is still fairly positive and when we talk to the distributors and the Industrial Supply Association (ISA) and all, there is not sense of real panic. And, given the fact that the real interest rate or positives, there are no other investment alternatives for them. So, coming into financial markets, through mutual funds will continue to be one of the portfolio allocations that households will maintain.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: You were talking about returning to some of the financials, consumer facing and even some of economy facing. Would that include any of the public sector lenders?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim</strong>: Again, I do not want to get into specific names, I am prohibited from mentioning it per se, but I will repeat that the fact that we do argue that many of these banks are beginning to price in on the potential stress. The timing of investment is something that you can debate.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Last year we saw midcaps still standing out and to be fair that Index is still not at its 52 week lows. It is a little distance away that is all. Do you think midcaps will have a place under the sun now or valuations would make 2016 a largecap year? </strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> If you look at the multiples the midcap Index is now trading at a premium to the largecap Index per se. Therefore you could potentially argue that there is some room for a catch-up to happen. However, in India they will always be stories and midcap companies which have specific growth and you cannot argue that you should stay away from all the names. What we have written about is that India continues to be bottom-up stock picking market. It will continue to be that way in my opinion. You are right midcap Index per se is more expensive than the lagecap Index now. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: Is there anything specific that foreign investors are looking for in the Budget that can stem the tide or turn the tide?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> What we have been saying is that the Union Government has limited room to spend into this slowdown, if there is one. The government is looking to cut deficit, nominal tax revenue is slow and there is increase in expenditure on the pay commission there isn&rsquo;t really too much money that the government can spend. <br /><br />Obviously, the measures that the government takes on the tax reform and the potential restructuring around that will have specific impact for companies. However, we have therefore argued that there is little hope of a very rapid investment recovery in the country because the government can&rsquo;t spend out too much and the private sector is unwilling to. Which brings you back to our argument that consumption and consumer focused names are the place to be in the market at the moment. <br /><br /><strong>Sonia: If the Central government does not have too much ability to stimulate the economy in this Budget is that something that the market has already priced in or factored in or will that come as a disappointment once the Budget passes? </strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> It is difficult to say to be honest. If you look at the industrial sector clearly that has underperformed for a while now. Sell side estimates are high but I don&rsquo;t think that many investors are still relying on those at the moment. I don&rsquo;t particularly think that the Budget will therefore be a big catalyst in terms of disappointment. Tax policies, like I said could create some sort of impact on stock. <br /><br /><strong>Latha: So, largely no big pre-Budget rally and no post Budget rally either is your best guess now? </strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> I don&rsquo;t know if I am best placed to argue that but we continue to say that look consumption is the place to be and it is very steady, safe sort of growth place for investors to look at. <br /><br /><strong>Sonia: You said consumption that is one theme that you have harped on anything else that you are advising investors to look at?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> On that, I hope it is the right time and that we mark the bottom but to argue that we have also tried to highlight rural investment because we think governments will be focused on that bottom of the pyramid. We have therefore spoken on the potential for cement demand increase in the country. Therefore you know may be that is the sector that investors could possibly do some work on.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: And pharmaceuticals? </strong><br /><br /><strong>Mookim:</strong> We like the space; our analyst has written many notes on why we think the growth is not over and that many large companies can continue to deliver the growth that we are perhaps been used to. The recent correction may therefore provide some opportunity to get into some select names. So, we do tend to like larger names in pharmaceutical.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/asian_markets_356_3011_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-10 10:26:15</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>