<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/subsidies_4792021.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Subsidies]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Pruning subsidies and reducing leakages have been among the key goals of the NDA government.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Pruning subsidies and reducing leakages have been among the key goals of the NDA government. In order to plug the loopholes, the government has also gone in for Direct Benefit Transfers (DBT). The government hopes to save Rs 15,000 crore in LPG subsidy leakages every year through this.</p>
<p>A large chunk of government expenditure is also on account of food subsidy. India's food subsidies for 2015-16 was estimated at around Rs 1.24 trillion. The government believes food subsidy savings through DBT will be much higher than that for LPG. The government is looking at Aadhaar-enabled cash transfer for food subsidy. The DBT food scheme has already been implemented in Chandigarh. Puducherry and Dadra and Nagar Haveli may soon follow. The government is also taking steps to implement DBT in fertiliser subsidy.</p>
<p>Apart from this, the government has also benefitted from lower crude prices. Chief Economic Adviser (CEA) Arvind Subramanian has said that the government hopes to save around Rs 6,500 crore due to lower crude oil prices.<br /><br />The government has also capped the subsidy payout on kerosene at Rs 12 per litre and domestic cooking gas (LPG) at Rs 18 per kg. Kerosene through public distribution system (PDS) is sold at Rs 14.96 per litre against the actual cost of Rs 29.91.<br /><br />Budget 2015-16 had provided for Rs 22,000 crore towards LPG subsidy and another Rs 8,000 crore on kerosene. This numbers could reduce further this year.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/s/subsidy_356x200_1648_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-08 14:38:46</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>