<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/expect-market-to-remain-volatile-for-3-4-months-antique_5473921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Expect market to remain volatile for 3-4 months: Antique]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Dhirendra Tiwari of Antique Stock Broking believes eventually investment recovery will come through, though it has been delayed. Keeping that in mind, investors need to find stocks that will benefit from investment cycle recovery over the next two years]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>There is a sense that value is emerging to a great extent in many pockets, such as the banking sector or a few of the auto stocks &mdash; a lot of correction has already happened, says Dhirendra Tiwari of Antique Stock Broking. He also believes eventually investment recovery will come through, though it has been delayed. Keeping that in mind, investors need to find stocks that will benefit from investment cycle recovery over the next two years.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Ashish Maheshwari of Antique Stock Broking says as far as the Union Budget is concerned, the market is not looking for micro details. It is infact looking for some kind of a vision statement, with an extremely strong execution policy &mdash; basically pro-business policy moves.</p>
<p>Antique is advising investors to buy quality stocks at attractive valuations, while at the same time expecting the market to remain volatile for the next 3-4 months.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the transcript of Dhirendra Tiwari and Ashish Maheshwari&rsquo;s interview with Latha Venkatesh and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Latha: What is the sense you are getting from foreign institutional investors (FII) and from other investors who are coming in. Is it a sense that now, value has returned?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Tiwari:</strong> Yes, there is of course, some feeling that value is emerging to a great extent in many pockets of the market. So, for example, if you look at the banking sector or a few of the auto stocks also, there is a lot of correction already seen and, given the fact that our overall belief has been that eventually the investment recovery will happen, though it has been delayed by a reasonably long period -- in our opinion and what we believe most foreign investors and local investors are also looking at -- find some of these stocks which are eventually going to benefit from the recovery in the investment cycle over the next two years. So, yes, value is emerging but one should also be aware that there will be obstacles on the way and therefore, one has to find good quality stocks at reasonable price and wait for an investment recovery to happen.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: You have a very impressive line-up of guests that are going to be present at your conference -- Devendra Fadnavis, Deepak Parekh, Yusuf Hamied, Adi Godrej. Now, the next big trigger of course, is what comes through in the Union Budget. I wanted to get a sense from you on what the market is keenly watching out for and what will disappoint the street if it does not come through.</strong><br /><br /><strong>Maheshwari:</strong> More than going down to micro details with regards to the sector, the market is definitely looking at some sort of a vision statement which is backed by an extremely strong execution plan. Crude has been a saviour and fiscal deficit is a number that people would watch.<br /><br />However, it is relatively easier to model that number with the current set of variables, which are now given. Market largely wants pro-policy, pro-business policy, they look at investments, how the government would essentially be cracking them. So, largely a strong vision statement with an extremely strong execution policy and how the markets would essentially benefit from them is what our take is, in terms of what the government should provide into the Budget.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: In any case, it does not look like the global markets are giving you a risk on very soon, even if the risk off has taken a temporary respite. At such times, what are you telling your investors? Where should they be hiding?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Tiwari:</strong> There are two ways to look at it. There is a six month investment horizon and there is one and half years investment horizon. So, we recently came out with the strategy piece where we highlighted 10 stocks where one can hide in the context of the ongoing volatility. Agreed, there will be some problem in the next three to four months because we are having certain issues, which are definitely hurting market sentiments. Of course the delay in the reform process, some of the bills have not been passed. Secondly, there is of course, turmoil in the global markets &ndash; global economy is slowing down. Thirdly, we have a Budget and possible Fed rate hike coming through.<br /><br />So, these are some of the events, which will cap the upside in the market. So, what we have advised people is that if you are looking for India investment for the next one and half year, you should definitely go for good quality stocks which will benefit from investment recovery. Meanwhile, there is a suggestion that one should also be looking at some of the stocks, which will not be impacted by this kind of volatility for the next three to six months.<br /><br />So, this is what exactly we are telling investors that the markets will remain choppy. You have to basically, align your portfolio keeping in mind that near-term valuation will get hurt if we are extremely exposed to cyclicals to say the least but, in the long-term they may play out. But in the meanwhile, you can also look at the stocks from pharmaceutical sectors, consumer sectors and to some extent IT sectors to tide over the near-term volatility. So, this is exactly the position that we have maintained in the last six months.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: One theme that has worked very well in this earnings season is the domestic consumption story. So, whether it is names like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/paintsvarnishes/asianpaints/AP31">Asian Paints</a>, <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/personalcare/marico/M13">Marico</a> or even some of the two-wheeler makers like <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/auto-23wheelers/heromotocorp/HHM">Hero MotoCorp</a>, they have done quite well in this quarter. I noticed that you have a lot of these stocks in your coverage and in your top places to hide. Is this a story that despite valuations, one can get into a couple of these spaces like paints, fast-moving consumer goods (FMCG), etc?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Tiwari:</strong> One has to look at it in the perspective that the names that you mentioned have benefitted from crude fall. Input prices are key driver for earnings for these kinds of companies. The thing is that we are worried that volume growth is not picking up. So, they may be very good defensive plays in the sense that they will maintain 12-18 percent kind of earnings growth in FY17 also, they will not fall to minus 10-20 percent. Therefore they make good investment for the next three-six months that I have mentioned. So, they are good places to hide. Valuations are definitely on the higher side, but the fact is that where valuations are low, you are not seeing earnings recovery as well.<br /><br />So, we have to be very careful and spot on as far as investment recovery happens and then we can probably shift the gear to more cyclicals. Having said that, it is also a reality that even in the investment recovery theme, there have been stocks, which have done pretty well as far as earnings and stock performance is concerned. The only problem is that some of the torch bearers, which are the leaders of the market, as far as investment recovery is concerned, whether it is <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/statebankindia/SBI">State Bank of India</a> (SBI) or <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/infrastructure-general/bharatheavyelectricals/BHE">Bharat Heavy Electricals Ltd</a> (BHEL) or <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/infrastructure-general/larsentoubro/LT">Larsen and Toubro</a> (L&amp;T), they have disappointed and therefore, the whole canvas gets negatively painted.<br /><br />Our point is that, if you go down in that space as well, you will find a Voltas or Siemens, stocks like that which have done reasonably well in the last four to five quarters and they should continue to be pursued on.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Since Dhirendra spoke about SBI and such likes, any thoughts on <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-publicsector/bankofbaroda/BOB">Bank of Baroda</a> (BoB), after you heard the management and the confidence they exuded about not wanting capital? Any thoughts at all, does it put a floor to that stock?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Maheshwari:</strong> Absolutely, when was the last time you heard in this particular result, a particular bank Chairman coming and saying that I do not need money from government. So, very strongly crafted statement, a future vision again, as they say. Valuations -- a market driven by flows can stay away from valuations for a fairly long time and people would look for comfort in terms of somebody coming in and laying down a completely strong strategy and that is what BoB management seems to have definitely done. We will probably be able to provide better inputs in terms of what their strategy going ahead is.<br /><br />Absolutely, I largely think public sector banks so far has been all painted under the same brush. Time has come to segregate one from the other. Competition is going to be intense and there are going to be a few guys who could probably double it from here, while a few could further go down from here.<br /><br />So, one has to stop looking at the entire space as a single trade and start picking names like Bank of Baroda. I would definitely recommend it for a portfolio addition now.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: I wanted to ask you if it also provides a bit of floor to the better banks. If an outsider to the public sector banking system is telling you that it is 9.6 and all the dirt is flushed out, does it put a floor even to the other better quality banking stocks?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Maheshwari:</strong> Today, the problem is, how do I really value these? There are so many unknown unknowns still lying over there. That is why, somebody, when they come in and take the conclusion away, we would start seeing a fair bit of premium. So, these stocks have been beaten down bad, ownerships are extremely low, on futures they are all extremely highly shorted. So, momentary bounces, single days of 8-10 percent returns are definitely possible. But then, unless you have the ability to value a stock, unless you know what is the denominator, how do you say that it is poised for a breakout?<br /><br />So, I would look forward to the bank chairman coming and absolutely putting whatever it is on paper and say, listen, this is what it is and this is how we intend to grow, which Bank of Baroda has so strongly and smartly done. So, I would still wait in terms of trying to figure out which is a substitute to this. I would much rather pick this only.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: I wanted your thoughts on the pharmaceutical space, because you do have GV Prasad, Dr Reddy&rsquo;s, attending you conference as well. This space has been hit a lot with US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) issues, but are you looking for opportunities here or do you think pharmaceuticals should be an underweight now?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Maheshwari:</strong> I largely think these are small speeding tickets in a long race. So, these stocks have all double-trebled over the last many years. As a business model, they all have exhibited a particular level of maturity in growth and they all throw cash, which is phenomenal, which is what Indian market tends to give most value to. So, yes, US FDA has been a big challenge across but then that is the road to maturity. If you look at a stock like Gilead Sciences, which probably worldwide is one of the best performing pharmaceutical stocks, that stock has been more than half the times less than 50 percent of its peak.<br /><br />So, businesses like pharmaceuticals are binary in nature and risks therefore, shall be the same. There are always binary risks in future modelling and volatility of earnings and volatility of stock price would stay but I think it is a largely secular earnings story over here and I will not take any of those names out of my portfolio.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/m/markets_sad_nifty_356x200_0730_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-15 09:32:51</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,API,MI25,HHM,SBI,BHE,LT,BOB,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>