<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/budget-2016-fm-arun-jaitley-offers-tax-sops-for-first-time-home-buyers_5668521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: FM Arun Jaitley offers tax sops for first time home buyers]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The Union Budget 2016 offers an additional tax benefit of Rs 50000 for first time home buyers.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />Finance Minister Arun Jaitley has come to the rescue of those individuals who are yet to buy their first house. In his speech announcing Union Budget 2016, FM offered an additional tax benefit of Rs 50000 on the interest paid on the home loan.<br /><br />As per extant rule for the self occupied property, the home buyer can avail a deduction of Rs 2 lakh towards the interest paid on the home loan. This limit is extended to Rs 2.5 lakh. The benefit however comes with a condition that the house should not be priced at more than Rs 50 lakh and the loan should not be more than Rs 35 lakh. Finance Minister however has not increased the deduction limit for the principal repaid of the home loan availed. Taxpayers have been expecting a hike in deduction on home loan principal repayment by Rs 50000. <br /><br />If you have not bought a house and living in a rented house, and need some time to go for one, do not lose heart. There is a good news for you too. FM has offered to increase the benefit available under section 80GG to Rs 60000 per year as compared to Rs 24000. This is applicable to those who do not own a house and do not get a house rent allowance from the employer. This was a long standing demand by individual tax payers for a long period of time and was fulfilled by Union Budget 2016.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/u/Union_Budget_2016_4_356X200_4101_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 13:39:22</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>