<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/non-financial-cos-to-gainhealthy-gdp-growth-moodys_4991261.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Non-financial cos to gain from healthy GDP growth: Moody's]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[According to the statement, Moody's expects upstream oil and gas companies to benefit from a lower fuel subsidy burden although low crude and domestic natural gas prices will continue to hurt profitability. 
]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Non-financial corporates in India will benefit from a healthy domestic growth and accommodative monetary policy, Moody's Investors Service and its Indian affiliate ICRA Limited today said.<br /><br /> "Most non-financial corporates we rate in India will benefit from a healthy 7.5 percent GDP growth in the country for 2016-17, and a pick-up in manufacturing activity will be broadly supportive of the business growth," a joint statement by Moody's Investors Service and ICRA quoted Moody's V-P and Senior Credit Officer Vikas Halan as saying. <br /><br />"But businesses remain vulnerable to the volatile Indian rupee as against the US dollar." ICRA said it expects corporate performance to be weighed down by over-leveraged large infrastructure groups.</p>
<p>Moody's and ICRA also highlighted the difficulties in implementing high-profile policy changes, including the proposed goods and services tax. "A failure to implement reforms could hamper investment levels in India against the backdrop of a weak global growth," the statement said. <br /><br />According to the statement, Moody's expects upstream oil and gas companies to benefit from a lower fuel subsidy burden although low crude and domestic natural gas prices will continue to hurt profitability.</p>
<p>Refining and marketing companies, meanwhile, should benefit from healthy margins as demand growth outpaces expected capacity addition, it said. For the auto sector, Moody's expects retail sales volume to grow 6 percent in 2016 on the back of sustained growth in passenger vehicles sales and a recovery in commercial vehicle sales.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/m/moodys_5840_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-13 18:39:53</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>