<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-india-rs-132620-cr-allocated-to-ayush-ministry_5712141.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 India: Rs 1,326.20 cr allocated to AYUSH Ministry]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The total allocation, including plan and non-plan head, for Ministry of Ayurveda, Yoga and Naturopathy, Unani, Siddha and Homoeopathy (AYUSH) is Rs 1,326.20, an increase of Rs 201.2 crore than last year's figure of Rs 1,125 crore.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>To give a boost to traditional and alternative medicines, Rs 1,326.20 crore have been allocated to the AYUSH Ministry in the Union Budget.</p>
<p>The total allocation, including plan and non-plan head, for Ministry of Ayurveda, Yoga and Naturopathy, Unani, Siddha and Homoeopathy (AYUSH) is Rs 1,326.20, an increase of Rs 201.2 crore than last year's figure of Rs 1,125 crore.</p>
<p>From the total allocation, Rs 1,050 crore has been given under the plan head and Rs 276.20 crore under the non-plan head.</p>
<p>To support the various AYUSH institutions across the country a total of Rs 266.70 crore has been given while Rs 447.10 crore are allocated for research and development in this field.</p>
<p>To strengthen AYUSH Delivery System which includes provision for development of AYUSH IT Tools, application and networks, pharmacovigilance initiative for ASU drugs, Central Drug Controller for AYUSH and information, education and communication, a sum of Rs 111.45 crore has been allocated.</p>
<p>Under the National Health Mission for AYUSH which includes provision for components of AYUSH services, AYUSH educational institutions, quality control of drugs and medicinal plants, a total of Rs 400 crore has been allocated.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Rupee_up_down_fiscal_deficit_356x200_3409_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 08:08:09</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>