<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/heremanoj-murlidharans-top-trading-ideas_5638761.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Here are Manoj Murlidharan's top trading ideas]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[In an interview to CNBC-TV18, Manoj Murlidharan of Religare Securities, spoke about his readings and outlook on Futures and Options (F&O) side of the market, specific stocks and sectors.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>In an interview to CNBC-TV18, Manoj Murlidharan of Religare Securities, spoke about his readings and outlook on Futures and Options (F&amp;O) side of the market, specific stocks and sectors.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Manoj Murlidharan's interview with Latha Venkatesh and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Latha: Your best guess on where this contract might end and how you will trade the Nifty today?</strong><br /><br />A: Expiries are difficult and needless to say we have a Railway Budget as well today but then looking at the data, what I feel is obviously the first one and a half hours of trade, the option premium at 7,000 Call and Put might start shrinking. The total of Rs 65, you might close to Rs 54 to Rs 55 but I recommend buying 7,000 Call and Put option close to around Rs 50-55 with a stop loss of Rs 20 and I am expecting a target of close to 8,200.<br /><br />Now the rationale here is with all the prevailing open interest (OI) that we have in the index, 7,000 is the highest Put option and we have in the Call option yesterday -- there was good Call writing which has happened in the 7,050 as well as 7,100 strike. I feel the expiry can be closer to 7,050 and expiry of 7,040 to 7,050 is where the maximum money can be earned by the writer. So I guess, there would be an intraday swing so try and buy 7,000 Call and Put option but try to buy it at least at Rs 52-55 so you will get it at Rs 13 lesser than what it closed yesterday, keep a stop loss of Rs 20 and I am expecting a target of Rs 100 on that.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: Stocks specifically what all are you looking at? You have trades in <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/electricequipment/cromptongreaves/CG">Crompton Greaves</a> and in <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/banks-privatesector/indusindbank/IIB">IndusInd Bank</a>?</strong><br /><br />A: We got three trades; first is with <a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/india/stockpricequote/mediaentertainment/tv18broadcast/IBN">TV18</a> that is a buy. This is one script because today we are just working on the concept of volume weighted average price (VWAP), that is a net prevailing open interest to the cash delivery that has happened and we are expecting a follow up buying to come in. So, TV18 for the current month future is a buy, at Rs 35.60 to Rs 36 you can buy that. The stop loss should be Rs 34.30 and we are expecting an expiry close to Rs 38 on that.<br /><br />IndusInd Bank would be a sell because we have seen there is a huge amount of open interest which is scheduled to be rolled in and there is still some cash base selling so we would expect that there might be some VWAP selling throughout the day. Rs 826 is where we recommend you can sell that. Stop loss at Rs 835 and the target should be closed to Rs 812 on that.<br /><br />The third would be Crompton Greaves; it is sell as well at Rs 136, with a stop loss of Rs 140 and target of Rs 129.<br /><br />Ideally, the concept here is there would be volatility intraday but the last 30 minutes of the trade precisely we feel, there would be some short covering which might come in through the Bank Nifty and the Bank Nifty stocks because if you see the rolled cost in the last three-four days is going up from a 28-30 basis points to a good 45 basis points. These are few indications that if we don't make a new low what we did at 68-60, there are chances that we might see the underperformance from banks might stop. Now that might happen over the course of this March contract but we are expecting some short covering to come through banks in the last 30 minutes of trade.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/m/manoj-murlidharan-356_1415_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 09:27:30</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><sc_id>,CG,IIB,GBN,</sc_id><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>