<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-promises-economic-growth-mayur-shah_5700081.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016 promises economic growth: Mayur Shah]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Mayur Shah, Managing Director of Marathon Group is of the view that Finance Minister has presented a Budget that promises economic growth through digitisation, rural and skill development and heavy expenditure on infrastructure.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mayur Shah, Managing Director, Marathon Group </strong><br /><br />"We would like to congratulate the Finance Minister in presenting a Budget that promises economic growth through digitization, rural and skill development and heavy expenditure on infrastructure. The real estate industry welcomes some of the announcements like exemption of dividend distribution tax from Real Estate Investment Trust (REITs). Provisions like 100 percent deduction to undertaking for construction of affordable housing and additional tax deduction on interest paid for loan amount on house less than Rs 50 Lakh is worth appreciating. These measures will boost affordable housing in the Mumbai Metropolitan Region and will at the same time achieve the Prime Ministers dream of Housing for All'. Increase in tax deduction from Rs 24000 to Rs 60000 for those living in rented house will also benefit the housing sector indirectly."</p>
<p>"However, the Finance Minister could have done few more things for the real estate sector that needed attention. Industry status at par with infrastructure for priority lending below 10 percent would have been icing on the cake. Single window clearance scheme were other topics that remained untouched."</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Sensex_Budget2016_nifty_bse_nse_stockmarkets_jaitley_FM_up_356x200_2752_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 17:01:13</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>