<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-unveiled-big-focusrevivalrural-demand_5717441.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA['Budget 2016 unveiled big focus on revival of rural demand']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Budget has unveiled a big focus on revival of rural demand through a carefully drafted focus on the agricultural sector that strives to increase agricultural productivity thereby paving the way for non-inflationary growth over medium term, says Soumya Kanti Ghosh, Chief Economic Adviser & GM, Economic Research Department, SBI.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Soumya Kanti Ghosh, Chief Economic Adviser &amp; GM, Economic Research Department, SBI</strong><br /><br />"The FY17 budget numbers are a positive surprise with Government sticking to the designated fiscal consolidation roadmap. On the back of it, FY17 Budget envisages a nominal GDP growth of 11 percent. Assuming&nbsp;that the Government is projecting a real GDP growth at around 7.4 percent&nbsp;(midpoint between 7-7.75 percent), the inflation rate (based on GDP deflator) turns out to be 3.7 percent. This is significantly higher than the projected&nbsp;GDP deflator at 1 percent for this fiscal, indicating that Government expects a significant traction in demand, particularly from the rural sector, that has seen the maximum push in the Budget.</p>
<p>There are special incentives for the MSME sector in the budget like incentivising the small businessmen. Additionally, we expect that the MUDRA scheme with a scaled up disbursement target at Rs 1,80000&nbsp;crore in FY17 (Rs 70,000 crore in FY16) could provide employment to a significant segment of the population. The Stand Up India Scheme, will ensure coverage of skilled / semi-skilled entrepreneurs&nbsp;in different geographies across the country.</p>
<p>The Budget has however not provided any additional number for bank recapitalisation (over and above Rs 70,000 crores over 4 years) numbers and we expect it to be an ongoing exercise.</p>
<p>To sum up, the Budget has unveiled a big focus on revival of rural demand through a carefully drafted focus on the agricultural sector that strives to increase agricultural productivity thereby paving the way for&nbsp;non-inflationary growth over medium term."</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_SENSEX_BSE_NSE_Stock_Market_up_356x200_2309_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 13:59:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>