<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-17positive-surprise-nomura_5705261.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016-17 a positive surprise: Nomura]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Overall, the budget is a positive surprise, relative to our expectations, says Sonal Verma of Nomura.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Sonal Verma of Nomura:</strong><br /><br />In the union budget presented today, the government chose macro stability over growth, delivering a positive surprise by sticking to its fiscal consolidation roadmap. <br /><br />The government expects to meet its fiscal deficit target of 3.9 percent of GDP in FY16 (year ending March 2016) and maintained its 3.5 percent target for FY17, as proposed last year. This is a positive surprise against market and our expectations of a fiscal slippage (Nomura: 3.7 percent) and also in contrast to the arguments set out in the economic survey. <br /><br />For the medium term, the government has maintained the fiscal deficit target of 3 percent for FY18. However, in his speech the Finance Minister proposed setting up a committee to review the FRBM (Fiscal Responsibility and Budget Management) Act. He stated that it may be prudent to have a fiscal deficit range for the medium term, instead of explicit year-wise targets, in order to create policy space to deal with macroeconomic developments. <br />Other key takeaways from the budget: <br /><br />&bull; <strong>Credibility of the fiscal arithmetic</strong>: We think the fiscal assumptions are optimistic on asset sales, but conservative on tax projections. Disinvestments and strategic sales are pegged at INR565bn (versus INR253bn in FY16), while revenue from the telecom spectrum (under the communication category, which includes past arrears and fresh auction receipts) has been budgeted at INR990bn (versus INR574bn in FY16). We view these as optimistic. However, gross tax revenues have been budgeted to rise only 11.7 percent y-o-y in FY17 versus 17.2 percent in FY16, which could be higher. On nominal GDP, the budget has assumed 11 percent growth in FY17 versus 8.6 percent in FY16, which we think is reasonable. In our view, the revenue target is achievable on an overall basis, with some overshoot on taxes and undershoot on non-tax revenues and asset sales. <br /><br />&bull; <strong>Accounting for pay commission and OROP</strong>: The total outlay on account of the pay commission and the &ldquo;one rank one pension&rdquo; scheme is estimated at Rs 1.1trn. At first glance, the budget seems to have under-budgeted for this, which suggests a staggered implementation of the pay commission&rsquo;s recommendations or greater outlay at a later stage. <br /><br />&bull; <strong>Quality of spend suffers</strong>: The quality of spending has deteriorated given the higher wages and pensions bill and elevated subsidies. Revenue expenditure (running expenses of the government) is budgeted to rise 11.8 percent y-o-y, up from 5.5 percent growth in FY16, while capital expenditure growth is budgeted to slow to 3.9 percent y-o-y from 20.9 percent in FY16, which suggests less budgetary support for capital expenditure and greater reliance on off-budgetary sources. <br /><br />&bull; <strong>Key expenditure announcements</strong>: There were no major steps to rationalise subsidies in the near term, except a plan to move to direct cash transfer to curtail leakages. Subsidies remain elevated at Rs 2.5 trn in FY17 (1.7 percent of GDP), compared with INR2.6trn in FY16 (1.9 percent of GDP). The budget also announced no increase in public sector bank recapitalisation, which has been left unchanged at INR250bn in FY17, lower than expected (Nomura: INR350bn). <br /><br />&bull; <strong>Gross borrowings</strong>: Gross market borrowings are slated to rise to INR6.0trn in FY17 from INR5.85trn in FY16, while net market borrowings are pegged at INR4.25trn, up from INR4.0trn in FY16, lower than expected. <br /><br />&bull;<strong> Key focus areas:</strong> On the reform side, key focus areas were (1) agriculture (irrigation, e-platform for unifying wholesale markets, crop insurance); (2) rural <br />infrastructure and employment (rural roads, RURBAN clusters, rural electrification, subsidised cooking gas to households below the poverty line, higher allocation for rural employment scheme); (3) health (INR0.1mn health cover per family); (4) education and skill creation (Higher Education Financing Agency); (5) infrastructure (higher allocation to roads, modernisation of ports and airports); and (6) financial sector reforms (bankruptcy bill, RBI Act amendment to set up a monetary policy committee, amendments to the SEBI Act to introduce new products in commodity markets). <br /><br />&bull; <strong>Key tax changes</strong>: (1) new tax amnesty scheme to improve tax compliance (45 percent tax on declaring undisclosed income); (2) lowering the corporate tax rate from 30 percent currently to 29 percent for small companies and 25 percent for new manufacturing companies; (3) GAAR implementation from 1 April 2017; (4) long-term capital gains on unlisted companies reduced to two years; and (5) infra cess on car sales. <br /><br /><strong>Our view:</strong><br /><br />Overall, the budget is a positive surprise, relative to our expectations. The commitment to adhere to the stated fiscal deficit targets suggests that the government has chosen to prioritise macro stability over growth. <br /><br />Much of the funding is coming via asset sales (disinvestment, strategic stake sales, telecom spectrum) where market conditions and balance sheet capacity (telecom) will play a key role, but lower tax assumptions suggest that the overall revenue collections are achievable. However, expenditure on account of the seventh pay commission seems to have been under-budgeted, which could lead to higher spending later. <br /><br />Given the government&rsquo;s commitment to fiscal consolidation, we believe that the RBI will perceive the budget as a positive event. Hence, we continue to expect a 25bp repo rate cut in April with a greater chance of an inter-meeting cut.]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_Arun_Jaitley_budget_FM_budget_356x200_4209_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 19:47:00</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>