<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/local-markets/rail-budget-2016-nifty-below-7000-railway-to-set3-freight-corridors_5641401.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Rail Budget 2016: Nifty below 7000; Railway to set up 3 freight corridors]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[HDFC, Sun Pharma, ONGC, Coal India and Hindalco are top gainers, up 1-2 percent while Infosys, TCS, ICICI Bank and Reliance Industries declined 0.5-1 percent.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau<br /><br />12:59 pm: </strong></strong>Railway ministery says Railway will develop national railway plan in consultation with states and this plan will synchronise rail with other modes of transport.<br /><br />It proposes to examine creation of holding company for railway units.<strong><strong><br /><br /></strong></strong>Railway will increase in track laying target to up demand for steel.<strong><strong><br /><br /></strong></strong>Container sector will be open to all select ores.</p>
<p>"We will raise non-tariff revenue by monetising assets going forward and invited FM Radio to provide train borne entertainment by installing PA systems," says Prabhu.<strong><strong><br /><br />Freight policy: </strong></strong>Prabhu says<strong><strong> c</strong></strong>urrent freight tariff policy will be reviewed.</p>
<p>"We will try to evolve a competitive rate structure for freight tariff," he adds.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:58 pm </strong></strong>Railway minister says at least 10 goods sheds will be developed via transloc in FY17 and proposes to develop rail site logistics warehousing.<br /><br />Warehouses will be created via PPP mode, he adds.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:56 pm Prabhu says d</strong></strong>etailed policy on suburban ecosystem is expected in 4 months.<br /><br />"Railway&nbsp;will partner with state government for suburban system in tech hub of Bengaluru and also&nbsp;intend partnering with Gujarat, Telangana, Tamil Nadu for suburban sections.<br /><strong><strong><br />12:55 pm Market Update</strong></strong>: Equity benchmarks remained lower. The Sensex fell 59.65 points to 23029.28 and the Nifty declined 28.25 points to 6990.45.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:54 pm </strong></strong>Railway will install hi-tech centralised network of 20,000 screens on 2000 stations&nbsp;<br /><strong><strong><br />12:51 pm </strong></strong>Railway minister says three direct services, fully airconditioned Humsafar will travel at 130 km per hour.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:49 pm Coach cleaning: Prabhu says </strong></strong>under 'Clean My Coach' passengers can request for coach cleaning via SMS.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:47 pm Women Reservation: </strong></strong>Railway will introduce a sub-quota of 33 percent&nbsp;for women in each of reserved categories.<br /><strong><strong><br />12:45 pm New Express: </strong></strong>Railway introduces Utkrisht Double-Decker Yatri Express, which will increase capacity by 40 percent.<br /><br />It also introduces Antyodaya Express, superfast train for long routes. All operational haults will be converted in commercial haults.<br /><strong><strong><br />12:43 pm Savings:&nbsp;</strong></strong>Railway minister says annualised savings of Rs 3,000 crore will be achieved in FY17 and railway plans to set up a new fund for financing projects.<br /><strong><strong><br />12:42 pm </strong></strong>Railway has entered into partnerships with global institutions to improve operations. Funding by LIC to ease pressure on debt market, Prabhu says.<br /><strong><strong><br />12:41 pm KEC International up 3.5%</strong></strong>: Electrification of 2000 km by Railway is positive for KEC International.<strong><strong><br /></strong></strong><br /><strong>12:40 pm</strong> <strong>Savings:</strong> Railway minister Suresh Prabhu says inventory management led to savings of Rs 64 crore.</p>
<p>He also says Railway University is being set up at Vadodara, Gujarat.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:37 pm </strong>Contracts:</strong> Suresh Prabhu says contracts of Rs 24,000 crore were awarded since November 2014 against Rs 13,000 crore in last 6 years.</p>
<p>All contracts for civil engineering works will be awarded soon, he adds.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:35 pm </strong></strong>Railway generated 65,000 additional berths via augmenting 884 coaches.</p>
<p>"We proposes to invite bids to develop few large stations under PPP model," Prabhu says.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:31 pm Ports: </strong></strong>Railway will set up Margao, Hazira ports in FY17 via public private partnership model.<br /><br />"We will set up 2 locomotive factories at the cost of Rs 40,000 crore," he says, adding FY17 gross budgetary support is seen at Rs 40,000 crore.<br /><strong><strong><br />12:29 pm: Fund raising: </strong></strong>"We will tap rupee bond market overseas to raise funds," <br />Prabhu says.<br /><br />Railway plans FY17 gross traffic revenue at Rs 1.85 lakh crore, up 10 percent YoY.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:25 pm Broad Gauge lines: </strong></strong>Suresh Prabhu says Railway will commission 9 km per day of broad gauge lines in FY18 &amp; 13 km per day in FY19.<br /><br />He also proposes to electrify 2,000 km of railway lines in FY17.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:23 pm Goods earnings target: </strong></strong>Prabhu says FY17 goods earnings target stood at Rs 1.18 lakh crore.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:20 pm Pension spending: </strong></strong>Railway targets FY17 pension spending at Rs 45,500 crore.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:21 pm Freight corridors: </strong></strong>Prabhu proposes to set up 3 freight corridors.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:19 pm Passenger revenue: </strong></strong>Railway targets passenger revenue at Rs 51,012 crore for FY17, up 12.4 percent over a year-ago period.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:18 pm LIC funding to Railway: </strong></strong>LIC has agreed to provide Rs 1.5 lakh crore to Railway for next five years.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:15 pm Capex: </strong></strong>Railway plans FY17 spending at Rs 1.21 lakh crore, up 21 percent compared to previous year.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:12 pm Railway Savings: </strong></strong>Suresh Prabhu expect savings at Rs 8720 croe in FY16.<br /><br /><strong><strong>12:09 pm Operational ratio: </strong></strong>Railway proposes FY17 operating ratio at 92% against 90 percent&nbsp;projected for current fiscal.<strong><strong><br /><br /></strong></strong><strong><strong>12:07 pm Rail Budget speech begins</strong></strong>: Government's vision is to make Railway backbone of India's development by improving quality of service. It should be&nbsp;template for transportation.<br /><br />"We are making all efforts to translate government's vision into realty," says Prabhu.<strong><strong><br /><br />12:05 pm Rail Budget expectations: </strong></strong>Analysts expect 20-25 percent&nbsp;YoY increase in capital outlay for railway for FY17 at Rs 1.25 lakh crore.<br /><br />During FY16, rail minister had promised an aggressive capex plan for the railways from 2015-19 at Rs 8.5 lakh crore. During FY16, the budgeted capital outlay was Rs 1 lakh crore.<br /><br />He targeted operating ratio for 2015-16 at 88.5 percent&nbsp;against 91.8 percent in 2014-15, which is the&nbsp;best in last 9 years.<br /><br />Analysts expect wagon procurement to increase to 18,000 - 19,000 units and also expect&nbsp;healthy improvement in allocation towards DFC (dedicated freight corridor).</p>
<p>Stocks lik Titagarh Wagons, Texmaco, Kalindee Rail, Siemens, ABB, CIMMCO, Stone India and BEML will be closely watched.<strong><br /><br />12:00 pm Market Check</strong><br /><br />The market remained rangebound in noon trade as the Railway Minister Suresh Prabhu will present his second Rail Budget now. The&nbsp;Sensex fell 23.38 points to 23065.55 and the Nifty declined 13.40 points to 7005.30.<br /><br />HDFC, Sun Pharma, ONGC, Coal India and Hindalco are top gainers, up 1-2 percent while Infosys, TCS, ICICI Bank and Reliance Industries declined 0.5-1 percent.<br /><br /><br /><br /><br /></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/r/Railway_BUDGET2016_Rail_BSE_Sensex_nse_stock_market_dalal_street_356x200_5855_356.png]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 12:00:39</Entry_Date><Category>Local Markets</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>