<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/want-to-see-investment-lift-off-35-fiscal-deficit-imp-ubs_5658401.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Want to see investment lift-off; 3.5% fiscal deficit imp: UBS]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[There is a need for investment lift-off and for that to happen, the government will have to mobilise the savings in the economy and make it available to the private sector, says Edward Teather, senior economist Asean & India of UBS Investment Bank]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Maintaining fiscal deficit at 3.5 percent of GDP is very important for the Indian economy, says Edward Teather, senior economist Asean &amp; India of UBS Investment Bank. The current structure is such that the pressure of the 7th Pay Commission is much higher on the states rather than the Centre. In such a scenario, the Centre has to show the way forward, he says.</p>
<p>However, there is also a need for investment lift-off and for that to happen, the government will have to mobilise the savings in the economy and make it available to the private sector, says Teather. He believes constraining consumption is the need of the hour.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Vivek Rajpal, rates strategist at Nomura India, says a 3.5 percent number will provide relief to the bond markets. A combination&nbsp; of 3.5 percent fiscal deficit, open market operations (OMO) and an interest&nbsp;rate cut by the Reserve Bank will ensure that bond rates move closer to the 7.6 percent level.<br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Edward Teather and Vivek Rajpal's interview with Latha Venkatesh and Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Latha: The 3.5 percent deficit is going to be adhered to, would you say that is a lot of good news that will make you welcome the Budget?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Teather:</strong> I think that is important. It is good news. Raghuram Rajan has highlighted that India needs to reduce its fiscal deficit and the Central government needs to lead the way with that because the pressure from the Pay Commission is much higher on the state government. So if you want to get the centre and state government deficit lower, you need to see the central government leading the way and that is what 3.5 percent gross domestic product (GDP) deficit target for FY17 would suggest. We would welcome that development.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: Do you think that could come at the cost of growth impetus because the sense we are getting is that the government may reduce the Seventh Pay Commission allocation by about Rs 15,000-25,000 crore. How would you react to that?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Teather:</strong> We are trying to support growth. What we want to see is investment lift off and if you want to see investment lift off, you need to make the funds available, the savings in the economy available to the private sector. So it can have a lower cost of capital, it can do with its bad assets, it can go and invest. And the way they make those savings available is to constrain consumption and reduce the fiscal deficit and make those funds available to the private sector.<br /><br />So curtailing the Pay Commission would be one way of doing that but it is something we were hoping the government would do but Finance Minister's Arun Jaitley's comments on February 5 suggests that it isn&rsquo;t going to happen in the upcoming Budget but it could be he changes his position.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Is 3.5 percent enough to ignite the bond markets if that were indeed announced on Monday, what kind of a borrowing programme will you be comfortable with?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Rajpal:</strong> 3.5 will definitely provide a relief to the bond market. I think that along with the open market operations should help bond markets stabilise. Though markets will first consolidate around current levels, it will take some time for us to see a meaningful rally. Having said that, 3.5 percent will definitely be a great relief and I believe markets will treat it very kindly.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: If there is a 3.5 percent fiscal deficit, last year around if you remember because the government stuck to the stated target or at least impressed the RBI with the quality of expenditure, they gave an unscheduled rate cut. You would expect one this time?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Teather:</strong> What matters is not just the number, not just the deficit figure, not just the 3.5 percent but how the government gets there. If the government arrives at that 3.5 percentage point to GDP deficit by promising a large slice of asset sales, then that might be poor quality fiscal consolidation unless these asset sales are truly transferring ownership to the private sector and so it is the mix that we see in the Budget not just at the absolute level, that is going to matter for RBI policy going forward but if you do get a 3.5 percent deficit with a drawn out of partial implementation of the Pay Commission that is a scenario where we would see more rather than less RBI policy rate cuts for the remainder of this year.<br /><br /><strong>Sonia: Government will definitely rely on proceeds from divestment in order to meet that fiscal deficit target. This time for the last year, the targeted full year divestment was Rs 69,500 crore and we all know that the government could hardly even get to about Rs 20,000 crore, Rs 15,000 crore at best. What do you think the realistic divestment target could be that the government could assume this time?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Teather:</strong> In our analysis, we published a note a couple of weeks ago called ''Budget 2016: Quality versus Quantity - don&rsquo;t ignore the states''. We look for a number in the region of 0.4 percentage points to GDP which is around Rs 500 billion. It might be a tall order but we are talking about the numbers that are going to the Budget not the numbers that finally come out at the end of the year.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: What is your growth forecast now? We had a fairly torrid earnings season, is it looking like growth is turning around?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Teather:</strong> As you know, the government has forecasted a number of 7.6 for this fiscal year and a lot of very clever people working on that. So I am not going to disagree with that number but I do think that growth could slow as we go into FY17. The reason for this is that the global economy is not going very well, exports will probably be a drag and we have already had some of the impulse from the interest rate cuts that Raghuram Rajan gave us last year, so we are forecasting 7.4 percent real GDP growth in FY17.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: Would you expect that if this 3.5 percent deficit is announced, there could be an unscheduled rate cut? If that happens, what is your bond price forecast or bond yield forecast for the 7.59?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Rajpal:</strong> I think if 3.5 happens then rate cut definitely looks more likely. I don&rsquo;t know whether that is unscheduled, whether it happens in the next monetary policy meeting but definitely the chances of rate cut increases. I would expect bond yields to move by another 20-25 bps if a combination of 3.5 percent on fiscal deficit along with a rate cut expectation, which I hope to get materialised occurs together.<br /><br /><strong>Latha: That is 7.6 then, I think the 7.59 is today at 7.8 thereabouts, you see it dipping below 7.6?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Rajpal:</strong> Yes, around that level if both these things materialise.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/f/fiscal_fiscal_deficit_deficit_1312_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 10:41:00</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>