<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/politics/budget-2016-opposition-to-corner-smriti-iraniparliamentjnu-row_5690081.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Opposition to corner Smriti Irani in Parliament on JNU row]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[After the Budget Session began on a note of confrontation last week, the second week of the session is also unlikely to transact legislative business, barring essential financial exercise like the Union Budget]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Parliament is expected to witness stormy scenes on Monday as two privilege motions are likely to be moved against HRD Minister Smriti Irani. The Opposition is targeting Smriti Irani over her speech in Parliament on the JNU issue and will even demand an apology from her.</p>
<p>While CPM MP Mohammed Salim will move the motion in Lok Sabha, JDU's KC Tyagi will move the motion in Rajya Sabha.</p>
<p>Congress vice president Rahul Gandhi will lead the party's charge against the government on Tuesday while participating in the debate on the Motion of Thanks on the President's Address.</p>
<p>After the Budget Session began on a note of confrontation last week, the second week of the session is also unlikely to transact legislative business, barring essential financial exercise like the Union Budget, as the government and opposition are again set to lock horns on issues like the JNU row and Dalit scholar Rohith Vemula's suicide.</p>
<p>Congress leader Ghulam Nabi Azad in Srinagar said Irani's statement inside Parliament over Rohith Vemula case had many contradictions and was a "fit case" for a privilege motion as she had "mislead" the nation.</p>
<p>Alleging that the HRD Minister has "not only been economical with truth but has also wilfully misled Parliament" on the unfortunate suicide of Vemula", Congress general secretary Mukul Wasnik said the party planned to bring privilege motion against her soon.</p>
<p>They have cited the outburst of Radhika, Rohith's mother, against Smriti and accused the BJP of being anti-Dalit.</p>
<p>Radhika had attacked the HRD minister, questioning on what basis did she declare Rohith to be "anti-national".</p>
<p>In a sharp riposte to Prime Minister Narendra Modi over his 'Satyamev Jayate' tweet following Smriti Irani's speech in Lok Sabha, Rahul Gandhi on Saturday requested him to hear the version of the mother of Vemula, the Dalit scholar who committed suicide in Hyderabad.</p>
<p>On Saturday, Vemula's mother Radhika and his brother met political leaders including Sonia Gandhi, Sitaram Yechury and KC Tyagi, seeking their support for enactment of a Rohith Act against caste discrimination in educational institutions.</p>
<p>They were accompanied by the leaders of Hyderabad University's Joint Action Committee for Social Justice.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/p/Parliament-356_3335_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 09:16:37</Entry_Date><Category>Politics</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>