<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/statutory-status-to-aadhaar-govt-to-bring-bill2-days_5711701.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Statutory status to Aadhaar; govt to bring Bill in 2 days]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Till date over 98 crore Aadhaar numbers have been generated. Per day average of 26 lakh biometric and over 1.5 lakh e-KYC transactions are made. Aadhaar numbers have been seeded in 11.19 crore DBTL accounts out of total 16.5 crore DBTL beneficiaries.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Government is set to introduce the Aadhaar Bill in Parliament in the next couple of days to give the platform a statutory backing, a move that will expand its range of utility in providing government benefits.</p>
<p>"I will introduce in one or two days. It is ready. I have also given notice," Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said while talking about his announcement on Aadhaar.</p>
<p>"We will undertake significant reforms, such as the enactment of a law to ensure that all government benefits are conferred upon persons who deserve it, by giving a statutory backing to the Aadhaar platform," Jaitley said in speech for Union Budget 2016-17.</p>
<p>Till date over 98 crore Aadhaar numbers have been generated. Per day average of 26 lakh biometric and over 1.5 lakh e-KYC transactions are made. Aadhaar numbers have been seeded in 11.19 crore DBTL accounts out of total 16.5 crore DBTL beneficiaries.</p>
<p>There is already a National Identification Authority of India Bill, 2010, pending in the Rajya Sabha.</p>
<p>The statutory status will provide a legal foundation to Aadhaar for expanding its use for a range of developmental purposes.</p>
<p>It has been suggested that all benefits, subsidies or services funded from the consolidated fund of India should be through Aadhaar platform.</p>
<p>Jaitley said that a critical component of minimum government and maximum governance is to ensure targeted disbursement of government subsidies to actual beneficiaries.</p>
<p>"First, we will introduce the targeted delivery of financial and other subsidiary benefits services by using the Aadhaar framework. The bill will be introduced in the current budget session of Parliament.</p>
<p>"The Aadhaar number or authentication shall however not confirm any rights of citizenship or domicile," he said.</p>
<p>The finance minister said the public money should reach the poor and deserving without any leakage.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/a/Aadhar_356_5917_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 07:46:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>