<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/rail-budget-2016-key-things-to-watch-outsuresh-prabhus-speech_5639241.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Rail Budget 2016: Key things to watch out in Suresh Prabhu's speech]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[During FY16, rail minister had promised an aggressive capex plan for the railways from 2015-19 at Rs 8.5 lakh crore. During FY16, the budgeted capital outlay was Rs 1 lakh crore. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau </strong><br /><br />Union Railways Minister Suresh Prabhu is set to present his second Rail Budget today. Analysts say FY17 Rail Budget is likely to focus on safety upgradation, electrification and doubling to clear traffic bottlenecks.<br /><br />Here are key things to watch out for: <br /><br />1) Capex plan: Expect 20-25 percent YoY increase in capital outlay for FY17 at&nbsp;Rs 1.25 lakh cr<br /><br />2) During FY16, rail minister had promised an aggressive capex plan for the railways from 2015-19 at Rs 8.5 lakh crore. During FY16, the budgeted capital outlay was Rs 1 lakh crore. <br /><br />3) Targeted operating ratio for 2015-16 at 88.5 percent against 91.8 percent in 2014-15: best in the last 9 years<br /><br />4) Wagon procurement is expected to increase to 18,000 - 19,000 units. <br /><br />5) Expect healthy improvement in allocation towards Dedicated freight corridor (DFC).<br /><br />6) Allocation towards coaches, MEMU and EMU expected to witness higher growth in FY17<br /><br />7) Fare changes unlikely; no pass through of lower diesel prices<br /><br />8) Progress and expansion of DFC<br /><br />9) Rollout and expansion of high speed network<br /><br />10) Building of 200-kmph train coaches indigenously<br /><br />11) Connecting J&amp;K, North East and hilly regions on a priority basis<br /><br />12) Implementation of new design coaches and vaccum toilets<br /><br />13) Progress towards elimination of all level crossings<br /><br />14) Upgradation of station complexes for comprehensive government services, skill development.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Suresh_Prabhu_2016_railways_rail_minister_356x200_2848_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-25 09:35:32</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>