<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-is-pro-village-pro-poor-pro-farmer-narendra-modi_5698161.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget is pro-village, pro-poor, pro-farmer: Narendra Modi]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA["This Budget is pro-village, pro-poor, pro-farmer. The main focus is to bringing about qualitative change in the country," Modi said, adding "there will be a big change in the lives of common people."]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Congratulating Finance Minister Arun Jaitley for the Union Budget 2016-17, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday said the Budget is pro-village, poor and farmers. He also said that the focus of the Budget is on bringing about qualitative change in the country and alleviating poverty through a slew of time-bound programmes.</p>
<p>"This Budget is pro-village, pro-poor, pro-farmer. The main focus is to bringing about qualitative change in the country," Modi said, adding "there will be a big change in the lives of common people."</p>
<p>He said the Budget has laid a roadmap to alleviate poverty in a time-bound manner. "Several steps have been taken for the farmers. The most important is Pradhan Mantri Krishi Yojana," he said.</p>
<p>Noting that electricity and roads are crucial for villages, the Prime Minister said by 2019, all villages of the country will be connected by roads, while all of them will be electrified by 2018. For MNREGA, there has been the biggest allocation, he said.</p>
<p>Talking about housing, Modi said every poor man dreams of owning a house and efforts will be made to strengthen this sector to ensure that the poor people realise their dreams.</p>
<p>At the same time, exemptions have been given to those living in rented accommodations, he noted.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/n/Narendra_Modi_Arun_jaitley_budget2016_FM_356x200_3920_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 16:00:42</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>