<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/expect-bold-movesfewer-tax-cutsunion-budget-2016_5320881.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Expect bold moves and fewer tax cuts in Union Budget 2016]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Given the tough task  of maintaining fiscal prudence and propelling economic growth, this year the budget may turn out to be more reformist and less populist. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Preeti Khurana</strong></em><br /><br />The preparations for Modi government&rsquo;s third budget must be in full swing. At this time some global challenges are knocking at our door. No one knows where China&rsquo;s economy and its stock markets are headed. Crude has reached levels no one imagined. With all this rocking our boat, the government is no longer harping on its ache din promise. As the finance minister readies his union budget speech, he has a tough task ahead of him. <br /><br /><strong>Minimum exemption limit</strong> - The working class is eager to see some enhancement in minimum exemption limit. This has been kept at Rs 2,50,000 since financial year 2014-15. However cutting down taxes may put pressure on our tax collections and the FM has a tough choice ahead of him with appeasing masses or retaining this limit as before. Given their comfortable majority, this may turn out to be the year in which the focus of budget shall be reform for businesses. The FM may keep the doles for the next year when some of the states are due for elections. Reforms for corporates were promised in last year&rsquo;s budget and it&rsquo;s likely this will be a business focussed budget.<br /><br /><strong>Section 80C limit</strong> - It&rsquo;s notable that Section 80C limit has not been revised since financial year 2014-15. But giving tax breaks on savings, and thereby letting us save more, may have a less beneficial impact on growth and expenditure. The government needs to find the fine balance in tax collections and its borrowings and then consider revising this limit. Without doubt, the FM will find himself in a tough spot balancing taxes and raising Section 80C limit, it may after all be a hard call. <br /><br /><strong>Making NPS popular</strong> - Last year the finance minister allowed an additional deduction of Rs 50,000 for investments made to NPS. But NPS continues to be unpopular since withdrawals on maturity are fully taxable. For those who do not get pension, NPS is the way forward. This is one benefit that the government must consider in this budget, and bring NPS in parity with PPF.<br /><br /><strong>Simplifying income tax laws</strong> &ndash; If the FM finds himself in a hard spot choosing between economic prudence &amp; reducing tax burden, a winning pick could be simplification of our existing tax laws. Steady amendments of our tax laws have made them incomprehensible to many. Some of our exemptions have lost relevance and need a serious re look. Take Section 80GG for example, a maximum of Rs 2,000 can be claimed as deduction for rent paid by those who do not receive HRA. Similarly, medical reimbursements have not been revised in a long time. It may be wiser to shelf some of the old deductions and enhance minimum exemption limits which can then be linked to an individual&rsquo;s level of income. The direct tax code was a step in this direction and once GST sees the light of the day, it may be worthwhile for the government to relook at the DTC and bring it up in the coming year.<br /><br />The government has made progress in the past months; refunds have been made fully electronic and are processed quickly, returns can be verified electronically and there is improved communication with taxpayers. Here&rsquo;s hoping there are progressive steps in budget 2016 to simplify taxes for all.<br /><br /><em><strong>Author is a Chartered Accountant and Chief Editor at <a href="https://cleartax.in/" target="_blank">ClearTax</a></strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/budget_2016_4_356X200_2919_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-05 09:31:02</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>