<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/job-creation_4792001.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Job Creation]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Economic growth will be meaningful and inclusive only if the standard of living of each and every Indian improved and in that context it is imperative that policymakers look at ways to create more jobs as bulk of Indians are of working age, President Pranab Mukherjee said recently.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Economic growth will be meaningful and inclusive only if the standard of living of each and every Indian improved and in that context it is imperative that policymakers look at ways to create more jobs as bulk of Indians are of working age, President Pranab Mukherjee said recently.</p>
<p>Since coming to power, the National Democratic Alliance (NDA) government has initiated campaigns such as 'Make in India' and 'Skill India', which have the potential to create jobs. The government in fact had allocated about Rs 5040 crore for skill development in Budget 2015-16.</p>
<p>However, a recent report by the Bureau of Labour Statistics paints a rather grim picture. For the January-March 2015 quarter, it estimates that the aggregate number of jobs created across survey establishments was 64000. The important point here is that it is the lowest number over the four quarters of FY14-15. Getting into specifics, in the manufacturing sector, only textiles saw an increase in jobs &mdash; by just 24,000 &mdash; during the period.</p>
<p>It may be worth noting that in his Independence Day Speech, Prime Minister Narendra Modi had spoken about two key economic policy initiatives and one of them was new schemes linking all public and private investments to creation of jobs.</p>
<p>But this may be easier said than done. India faces a lot of problems as far as skilling is concerned and hence the opportunity to be meaningfully&nbsp; or gainfully employed. Official data shows, less than one adult out of 10 has any form of vocational training. Even in that, the type of training is not up to the mark and not what employers are seeking, with majority having just a hereditary skill or learned on the job.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/u/us-jobs-356_4937_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-08 14:39:08</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>