<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/insurance/budget-2016-allow-health-insurers-to-carry-forward-losses-for-10-years_5599901.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: Allow health insurers to carry forward losses for 10 years]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Government should take various measures to ensure increased penetration of health insurance in India.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<em><strong>Sandeep Patel</strong></em><br /><br />India has undertaken significant strides in overcoming the challenges of availability, accessibility and affordability of quality healthcare. Public as well private players have contributed to quality healthcare through enhanced geographical coverage, enhanced healthcare services and increasing healthcare expenditure. The Indian healthcare industry is projected to continue its rapid expansion, with an estimated market value of US&#36; 280 billion by 2020. <br /><br />However, the challenges pertaining to demand and supply, lack of health infrastructure, etc. continue to exist.<br /><br />The Union Budget 2016 looks promising to make an essential withdrawal from the past, and expectations from the government are high. Some of the key aspects that need to be looked upon are:<br /><br /><strong>PPP partnership</strong> - The Union Budget 2016 may stress on the need for public and private partnership in ensuring quality healthcare facilities and health insurance for all across the country. Expanding the public/government funded health insurance schemes to cover every Indian may be an important and essential step the government should address. <br /><br /><strong>Tax deduction limit</strong> - Health Insurance premium limit under section 80D should be increased further considering increasing medical costs<br /><br /><strong>Further tax deduction for buying health insurance for personal service providers -</strong> Health Insurance premium paid by an individual to cover the health of any person employed as personal service provider &ndash; maid, driver, cook, gardener, housekeeping, security, nurse, helper, etc. should be allowed as deduction under section 80D. It will help penetrate health insurance at large and will also address the rising need for access to healthcare across all sections of the society. The benefit of health claim will go to the beneficiary with insurable interest of the person making the premium payment to maintain health of the beneficiary.<br /><br /><strong>Carry forward losses up to 10 assessment years -</strong> Health Insurance companies should be allowed to carry forward losses up to 10 assessment years (from 8 assessment years now) due to long gestation period in achieving break even.<br /><br /><strong>Service tax waiver -</strong> service tax that people pay while buying a health cover should be waived in order to enhance affordability of health insurance among all and in turn increase penetration. <br /><br /><em><strong>Author is MD &amp; CEO of Cigna TTK Health Insurance</strong></em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/i/indian_currency_rupee_health_insurance_claims_4154_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-23 09:50:50</Entry_Date><Category>Insurance</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>