<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/macro-economic-survey-2016-to-plug-lpg-subsidy-leakage-cut-yearly-capcylinders-to-10_5666201.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Macro Economic Survey 2016: To plug LPG subsidy leakage, cut yearly cap on cylinders to 10]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Also, while households can buy only 12 subsidised cylinders a year, they can buy an unlimited number of unsubsidised cylinders. However, these cylinders are still 30 per cent cheaper than commercial cylinders due to differential tax treatment of household and commercial LPG. So households can technically sell these to commercial establishments]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />The Macro Economic Survey has said that leakages in Liquefied Petroleum Gas (cooking gas) subsidy can be reduced further without the poor being hurt.<br /><br />It has proposed that the annual household cap on cylinders be reduced to 10 from 12. <br /><br />"Even the richest households&mdash;the top 10 per cent&mdash;typically do not consume more than 10 cylinders per year, so reducing the household cap will be&nbsp;unlikely to hurt the poor," the Survey said.<br /><br />It also pointed to a &lsquo;March problem&rsquo;.<br /><br />"Because March is the end of the fiscal year, distributors have strong incentives to invoice unconsumed subsidized cylinders to households and resell them in the black market," the Survey said.<br /><br />Also, while households can buy only 12 subsidised cylinders a year, they can buy an unlimited number of unsubsidised cylinders. However, these cylinders are still 30 per cent cheaper than commercial cylinders due to differential&nbsp;tax treatment of household and commercial LPG. So households can technically sell these to commercial establishments.<br /><br />Commercial LPG is subject to customs and excise duties of 13 per cent and state taxes of between 5 per cent (Assam) and 20.5 per cent (Bihar) over-and-above domestic LPG. <br /><br />&ldquo;This creates another source of leakage&mdash;a shortfall of tax revenue in this<br />case rather than excess subsidy burden,&rdquo; the Survey said]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/l/lpg_16X9_0534_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 16:59:11</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>