<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/chouhan-hails-visionary-fm-cong-slams-jugglerywords_5699081.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Chouhan hails 'visionary' FM; Cong slams 'jugglery of words']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[However, Congress described it as "jugglery of words" and said that it is "unconstitutional" on the part of Finance Minister to dole out dreams of 2022 when the government has so far got the mandate till 2019.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Terming Finance Minister Arun Jaitley as "visionary", Madhya Pradesh Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan today said the Union Budget is in the interest of farmers, poor and vulnerable people, and will enhance thrust on social sectors.</p>
<p>However, Congress described it as "jugglery of words" and said that it is "unconstitutional" on the part of Finance Minister to dole out dreams of 2022 when the government has so far got the mandate till 2019.</p>
<p>Congratulating Jaitley, Chouhan, in a series of tweets, said, "Interests of farmers, poor and vulnerable have been given due consideration. I congratulate FM Arun Jaitley for (being) visionary." He said Jaitley has "enhanced thrust on social sectors, skill building and job creation in the Budget. It will help a great deal in fulfilling aspirations of people." Chouhan termed the target to double farmers' income as a revolutionary step and welcomed the allocation of Rs 35,984 crore for their welfare.</p>
<p>"Target to double farmers' income in five years a revolutionary step, #Vikas Ka Budget (Development Oriented Budget). Welcome the allocation of Rs 35,984 crore for their welfare," he said in a tweet.</p>
<p>Chouhan also said that "the focus on agriculture and infrastructure will definitely lead the economy to double digit growth and the nine pillars outlined by the Finance Minister reflect vision of resolute government to transform the country. It will further accelerate the growth." However, state Congress president Arun Yadav, in a statement, termed the budget as "jugglery of words" and criticised the government for raising tax on all types of services used by common man from 14.5 percent to 15 percent.</p>
<p>Yadav also said, "By showing dreams of 2022 in different statements in the Budget, the government acted in an unconstitutional manner as it has got the mandate till 2019." "Why it is crossing the definite time frame and doling out false promises to the people?" he asked.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget12_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 16:16:04</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>