<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/top-5-policy-level-initiatives-smes-can-expectbudget-2016_5324641.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Top 5 policy level initiatives SMEs can expect in Budget 2016]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Following are the excerpts of a live chat on Moneycontrol-SME with Mr. Anil Bhardwaj, Secretary General, FISME ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Which are the top 5 policy level initiative that you expect will be announced in Budget 2016 which will change the fate of Indian SMEs?</strong></p>
<p>I think the following five measures can be important for MSMEs: <br /><br /><strong>1.</strong> Inter-state GST in the interim to the GST Inter-state GST could be implemented prior to the full-fledged GST. As the subject being in the central domain, the move does not require the Parliamentary approval. <br /><br /><strong>2.</strong> Investment allowance on Capex Section 80-I, investment allowance on capex leaves MSMEs at present; could be without any lower threshold which will help MSMEs. <br /><br /><strong>3.</strong> Incentive for employment Any increase in social welfare and bonus expenses may be allowed as a 300% weighted deduction for the purpose of tax calculations. On the Non-Tax side: <br /><br /><strong>4.</strong> Offsets for MSMEs in all Public funded infrastructure projects above a threshold Massive public investment- in infrastructure- Roads, Ports, Airports, Railways, Power, Smart Cities etc. The impact could be multiplied if suitable offset clause introduced. All centrally funded projects beyond a threshold say of Rs. 500 crore that say 20% of procurement would be done from MSMEs. <br /><br /><strong>5.</strong> Project Financing Gap: The State Financial Corporations played key role in creation of first wave of MSME entrepreneurship through 60s and 70s. Now SFCs are defunct. But no replacement of SFCs. Need to look at SFCs with fresh pairs of eyes. I think a high level committee may be set up to look at reviving the SFCs and also exploring possibility of initiating similar institutions in PPP or Private mode.</p>
<p><strong>How do you see GST and the indecision around it impacting the business possibilities and how do you think the FM is going to work around the problem pertaining to GST as a part of is Budget 2016?</strong></p>
<p>He may introduce inter-state GST straight away. He doesn`t need Parliamentary approaval for that. And, wait for the Rajya Sabha composition to change, to get the full GST passed.</p>
<p><strong>Budget may roll out more support for start-ups as the government is keen to create the best ecosystem for start-ups and is likely to come up with more incentives for budding entrepreneurs in the upcoming Budget on the lines of Singapore. What are some of these initiatives that would be announced in Budget 2016 to boost startups in India? And what is your wish list?</strong></p>
<p>Just two things can dramatically alter the scenario: induce competition in the banking and financial markets. Let capital chase ideas! (Currently 75% of banking sector comprise of Public Sector Banks). Second, have modern bankruptcy laws, let ideas been tried out: either fail quickly or scale up quiclly. (Currently, we are the only large size economy having NO insolvency/ bacnkruptcy mechanism! A Bill is introduced now under review of a Parliemantry Standing Committee )</p>
<p><strong>It was reported that DIPP wants to create the best ecosystem for start-ups in the country so that they should not move to Singapore. It has studied several start-up ecosystems of countries, including Israel, the US, the UK, Taiwan, Australia and Germany, but the best one is in Singapore. According to you what should be done and which are the top critical steps that Indian government should take to create and give that type of environment and support to our start-ups &amp; SMEs to stay and operate in India?</strong></p>
<p>Giving impetus to manufacturing/ start-ups requires a lot of work to be done simultaneously at many levels. Firstly, there is a need to create a &lsquo;rent&rsquo; &ndash; a clear vested interest for someone to manufacture here than simply import, through a right mix of tariff and non-tariff measures. Second, getting our infrastructure right to bring down energy and transportation costs. Thirdly, reforms in administrative set-up making the officials at local level responsible for investment and employment creation. Reward and punishment for those responsible for growth of industry. Fourthly, banking and financial sector reforms- doing a telecom in the banking sector, so that capital chases ideas and not used to finance the govt. deficits through public sector banks. And finally, set-up a mechanism of mandatory Regulatory Impact Assessment- to conduct rigorous cost-benefit analysis, for all laws/ regulations- periodic review of existing ones and before promulgating new ones.</p>
<p><strong>Do you think all the national level high pitched initiatives that are launched by the government like Make in India, Start-up India and ZED are a prelude to the pro-business and manufacturing orientation of Indian economy? Please elaborate your answer.</strong></p>
<p>For far too long the environment in India has been hostile to businesses: our position in the World bank`s Ease of Doing Business index underscores that. These high pitich initiatives are to challenge that mind-set and to send a strong message to the govt. machinery down the line that businesses are valuable. They are a priority. That sets the ball rolling.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/budget_2016_4_356X200_2919_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-05 13:07:23</Entry_Date><Category>SME</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>