<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/current-affairs/jewellers-protest-excise-duty-shops-shut-for-15th-day_5900141.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Jewellers protest excise duty, shops shut for 15th day]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Striking associations in different parts of the country have decided to hold a protest rally in Ramlila Maidan here tomorrow against the proposal, said All India Sarafa Association Vice-President, Surinder Kumar Jain.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Gold and jewellery establishments across the country remained closed for the 15th day today as traders are protesting the Budget proposal to levy 1 percent excise duty on non-silver jewellery.</p>
<p>Most jewellery houses have been closed since March 2, demanding withdrawal of the proposed excise duty.</p>
<p>Jewellers are also opposed to mandatory quoting of PAN by customers for transactions of Rs 2 lakh and above.</p>
<p>Striking associations in different parts of the country have decided to hold a protest rally in Ramlila Maidan here tomorrow against the proposal, said All India Sarafa Association Vice-President, Surinder Kumar Jain.</p>
<p>Thousands of jewellers, bullion traders and artisans in the industry will take part in tomorrow's rally, Jain told PTI.</p>
<p>"Our protest will continue till the government withdraws the Budget proposal of 1 percent excise duty on non-silver jewellery," Jain said.</p>
<p>The trade is estimated to have incurred huge losses during the strike so far, he added.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley in the Budget 2016-17 proposed 1 percent excise duty on jewellery without input credit, or 12.5 percent with input tax credit, on jewellery, excluding silver other than studded with diamonds and some other precious stones.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry later clarified only jewellers with turnover of more than Rs 12 crore will be liable to pay 1 percent excise duty on non-silver jewellery items.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/s/strike_356x200_1334_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-16 15:30:19</Entry_Date><Category>Current Affairs</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>