<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2016-17-govt-commitment-to-modernise-agri-mktwelcome-move_5732121.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2016-17: Govt commitment to modernise agri mkt a welcome move]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[An all-time high agricultural credit of Rs. 9 lakh crore as well as provision of Rs. 15000 crore towards interest subvention to reduce burden of loan repayment is a very important announcement. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Samir Shah </em></strong><br /><br />In the backdrop of increased rural distress due to back-to-back droughts, untimely rains during the rabi season and downtrend in commodity prices in the global market, the thrust provided to speed up the growth of rural and agriculture sectors has been well-timed and apt move.</p>
<p>An all-time high agricultural credit of Rs. 9 lakh crore as well as provision of Rs. 15000 crore towards interest subvention to reduce burden of loan repayment is a very important announcement. This is likely to augment resources for agriculture and is aimed at enhancing growth. Interest subvention as an incentive for prompt repayment will reward timely repayment of crop loans and is a good step towards inculcating fiscal discipline amongst farmers.</p>
<p>Focused on assuring income security to farmers, the Budget has rolled out a series of measures that would reduce the cost of cultivation, increase productivity, and improve connectivity of farmers to markets. The emphasis on thinking beyond &lsquo;food security&rsquo; and giving back to our farmers a sense of &lsquo;income security&rsquo; is a welcome step.</p>
<p>The Union Budget shows the governments&rsquo; big commitment to using technology in bringing about transparency and efficiency in agricultural markets and helping connect the smallest farmer to the markets.<br /><br /> NCDEX through its subsidiary NeML has pioneered online markets in the country, helping state governments and agencies in procurement of commodities. The Governments embracing of online markets and encouraging states to adopt it is a huge reaffirmation of our efforts towards the same.<br /><br /><em>(Samir Shah is MD &amp; CEO of NCDEX)</em><br /><br /><br /></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_farmers_GDP_Growth_farm_356x200_2919_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-02 10:34:48</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>