<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-unlikely-to-fire-market-ormood-citigroup_5715841.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget unlikely to fire market or the mood: Citigroup]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[The global financial services major said the Budget seeks fiscal consolidation but is cautious in its approach as it focuses on process rather than pushing the boundaries.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The Budget is not likely to "fire" the market or the mood, Citigroup said in a research report, maintaining a positive view on India with an year-end Sensex target of 27,200.</p>
<p>The global financial services major said the Budget seeks fiscal consolidation but is cautious in its approach as it focuses on process rather than pushing the boundaries.</p>
<p>"This will keep India positioned and in play for upsides, but the Budget is unlikely to fire the market or the mood," Citigroup said in a research note.</p>
<p>According to the global brokerage firm, the Budget lacks growth impulses and is not likely to spur economic or market momentum.</p>
<p>The equity market will need a more bottom-up earnings / growth uptick to respond to what should be a stable top-down India, the report said maintaining a positive view on the country, with a 27,200 December 2016 Sensex target.</p>
<p>Post Budget, the 30-share benchmark index Sensex closed down 152 points at 23,002. Intra-day, it tanked nearly 660 points on February 29.</p>
<p>It bounced back and was at 23,509.81, higher by 507.81 points in morning trade on BSE.</p>
<p>The report noted that the Budget has taken a decisive call on fiscal consolidation as it stayed on track with a 3.5 per cent target. "The rating agencies and RBI should like this," the report added.</p>
<p>In February 2 policy review meet, RBI governor Raghuram Rajan left the key interest rates unchanged citing inflation risks and growth concerns, while pegging further easing of monetary policy on government's Budget proposals.</p>
<p>"The Budget presents a credible fiscal consolidation plan despite strong headwinds which should create the space for some monetary easing," Citigroup noted in a separate report.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/b/Budget2016_markets_nse_bse_stock_markets_356x200_3132_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-01 12:32:02</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>