<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/pragmatic-budget-rbi-may-cut-rates-soon-vallabh-bhanshali_5692701.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Pragmatic Budget; RBI may cut rates soon, Vallabh Bhanshali]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Sticking to fiscal prudence was the most important thing, which gives room for RBI to cut rates and would be disappointed if he did not see that come from RBI as early as today, says Vallabh Bhanshali, Chairman, Enam Securities.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Vallabh Bhanshali, Chairman, Enam Securities clearly believes it was a pragmantic Budget. <br />
<p>Sticking to fiscal prudence was the most important thing, which gives room for RBI to cut rates and would be disappointed if he did not see that come from RBI as early as today.</p>
<p>The Finance Minister has earlier said that he is not looking at a big bang Budget. Sensible things have been done in the Budget, he adds.</p>
<p>With regards to bank recapitalisation, he says although a bigger number than Rs 25000 crore would have been welcome but as the economic survey had mentioned there are too many complicated things there.</p>
<p>All in all focus on rural development and making life simpler for common man, the government has shown pragmatism, says Bhanshali.<br /><br /><strong><em>Below is the verbatim transcript of Vallabh Bhanshali's interview with Udayan Mukherjee &amp; Sonia Shenoy on CNBC-TV18.</em></strong><br /><br /><strong>Udayan: The biggest beneficiary of this Budget seems to be the bond market because the yields have cooled down about 10-12 basis points and now, everybody will start talking about a rate cut from the RBI because we have got 3.5 percent target held on to. Do you think that yields will cool down further and should one expect an RBI rate cut in the next few weeks?</strong><br /><br />Bhansali: For me, the most important development today was what the RBI governor did. And if you look at the whole making of the Budget, this 3.5 percent was probably the most sacrosanct and everything else was derived from that and therefore, I would be very disappointed if I did not see a major cut as early as today. And as far as the stock market gain is concerned, it is a reflection of the pragmatism in the bank. Finance Minister has already said, last year that they are not for big bank Budget. And his colleague, Economic Advisor warned us that the world is extremely volatile putting a range of 75 basis points in his growth estimate which is very unusual. Normally, it is 25 basis points. <br /><br />And given that, I think very sensible things have been done. The question of whether Budget is really an occasion to restructure the way the country is governed, is a moot point and that follows from much greater political will or political opportunism. It would have happened in the first Budget or the second Budget. Third Budget, that kind of surgery normally does not happen. So, I wasn&rsquo;t even expecting that. <br /><br />As far as the bank capitalisation is concerned, we would have all liked a large number because it sounds better than a small number. But, as the economic survey said, there are complicated issues there. Fixing twin balance sheet is not just done by putting a large blob of capital, therefore I was not disappointed by that. Of course, one has to see that unless the banks are tackled quickly and firmly, we may have a very grim situation there. <br /><br />But, I would like to give the benefit of doubt to the Finance Minister, when he said that whatever is needed will be done and we have to find the resources. Without finding the resources, you cannot put a large number in public. Therefore, all-in-all, boost to rural demand, the desire to make life simpler for citizens who can really take the growth forward in this country and which is the principle of this government, has shown fair bit of pragmatism for me.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2016/356x200/s/Sensex_Budget2016_nifty_bse_nse_stockmarkets_jaitley_FM_finance_Down_stock_markets_356x200_4912_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 13:27:29</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>