<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/market-outlook/not-much-money-to-be-mademkt-currently-mizuho-bk_5666541.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Not much money to be made in mkt currently: Mizuho Bk]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Tirthankar Patnaik, India Strategist at Mizuho Bank says that there could be a relief rally if there is no adverse move on long term capital gains (LTCG) or securities transaction tax (STT) in the upcoming Budget. ]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[Budget fear alongwith disappointment over no fare hike in the rail Budget and the current non-performing assets (NPAs) situation of banking sector is impacting the market sentiments, says Tirthankar Patnaik, India Strategist at Mizuho Bank. <br /><br />Patnaik adds that domestic market is also trailing the global markets. Discussing the volatility in the market, Patnaik says:&rdquo;not much money to be made in Indian market currently.&rdquo; <br /><br />Significant capital outflows and stressed asset&nbsp;situation, which is expected to remain same in Q4, continues to hurt the market, he says adding that earnings too are expected to remain low in the medium term. <br /><br />However, he says that there could be a relief rally if there is no adverse move on long term capital gains (LTCG) or securities transaction tax (STT) in the upcoming Budget. <br /><br />Market, anyways, is not expecting much from the Budget, he says. <br /><br />The economic survey points at rethinking of mid-term fiscal consolidation, he says. If the government is able to show FY18 fiscal consolidation of 3 percent without any draconian moves, then there could be a relief rally, he adds.<br /><br />Patnaik expects a 25 basis points rate cut by the Reserve Bank before the next fiscal. <br /><br /><em><strong>Below is the verbatim transcript of Dr. Tirthankar Patnaik&rsquo;s interview with CNBC-TV18's Anuj Singhal..</strong></em><br /><br /><strong>Q: The global market has been underperforming. Our market clearly even on good days we are not able to latch on to those good cues and on bad days we are underperforming any way. Do you think there is a bit of Budget fear and the follow up question is post Budget do you think there is a risk of further sell off in our market?</strong><br /><br />A: There is a bit of a Budget fear. There has been talk about the long term capital gains on equities coming in and the Securities Transaction Tax (STT), and you keep hearing about it near the Budget STT remaining and there has been also some amount of disappointment at what was done. There was no fare hike in the Railway Budget. Add to that the bank asset quality issues we have been having lately in the just concluded earnings season and you have a slew of negative points that add to the global negatives and there is no surprise why our markets have been actually trailing global markets.<br /><br /><strong>Q: The counter question is can something be done in Budget where fears are allayed and the market has a big rally. If we don't have any move on the LTCG, if we don't have any other so called draconian moves is there a ground for the market to rally from that point on then?</strong><br /><br />A: If there is no adverse move on these LTCG and similar other draconian moves that the government is contemplating or that are being discussed there will certainly be a relief rally. From an expectations perspective the market does not expect too much from this Budget. We see that the fiscal math including the seventh central pay commission does become fairly tight. So, the arguments are whether we should go for fiscal consolidation or should we take a break.<br /><br />The Economic Survey points out that you could see a rethink on medium term fiscal consolidation path. From that perspective the market will essentially see if the fiscal consolidation path is being adhered to are we really looking at a three percent kind of number in FY18. But the sense is that if the government is able to show that they will target three percent in FY18 along with the lack of draconian measures we should see some amount of relief rally before we get back into our problems with bank asset quality. So, to answer your question yes, we should see some kind of a positive after the Budget.<br /><br /><strong>Q: The other problem for this market has been the texture of stocks that have started to fall. Earlier it was ICICI Bank, Larsen &amp; Toubro, ITC, these kind of stocks leading to decline. But now we have some of the holy stocks HDFC twins, Kotak Mahindra Bank, even they are starting to fall. What do you make of that?</strong><br /><br />A: Not to comment on specific stocks but the sense is we have been having significant capital outflows from the Indian markets in equities and the sense is that with the global environment being what it is there is fairly low likelihood that Indian markets would or Indian economy would move ahead or would streak a path where the other economies are not really going at this point of time. Add to that as I pointed out earlier our own bank asset quality issues which are unlikely to go away in a hurry we have seen how for certain large private banks the non-performing assets (NPA) numbers have been fairly large, the provisioning numbers have been fairly large and they are expected to remain so at least for the next quarter and it is very important that we use the word at least here because given the economic environment you might see NPA numbers coming in bad even in the first quarter of FY17. From that perspective there is not much money to be made in the Indian markets at the moment despite what we have discussed the relief rally and therefore it is not a big surprise that holy stocks as you pointed out could also see some kind of selling.<br /><br /><strong>Q: Post Budget do you think it is back to global cues or do you think domestically we could do something which could change sentiment and could be the ground for the next round of rally or do you think downward grind is going to continue?</strong><br /><br />A: If the Budget gets the fiscal prudence math right, if the Budget really puts the tax evasion issues as we have had with major companies that issue behind us, if the budget does not do any kind of negative move on LTCG, STT at all then we should get to global cues for the time being and we should see a relief rally.<br /><br />The worries on bank asset quality are likely to remain. Once we start the next earnings season which will be mid April or so that is when we will again see banks coming up with a lot of NPA numbers. In between that we expect the RBI to cut rates by about 25 bps. So, there should be some more support coming in from the market from a reduced cost of funds perspective. But yes, from a medium term perspective we see earnings fairly weak at the moment. So, global cues will drive and we will also have Indian cues that might drive the market lower.<br /><br /><em>(Interview transcribed by Binu Panicker)</em>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2014/356x200/m/mkt_356_0910_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 17:30:34</Entry_Date><Category>MARKET OUTLOOK</Category><Video_flag>1</Video_flag></article></news>