<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/tax/savecapital-gains-by-investingstart-ups_5718121.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Save on capital gains by investing in start-ups]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[There are several elements related to this entire process that needs to be considered because it is very different from what the investor has experienced till now with respect to their capital gains tax saving investments.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>Arnav Pandya</strong></em></p>
<p>Individual taxpayers have been used to investing their capital gains in areas like a residential house property and bonds in order to avoid paying capital gains that they have earned. Now there are a couple of different options that are available to the taxpayers so that they can save their capital gains but this is a completely different ball game as it involves investing in start ups. <br /><br />There are several elements related to this entire process that needs to be considered because it is very different from what the investor has experienced till now with respect to their capital gains tax saving investments.</p>
<p><strong>Fund of Funds</strong></p>
<p>One newly introduced area for tax benefit for long term capital gains comes under Section 54EE. Here if there is a long term capital gains earned by a taxpayer and then this gain is invested in the units of a Fund of Funds that has been specified by the government to invest in start ups to finance them at the initial stage of their existence, the amount invested would not be considered as capital gains for tax to be paid on it.<br /><br /> There are two additional conditions that are involved with this benefit where the first one is that the amount that can be invested in such a fund is restricted to a sum of Rs 50 lakh. The other concerns the time period for which the amount would be locked in which is three years. If the amount is withdrawn before this then the tax benefit would be reversed.</p>
<p><strong>Direct investment</strong></p>
<p>There is one more way in which an individual who has capital gains can now invest in start ups and get an exemption from their long term capital gains and this is under Section 54 GB. If there is a long term capital gains arising out of the sale of a residential property and then the gain is invested in the shares of an entity that is eligible for being classified as a start up then the gains would not have tax to be paid on it. Once again there are a couple of conditions that need to be met when this process is done.<br /><br /> The individual has to hold more than 50 per cent shares of the start up which means that the person has to have controlling ownership and not some part investment which is passive in nature. At the same time the start up has to utilise the amount invested to purchase assets before the filing of the income tax return by the individual.</p>
<p><strong>Risk</strong></p>
<p>One of the biggest areas that an individual must consider when they look at these options is that the nature of the risk changes when compared to other options where they can save capital gains. In case of bonds there is no capital risk and when the amount is reinvested into property there is also some element of comfort here. <br /><br />The situation is radically different when the amount goes to a start up because there are high levels of failure so when one starts an entity on their own or even invests in the fund that will invest in start ups. So there is a strong chance that they could end up losing the money less end up earning returns on it. This should be weighed and only if this is palatable should the investor consider these options otherwise it could be that hard earned gains from one capital asset are lost elsewhere.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/s/startups_356x200_5916_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-03-02 10:33:19</Entry_Date><Category>Tax</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>