<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/economic-survey-how-india-faredemissions-climate-change-last-year_5665921.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Economic Survey: How India fared on emissions, climate change last year]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Though 2015 was declared as the warmest year by the World Meteorological Organization, India contributed fairly less towards carbon emission as compared to US, China and EU.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moneycontrol Bureau</strong><br /><br />India continued to push forward for implementation of non-conventional sources of energy and made headway in&nbsp;tackling climate change,&nbsp;according to the Economic Survey tabled by the government today.</p>
<p>The report said that though 2015 was declared as the warmest year by the World Meteorological Organization, India contributed fairly less towards carbon emission as compared to US, China and EU.</p>
<p>The country's past&nbsp;carbon-di-oxide emissions record has also been good: from 1970 to 2014, India stood way behind the top three emitters&mdash;US, China, EU&mdash;with &nbsp;emission being at 39 gigatonne (Gt).</p>
<p><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2016/c/climate.JPG" alt="" width="586" height="463" align="left" /></p>
<p><br /><br />In 2014 as well, India was way behind the three major CO2 emitters.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_image_files/2016/c/climate2.JPG" alt="" width="574" height="337" align="left" /></p>
<p><br /><br />The year 2015 also witnessed the landmark adoption of a new climate change agreement at the COP21 held in Paris. <br /><br />At the event, India played a major role in preserving the aspirations and expectations of developing nations and made sure that vulnerable and poor nations don&rsquo;t end up carrying the burden to curb climate change.<br /><strong><br />Read more: </strong><strong><a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world-news/key-draft-highlights-paris-climate-change-talks_4690381.html">Key draft highlights: Paris climate change talks</a></strong></p>
<p>Power&nbsp;Minister Piyush Goyal had said at&nbsp;the Paris summit that western countries developed on the back of cheap fossil fuels and it&nbsp;is time for developing nations&nbsp;to benefit from the same.<br /><br /><iframe src="//renderer.qmerce.com/interaction/56cf52e75762585b453dbb60" width="100%" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/i/Indian_Economy_economy_Indian_Economy_survey_Indian_Budget_365x200_5242_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-26 17:40:05</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>