<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/sme/leverage-import-duties-to-support-makeindia-fisme_5046801.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Leverage import duties to support Make in India: FISME]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Rates of Custom Duties on various stages of production - from raw material to finished products may be finely differentiated allowing small breathing space to each of the value adding company.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>FISME in its budget recommendation suggested that Instead of having just two slabs, the duties could be intelligently tweaked within the framework of multi-lateral and regional commitments to create a pull for &ldquo;Make in India&rdquo; and encourage backward integration.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><u>Leveraging Import duties to support &lsquo;Make in India&rsquo;</u></strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Every country that has been industrialized used differential rates of duties toencourage domestic value addition. Instead of having just two slabs, the duties could be intelligently tweaked within the framework of multi-lateral and regionalcommitments to create a pull for &ldquo;Make in India&rdquo; and encourage backwardintegration.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suggestion:</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Rates of Custom Duties on various stages of production - from raw material tofinished products may be finely differentiated allowing small breathing space toeach of the value adding company. A study could be commissioned to identify potentialsectors and slabs to encourage such backward integration.</p>
<p><strong><u>Small exporters, custom duty and duty drawback</u></strong></p>
<p>Duty free import of raw materials is allowed for goods to be exported and dutydrawback is given for the use of indigenous raw materials. Presently indigenousraw material suppliers keep their price on parity with landed price of imported rawmaterials. Small exporters find themselves unable to import raw materials everytime and use indigenous raw materials and get duty draw back. The dutydrawback rates are low in comparison of custom duty. (For example, rates ofduty draw back are 2% on Mig wires &amp; welding electrodes, while import duty onraw steel is 12.5%.)</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suggestion:</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>The duty drawback rates should be aligned with the custom duty on its rawmaterials and on calculated quantity based on input-output norms alreadyestablished. The drawback mechanism should also incorporate the temporaryanti-dumping / safe-guard duties levied from time to time.</p>
<p><strong><u>Capital Gains Tax: A disincentive to grow from Micro to Small to Medium</u></strong></p>
<p>One major concern with regards to MSME sector is that majority of them fail tograduate from Micro to Small and Medium Enterprises. It is observed that thecurrent Capital Gains Tax regime also exacerbate this. In the presentdispensation when one sells industrial property to shift to another locationexemption in Capital Gains are allowed only if we shift to: Urban Area to a RuralArea ( 20 Km from Municipal Limits) or Urban area to any Special EconomicZone (54 GA).</p>
<p>MSMEs in their growth journey also need to expand and shift tolarger locations not-necessarily to the areas defined in the exemption. The fear ofattracting Capital Gains Tax acts as a deterrent for expansion.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suggestions:</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>MSME may be allowed exemption from CGT if they sell existing space and shiftto larger space or add to existing units by selling another piece of propertyirrespective of location.</p>
<p><strong><em>Courtesy FISME</em></strong></p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d01.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/2015/356x200/m/make_in_india_make_2252_356.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-01-18 10:51:41</Entry_Date><Category>SME</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>