<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/budget-2016-bjp-says-budget-is-visionary-progressive_5695521.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Budget 2016: BJP says Budget is 'visionary, progressive']]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Similar views were echoed by other ministers of the ruling party with Union minister Mukhtar Abbas Naqvi calling it a "perfect, people-friendly and progressive Budget".]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>Terming the Union Budget as "visionary and progressive", BJP today said that it gives priority to farmers and weaker sections and will also lead to empowerment of the youth.</p>
<p>"The Budget is for everybody. Budget has been provided for infrastructure like ports, rail, airports. In the health sector, for poor people, upto Rs one lakh cost of hospitalisation will be borne by the government. This is a progressive and visionary Budget," Union Environment Minister Prakash Javadekar said.</p>
<p>Similar views were echoed by other ministers of the ruling party with Union minister Mukhtar Abbas Naqvi calling it a "perfect, people-friendly and progressive Budget".</p>
<p>"India is a country where agriculture holds a prime place but it is after years that this has been reflected in a Budget which gives priority to farmers as well as weaker sections.</p>
<p>This Budget is one which will also lead to empowerment of the youth," he said.</p>
<p>Union Health Minister J P Nadda termed it as a "positive and balanced" Budget and said that there were several initiatives for health and other social sectors which reflect Prime Minister Narendra Modi's vision of 'Sabka Saath Sabka Vikas'.</p>
<p>"My congratulations to the finance minister @arunjaitley for bringing such a good, positive and balanced Budget. There are several initiatives for health and other social sectors which truly reflect PM Sh @narendramodi 's vision of Sabka Saath,Sabka Vikas.</p>
<p>"Proposed Health Protection Scheme will greatly benefit the common people of the country. This Budget will help India achieve twin objectives of economic growth, equitable distribution of benefits and resources at an accelerated pace," Nadda said in a series of tweets.</p>
<p>He said that farmers, artisans, women, unorganised workers, people living below the poverty line and the youth of the country will greatly benefit through this Budget. PTI ADS TDS .</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d03.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget1_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 14:20:06</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>