<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><news><article><URL><![CDATA[http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/economy/union-budget-2016-17-govt-announces-05-krishi-kalyan-cess-to-fund-farm-programmes_5696381.html]]></URL><Heading><![CDATA[Union Budget 2016-17: Govt announces 0.5% Krishi Kalyan Cess to fund farm programmes]]></Heading><Summary><![CDATA[Jaitley also proposed to amend section 35AD of the Income-tax Act so as to reduce the deduction from 150 percent to 100 percent in the case of a cold chain facility, warehousing facility for storage of agricultural produce, production of fertiliser among others effective from April 1.]]></Summary><Body><![CDATA[<p>The government today announced a Krishi Kalyan Cess of 0.5 percent on all taxable services effective from June 1 this year to fund farm initiatives.</p>
<p>It also proposed cut in excise duty on irrigation pumps and soil nutrients besides slashing import duty on cold storage related equipments.</p>
<p>"I propose to impose a Cess, called the Krishi Kalyan Cess, at 0.5 percent on all taxable services, proceeds of which would be exclusively used for financing initiatives relating to improvement of agriculture and welfare of farmers," Finance Minister Arun Jaitley said while presenting the Budget for 2016-17.</p>
<p>He said the cess would come into force with effect from June 1, 2016. "Input tax credit of this cess will be available for payment of this cess," he added.</p>
<p>Jaitley also proposed to amend section 35AD of the Income-tax Act so as to reduce the deduction from 150 percent to 100 percent in the case of a cold chain facility, warehousing facility for storage of agricultural produce, production of fertiliser among others effective from April 1.</p>
<p>For expenditure on agricultural extensions project, he proposed to amend section 35CCC of the Income-tax Act to restrict the deduction to 100 percent from financial year 2017-18 (Assessment Year 2018-19).</p>
<p>To encourage cold storage facilities in the farm sector, Jaitley exempted service tax on all facilities provided by the state-run National Centre for Cold Chain Development effective from April 1.</p>
<p>At present, the service tax rate is 14 percent.</p>]]></Body><Image><![CDATA[http://img-d02.moneycontrol.co.in/news_image_files/default/Budget1_356x200.jpg]]></Image><Entry_Date>2016-02-29 14:50:10</Entry_Date><Category>Economy</Category><Video_flag>0</Video_flag></article></news>